<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4458423957807258363</id>
   <published>2014-08-21T10:19:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2014-08-21T10:19:21.937-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Latin"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Grammar"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Primer"/>
   <title type="text">A New Allen and Greenough</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://blogs.dickinson.edu/dcc/2014/08/21/a-new-allen-and-greenough/">A New Allen and Greenough</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">With support from the Mellon Digital Humanities Fund and the Roberts  Fund for Classical Studies at Dickinson, we have completed a <a href="http://dcc.dickinson.edu/allen-greenough/">new digital version</a> of that perennially useful tool, <em>Allen and Greenough’s New Latin Grammar for Schools and Colleges</em>, edited by J.B. Greenough, G.L. Kitteredge, A.A. Howard, and Benjamin L. D’Ooge. Boston: Ginn &amp; Company, 1903.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://dcc.dickinson.edu/allen-greenough/"><img alt="Allen_and_Greenough_screenshot" class="alignnone wp-image-832 size-large" height="257" src="http://blogs.dickinson.edu/dcc/files/2014/08/Allen_and_Greenough_screenshot-1024x452.png" width="584" /></a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"></span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The project involved re-scanning the book to have good quality page  images, then editing&nbsp;a set of existing XML files kindly provided by the <a href="http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper/text?doc=Perseus%3Atext%3A1999.04.0001&amp;redirect=true">Perseus Project</a>.  We added to that the newly digitized index, which was not in the  Perseus XML. The purpose there was to make the book browsable via the  index, which is important for user utility, and absent in all other  online versions.&nbsp;On March 23, 2014, Kaylin Bednarz (Dickinson ’15)  finished revision of XML files for Allen &amp; Grenough, and the  creation of html files based on the new XML. She was assisted and  trained in the use of Oxygen software (which converts the XML into  web-ready html) by Matthew Kochis, Postdoctoral Fellow in Digital  Humanities, who also helped with day to day project management.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">In late March, Dickinson web developer Ryan Burke uploaded the html  and XML files to Dickinson servers, and created the web interface for  A&amp;G in html. This revealed issues of formatting: indentations were  often not preserved, resulting in lack of clarity. Some character  formatting was not right, and footnotes from the original print resource  were not clearly displayed. Forward and back buttons had to be put in  for each of the 638 sections.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">On May 20, 2014, Meagan Ayer (PhD in classics and ancient history,  University of Buffalo, 2013) began work hand-editing Allen &amp;  Greenough html files, removing errors and fixing formatting, adding  navigational infrastructure using Adobe Dreamweaver. A few missing XML  files had to be added and converted to html, and those finishing touches  were put on last week.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The differences between our version of A&amp;G and others available on the internet are:</span><br /> <ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Page images attached to every section</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Analytical index makes finding what you need easier</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Functioning word search for the entire work</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Attractive presentation with readable fonts and formatting</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Fully edited to remove spelling errors and OCR misreads (further error notifications appreciated!)</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">And of course the whole is freely available under a Creative Commons  CC-BY-SA license. We plan to systematically link to this version of  A&amp;G in our Latin commentaries, and we are planning to have a similar  work on the Greek side up soon:</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Thomas Dwight Goodell, <em>A School Grammar of Attic Greek</em> (New York: D. Appleton and Co., 1902). This excellent work was scanned by the <a href="https://openlibrary.org/books/OL13517866M/A_school_grammar_of_Attic_Greek">Internet Archive</a>.&nbsp;Last year Bruce Robertson of Mont Allison University kindly performed the OCR using <a href="https://github.com/brobertson/rigaudon">Rigaudon</a>, the output of which is available on <a href="http://heml.mta.ca/lace/runs/schoolgrammarofa00goodrich">Lace</a>.  At Dickinson the OCR output was edited and the XML and html pages  created by Christina Errico. Ryan Burke has created the web interface.  Meagan Ayer is in the process of editing and correcting the html pages.  So look for that in the next few months!</span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">And see also AWOL's&nbsp; list of</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/09/open-access-textbooks.html">Open Access Textbooks and Language Primers Relating to the Ancient World </a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4458423957807258363/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/08/a-new-allen-and-greenough.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4458423957807258363"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4458423957807258363"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/08/a-new-allen-and-greenough.html"
         title="A New Allen and Greenough"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
