<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3945456993936531226</id>
   <published>2015-10-02T12:54:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-10-02T12:54:00.694-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Cultural Heritage"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="UK"/>
   <title type="text">New Open Access Journal: Furnace: The Postgraduate Journal of the Ironbridge International Institute for Cultural Heritage, University of Birmingham</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: small;"><a href="https://furnacejournal.wordpress.com/">Furnace: The Postgraduate Journal of the Ironbridge International Institute for Cultural Heritage, University of Birmingham</a></span><br />ISSN: 2057-519X<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="https://furnacejournal.files.wordpress.com/2014/12/frontpage2.jpg?w=424&amp;h=600" height="200" src="https://furnacejournal.files.wordpress.com/2014/12/frontpage2.jpg?w=424&amp;h=600" width="141" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Postgraduate Journal of the Ironbridge International Institute for Cultural Heritage, University of Birmingham</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">This is a CFP for contributions to a new, open access, postgraduate/ graduate journal called <em>furnace</em> that is edited by young scholars in the Ironbridge International  Institute for Cultural Heritage (IIICH) at the University of Birmingham.  <em>furnace</em> hopes to be a facilitator for sparking debates and  discussions surrounding the expanding and diversifying disciplinary  field of cultural heritage.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The journal’s title references the Institute’s close association with  the Ironbridge Gorge World Heritage Site while suggesting the exciting  percolations of new ideas that come together in intellectual crucibles –  in this case, cultural heritage centres. This third issue of the  journal is edited in collaboration with our partners at CHAMP  (Collaborative for Cultural Heritage Management and Policy) at the  University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Since the establishment of their collaboration in 2012 both IIICH and  CHAMP have sought to generate a series of research questions which  examine Old World and New World perspectives on cultural heritage. Each  side of the Atlantic – North and South – has unique geography, culture  and history that is expressed through their individual heritage. Every  day, however, people, objects and ideas flow backward and forward across  the Atlantic, each shaping the heritage of the other for better or  worse and each shaping the meanings and values that heritage conveys.  Where, and in what ways are these Trans-Atlantic heritages connected?  Where, and in what ways are they not? What can we learn from reflecting  on the different contexts and cultures as they produce, consume, absorb,  resist, and experience the heritage of the other?</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><ul class="children"><li class="page_item page-item-86"><a href="https://furnacejournal.wordpress.com/edition-one/edition-one-cultural-heritage-in-an-international-age/">Issue One: Cultural Heritage in an International&nbsp;Age</a></li><li class="page_item page-item-152"><a href="https://furnacejournal.wordpress.com/edition-one/issue-two/">Issue Two: Cultural Heritage in a Digital&nbsp;Age</a></li></ul></blockquote><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span> <span>See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></span></div><span style="font-size: small;"></span><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span><br /></span></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size: small;">And see <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/09/list-of-student-journals.html">AWOL's List of Student Journals</a>&nbsp;</span>&nbsp; </span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3945456993936531226/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/10/new-open-access-journal-furnace.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3945456993936531226"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3945456993936531226"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/10/new-open-access-journal-furnace.html"
         title="New Open Access Journal: Furnace: The Postgraduate Journal of the Ironbridge International Institute for Cultural Heritage, University of Birmingham"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
