<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3727297802038323918</id>
    <published>2014-09-05T05:54:00.000-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-09-05T06:50:56.046-04:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Maps"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Atlas"/>
    <title type="text">Digital Atlas of Roman and Medieval Civilization (DARMC)</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">[First posted in AWOL 12 October
      2010. Updated 5 September 2014] </span><br /><br /><a
      href="http://medievalmap.harvard.edu/icb/icb.do">Digital Atlas of Roman and Medieval
      Civilization (DARMC)</a><br /><div style="text-align: left;"><blockquote
      class="tr_bq"><div><img
      alt="http://isites.harvard.edu/fs/docs/icb.site40108.files//DARMC_Header.gif"
      src="http://isites.harvard.edu/fs/docs/icb.site40108.files//DARMC_Header.gif" height="28"
      width="640" /></div></blockquote></div><blockquote
      class="tr_bq"><h4 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;">DARMC
      1.3.1 (8/10/2014)</span></h4></blockquote><blockquote><span
      style="font-size: 10pt;"><span style="color: black;">The <i>Digital Atlas of
      Roman and Medieval Civilization</i>(<i>DARMC</i>) makes freely available on
      the internet the best available materials for a Geographic Information Systems (GIS) approach
      to mapping and spatial analysis of the Roman and medieval worlds. <i>DARMC</i>
      allows innovative spatial and temporal analyses of all aspects of the civilizations of western
      Eurasia in the first 1500 years of our era, as well as the generation of original maps
      illustrating differing aspects of ancient and medieval civilization. A work in progress with no
      claim to definitiveness, it has been built in less than three years by a dedicated team of
      Harvard undergraduates, graduate students, research scholars and one professor, with some
      valuable contributions from younger and more senior scholars at other institutions. For more
      details on who we are, please see the People page</span></span><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">...</span></blockquote><div
      class="wrap"><blockquote><ul></ul><div
      class="wrap"><ul></ul><div class="wrap"><ul><li
      class="active"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="now"
      href="http://medievalmap.harvard.edu/icb/icb.do?keyword=k40248&amp;pageid=icb.page188865">Main</a></span></li><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="http://medievalmap.harvard.edu/icb/icb.do?keyword=k40248&amp;pageid=icb.page188868">Maps</a></span></li><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="http://medievalmap.harvard.edu/icb/icb.do?keyword=k40248&amp;pageid=icb.page188870">Bibliography</a></span></li><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="http://medievalmap.harvard.edu/icb/icb.do?keyword=k40248&amp;pageid=icb.page315009">People</a></span></li><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="http://medievalmap.harvard.edu/icb/icb.do?keyword=k40248&amp;pageid=icb.page639171">Map
      Sources</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><a
      href="http://medievalmap.harvard.edu/icb/icb.do?keyword=k40248&amp;pageid=icb.page314952">Links</a></span></li><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="http://medievalmap.harvard.edu/icb/icb.do?keyword=k40248&amp;pageid=icb.page601659">Data
      Availability</a></span></li><li class="last"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><a
      href="http://medievalmap.harvard.edu/icb/icb.do?keyword=k40248&amp;pageid=icb.page188871">Contact
      Us</a></span></li></ul></div><ul></ul></div><ul></ul></blockquote></div><br
      /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>DARMC
      Scholarly Data Series 2014-1:</b><br /> <a
      href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B4KitLDpLpYfMGFuN19HaFJUUHM/edit?usp=sharing"
      target="_blank">M Keil and H Hamerow 2014 - Geodatabase of Rural Anglo-Saxon
      Settlements</a><br /> <i>Abstract: This database presents archaeological
      evidence of Anglo-Saxon rural settlements in England in a format suitable for spatial analysis
      and visualization. It includes details about the presence of archaeological features, site
      occupation dates, and selected bibliographic information for 84 sites. The database was created
      entirely from the data presented in Hamerow 2012, which should be consulted for further
      information and full bibliographic references. Corrections and additions will be gratefully
      received by email at darmc@harvard.edu. We are grateful to Prof. Hamerow for her advice and
      support; all errors or shortcomings are of course our
      responsibility.</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">
      </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><b>DARMC Scholarly Data
      Series 2013-6:</b><br /> </b><a
      href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B4KitLDpLpYfd3NVeXdDTUZidEk/edit?usp=sharing"
      target="_blank">S Coupland 2013 - Geodatabase of Carolingian Coin Hoards: AD
      751-987</a>&nbsp;(Version 1.1) <br /> <i>Abstract:&nbsp;This
      geodatabase is a digital edition of the data provided in Simon Coupland's 2011 "A Checklist of
      Carolingian Coin Hoards 751-987," which gives a comprehensive summary description of hoards
      containing more than three coins issued by the Carolingian dynasty and found in Europe up to
      the date of publication. DARMC contributors have expanded Dr. Coupland's work by adding
      geographic coordinates to hoard findspots and coding numeric fields to facilitate the spatial
      and quantitative analysis of this data. This dataset is not exhaustive of the information from
      Coupland 2011 and careful attention should be paid to the additional notes in the original
      study.</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">
      </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>UPDATE: Version 1.1 of this study
      contains updated and corrected geocodes for selected sites. We are grateful for the assistance
      of Simon Coupland and Johan Ahlfeldt in making these improvements. As this corrected dataset
      supercedes all previous releases, study version 1.0 will no longer be available for
      download.</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">
      </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>DARMC Scholarly Data Series
      2013-5:</b></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B4KitLDpLpYfN3hKM3E2YWltWm8/edit?usp=sharing"
      target="_blank">M McCormick et al. 2013 - Roman Road Network (version 2008)
      [Shapefile]</a></span> <span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><i>Abstract:This file provides a portable, digital version of the Roman
      roads identified in the Barrington Atlas, which users can visualize in combination with their
      own historical data.</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">
      </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>DARMC Scholarly Data Series
      2013-4:</b></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B4KitLDpLpYfRjdORWw2QlRfZTA/edit?usp=sharing"
      target="_blank">L Grigoli and B Maione-Downing 2013 - France: Diocese and Archdiocese
      Boundaries ca. 1000</a></span> <span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><i>Abstract: This shapefile represents our best current approximation of the
      boundaries and provincial (or archidiocesan) organization of the bishoprics of the territory of
      modern France as they existed ca. 1000. The contributors have drawn on the diocesan and
      archdiocesan (provincial) boundaries as reported in Parisse and Leuridan
      1994.</i>&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">
      </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>DARMC Scholarly Data Series
      2013-3:&nbsp;</b></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B4KitLDpLpYfblFRcndaTkRrQ00/edit?usp=sharing"
      target="_blank">M McCormick et al. 2013 - Archaeology of Rats AD 1-1500</a> [<a
      href="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B4KitLDpLpYfdWdoRFVoMTdHMG8/edit?usp=sharing"
      target="_blank">Shapefile Version</a>] </span> <span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><i>Abstract: This database represents an attempt to unify reported finds of
      rat remains - particularly of the black rat (R. Rattus) - in archaeological contexts dated
      between 1 and 1500 AD, and was originally created to underpin the synthesis in McCormick 2003;
      it contains a few additions made since then. In recent years, historians and archaeologists
      have come to understand these remains to be an important proxy for the spread of disease,
      patterns of human migration and economic activity. When possible, attempts have been made to
      geocode these archaeological sites to present a database that will allow analysis of patterns
      over time and space. Although this database contains some records of rat finds (or potential
      rat finds) in contexts dated to the pre-Christian era, no attempt is made to cover these years
      comprehensively.</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">
      </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>DARMC Scholarly Data Series
      2013-2:</b></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B4KitLDpLpYfUlhfc0hIM1lYazA/edit?usp=sharing"
      target="_blank">A de Graauw 2014 - Geodatabase of Ancient Ports and Harbors (version
      1.1)</a></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Abstract: This
      database presents work done by Arthur de Graauw to collect, identify and locate ancient
      harbours and ports. It is based on a study of existing documentation and does not aim to find
      unknown ports. The result is a list of around 2900 ancient ports based on the writings of 66
      ancient authors and a few modern authors, incl. the Barrington Atlas. A harbour is a place
      where ships can seek shelter. In the concept of "shelter" must be included anchorages, landing
      places on beaches and ports with structures like, access channels, breakwaters, jetties,
      landing stages, quays, warehouses for storage of commodities and equipment, shipsheds and
      slipways for ships. Shelters of interest for this catalogue include all places which may have
      been used by seafarers sailing over long distances. This means that shelters for e.g. local
      fishermen who may have landed their boats on the beach in front of their homes, are of lesser
      interest. Only maritime harbours are listed, but some river ports that could be reached by deep
      sea ships are also included.</i></span><br /><span style="font-size:
      x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>UPDATE: Version 1.1
      of this study brings this geodatabase into line with the places listed in "Ancient Ports and
      Harbors: The Catalog" 4th ed.</i></span><br /><span style="font-size:
      x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>DARMC Scholarly
      Data Series 2013-1:</b></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B4KitLDpLpYfM085TTZZUnNEdkU/edit?usp=sharing"
      target="_blank">M McCormick et al. 2013 - Summary Geodatabase of Shipwrecks: Status
      2008</a>&nbsp;[-<a
      href="http://cga-3.hmdc.harvard.edu/darmc/data/Michael%20McCormick%20et%20al.,%20Summary%20Geodatabase%20of%20Shipwrecks%20AD%201-1500,%20Status%202008.xlsx"
      target="_blank">Alternate Link</a>-]</span> <span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><i>Abstract:&nbsp;This summary database provides basic geographic and
      archaeological information on 1064 shipwrecks documented by A.J. Parker 1992 and subsequent
      publications. The geodatabase includes, where available, concise information about main
      cargoes, ship or wreck distribution sizes, ship gear, and essential bibliography. The user
      should refer to the original publications for full details. This file represents the state of
      the geodatabase in April 2008, when M. McCormick 2012 "Movements and markets in the first
      millennium: information, containers and shipwrecks" was sent to press; a small number of wrecks
      were added down to 2010. Our team continues to work toward future updates of the geodatabase of
      shipwrecks. Additional information, corrections, and data about new wrecks will be received
      gratefully at darmc@harvard.edu.</i></span><br /><span style="font-size:
      x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>DARMC Scholarly
      Data Series 2012-2:</b></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="http://cga-3.hmdc.harvard.edu/darmc/data/Michael%20McCormick%20Historical%20Precipitation%20Central%20Europe%20AD%201013-1504.xlsx"
      target="_blank">M McCormick et al. 2012 - Historical Precipitation in Central Europe, AD
      1013 - 1504</a></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Abstract:
      Climate variations influenced the agricultural productivity, health risk, and conflict level of
      preindustrial societies. Discrimination between environmental and anthropogenic impacts on past
      civilizations, however, remains difficult because of the paucity of high-resolution
      paleoclimatic evidence. We present tree ring–based reconstructions of central European summer
      precipitation and temperature variability over the past 2500 years. Recent warming is
      unprecedented, but modern hydroclimatic variations may have at times been exceeded in magnitude
      and duration. Wet and warm summers occurred during periods of Roman and medieval prosperity.
      Increased climate variability from ~250 to 600 C.E. coincided with the demise of the western
      Roman Empire and the turmoil of the Migration Period. Such historical data may provide a basis
      for counteracting the recent political and fiscal reluctance to mitigate projected climate
      change. The present geodatabase presents the details of the historical records which were used
      to test the accuracy of the AMJ precipitation record reconstructed from the dendrodata. See
      Büntgen et al. 2011, 579 and Figure 3A; and Supporting Online Material,
      5.</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">
      </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>DARMC Scholarly Data Series
      2012-1:</b></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Ah3vc5ApPJLRdDNsR2pWckNKNWpzbTBES1N1OXdkbVE&amp;usp=sharing"
      target="_blank">M McCormick, K Harper, A M More, K Gibson 2012 - Historical Evidence on
      Roman and Post-Roman Climate, 100 BC to 800 AD</a></span> <span
      style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Updated 8/6/2014 - Formatting
      Changes</b>&nbsp;<i><i>Abstract: Growing scientific evidence from modern
      climate science is loaded with implications for the environmental history of the Roman Empire
      and its successor societies. The written and archaeological evidence, although richer than
      commonly realized, is unevenly distributed over time and space. A first synthesis of what the
      written records and multiple natural archives (multi-proxy data) indicate about climate change
      and variability across western Eurasia from c. 100 B.C. to 800 A.D. confirms that the Roman
      Empire rose during a period of stable and favorable climatic conditions, which deteriorated
      during the Empire's third-century crisis. A second, briefer period of favorable conditions
      coincided with the Empire's recovery in the fourth century; regional differences in climate
      conditions parallel the diverging fates of the eastern and western Empires in subsequent
      centuries. Climate conditions beyond the Empire's boundaries also played an important role by
      affecting food production in the Nile valley, and by encouraging two major migrations and
      invasions of pastoral peoples from Central Asia.&nbsp;This geodatabase of climate events
      documented in and around the Roman Empire and its successor societies in ancient and early
      medieval written sources was created by the DARMC contributors on the basis of the secondary
      and primary sources cited in the geodatabase. It is not surely not exhaustive, but we hope that
      as such, it will already be useful to other researchers. We welcome additional evidence and
      corrections.</i></i></span><br /><span style="font-size:
      x-small;"> </span><br /><hr /><span style="font-size: x-small;">
      </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>DARMC WMS
      Services</b><br />DARMC offers all its databases as WMS format (<a
      href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_Map_Service" target="_blank">Web Map
      Server</a>), and REST format (<a
      href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_state_transfer"
      target="_blank">Representational state transfer</a>). You can browse the full list of
      DARMC WMS and REST services here: (<a
      href="http://cga6.cga.harvard.edu/arcgis/rest/services/darmc/roman/MapServer"
      target="_blank">http://cga6.cga.harvard.edu/arcgis/rest/services/darmc/roman/MapServer</a>).
      If you would like to visualize the DARMC WMS in ArcGIS, plese read the&nbsp;<a
      href="http://help.arcgis.com/en/arcgisdesktop/10.0/help/index.html#//00sp0000000s000000.htm"
      target="_blank">ESRI Documentation</a>&nbsp;for WMS.</span><br
      /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">Below few steps to get the correct DARMC WMS URL:</span><br /><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><br /><ol><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">Full DARMC WMS URL(&nbsp;<a
      href="http://cga6.cga.harvard.edu/arcgis/services/darmc/roman/MapServer/WMSServer?request=GetCapabilities&amp;service=WMS"
      target="_blank">http://cga6.cga.harvard.edu/arcgis/services/darmc/roman/MapServer/WMSServer?</a>)</span></li><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">Read&nbsp;<a
      href="http://help.arcgis.com/en/arcgisdesktop/10.0/help/index.html#//00sp0000000s000000.htm"
      target="_blank">the instruction provided by ESRI</a>&nbsp;to add the WMS in
      ArcGIS.</span></li></ol><span style="font-size: x-small;">
      </span><br /><div class="p1"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><b>DARMC WMS Services and
      WorldMap</b></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">
      </span><br /><div class="p2"><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you
      would like to visualize the DARMC WMS in WorldMap (<a href="http://worldmap.harvard.edu/"
      target="_blank"><span class="s1">http://worldmap.harvard.edu/</span></a>),
      please read the instruction provided in the WorldMap Help doc under Section 4 (<a
      href="http://worldmap.harvard.edu/site_media/docs/WorldMap_Help.pdf"
      target="_blank"><span
      class="s1">http://worldmap.harvard.edu/site_media/docs/WorldMap_Help.pdf</span></a>)</span></div></blockquote><div
      class="p2" style="text-align: center;">And see AWOL's <a
      href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/09/roundup-of-resources-on-ancient.html">Roundup
      of Resources on Ancient Geography</a></div><div class="p2"><br
      /></div><script
      src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986"
      type="text/javascript"></script>]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3727297802038323918/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/09/digital-atlas-of-roman-and-medieval.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3727297802038323918"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3727297802038323918"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/09/digital-atlas-of-roman-and-medieval.html"
         title="Digital Atlas of Roman and Medieval Civilization (DARMC)"/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
