<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-819832869923324809</id>
   <published>2015-08-01T14:28:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-10-14T11:15:03.450-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Reception"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Arabic"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greek"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Studia graeco-arabica</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">&nbsp;[First posted in AWOL 2 April 2011. Updated 1 August 2015]</span><br /><br /><a href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/index.php?id=20">Studia graeco-arabica</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">&nbsp;<img alt="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/immagini/testata.jpg" class="decoded" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/immagini/testata.jpg" height="42" width="400" /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i> </i></span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: left;"><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Studia graeco-arabica</i> is the journal on line of the European Research Council Advanced Grant 249431 <a href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/"><i>Greek into Arabic. Philosophical Concepts and Linguistic Bridges</i></a>.  It features critical articles and reviews on the transmission of  philosophical and scientific texts from and into various languages –  Greek, Syriac, Arabic, and Latin – from late Antiquity to the Middle  Ages and Renaissance.</span></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><ul style="text-align: left;"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/index.php?id=203">Studia graeco-arabica 5 (2015)</a><a href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/index.php?id=203"><br /></a></span></li></ul><div class="text"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="data_text" style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 1-11</span></div><div class="titolo_news" style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/1-SGA_V_2015_CHIARADONNA.pdf">Logica  e teologia nel primo neoplatonismo A proposito di Anon., In Parm. XI  5-19 e Iambl., Risposta a Porfirio [De Mysteriis] I, 4</a></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Riccardo Chiaradonna</b><br />    According to the anonymous commentator on Plato’s Parmenides the  One-being can (under certain conditions) be thought to participate in  the first One above being (In Parm., XI-XII). The commentator offers two  explanations of this fact, the first of which (In Parm., XI, 5-19) is  closely reminiscent of the Peripatetic doctrine of essential  predication. Accordingly, the structure of the second One can be equated  to that of a species resulting from the composition of a genus (one)  and a specific differentia (being / ousia). Several parallels connect  this solution with the debates on Aristotle’s theory of predication  attested in the Neoplatonic commentaries on the Categories. The  parallels with Porphyry’s logical works are particularly valuable.  Furthermore, in his Response to Porphyry, Iamblichus presents Porphyry’s  account of the divine hierarchy as misleadingly implying that divine  beings are species under the same common genus: a position which is  virtually identical to that of the anonymous commentator, and finds no  parallel in Neoplatonic authors other than Porphyry. This hitherto  unnoticed parallel further suggests that Porphyry is the author of the  anonymous commentary, as advanced by R.&nbsp;Chiaradonna, “Nota su  partecipazione e atto d’essere nel neoplatonismo: l’anonimo Commento al  Parmenide”, Studia graeco-arabica, 2 [2012], pp. 87-97.     </span></div></blockquote></div><blockquote><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 13-26</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/2-SGA_V_2015_CODA.pdf">Un  fragment du commentaire perdu au De Caelo d’ Alexandre d’ Aphrodise sur  les différents sens des termes “engendré” et “inengendré” (Thémistius,  In De Caelo, p. 43.3-44.17 Landauer)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Elisa Coda</b><br />     Well before Philoponus’ attack against eternalism and Simplicius’  response, taking the form of a colossal commentary on Aristotle’s De  Caelo, another thinker, the 4th century rhetorician and philosopher  Themistius, had embarked upon a running exegesis of the this  Aristotelian work. Themistius still had at his disposal the commentary  on the De Caelo penned by Alexander of Aphrodisias, lost to us.  Notwithstanding its importance, Themistius’ paraphrase of the De Caelo  is poorly known: the Greek text is lost; a medieval Hebrew translation  made on the basis of a lost Arabic one survives, together with a Latin  translation of the Hebrew text, made during the Renaissance. From this  unpromising material it is however possible to unravel important issues.  This article deals with Themistius’ and Alexander’s exegeses of the  meaning of the key terms “generated” and “ungenerated” and argues that  Themistius attests the classification made by Alexander, but in his own  exegesis endorses the typical Neoplatonic distinction between  “generated” as “temporally generated”, on the one hand, and “generated”  as “having a cause of its coming into being”, on the other.      </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 27-52</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/3-SGA_V_2015_Hoffmann.pdf">Le σκοπός du traité aristotélicien Du Ciel selon Simplicius. Exégèse, dialectique, théologie</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Philippe Hoffmann</b><br />    A six-page Prologue introduces the commentary on Aristotle’s De  Caelo written by Simplicius after 529 AD. As usual in the exegeses  typical of the Neoplatonic schools of late Antiquity, this Prologue  addresses a series of preliminary questions that are meant to steer the  interpretation in its entirety, as well as to frame the text to be  commented upon within the reading canon of the Aristotelian works, which  were intended to provide the propaedeutics to the reading canon of  Plato’s dialogues. Simplicius addresses the question of the scope of De  Caelo, discussing the interpretations advanced by Alexander of  Aphrodisias, Iamblichus, and Syrianus. According to Alexander, this  treatise deals with the universe as a whole, as well as with the five  simple bodies contained in it. It was with Iamblichus, who advocated the  idea that for each Platonic dialogue there was only one σκοπός, that  the unity of a philosophical work was raised to the rank of a general  rule. According to Iamblichus, the σκοπός of the De Caelo is the divine  body of heaven. As a consequence, the primary elements that depend upon  the heavens are included in the treatise. Syrianus deepens the  theological tendency implied in Iamblichus’ interpretation: for him, the  σκοπός of the De Caelo is primarily the divine body of heaven, and only  secondarily the set of sublunar elements. Simplicius treasures the  commentary by Alexander; nevertheless, he questions the σκοπός assigned  by him: Alexander underestimated the importance of the unity of the  treatise, even though his intention to account for each and every  question raised by Aristotle was laudable. Contrarily, Syrianus was  right in emphasizing the theological vein of the De Caelo, but focussed  only on the section on the divine body of heaven, playing down books III  and IV as if they were only ancillary, thus forgetting that the σκοπός  must account for the whole of the treatise at hand. Between the two  positions, Simplicius advocates the idea of a synthetical σκοπός,  following in the footsteps of Iamblichus’ interpretation, but taking  systematically into account the best of Alexander’s. The σκοπός of the  De Caelo is the divine heaven, that “communicates” its perfections to  the entire universe. Simplicius’ position is revealed to be very  different with respect to that of other commentators like Ammonius and  Philoponus, who both considered that the title was self-evident and  required no special investigation.     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 53-104</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/4-SGA_V_2015_Hugonnard-Roche.pdf">Questions de logique au VIIe siècle Les épîtres syriaques de Sévère Sebokht et leurs sources grecques</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Henri Hugonnard-Roche</b><br />    The aim of this paper is to provide the edition, with translation  and commentary, of a short Syriac epistle by Severus Sebokht, bishop of  Qenneshre (7th century), in which the author discusses some issues  related to Aristotle’s Peri Hermeneias and Analytics. The commentary  examines in detail Severus’ Syriac text by comparison with the Greek  sources, namely the commentaries by Alexander of Aphrodisias, Ammonius,  and Philoponus. In addition, in an appendix a study is included of a  part of another epistle by Severus, concerning the existence of the  possible, which shows a remarkable similarity with Alexander’s Question  II 4.     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 /2015, pp. 105-128</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/5-SGA_V_2015_VILLEY_01.pdf">Ammonius d’ Alexandrie et le Traité sur l’astrolabe de Sévère Sebokht</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Émilie Villey</b><br />    This contribution presents the text and translation of an  unpublished part of the Syriac Treatise on the Astrolabe by Severus  Sebokht recently found in a manuscript of Mardin (Turkey). This  supplement to the text contains an astronomical exercise applied to the  year 523 AD. Thanks to this date and to a detailed analysis of the  structure of the text, we are now able to date the Greek treatise used  by Severus Sebokht, and to specify how this 7th century Syriac scholar  integrated it into his composition. Unfortunately, the name of the Greek  author is never given in our document; nevertheless a combination of  external information points to Ammonius of Alexandria as to its author.     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 129-143</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/6-SGA_V_2015_ZONTA.pdf">Iwānnīs of Dārā On Soul's Virtues. About a Late Antiquity Greek Philosophical Work among Syrians and Arabs</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Mauro Zonta</b><br />    The Syriac author Iwānnīs of Dārā (first half of the 9th century),  in his still unpublished Treatise on the Soul, employed a  pseudo-Platonic treatise On the Subsistence of Soul’s Virtues among his  sources: a treatise whose text is lost in Greek, but is preserved in an  Arabic version. A comparison of the Arabic version with the Syriac  quotations found in Iwānnīs of Dārā’s work strongly suggests that the  former depends upon a lost Syriac complete version, from which the  latter was taken, too. The Syriac version also influenced some passages  of Severus bar Šakkō’s Book of Dialogues, so showing the diffusion of  this text by this way in Near East till to 1240. Moreover, there is a still unknown influence of it upon a passage of a  work by a Judaeo-Arabic author, a contemporary and compatriot of Iwānnīs  of Dārā: Dawūd al-Muqammiṣ’s Twenty Chapters, where the same Syriac  text found in Iwānnīs of Dārā’s own work seems to have been used as a  source. This passage of Dawūd al-Muqammiṣ’s work might have influenced  even a passage of Aḥmad ibn Miskawayh’s Correction of Morals. In the  Appendix, the Syriac terminology of some important passages of Iwānnīs  of Dārā’s work are compared with the terminology found in the  corresponding passages of some Patristic Greek and Arabic texts.     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 145-164</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/7-SGA-V_2015-MENCHELLI.pdf">Nota  storico-tradizionale al Commento al Timeo di Proclo nelle età macedone,  comnena, paleologa tra supporti librari e documentari (il rotolo di  Patmos, Eileton897, il Marc.gr.195 e la collezione filosofica; il  Coisl.322, il Chis. RVIII58, il Marc.gr.194</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Mariella Menchelli</b><br />    In this paper some notes on the text tradition of Book I and Book  III of Proclus’ Commentary on Plato’s Timaeus are offered, on the basis  of new palaeographical studies of the manuscripts Marc. gr. 194, Par.  Coisl. 322, Chis. R VIII 58, and on that of the new finding of a paper  scroll containing long sections of Book III in Patmos, Monastery of St.  John the Theologian. As for Book I, I will show that the manuscripts  Marc. gr. 194 (until p. 130.24 Diehl) and Chis. R VIII 58 (from p.  130.24 Diehl) are new primary witnesses, and that the manuscript Par.  Coisl. 322 (dated 13th-14th&nbsp;cent.) deserves more attention for the  ancient transmission of the text. As for Book III, I will show that the  oldest extant source is now the Patmos scroll, near to Marc. gr.195,  also for the extant scholia, and presumably to the exemplar belonging to  the “Philosophical Collection”.     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 165-204</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/8-SGA_V_2015_DANCONA.pdf">Hellenistic Philosophy in Baghdad. Plotinus’ anti-Stoic Argumentations and their Arabic Survival</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Cristina D'Ancona</b><br />    Submitted to the conference “Die Blüte der arabischen Philosophie  und ihre Früchte in Europa. Festkolloquium zum 75. Geburtstag von  Gerhard Endreß” organized by Jörn Thielmann and Cleophea Ferrari in  Bochum, November 26-27, 2014, this paper deals with Plotinus’ arguments  against total blending (κρᾶσις δι’ ὅλων) and their reception in the  formative period of Arabic philosophy. Actual dissection of a body by a  body to infinity proves to be impossible: hence, only an incorporeal  reality – the soul – can be omnipresent in the body. This Plotinian  topic, reminiscent of the interschool polemics of the Imperial age, was  transmitted to the Arabic-speaking philosophers through the adapted  version of Ennead IV 7[2].     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 205-245</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/9-SGA_V_2015_WAKELNIG.pdf">Greek Sages on the Tawḥīd Ancient Philosophy in Accord with the Islamic Doctrine of the Oneness of God</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Elvira Wakelnig</b><br />    The aim of this article is to present and put into context a curious  little treatise preserved in a Tehran manuscript with the intriguing  title Nawādir min Kalām al-Falāsifa al-Muwaḥḥidīn wa-l-aʿlām al-māḍiyīn,  The Most Precious Words of the Philosophers Professing the Oneness of  God and of the Authorities of the Past. The treatise contains a  collection of sayings of the ancient Greeks like Hermes, Pythagoras and  Plato and of the Alexandrians related to the central doctrine of Islam,  the oneness of God (tawḥīd). The material recalls the first Christian  apologies addressing the pagans in an attempt to win them over to the  new religion by demonstrating that already their authorities of the past  had believed in only one god. The treatise is, however, strikingly  different from other Arabic texts which link Greek philosophers to the  tawḥīd as I want to show by excerpts from Christian apologies and the  philosophical tradition of al-Kindī.     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 247-280</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/10-SGA_V_2015_GOODMAN.pdf">How Epicurean was Rāzī?</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Lenn E. Goodman</b><br />    Muḥammad b. Zakariyāʾ al-Rāzī, a major contributor to the Galenic  tradition in medicine, pursued philosophy as well, as Galen had urged  physicians to do. Rāzī believes in critical thinking and intellectual  progress. He rejects the authority of prophets: They are, at best,  impostors, and the exclusivity of claims to revelation breeds bloodshed  rather than salvation. God enlightens us, Rāzī argues, through the gift  of reason, not the visions of a few: All of us are capable, if we put  our minds to it, of thinking for ourselves, well enough in fact for the  soul to make her way back to her true home. Creation, Rāzī argues,  resulted from the over-ebullience of a soul too eager for embodiment,  too spontaneous to control herself without the gift of reason, and too  innocent to foresee that her sufferings would inevitably outweigh the  peaceful pleasures she would seek in the world her vivacity sets in  motion. Rāzī’s world did begin. But matter, time, space, and soul, as  well as God, are eternal. Space and time, pace Aristotle, are absolute.  Atoms are uncreated and indestructible. Rāzī hoped for immortality but  had no truck with the tales of physical resurrection. He grounds his  ethics chiefly on prudential counsels: The appetites are self-enlarging;  the passions, self-aggravating and inevitably frustrate. Pleasures,  rightly understood, result from the relief of pain or other dislocation.  Their optimum is found not in ever more intense sensation but in the  respite that awaits us when we rein in desire. The present paper  explores the roots of Rāzī’s ethics and cosmology, seeking to understand  his affinities with Epicurus and other predecessors including Plato –  with Galen frequently the mediator. Rāzī learns from Galen much of what  he knows of philosophy. But independence of mind is his most striking  philosophical attribute.     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 281-298</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/11-SGA_V_2015_WOERTHER.pdf">De  l’ ὑπόκρισις (hypokrisis) au أخذ بالوجوه&nbsp;(aḫḏ bi-l-wuǧūh).  L’ interprétation de l’ action oratoire par Averroès dans le Commentaire  moyen à la Rhétorique d’ Aristote</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Frédérique Woerther</b><br />    The notion of ὑπόκρισις (hypokrisis) was employed for the first time  with the meaning of “rhetorical delivery” in Aristotle’s Rhetoric,  where it is the target of a short and highly critical analysis. A  practice borrowed directly from the theatre, and apparently resistant to  any form of technicisation that might give it a legitimate place  alongside the other means of rhetorical persuasion, ὑπόκρισις  (hypokrisis) was nevertheless extremely effective–as Aristotle  acknowledged with undisguised irritation. In the face of Aristotle’s  ambivalence, and torn between a purist and idealist conception of  rhetoric on the one hand, and the contemporary reality of speech, which  required him to recognise a practice of which he could not approve, on  the other, what was Averroes’ attitude in his Middle Commentary on the  Rhetoric? Dependent on the Arabic version of the Rhetoric where the term  ὑπόκρισις (hypokrisis) was – with one exception – translated by the  expression أخذ بالوجوه (aḫḏ bi-l-wuǧūh) – “the taking of faces” –, has  Averroes followed Aristotle in his hesitations and reticences? Or has he  instead chosen to legitimise the use of hypokrisis in rhetorical  technique? The analysis of the Rushdian interpretation of the ‘taking of  faces’ will allow a better understanding of Averroes’ exegetical  method, and grasp of what it meant, to him, to be faithful to the First  Master.     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 299-320</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/12-SGA_V_2015_TERRIER.pdf">La  représentation de la sagesse grecque comme discours et mode de vie chez  les philosophes šīʿites de l’ Iran safavide (XIe/XVIIe siècle)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Mathieu Terrier</b><br />    This article analyzes the references to Pythagoras, Empedocles,  Socrates, Plato, Aristotle, and Diogenes in the works of the Šī‘i  philosophers of Safavid Iran Mīr Dāmād, Mullā Ṣadrā, and Quṭb al-Dīn  Aškevarī. Despite their lacunar knowledge of the aforementioned  philosophers, these Persian thinkers saw ancient philosophy – labelled  “wisdom” (ḥikma) – both as a speech of truth and as a way of life, a  position that is at times reminiscent of Pierre Hadot’s approach to  ancient philosophy as a whole. This “wisdom” was part and parcel of  their own philosophical project. In their eyes the representation of  Greek wisdom is grounded on a historiography connecting the Greek sages  to the “niche of the prophetic lights” (miškāt anwār al-nubuwwa). This  representation includes, in its theoretical dimension, a pedagogy, a  theology, an onto-cosmology, a psychology, and an eschatology. In its  practical dimension, it conjugates asceticism with a position of  compromise with intra-mundane life. On all these topics, the Šī‘i  philosophers try to conciliate the views of the Greek philosophers with  the ḥadīṯs of the Imāms.     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 321-344</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/13-SGA_V_2015_EKSELL.pdf">Pragmatic Markers from Greek into Arabic. A Case Study on Translations by Isḥāq ibn Ḥunayn</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Kerstin Eksell</b><br />    Classical Greek is known for its abundant use of particles and  connectives for organising the textual discourse. In Arabic, on the  other hand, such markers are much less frequent, which causes problems  in translating from Greek into Arabic. The aim of this study is to  examine the transfer of Greek particles into Classical Arabic texts. The  material consists of short text samples from the Physics by Aristotle  and the Elements by Euclid, both of which were translated by the  well-established translator Isḥāq ibn Ḥunayn. The translator seems to  have followed a consistent regime of strategies, with the general aim to  translate as closely and accurately as possible, while avoiding direct  borrowing from Greek. The taxis of the source text was used as a model  for the target text, which is characterised by its syntactic iconicity  in relation to the source text. It is suggested that a special generic  style became established for expressing a scholarly identity of mixed  Greek and Arabic origin, different from other stylistic developments of  literature within the Arabo-Islamic space.     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 345-363</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/14-SGA_V_2015_ROEDER.pdf">Alpha into Alif. Schnittstellen zwischen Schriftkunde und Informatik am Beispiel von Unicode im Glossarium Graeco-Arabicum</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Torsten Roeder</b><br />    The project Glossarium Graeco-Arabicum connects the study of writing  systems with the field of information science, utilizing the Unicode  standard. This paper points out particular historical developments both  in philology and informatics that help to develop a modern approach to  working in digital poly-alphabetical environments, based on  interdisciplinary expertise. A description of how Unicode was  implemented to represent ancient Greek and classical Arabic is followed  by a historical outline of computer writing systems. Essential aspects  are letter collationing, writing directions and user interfaces. The  conclusion emphasizes the importance of a bilateral understanding of  historical and technical disciplines.     </span></div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 367-374</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/a-_Reviews__S._Alexandru-Aristotle_s_Metaphysics_Lambda.pdf">[Reviews]  S. Alexandru, Aristotle’s Metaphysics Lambda. Annotated Critical  Edition based upon a Systematic Investigation of Greek, Latin, Arabic  and Hebrew Sources, Brill, Leiden 2013 (Philosophia Antiqua, 135)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Cristina D'Ancona</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 375-384</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/b-_Review__I._Hadot-Athenian_and_Alexandrian_Neoplatonism_and_the_Harmonization_of_Aristotle_and_Plato.pdf">[Review]  I. Hadot, Athenian and Alexandrian Neoplatonism and the Harmonization  of Aristotle and Plato, translated by M. Chase, Brill, Leiden – Boston  2015 (Studies in Platonism, Neoplatonism, and the Platonic Tradition,  18)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Cristina D'Ancona</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 385-388</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/c-_Review__I._Hadot__Le_neoplatonicien_Simplicius_a_la_lumiere_des_recherches_contemporaines._Un_bilan_critique-CHEMI.pdf">[Review]  I. Hadot, Le néoplatonicien Simplicius à la lumière des recherches  contemporaines. Un bilan critique. Avec deux contributions de Ph.  Vallat, Academia-Verlag, Sankt Augustin 2014</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Germana Chemi</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 389-394</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/d-_Review_-Villey-Les_sciences_en_syriaque-CELIA.pdf">[Review] É. Villey (éd.), Les sciences en syriaque, Geuthner, Paris 2014 (Études Syriaques, 11)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Francesco Celia</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 395-398</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/e-_Review_-Geoffroy-Janssens-Sebti-Avicenna-Commentaire-Lambda-MARTINIBONADEO.pdf">[Review]  Avicenne (Ibn Sīnā), Commentaire sur le livre Lambda de la Métaphysique  d’ Aristote (chapitres 6-10)..., Édition critique, traduction et notes  par M. Geoffroy, J. Janssens et M. Sebti, Vrin, Paris 2014 (Études  Musulmanes, 43)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Cecilia Martini Bonadeo</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 399-407</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/a-_Book_Announcement__The_Routledge_Handbook_of_Neoplatonism.pdf">[Book  Announcement] The Routledge Handbook of Neoplatonism, ed. by P. Remes  and S. Slaveva Griffin, Routledge, London – New York 2014 (Routledge  Handbooks in Philosophy)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Cristina D'Ancona</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 407-410</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/b-_Book_Announcement_-Goulet-Caze-Cynisme.pdf">[Book Announcement] M.-O. Goulet-Cazé, Cynisme et christianisme dans l’ Antiquité, Vrin, Paris 2014 (Textes et traditions, 26)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Cristina D'Ancona</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica, pp. 410-412</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/c-_Book_Announcement_-Gerts-Dillon-Russell-Aeneas-of-Gaza.pdf">[Book  Announcement] Aeneas of Gaza: Theophrastus. With Zacharias of Mytilene:  Ammonius, translated by S. Gerts, J. Dillon &amp; D. Russell, Preface  by R. Sorabji, Bloomsbury, London - New Delhi - New York - Sydney  (Ancient Commentators on Aristotle)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Cristina D'Ancona</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 412-414</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/d-_Book_Announcement_-Moezzi-De-Smet-Controverses.pdf">[Book  Announcement] Controverses sur les écritures canoniques de l’Islam,  sous la direction de D. De Smet - M. A. Amir-Moezzi, Éditions du Cerf,  Paris 2014 (Islam. Nouvelles approches)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Elisa Coda</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 414-415</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/e-_Book_Announcement_-Al-Khalili-La-casa-della-saggezza.pdf">[Book  Announcement] Jim Al-Khalili, La casa della saggezza. L’epoca d’oro  della scienza araba, trad. di Andrea Migliori, Bollati Boringhieri,  Torino 2013 (Saggi Scienze)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Marco Di Branco</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 416-417</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/f-_Book_Announcement_-Gutas-Avicenna.pdf">[Book  Announcement] D. Gutas, Avicenna and the Aristotelian Tradition.  Introduction to Reading Avicenna’s Philosophical Works. Second, Revised  and Enlarged Edition, Including an Inventory of Avicenna’s Authentic  Works, Brill, Leiden&nbsp;- Boston 2014 </a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Cecilia Martini Bonadeo</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 417-419</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/g-_Book_Announcement_-Ad-notitiam-ignoti.pdf">[Book  Announcement] Ad notitiam ignoti. L’Organon dans la translatio  studiorum à l’époque d’ Albert le Grand, édité par Julie  Brumberg-Chaumont, Brepols, Turnhout 2013 (Studia Artistarum, Études sur  la Faculté des Arts dans les universités médiévales 37)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Cleophea Ferrari</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, pp. 419-421</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/h-_Book_Announcement__A_Companion_to_the_Latin_Medieval_Commentaries_on_Aristotle-Metaphysics.pdf">[Book  Announcement] A Companion to the Latin Medieval Commentaries on  Aristotle’s Metaphysics, ed. by F. Amerini and G.&nbsp;Galluzzo, Brill,  Leiden - Boston 2014 (Brill’s Companions to the Christian Tradition, 43)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Cristina D'Ancona</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, p. 422</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/i-_Book_Announcement_-Pfeiffer-Tariz.pdf">[Book  Announcement] Politics, Patronage and the Transmission of Knowledge in  13th-15th Century Tabriz, ed. by J. Pfeiffer, Leiden-Brill, Boston 2014  (Iran Studies, 8)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Marco Di Branco</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, p. 423</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/l-_Book_Announcement_-Leicht-Freudenthal-Steinschneider.pdf">[Book  Announcement] Studies on Steinschneider. Moritz Steinschneider and the  Emergence of the Science of Judaism in Nineteenth Century Germany,  edited by R. Leicht and G. Freudenthal, Brill, Leiden&nbsp;-&nbsp;Boston 2012  (Studies in Jewish History and Culture, 33)</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Elisa Coda</b></span>         </div></div><div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"><div class="icona"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /></span></div><div class="text"><div class="data_text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studia graeco-arabica 5 / 2015, p. 424</span></div><div class="titolo_news"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/Paolo-Accattino_In-Memoriam.pdf">Paolo Accattino. In Memoriam</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Bruno Centrone</b></span>         </div></div><div id="stampa" style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/index.php?id=203#" title="stampa"><img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/bt_stampa.gif" height="28" width="26" /></a></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div></blockquote></blockquote><div style="text-align: left;"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><ul style="font-family: Arial;"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/index.php?id=29">Studia graeco-arabica 1 (2011), Pacini Editore, Pisa 2012</a></span></li></ul><ul style="font-family: Arial;"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/index.php?id=79">Studia graeco-arabica 2 (2012). In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds, Pacini Editore, Pisa 2012</a></span></li></ul><ul style="font-family: Arial;"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/index.php?id=101">Studia graeco-arabica 3 (2013), Pacini Editore, Pisa 2013</a></span></li></ul><ul style="font-family: Arial;"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/index.php?id=186">Studia graeco-arabica 4 (2014), Pacini Editore, Pisa 2014</a></span></li></ul></blockquote></div><br />See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a><br /><br />And see also <a href="http://www.graeco-arabic-studies.org/" target="_blank">A Digital Corpus for Graeco-Arabic Studies</a> </div><div><br /><br /><br /><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js#username=xa-4b4cc6be5f7e0135" type="text/javascript"></script></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/819832869923324809/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/04/new-open-access-journal-studia-graeco.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/819832869923324809"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/819832869923324809"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/04/new-open-access-journal-studia-graeco.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Studia graeco-arabica"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
