<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7085699127967221436</id>
   <published>2016-01-22T10:52:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-01-22T10:52:06.267-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Visible Language</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://visiblelanguagejournal.com/">Visible Language</a><br />ISSN: 0022-2224<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><i>Visible Language</i> is a peer-reviewed design journal that advocates  the potential for the research and practice of visual communication to  enhance the human experience. Published by the School of Design at the  University of Cincinnati, Visible Language balances artfulness with  science, innovation with respect for human patterns of use,  evidence-based research with intuitive exploration, and technology with  humanity.<br /><br /><a href="http://visiblelanguagejournal.com/issue/172">Issues Online </a>(3(?) year moving wall)</blockquote>Visible language is not strictly speaking focused on Antiquity, but it has many articles on ancient writing including (but not limited to) the following (in no particular order): <br /><div class="col-xs-9">                <blockquote class="tr_bq"><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Communicating Cuneiform: The Evolution of a Multimedia Cuneiform Database</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 36 | Issue 3 | September 2002</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">S.I. Woolley</span></div></div><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">T.R. Davis</span></div></div><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">N.J. Flowers</span></div></div><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">J. Pinilla-Dutoit</span></div></div><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">A. Livingstone</span></div></div><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">T.N. Arvanitis</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Our paper presents the work of the  Cuneiform Digital Forensic Project (CDFP), an interdisciplinary project  at The University of Birmingham, concerned with the development of a  multimedia database to support scholarly research into cuneiform,  wedge-shaped writing imprinted onto clay tablets and indeed the earliest  real form of writing. We describe the evolutionary design process and  dynamic research and developmental cycles associated with the database.  Unlike traditional publications, the electronic publication of resources  offers the possibility of almost continuous revisions with the  integration and support of new media and interfaces. However, if on-line  resources are to win the favor and confidence of their respective  communities there must be a clear distinction between published and  maintainable resources, and, developmental content. Published material  should, ideally, be supported via standard web-browser interfaces with  fully integrated tools so that users receive a reliable, homogenous and  intuitive flow of information and media relevant to their needs.  We discuss the inherent dynamics of the design and publication of our  on-line resource, starting with the basic design and maintenance aspects  of the electronic database, which includes photographic instances of  cuneiform signs, and shows how the continuous review process identifies  areas for further research and development, for example, the “sign  processor” graphical search tool and three-dimensional content, the  results of which then feedback into the maintained resource. </span></div></blockquote></div><blockquote>             <div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">                         <div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Construction and Implementation of the Cuneiform System</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 15 | Issue 4 | October 1981</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">M.W. Green</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Cuneiform was, from its inception,  not merely a collection of individual symbols, but a coherent system of  information manipulation for which written characters were the main,  but not the only, component. This system did not evolve by itself, but  was manufactured, developed, and implemented within the framework of a  bureaucratic organization which controlled the distribution not only of  goods and services but also of status and information. That institution  produced the demand for a control technology for which the cuneiform  writing system was the eventual realization. While the user institution  imposed specific, characteristic constraints and demands, it also  adjusted its own needs and goals to adapt to restrictions and functions  of the technology itself. We look at the early development of the  cuneiform writing system with special attention to the less well  recognized peripheral components and to interactions between the  technology and its user.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">                         <div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Visual Sentences in Cuneiform Hittite</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 15 | Issue 4 | October 1981</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Carol Justus</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">On the premise that horizontal  Hittite scribal rulings be taken seriously as punctuation, this study  investigated their content and found that in fact they punctuate a  structure similar to the periodic sentence in older Greek and Latin. As  such they are to be compared with the oldest (alphabetic) Greek mark of  punctuation, the paragraphos, which begins to be replaced in Alexandrian  Greek by marks which segment the language on the basis of prosodic  features, as in English. Hittite “visible sentences,” moreover, signal  in visual form underlying differences in language structure and cohesive  basis which can be correlated with differences in word order type and  changes which the genetically related Indo-European (IE) languages have  undergone over a period of c. 4000 years of written attestation.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">                         <div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">The Temple Scribe in Chaldean Uruk</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 15 | Issue 4 | October 1981</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ronald H. Sack</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The education and activities of  the Eanna temple scribe in sixth-century BC. Uruk varied little from  what they had been prior to the Chaldean era. The cuneiform writing  system was still in use, and Akkadian economic documents continued to be  composed and literary texts preserved in a manner not unlike that of  previous periods. These traditions, however, did not preclude the  scribe’s attending to his own private business affairs or prevent his  engaging in the collection or composition of literary documents that  reflect either his own personal interests or the necessity to prepare  materials with decidedly political overtones. The result of these  endeavors is a body of texts which, in many respects, indicates both the  influence of spoken Aramaic or written Akkadian and the everchanging  political situation (from both official and private perspectives) in  southern Mesopotamia in the Chaldean period.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">                         <div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Three Problems in the History of Cuneiform Writing: Origins, Direction of Script, and Literacy</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 15 | Issue 4 | October 1981</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Marvin A. Powell</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">“Origins” suggests that cuneiform  was invented in a short period of time around 3000 BC by a citizen of  the Sumerian city of Uruk and that it arises conceptually out of the  token system described by D. Schmandt-Besserat. “Direction of script”  agrees with S. Picchioni that cuneiform was written and read vertically  down through c. 2300 BC, but it emphasizes the use of reed patterns to  demonstrate the manner in which the stylus was manipulated and sees this  mode of manipulation at the motivating force behind the transition to  horizontal script. “Literacy” argues that cuneiform was not as difficult  as usually assumed, that the alphabet had no demonstrable effect on the  level of functional literacy, and that the superiority of the alphabet  over cuneiform has been exaggerated.</span></div></div></div></div><br /><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">                         <div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Letter Names of the Latin Alphabet</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 5 | Issue 3 | July 1971</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Arthur E. Gordon</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Contemporary and earlier studies  of the Latin language have failed to present and discuss adequately  letter names of the Latin alphabet—in contrast, for example, with the  Greek alpha, beta, gamma, etc. Several theories, and their derivation,  about the letter names are presented. The ancient evidence—from the  third/second century B.C. to the seventh century A.D.—is rather scant  and not always clear. While the names of the vowels and of all the  consonants except the continuants (F, L, M, N, R, S, X) seem certain,  the names of these continuants seem to have undergone changes in the  course of history and to be clear only toward the end of antiquity (from  the fourth century A.D. on).</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">                         <div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Ancient Maya Writing and Calligraphy</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 5 | Issue 4 | October 1971</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Michael D. Coe</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Maya hieroglyphic writing was  carved on stone monuments, written in bark-paper codices, and painted  upon funerary pottery. The stone inscriptions, formerly thought to  record only calendrical information, have been found to contain dynastic  histories. The codices treat exclusively of ritual matters, while the  texts and pictures on the pottery are concerned with the perilous voyage  of the soul to the underworld. The script evolved from a highly  pictographic system into one that had a strong phonetic-syllabic  component. As calligraphy, Maya writing was a basically painterly art.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">            <div class="col-xs-3">                <div class="search-issue-cover-container">                    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a data-lightbox="6.1" href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/visiblelanguage/images/cover/6.1.png">                       </a></span></div></div><div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Origin of the Sexagesimal System: Interaction of Language and Writing</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 6 | Issue 1 | January 1972</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Marvin A. Powell, Jr.</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The origin of the sexagesimal  system has been much debated, but all past theories have neglected the  linguistic evidence of the ancient cuneiform lexica. The problem or  origin is twofold: 1) the origin of counting with sixty as a base and 2)  the origin of sexagesimal place notation. The first problem is  linguistic and anthropological in nature and must be studied through the  ancient lexica. The second can be elucidated by a combined analysis of  the Sumerian number words and the symbols used to represent them. Such  an analysis indicated that sexagesimal place notation arose from an  interaction between the numerational framework of the Sumerian language  and the symbols used to write those numbers, but the sudden appearance  of place notation about 2050 B.C. indicates that the final step toward  the creation of place notation was an act of conscious invention.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">            <div class="col-xs-3">                <div class="search-issue-cover-container">                    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a data-lightbox="20.1" href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/visiblelanguage/images/cover/20.1.png">                       </a></span></div></div><div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">The Figured Poem: Towards a Definition of Genre</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 20 | Issue 1 | January 1986</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ulrich Ernst</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">A poetological analysis of the  genre of pattern poetry is presented which distinguishes among various  forms of picture text composition, and attempts to classify the various  sorts of carmina figurata typologically while dealing with the question  of continuity and discontinuity of figured poems in ancient, medieval,  and modern times.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">            <div class="col-xs-3">                <div class="search-issue-cover-container">                    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a data-lightbox="20.1" href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/visiblelanguage/images/cover/20.1.png">                       </a></span></div></div><div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">The Labyrinth Poem</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 20 | Issue 1 | January 1986</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Piotr Rypson</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The labyrinth, the mythical  structure conceived by Daedalus, has been a persistent motif throughout  the history of Mediterranean culture. We find it both in visual art of  all kinds as well as in literature, and also in the fascinating  noman’s-land between these two. In the area of word-image interaction  there exists a whole collection of texts that were given the name  “poetical labyrinths.” The origin of labyrinthine poems goes back to the  Rome of Augustus Caesar; the visual pattern of these pieces seems to  indicate the pattern of a magical dance, perhaps the ancient Greek dance  of the Grue. The idea of the poem in medieval times seems also to  encompass the idea of the city, of the heavenly Jerusalem. Medieval  poetical labyrinths have definite religious connotations, as is also  evident in the later works of this genre, influenced by the Jewish  Kabbala. This hermeneutic is still valid for the baroque in the case of a  number of works, yet more and more labyrinth poems appear in a  secularized, ornamental context. This article traces the most  significant of these lines of development of this form and its function.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">            <div class="col-xs-3">                <div class="search-issue-cover-container">                    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a data-lightbox="7.1" href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/visiblelanguage/images/cover/7.1.png">                       </a></span></div></div><div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Greek Letterforms on the Parthian Drachms</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 7 | Issue 1 | January 1973</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Richard A. Olson</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">One of the most unusual coinages  in antiquity was the coinage of the Parthian empire, largest of the  later Hellenistic empires. The Parthians were a non-Greek people who  used Greek as their first official language of state and as the  predominant language on their coins. Their most common denomination, the  silver drachm, bore Greek legends for almost half a millennium, and the  letterforms underwent a significant transformation in the process.  Since the coinage constitutes the largest body of primary source  material extant concerning ancient Parthia, that transformation is of  significant interest to the classification historian.</span></div></div></div></div></blockquote><div class="search-item ng-scope"><blockquote>        </blockquote><div class="row"><blockquote>                         </blockquote><div class="col-xs-9"><blockquote>                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Archives in the Ancient World</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 7 | Issue 2 | April 1972</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ernest Posner</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Focusing on archives in Greece,  Rome, Egypt and Meopotamia, the article compares archival criteria with  the present day practice and finds similarities including: 1) law, 2)  administrative action, 3) accounting, 4) land records and ownership, 5)  control over people with regard to servitude and taxation and 6)  business transactions.</span></div><div class="ng-binding"><br /></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">                         <div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Deciphering Maya Hieroglyphic Writing: The State of the Art</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 24 | Issue 1 | January 1990</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Virginia M. Fields</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">A brief description of the  historical approaches to the decipherment of ancient Maya writing is  presented in order to provide the background for a description of our  current knowledge of the nature and structure of their system. Maya  hieroglyphic writing is recognized as a true writing system in that it  represents the sounds and structure of spoken language. The writing  system is defined as a mixed logographic system containing both  pictographic and phonetic elements.   Maya hieroglyphic writing appears in the latter part of the Late  Preclassic Period (ca. 150 B.c.-A.D. 100) and is primarily associated  with documenting political history and legitimacy. Writing was used to  record the events of a ruler’s life, validating his right to the throne  by documenting his parentage, his accession to power, his conquests, and  his performance of important ritual and ceremonial acts. Calendrical  information also comprises a major component of Classic Maya  inscriptions. Historic events are documented by means of a complex  system that both fixes events in time and ties them cyclically to the  mythological past.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">            <div class="col-xs-3">                <div class="search-issue-cover-container">                    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a data-lightbox="24.2" href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/visiblelanguage/images/cover/24.2.png">                       </a></span></div></div><div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Handwriting—How Much Do We Know About It?</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 24 | Issue 2 | May 1990</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Rosemary Sassoon</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">For a thousand years before the  alphabet, the scribal schools in Mesopotamia and Egypt had studied and  taught their scripts, cuneiform and hieroglyphics, but no record of the  original alphabet or any reference to it has been found among the  hundreds of thousands of tablets from scribal archives. The silence in  which the origin of the alphabet is shrouded invites comment but  receives none. Among the ancient tablets of Sumer are numerous wordlists  containing, for instance, the names of animals or of plants or of legal  terms and many others. Some word lists are bilingual given the Sumerian  words with their Akkadian or their Eblaite translations. Their  classified lists of words were used as reference sources in early  proto-science and as teaching material in the scribal schools. Scholarly  exchange between Ebla and Mesopotamia has been established by more than  a hundred word lists in Sumeria found at Ebla that are identical with  word lists from cities in Mesopotamia.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">            <div class="col-xs-3">                <div class="search-issue-cover-container">                    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a data-lightbox="24.2" href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/visiblelanguage/images/cover/24.2.png">                       <br />                    </a></span>                </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="go-to-article" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">                    </a></span>            </div><div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Who on Earth Invented the Alphabet?</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 24 | Issue 2 | May 1990</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">John Sassoon</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">There is neither record of nor  reference to the invention of the alphabet in any known source. That in  itself may say something about the invention—that it probably did not  take place in the scribal community. The alphabet grew out of the  syllabaries which precede it, of which the most widespread were  cuneiform and hieroglyphics. It probably emerged from the commercial  communities of the ancient Near East but owed its consonatal principle  to the Egyptians. A Canaanite in north Syria around 1800 B.c. is the  most likely inventor, and the city of Ebla is taken as a hypothesis. The  early Mesopotamian scribal tradition of which Ebla was part is  outlined. Opinions about how the alphabet was invented are considered,  concluding that it was probably a single “giant leap,” and by one man.  The inventor’s necessary background, creation of letter shapes, the  writing medium and direction of script are reviewed. For the tricky  problem of initial acceptance and diffusion, for which these is no  evidence, a possibility is postulated. At the end, the whole process is  encapsulated in a brief story.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">            <div class="row">                <div class="search-issue-cover-container">                    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a data-lightbox="25.2-3" href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/visiblelanguage/images/cover/25.2-3.png">                       </a></span></div><div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Bilingual Babel: Cuneiform Texts in Two or More Languages from Ancient Mesopotamia and Beyond</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 27 | Issue 1-2 | January 1993</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Jerrold  Cooper</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ancient Mesopotamia was the  birthplace of the earliest known writing system. It was also a land of  ethno-linguistic diversity, that included Sumerians, who invented  cuneiform writing, and an increasingly large number of speakers of  Semitic languages. As cuneiform spread throughout Mesopotamia and into  neighboring regions, it was adapted to write Semitic and other  languages, and bilingual and even trilingual cuneiform tablets were  produced, containing Sumerian texts and their translations, usually into  Semitic Akkadian. Various formats were developed to set off the  translation from the original, and the practice, which began around 2400  B.C., continued almost to the beginning of own own era.</span></div></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">    </div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">            <div class="col-xs-3">                <div class="search-issue-cover-container">                    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a data-lightbox="32.3" href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/visiblelanguage/images/cover/32.3.png">                       </a></span></div></div><div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Tale of the Origin,  A Rhetorical Visual Analysis of a Mexican Mythical Tale</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 32 | Issue 3 | September 1998</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Alejandro Brizuela</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">A contemporary designer pays  homage to the ancient codex designers or Tlacuilo. “Tale of the origin”  is a Mesoamerican science-religion story of the beginning and end of  life. The myth is presented first as a Spanish language artist’s book in  a documentary style. Key moments and characters in the myth are  symbolically visualized. This document is then analyzed and interpreted  using rhetoric as a subtext or key to understanding the ideas of the  myth as well as the visual structure of the unfolding story and book.  Yet another subtext translates the myth into English.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">            <div class="col-xs-3">                <div class="search-issue-cover-container">                    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a data-lightbox="8.4" href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/visiblelanguage/images/cover/8.4.png">                       </a></span></div></div><div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Records, Writing, and Decipherment</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 8 | Issue 4 | October 1974</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">I. J. Gelb</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Written records together with  material remains derived from excavations form the main bases for our  understanding of past civilizations and their underlying language  systems. There is no systematic treatment of written records, and little  attention has been paid to the interrelationship between ancient  writing and language. Full systems of writing express language at two  levels—morphological and phonetic—which give rise to three basic writing  systems types—logo-syllabic, syllabic, and alphabetic. Four categories  of decipherment—based on our relative knowledge of the writing system  and the language—are discussed: known writing/known language; unknown  writing/known language; known writing/unknown language; and unknown  writing/unknown language. From a cryptanalytic point of view there are  two general decipherment methods: 1) utilization of external information  to determine probable contents (e.g., bilingual texts,) and 2) internal  information from an analysis of the text itself (structure and  typology). The assumption of the underlying language is critical for  deciphering procedures and provides the test of successful decipherment.</span></div></div></div></div><div class="search-item ng-scope">        <div class="row">            <div class="col-xs-3">                <div class="search-issue-cover-container">                    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a data-lightbox="10.3" href="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/visiblelanguage/images/cover/10.3.png">                       <br />                    </a></span>                </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="go-to-article" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">                                     </a></span>            </div><div class="col-xs-9">                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">An "Ikon of the Soul": The Byzantine Letter</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 10 | Issue 3 | July 1976</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">A.R. Littlewood</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Byzantine epistolographic concepts  are a natural development of the concepts of classical antiquity, and  especially of the Second Sophistic, that were adapted to fit the  requirements of Christian ontology. The surviving letters were intended  not always to convey information, for which the courier or “living  letter” was often responsible, but usually to fulfill the obligations  and genuine needs of friendship and to serve as much prized pieces of  literary art in their own right. In the one case the letter was deemed  an “ikon of the soul,” creating an illusion of the presence of the  writer and thereby demanding tokens of his individual characteristics.  In the other it was required to be original within the strict framework  imposed by the imitation of ancient models; and by adherence to changing  stylistic canons it came both to foster obscurity and to embrace  subject-matter not commonly associated with the letter.</span></div></div></div></div></blockquote><div class="search-item ng-scope"><blockquote>        </blockquote><div class="row"><div class="col-xs-9"><blockquote>                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Writing and the Concept of Law in Ancient Greece</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 14 | Issue 2 | April 1980</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Jon Stratton</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The concept of law is too often  treated as an a-historical category; similarly, the impact of writing  (when used as a medium of communication) on the conceptual order and on  the social structure of a society has been little analyzed. These two  problems are brought together in the context of ancient Greece to  demonstrate how the concepts “law” and “justice” developed in relation  to changes in the social structure of that society. The impact of  writing on Greek society not only produced the situation in which these  changes took place but also helped form those changes.</span></div><div class="ng-binding"><br /></div></blockquote><div class="col-xs-9"><blockquote>                <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="ng-binding" href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Seeing in Depth: the Practice of Bilingual Writing</a></span></h3><h6 class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 27 | Issue 1-2 | January 1993</span></h6><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Richard Hodgson</span></div></div><div class="ng-scope">                    <div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ralph Sarkonak</span></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Producing and reading a bilingual  text, much like creating and viewing a stereoscopic image, involve a  much more complex process of perception and decoding than do the writing  and deciphering of a monolingual one. Working with bilingual texts  creates both special problems and unique opportunities for the writer,  the graphic designer, the reader and for those of us who are fascinated  by visible language in all its forms. Most studies on bilingualism tend  to neglect the written manifestations of the phenomenon in favor of the  psychological, social and pedagogical dimensions of the problem as they  appear in the spoke language. This issue explores the practice of  bilingual writing in a wide variety of texts, from cuneiform tablets and  bilingual dictionaries to contemporary fiction and bilingual editions  of texts. “Texts” can be anything from polyglot bibles to advertising  slogans and brand names. The main objective of this issue devoted to  writing “in stereo” is to bring together specialists in a wide range of  fields, from graphic design and lexicography to text-linguistics and  literary theory, to study the practice of bilingual writing at the level  of the word (company logos and bilingual dictionaries), the sentence  (code-switching) and the entire text. The examples chosen involve both  visible and invisible bilingualism (depending on the reader/viewer’s  knowledge of the languages in question).</span></div></blockquote></div><div class="ng-binding" style="text-align: center;">See AWOL's <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">Alphabetical List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div></div></div></div><div class="ng-binding"><br /></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7085699127967221436/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/01/open-access-journal-visible-language.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7085699127967221436"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7085699127967221436"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/01/open-access-journal-visible-language.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Visible Language"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
