<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5716343769334303349</id>
   <published>2015-01-24T09:59:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-01-24T10:02:46.857-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Nubia"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Sudan"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Oriental Institute Nubian Expedition Publications</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 class="post-title entry-title" itemprop="name"><span style="font-size: xx-small;">&nbsp;</span><span style="font-weight: normal;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-size: xx-small;">[First posted in AWOL 31 March 2014, updated 24 January 2015]</span></span></span></h3><h3 class="post-title entry-title" itemprop="name"><span style="font-weight: normal;"><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;Oriental Institute Nubian Expedition Publications</span></span></h3><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h1 class="subtitle"><span style="font-weight: normal;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/projects/oriental-institute-nubian-expedition"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Oriental Institute Nubian Expedition</span></a></span></h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Oriental Institute has had a long history of research in  ancient Nubia.Oriental Institute Founder, James Henry Breasted traveled  to <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/museum/collections/pa/breasted/" target="_self" title="The 1905-1907 Breasted Expeditions To Egypt and The Sudan">southern Egypt and northern Sudan in 1905-07</a>, to document ancient Egyptian and Nubian monuments. A <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oimp/oimp24.html" target="_self" title=" A Centennial Exhibit of Photographs from the 1905-1907 Egyptian Expedition of the University of Chicago">selection of the Breasted Expedition photographs</a> was exhibited in the Oriental Institute Museum in 2006. In addition to  this early work by our founder, between 1960 and 1968 the Oriental  Institute participated in the <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/projects/nub/" target="_self" title="Nubia Salvage Project">international archaeological campaign organized by UNESCO</a> in the areas threatened by the construction of the Aswan High Dam. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/" target="_self">Nine volumes</a> of final reports have been published. The <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/museum/nubia/" target="_self">Robert F. Picken Family Nubia Gallery</a>,  which opened in 2006, displays some of the approximately 15,000 objects  brought back to the Oriental Institute as a result of the work in the  1960s.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The return of the Oriental Institute to Nubia began in 2006 with a  preliminary reconnaissance trip to evaluate the possibility of  participating in an archaeological salvage project in Sudan. The <a href="http://www.merowedam.gov.sd/" target="_blank">Merowe Dam Project</a> at the 4th Cataract of the Nile, upon its completion in 2008, flooded  an area of approximately 100 miles in the Nile Valley. Between January  and March 2007, the Oriental Institute joined international teams in the  4th Cataract region in archaeological investigation of the area, an  area that had, prior to the salvage project, received virtually no  attention. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Oriental Institute excavations in the 4th Cataract were supported by the Packard Humanities Institute and National Geographic.</span><br /><h3 class="post-title entry-title" itemprop="name"></h3></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><blockquote class="tr_bq"></blockquote></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h2><span style="font-weight: normal;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/projects/nubia-salvage-project"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Nubia Salvage Project</span></a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="right" src="http://oi.uchicago.edu/i/Nubia.gif" /></span><br /><ul class="anchor"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/projects/nub/#Introduction">INTRODUCTION</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/museum/special/nubia/">1987 Exhibition Brochure - NUBIA "Its glory and its people"</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/gallery/nubia_1992/">1992 Exhibition Brochure - VANISHED KINGDOMS OF THE NILE: The Rediscovery of Ancient Nubia</a></span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><br /><hr /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="Introduction" name="Introduction"></a>INTRODUCTION</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Oriental Institute participated in the UNESCO international  salvage excavation project in the reservoir area of the Aswan High Dam  in Upper Egypt in 1960-64. The project was directed by Keith Seele,  Professor of Egyptology at the Institute. The expedition was based on  the former Cook tourist boat "Fostat", accompanied by another houseboat,  the "Barbara", a tug boat, and a motor launch, all purchased and  modified to provide mobile housing, laboratories and storage space. In  the first season the project produced an epigraphic record of the Beit  El-Wali Temple, near the High Dam. In subsequent seasons the expedition  moved its little fleet up the Nile to a new concession between the  temples at Abu Simbel and the border of the Sudanese Republic.  Excavations were conducted in a monastery, at habitation sites, and in a  number of cemeteries extending for miles along both banks of the Nile.  These excavations contributed information on every period of Egyptian  Nubia from the Old Kingdom through Coptic times.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">After the death of Professor Seele in 1971, the Institute initiated a  project to complete the publication of the results of the Egyptian  Nubia excavations. The publication project was entrusted to Bruce  Williams, Ph.D., a graduate of the University of Chicago in Egyptology.  The first two volumes were published before Williams was assigned to the  project. Since then Williams has completed eight monumental monographs  (1986-93) that will stand as the fundamental sources for the archaeology  and history of Egyptian Nubia. Williams is currently working on two  additional volumes. Another two volumes are also in preparation by  collaborators, including one Ph.D. dissertation. Williams has devoted  his entire academic career to the Nubia publications. His dedication is  admirable and the Institute takes pride in the fact that the Nubia  publication project is near completion.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Because the Nubian expedition was a part of the UNESCO salvage  project, the Egyptian Government granted export license for a large  collection of objects recovered by the expedition. These artifacts are  now a part of the perminent collection of the Institute and will serve  as a valuable resource for generations of scholars as new questions are  raised and new techniques of analysis are introduced. Two museum  exhibitions of Nubian materials from the collection have been mounted;  one of magnificent textiles at the Art Institute, and a fine educational  exhibition in the Oriental Institute Museum. The exhibit in our museum,  Vanished Kingdoms of the Nile: The Recovery of Ancient Nubia, attracted  many enthuiastic new visitors to the museum and received a "Superior  Achievement" award from the Congress of Illinois Historical Societies  and Museums in 1992, as well as considerable press coverage, including a  favorable review in the New York Times.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Oriental Institute has had a long history of research in ancient Nubia.Oriental Institute Founder, James Henry   Breasted traveled to <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/museum/collections/pa/breasted/" target="_self" title="The 1905-1907 Breasted Expeditions To Egypt and The Sudan">southern Egypt and northern Sudan in 1905-07</a>, to document ancient Egyptian and Nubian monuments.  A <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oimp/oimp24.html" target="_self" title="Lost Nubia: A Centennial Exhibit of Photographs from the 1905-1907 Egyptian Expedition of the University of Chicago">selection of the Breasted Expedition photographs</a> was exhibited in the Oriental Institute Museum in 2006. In addition to  this early work by our founder, between 1960 and 1968 the Oriental  Institute participated in the <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/projects/nub/" target="_self" title="Nubia Salvage Project">international archaeological campaign organized by UNESCO</a> in the areas threatened by the construction of the Aswan High Dam. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/" target="_self">Nine volumes</a> of final reports have been published.    The <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/museum/nubia/" target="_self">Robert F. Picken Family Nubia Gallery</a>,  which opened in 2006, displays some of the approximately 15,000 objects  brought back to the Oriental Institute as a result of the work in the  1960s.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The return of the Oriental Institute to Nubia began in 2006 with a  preliminary reconnaissance trip to evaluate the possibility of  participating in an archaeological salvage project in Sudan. The <a href="http://www.merowedam.gov.sd/" target="_blank">Merowe Dam Project</a> at the 4th Cataract of the Nile, upon its completion in 2008, flooded  an area of approximately 100 miles in the Nile Valley. Between January  and March 2007, the Oriental Institute joined international teams in the  4th Cataract region in archaeological investigation of the area, an  area that had, prior to the salvage project, received virtually no  attention.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Oriental Institute excavations in the 4th Cataract were supported by the Packard Humanities Institute and National Geographic.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/projects/oine/oine2007.html">2007 Excavations</a></span></h3><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/projects/oine/oine2008.html">2008 Excavations</a></span></h3></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><b>Oriental Institute Nubian Expedition (OINE)</b> [All available for open access download]<a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/"> </a><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">OINE 10. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine10.html">Excavations   at Serra East, Parts 1-5: A-Group, C-Group, Pan Grave, New Kingdom,  and  X-Group Remains from Cemeteries A-G and Rock Shelters.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1993.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">OINE 9. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine9.html">Excavations   Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 9: Noubadian X-Group   Remains from Royal Complexes in Cemeteries Q and 219 and Private   Cemeteries Q, R, V, W, B, J, and M at Qustul and Ballana.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1991.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">OINE 8. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine8.html">Excavations   Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 8: Meroitic Remains   from Qustul Cemetery Q, Ballana Cemetery B, and a Ballana Settlement.</a> By B. B. Williams, et. al. Originally published in 1991.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">OINE 7. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine7.html">Excavations   Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 7: Twenty-Fifth  Dynasty  and Napatan Remains at Qustul Cemeteries W and V.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1990.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">OINE 6. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine6.html">Excavations   Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 6: New Kingdom Remains   from Cemeteries R, V, S, and W at Qustul and Cemetery K at Adindan.</a> Bruce B. Williams. 1992.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">OINE 5. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine5.html">Excavations   Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 5: C-Group, Pan Grave,   and Kerma Remains at Adindan Cemeteries T, K, U, and J.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1983.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">OINE 4. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine4.html">Excavations   Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Parts 2, 3, and 4:   Neolithic, A-Group, and Post A-Group Remains from Cemeteries W, V, S, Q,   T, and a Cave East of Cemetery K.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1989.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">OINE 3. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine3.html">Excavations Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 1: The A-Group Royal Cemetery at Qustul, Cemetery L.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1986.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">OINE 2. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine2.html">Ausgrabungen von Khor-Dehmit bis Bet El-Wali.</a> H. Ricke. Originally published in 1967.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">OINE 1. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine1.html">The Beit el-Wali Temple of Ramesses II.</a> By Herbert Ricke, George R. Hughes, and Edward F. Wente. Originally published in 1967.</span></li></ul><ul><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oimp/oimp24.html">OIMP 24. Lost Nubia: A Centennial Exhibit of Photographs from the 1905-1907 Egyptian Expedition of the University of Chicago.</a> John A. Larson. 2006.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="https://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oimp/ancient_nubia.html">Ancient Nubia. Oriental Institute Museum. Originally published in 2006."</a></span></span></li></ul></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><ul style="list-style-type: disc;"><li style="-moz-font-feature-settings: normal; -moz-font-language-override: normal; background-color: #fcfdf8; color: #4f4115; font-size-adjust: none; font-size: 12px; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal; margin: 0px 0px 40px;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/textiles.html">Ancient Textiles from Nubia: Meroitic, X-Group, and Christian Fabrics from Ballana and Qustul.</a></span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: black; font-size: x-small;"><blockquote class="tr_bq" style="display: inline !important;"><ul style="display: inline !important; list-style-type: disc;"><span style="color: #333233;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: xx-small;">Christa C. Mayer Thurman and Bruce Williams. Originally published in 1979.</span></span></ul></blockquote></span></span></li></ul><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><span style="font-size: xx-small;"></span> </span></blockquote><span style="font-size: xx-small;">&nbsp;</span><br /><div style="text-align: center;">And for an up to date list of all Oriental Institute publications available online see</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/10/oriental-institute-open-access.html">The Oriental Institute Open Access Publications</a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5716343769334303349/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/03/open-access-oriental-institute-nubian.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5716343769334303349"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5716343769334303349"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/03/open-access-oriental-institute-nubian.html"
         title="Open Access Oriental Institute Nubian Expedition Publications"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
