<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3816607817158422476</id>
   <published>2015-10-04T21:34:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-10-04T21:34:54.671-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Oxford Archaeology Image Database</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://oaid.co.uk/">Oxford Archaeology Image Database</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The OAID was established in June 2015 by Tim Clayden (Wolfson  College, Oxford) with support from the Lorne Thyssen Research Fund for  Ancient World Topics. Its initial aim was to preserve and make available  to as wide an audience and user group as possible images of  archaeological sites recorded on slide film. The concern being that as  the slide films age and decay the quality of the images deteriorates. In  many cases these images are a unique record of the sites at a  particular time and once the slide is lost, so too is the image and the  information it contains. More recent events in Iraq and Syria have urged  a more pressing need to record and preserve the record of some  archaeological sites. For that reason the project has expanded to  include images in whatever format they are available.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The basic  principle of the OAID is that images can only be uploaded under  controlled circumstances with persons expert (the site ‘editor’) in the  study of a particular site or sites adding a ‘tag’ which identifies what  is in the image. These ‘tags’ can then be searched using any standard  internet search engine and the images viewed in an uncontrolled fashion.  The objective being to make available to as many interested people as  possible images of sites which are now either inaccessible, damaged or  excavated further thus removing remains.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Use of the images in  research and academic publications is encouraged. The use of the images  is governed by the UK law on Copyright and in particular the principle  of Fair Dealing (sections 29 and 30 of the UK Copyright, Designs and  patents Act 1988). In summary this allows use of images in research and  private study, for criticism or review, teaching materials, personal use  or for reporting on current events (see <a href="https://www.gov.uk/exceptions-to-copyright">https://www.gov.uk/exceptions-to-copyright</a> for more detailed guidance). All other use of the images should only be  done after consultation with OAID and in some cases a charge may be  made for use of the image.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In using an image from the OAID  database acknowledgement should be made in the format – OAID (unique  number), name of photographer, date of photograph.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The OAID is a  project and while there are a number of slide collections ready to load  into the database, more are always welcome. Viewers are invited to  submit any images they might wish to have considered for uploading.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">It  should be stressed that while efforts are made to ensure that the  uploaded image is good quality, in many cases the original slides are  old, scratched and with colour distortion. These issues can to a certain  extent be ‘repaired’, but not completely. It should also be noted that  the photographs were taken as research tools and not as works of  photographic art. In those cases were persons appear in the images, they  are sometimes identified. Otherwise faces are blurred leaving the  figures in as they do act as a useful scale.</span></blockquote><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="collapse navbar-collapse" id="ompa-main-navbar-collapse"><ul class="nav navbar-nav"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oaid.co.uk/#/news-item/list">Latest news</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oaid.co.uk/#/site/list">All sites</a></span></li><li class=""><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oaid.co.uk/#/about">About the project</a></span></li></ul></div></blockquote><br /><br />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3816607817158422476/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/10/oxford-archaeology-image-database.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3816607817158422476"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3816607817158422476"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/10/oxford-archaeology-image-database.html"
         title="Oxford Archaeology Image Database"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
