<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3882565483606472402</id>
   <published>2016-10-30T20:09:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-10-30T20:09:41.408-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Latin"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greek"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Perseus"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dictionary"/>
   <title type="text">ΛΟΓΕΙΟΝ - Logeion</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">&nbsp;[First posted in AWOL 7 May 2012, updated 30 October 2016]</span><br /><br /><a href="http://logeion.uchicago.edu/">ΛΟΓΕΙΟΝ - Logeion</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://logeion.uchicago.edu/" target="_blank">Logeion</a> (literally, a place for words; in particular, <a href="http://logeion.uchicago.edu/index.html#%CE%BB%CE%BF%CE%B3%CE%B5%E1%BF%96%CE%BF%CE%BD" target="_blank">a speaker's platform</a>, or an <a href="http://logeion.uchicago.edu/index.html#logeum" target="_blank">archive</a>) was developed after the example of <a href="http://dvlf.uchicago.edu/" target="_blank" title="">dvlf.uchicago.edu</a>,  to provide simultaneous lookup of entries in the many reference works  that make up the Perseus Classical collection. As always, we are  grateful for the Perseus Project's generosity in sharing their data.  None of this would be possible without their commitment to open access.  To improve the chronological range for which the dictionaries are  useful, we have added DuCange (see further updates below!), and to  enhance this site as both a research and a pedagogical tool, we add  information based on corpus data in the right side bar, as well as  references to chapters in standard textbooks. More such 'widgets' will  be added over time, along with, we hope, still more dictionaries.</span> </li><div style="padding-right: 72px; padding-top: 0px; text-align: justify;">  </div><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Update January 2016: </b>We are delighted to announce the advent of the <a href="http://www.dmlbs.ox.ac.uk/">Dictionary of Medieval Latin from British Sources</a> in Logeion. Many thanks to the <a href="http://www.britac.ac.uk/">British Academy</a> (specifically, its Projects committee and its DMLBS committee), and in particular to the editor of <i>DMLBS</i>, <b>Richard Ashdowne</b>,  for making this happen. We are thrilled to add another newly-released  resource on the Latin side. Academic users: please do urge your  libraries to <a href="http://www.dmlbs.ox.ac.uk/publications/dictionary">purchase print copies</a> of DMLBS (and DGE!), if they have not yet done so. </span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Many thanks to Matt Shanahan, Josh Day, and XSLT wizard Alex Lee for their help in bringing DMLBS to Logeion.  <br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <i>Dictionary of Medieval Latin from British Sources</i> is the work  of a century-long British Academy project, based first in London and  then at the University of Oxford, that ran from 1913 to the completion  of the printed dictionary in 2013. The <i>DMLBS</i> has been based  wholly on original research and it documents the vocabulary of Latin in  medieval Britain from the sixth to the sixteenth centuries. The <i>DMLBS</i> is a copyright work and the text appears on the Logeion  site under licence from the British Academy, to whom we express our  thanks.   Users will find the following resources at the DMLBS project website  helpful:  A <a href="http://www.dmlbs.ox.ac.uk/publications/a-guide-for-users">user's guide to the dictionary</a>, the <a href="http://www.dmlbs.ox.ac.uk/publications/bibliography">bibliography and notes to the bibliography</a>, and <a href="http://www.dmlbs.ox.ac.uk/publications/dictionary">guidelines for citing DMLBS</a>.    <br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Hellenists also have reason to rejoice: The <a href="http://www.woordenboekgrieks.nl/">Woordenboek Grieks/Nederlands</a>, a Dutch project in progress, has made its finished letter ranges available to us. We thank the editors-in-chief, <b>Ineke Sluiter</b>, <b>Albert Rijksbaron</b>, and <b>Ton Kessels,</b> and their project coordinator, <b>Lucien van Beek.</b> <a href="http://www.woordenboekgrieks.nl/colofon.html">A full roster</a> of the team of writers and editors, and further information about the  project, can be found on its website. At Logeion we believe that all  users stand to benefit from up-to-date Greek dictionaries such as DGE  and Grieks/Nederlands, regardless of their mother tongue. This is the  first dictionary that <b>Walt Shandruk</b> has handled for Logeion; and  while it takes skill to adapt third-party data, Walt has dealt with that  but also confronted third-party code - with aplomb. Many thanks.  <br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">In other news, <b>BWL</b>, which is derived from a useful Dutch  resource for intermediate Latin students, and illustrates important  constructions and idiomatic usages of the most frequent Latin words, now  features translations for its example sentences. This was a long-time  desideratum, and we thank <b>Rebekah Spearman</b> for doing the last  push that this project needed. She, however, cannot be held responsible  for all the thousands of translated sentences! Please send your comments  our way if you encounter problems. The other existing dictionaries,  too, have seen the usual additional cleanup of infelicities in the  original data entry process. Many thanks to all users who pointed out  errors. If you find more, please report them: we are grateful for your  assistance in incrementally improving this resource.  <br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Update January 2015: We are grateful to <b>Philip Peek</b> of Bowling Green State University for making available his file with vocabulary for <b>Chase &amp; Phillips.</b> <br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Update August 2014: In addition to the usual editing of existing  dictionaries and morphology (keep reporting typos to us, please!), we  are delighted to add a first author-specific lexicon on the Latin side,  thanks to efforts at <b>Dickinson College</b>. Users will now encounter <b>Frieze-Dennison's lexicon to Vergil's Aeneid</b> for relevant entries. Many thanks to <b>Christopher Francese</b> and the DCC 'crew'! On another note, Logeion and the Logeion app got a mention in the <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/08/24/books/review/gateways-to-the-classical-world.html?ref=books&amp;_r=0">New York Times</a>,  which we are thrilled about. We are, as always, grateful to Josh, Matt  &amp; Josh for developing this site and the app, and to the College of  the University of Chicago for its support and its 'ambidextrous'  undergrads, who know their way around Python and XML as well as around  Greek and Latin.<br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Update December 2013: We are delighted to announce that we are adding the premier dictionary for Ancient Greek, the <a href="http://dge.cchs.csic.es/">Diccionario Griego-Español (DGE)</a>,  to Logeion. Both for entries from DGE and from DuCange, we will include  a link to these dictionaries' home sites for every entry we display. As  we work on displaying these entries better, we recommend (also)  visiting the home sites, which look positively elegant. This update also  brings the Latin-Dutch dictionary, LaNe, up to date with the printed  6th edition, which will be coming out soon. <br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Update October 2013: Logeion is now available as an <a href="http://logeion.uchicago.edu/about-logeion-ios.html">app for iOS</a>, so that you can consult it even without a working internet connection. Find the <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/logeion/id727860177?mt=8">Logeion app</a> in Apple's app store.<br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Update January 2012:  We have now added a Latin-Dutch dictionary to the collection: The <i>Woordenboek Latijn/Nederlands.</i> One notable feature of this dictionary, for those who do not speak  Dutch, is that a lot of attention has been paid to ensure accuracy of  vowel length for the lexical entries. For further information see below.  </span></li></ul></blockquote><ul></ul><ul></ul>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3882565483606472402/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/05/online.html#comment-form"
         title="1 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3882565483606472402"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3882565483606472402"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/05/online.html"
         title="ΛΟΓΕΙΟΝ - Logeion"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
