<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-82873288127438454</id>
   <published>2016-04-15T12:26:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-04-15T12:26:53.372-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Classics"/>
   <title type="text">Group Blog: Social Science Ancient History: New approaches to the study of classical antiquity…</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://socsciah.wordpress.com/" rel="home">Social Science Ancient History: New approaches to the study of classical antiquity…</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">‘Social Science Ancient History’ is an open, inclusive approach to  the study of the history of classical antiquity – more of a temperament  or an attitude than a clearly-defined field or methodology. It is  founded on a conviction that historical research on classical antiquity  must be analytical rather than descriptive, that it must be deductive  rather than inductive, and that the historian’s questions, concepts and  assumptions should always be discussed explicitly rather than taken for  granted or ignored.&nbsp;It encompasses the use of theories, models and  concepts drawn from the social sciences in order to make sense of the  ancient world, but without any prejudice for or against economics,  sociology, anthropology, cultural studies or any other field of  scholarship. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This blog is particularly but not exclusively associated with the Antiquity Network of the biennial <a href="https://esshc.socialhistory.org/">European Social Science History Conference</a>,  where we first had the idea. It aims to serve as a point of contact and  information hub for past and potential contributors to the Antiquity  sessions at that conference, and a means for advertising the Network’s  activities. However, it also seeks to promote social scientific  approaches to ancient history more generally: by organising ‘book  events’ several times a year, where a number of contributors offer their  personal views of a key work as a starting-point for discussion, and by  publishing relevant posts on research topics from established scholars,  early career researchers and postgraduate students. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you are interested in contributing to this blog, please contact the current organiser, Neville Morley (neville.morley(at)<span class="skimlinks-unlinked">bristol.ac.uk</span>) to discuss your ideas. If you’re not familiar with this sort of writing, you can consult a&nbsp;brief introductory guide,&nbsp;<a href="https://socsciah.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/introduction-to-blogging.doc" title="Introduction to Blogging">Introduction to Blogging</a>, written with academics in mind (n.b. if you <em>are</em> familiar with this sort of writing, you will find this absurdly basic), as well as some notes on <a href="https://socsciah.files.wordpress.com/2016/04/organising-a-book-event.docx" title="Organising a Book Event">Organising a Book Event</a>.</span><br /></blockquote><div class="site-branding">		</div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/82873288127438454/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/04/group-blog-social-science-ancient.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/82873288127438454"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/82873288127438454"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/04/group-blog-social-science-ancient.html"
         title="Group Blog: Social Science Ancient History: New approaches to the study of classical antiquity…"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
