<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8201556060960936170</id>
    <published>2014-09-29T06:50:00.000-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-09-29T06:50:10.322-04:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <title type="text">Internet Archaeology is now fully Open Access</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://intarch.ac.uk/open_access.html">Internet Archaeology
      is now fully Open Access</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img
      alt="http://intarch.ac.uk/logo/ia-logo.gif" class="decoded" height="65"
      src="http://intarch.ac.uk/logo/ia-logo.gif" width="200" /></blockquote><blockquote
      class="tr_bq">As of today, Internet Archaeology is an open access journal. We've concluded
      our hybrid phase and will no longer charge a subscription for access to
      <em>any</em> of our past and future content. </blockquote><blockquote
      class="tr_bq"> Several things have spurred this decision. Over the last 4 years, we have
      made active efforts in this direction, by switching to a default CC-BY license, by opening up
      our back issues with an annual rolling wall, and by adjusting our subscription charges
      accordingly. During this time, we have also witnessed a marked increase in quality, funded
      submissions, including several themed issues. Internet Archaeology has always tried to be more
      than 'just a journal'. We explore the possibilities of the web and have delved into many
      different publication formats. This flexibility extends into everything we do. Being a small
      operation has meant we could be responsive to changes in the wider scholarly landscape, and the
      journal has simply reached the <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.11141/ia.30.6">tipping
      point</a>. </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"> Funded through JISC's eLib
      programme, Internet Archaeology was launched in 1995 as a born-digital journal and published
      its first issue in 1996. It was also open access before the term was really invented. As part
      of the initial funding agreement, and as the only sustainable option for us at that time, we
      introduced institutional subscriptions in 2000, followed by subscriptions for individuals in
      2001. By 2010, the open access debate had truly sparked into life and it was around that time
      that we started to publish open access content where funds were available. By the start of 2014
      however, over 50% of the articles we had published were open access, so we have decided to make
      open access the focus of our efforts from now on. </blockquote><blockquote
      class="tr_bq"> There will always be challenges of course but I'm very excited to be taking
      the journal into this new phase. </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"> Judith
      Winters, Editor<br />29 September 2014</blockquote>]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8201556060960936170/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/09/internet-archaeology-is-now-fully-open.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8201556060960936170"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8201556060960936170"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/09/internet-archaeology-is-now-fully-open.html"
         title="Internet Archaeology is now fully Open Access"/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
