<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6721776977391355222</id>
   <published>2015-07-07T08:10:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-07-07T08:10:45.545-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Hydrology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <title type="text">Water Supply and Management in the Near East 63BC-AD636</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/kamash_2006/">Water Supply and Management in the Near East 63BC-AD636: PhD Thesis, University of Oxford (2006)</a>   <br /><div id="archiveheader"><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-top: 0px;">   Zena Kamash, 2009&nbsp;</div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-top: 0px;"><img alt="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/kamash_2006/images/Fig03.4.jpg" height="198" src="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/kamash_2006/images/Fig03.4.jpg" width="200" /> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The aim of this thesis is to assess the ancient systems of water  supply and management in the Near East from 63 BC to AD 636, from both a  technological and sociological perspective. Some of the main themes to  be discussed are of direct relevance to water supply studies such as the  debate over productive rural aqueducts versus consumptive urban  aqueducts and the constant-offtake principle.</span><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;">This analysis considers differences and similarities between the  pre-Roman period and the period between 63 BC - AD 636 as well as  between the Roman and late Roman periods. There were limited  technological improvements in water management techniques, mostly  related to dams, water-lifting techniques and the introduction of the  arch to aqueducts. It would seem that Herod was a key agent of  transmission of arcade technology, which suggests that his Romanophile  tendencies extended into the realm of water supply. The main trend in  the late Roman period was an intensification of previous Roman and  pre-Roman practices, in which process the Church and the late Roman army  were influential agents.</span><br /><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;">This work also investigates whether all areas of the East used the  same methods of water management and if not, what caused these  differences: landscape, climate and geology or culture? On a wider  scale, how water management in the East fitted into the Empire as a  whole is looked at with a similar set of questions. In some cases, such  as the selection of irrigation channels from rivers or qanats from  aquifers for irrigation, landscape was the over-riding deciding factor.  In other cases, particularly in the use of latrines, religious and  cultural identities seemed to have been the governing factor. This  suggests that identity, individual or group, and perceived changes to  that identity, may have a significant impact on choices of water supply  and management.</span><br /><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;">Chapters 1 and 2 provide geographical background and an overview of  the pre-Roman water technologies of the Near East. Chapters 3-10, which  are accompanied by gazetteers in volume III, investigate types of water  management techniques or installations (water-lifting, dams, irrigation  and aqueducts) or zones of water supply and management (in towns and  cities, in bathhouses and latrines, in the domestic sphere and in  industrial processes). Chapter 11 presents the conclusions of the  thesis, synthesising the key themes identified above (and expanded in  the Introduction).</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume I contains the text, volume II the illustrations and volume III the gazetteers.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">                                                        <br /><ul class="dlMenu"><li>  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/kamash_2006/index.cfm">Introduction</a> </span></li><li>   <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/kamash_2006/download.cfm">Downloads</a></span>  </li><li>   <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/kamash_2006/metadata.cfm">Metadata</a></span>  </li><li>   <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/kamash_2006/stats.cfm">Usage Statistics</a></span>  </li></ul></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-top: 0px;"><br /></div></blockquote></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6721776977391355222/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/07/water-supply-and-management-in-near.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6721776977391355222"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6721776977391355222"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/07/water-supply-and-management-in-near.html"
         title="Water Supply and Management in the Near East 63BC-AD636"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
