<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3631018148970142416</id>
    <published>2014-03-05T04:36:00.000-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-08T13:59:41.582-04:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Palestine"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Megiddo"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Israel"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
    <title type="text">New Book from the Oriental Institute: OIP 139. Early Megiddo on the East Slope
      (the “Megiddo Stages”): A Report on the Early Occupation of the East Slope of Megiddo (Results
      of the Oriental Institute’s Excavations, 1925-1933).</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a
      href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip139.html">OIP 139. Early Megiddo
      on the East Slope (the “Megiddo Stages”): A Report on the Early Occupation of the East Slope of
      Megiddo (Results of the Oriental Institute’s Excavations, 1925-1933)</a>.<br
      /><blockquote class="tr_bq">By Eliot Braun, with David Ilan, Ofer Marder, Yael Braun,
      and Sariel Shalev. 2013. <br /><b><span style="font-weight: normal;"><a
      class="download" href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/pdf/oip139.pdf" title="Download PDF">Download
      PDF</a>&nbsp; </span></b><br /><a class="terms"
      href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/epi.html">Terms of
      Use</a></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">&nbsp;Oriental Institute&nbsp; Publications
      (OIP)139</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span
      style="font-size: xx-small;"><img alt="http://oi.uchicago.edu/i/oip139.jpg"
      class="decoded" src="http://oi.uchicago.edu/i/oip139.jpg" height="320" width="222"
      /></span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span> <br /><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">Between 1925 and early 1933 the University of Chicago’s Oriental Institute’s
      expedition to Megiddo created a large dumping area in a convenient locale to the southeast of
      the high mound for fills removed from excavations on the upper tell. So that the new dumps
      would not additionally cover any ancient remains in the vicinity of the tell, that area the
      excavators labeled the “East Slope” was systematically and incrementally stripped bare of its
      soil overburden and archaeological deposits down to bedrock. Excavations on that rocky East
      Slope unearthed a patchy and confusing series of sequences of human utilization, most of which
      could not be easily correlated with finds on the high mound.</span><br /><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Although a
      final report on the excavation of the East Slope was planned, the vagaries of the several
      excavators’ careers, their states of health, and cessation of the expedition’s work due to
      World War II effectively prevented creation of final reports for that and other areas of the
      site. Until the present the sole published evidence for the East Slope (sometimes, albeit
      erroneously, known as the “Megiddo Stages”) was confined to several preliminary reports, all
      published prior to the second half of the last century. The present work synthesizes all
      available documentary and artifactual evidence, most unpublished, found in two primary
      repositories, the Oriental Institute in Chicago and the Israel Antiquities Authority in
      Jerusalem. The aim of this project was to recreate a detailed and definitive account of the
      archaeological record of the East Slope unearthed by its excavators, as far as it is possible
      more than eight decades after the excavations’ completion.</span><br /><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This
      report presents never before published plans, photographs, descriptions from field diaries, and
      stratigraphic observations that show clear evidence of architectural remains, caves, niches and
      quarries, tombs, and both rock-cut and built installations in select and non-contiguous
      locales, as well as artifacts associated with the earliest periods found on the East Slope,
      dating from the Neolithic period through the Early Bronze Age. This report also offers limited
      documentation of human activity there in later periods. These are found primarily in
      documentation of vestiges of numerous constructions, many superimposed on late prehistoric
      remains, and in evidence of extensive quarrying activity in bedrock.</span><br
      /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">In addition to detailed descriptions of remains and finds from the early periods,
      the authors have analyzed and interpreted the significance of the archaeological record in
      light of modern scholarship, with special attention paid to results of more recent excavation
      reports on sites within the region. Discussions concern the chronology of East Slope deposits,
      chrono-cultural attributions and associations of ceramic, groundstone, and chipped stone
      artifacts as well as the significance of architectural, mortuary, and regional traditions.
      Those issues are synthesized in summaries that set forth their socio-chronological implications
      for understanding the late prehistory of the southern Levant.</span><br /><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Table Of
      Contents</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><br
      /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Chapter 1. Introduction to the
      East Slope</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Chapter 2.
      Early Deposits on the East Slope</span></li><li><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">Chapter 3. Artifacts from the East Slope</span></li><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">Chapter 4. Sealings, Potters’ Marks, and Potmarks from the East
      Slope</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Chapter 5. The
      Chipped Stone Collection from the Oriental Institute’s Excavation of the East Slope and the
      High Mound. Ofer Marder</span></li><li><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">Chapter 6. The Early Bronze Age Tombs of Megiddo: A Reappraisal. David
      Ilan</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Chapter 7. Human
      Activity on the East Slope: A Summary</span></li><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">Appendices</span></li><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">Index of Acquisition and Field
      Numbers</span></li><li><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">Plates</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">
      </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Information</span><br
      /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><br
      /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Oriental Institute
      Publications 139</span></li><li><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">Chicago: The Oriental Institute of the University of Chicago, 2013
      </span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Pp. xxxii + 174; 34
      figures, 98 plates, 22 tables</span></li><li><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">ISBN 978-1-885923-98-1</span></li><li><span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><span
      class="pubprice">$75.00</span></span></li></ul></blockquote><div
      style="text-align: center;">See</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a
      href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/02/a-quick-list-of-oriental-institute.html">A
      list of Oriental Institute publications on the archaeology of
      Megiddo</a></div><br /><div style="text-align: center;">And for an up
      to date list of all Oriental Institute publications available online see</div><div
      style="text-align: center;"><a
      href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/10/oriental-institute-open-access.html">The
      Oriental Institute Open Access Publications</a></div>]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3631018148970142416/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/03/new-from-oriental-institute-oip-139.html#comment-form"
         title="2 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3631018148970142416"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3631018148970142416"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/03/new-from-oriental-institute-oip-139.html"
         title="New Book from the Oriental Institute: OIP 139. Early Megiddo on the East Slope (the “Megiddo Stages”): A Report on the Early Occupation of the East Slope of Megiddo (Results of the Oriental Institute’s Excavations, 1925-1933)."/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
