<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6422938941757513069</id>
   <published>2016-02-05T07:51:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-02-05T07:51:11.905-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="papyrology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greek"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Literature"/>
   <title type="text">Webinar: Online Approaches to Editing Greek Literature. The Philosophical Papyri</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.stoa.org/archives/2201" rel="bookmark" title="Permanent Link: Webinar: Online Approaches to Editing Greek Literature. The Philosophical Papyri">Webinar: Online Approaches to Editing Greek Literature. The Philosophical Papyri</a><br /> February 5th, 2016 by Gabriel Bodard<br />In <a href="http://www.stoa.org/">The Stoa Consortium</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Rodney Ast (University of Heidelberg) and Holger Essler  (University of Würzburg), in cooperation with Heidelberg’s Center for  Cultural Heritage, are offering in Summer Semester 2016 an online  seminar on Greek literary papyri. Special emphasis will be placed on  philosophical texts. Out of a total of 550 texts published so far, 45%  were found at a single site, the Villa dei Papiri in Herculaneum, the  remainder coming from various places in Egypt. Comparison of the two  groups suggests itself and it will be greatly facilitated by the Digital  Corpus of Literary Papyri (DCLP) (a bilateral project led by the  University of Heidelberg and NYU, with the involvement of the University  of Leuven, Duke University, and the University of Würzburg); it already  contains 95% of the philosophical texts from Herculaneum. The seminar  will focus on philosophical texts from Egypt preserved on papyrus only  (for an example click here). Participants will use the DCLP for  instruction and to create digital editions, but other databases and  approaches will be discussed as well. In particular, we will explore  questions of editorial decision-making and technique, transmission,  paleography, and the socio-cultural context in which the texts were  copied.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The course is free of charge and will take place Thursdays,  16:15–17:45, Central European Time. The first meeting will be the 14th  of April and the last the 7th of July. The language of instruction is  English, and good knowledge of Greek is required. Participants should  already have a Skype account set up by the first session. Certificates  will be issued upon successful completion of the class.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Those interested in taking part should send a statement of interest and CV to Michaela Böttner, <a href="mailto:boettner@uni-heidelberg.de">boettner@uni-heidelberg.de</a>, by March 4th. Questions about the course can be directed to Rodney Ast (<a href="mailto:ast@uni-heidelberg.de">ast@uni-heidelberg.de</a>) and/or Holger Essler (<a href="mailto:holger.essler@uni-wuerzburg.de">holger.essler@uni-wuerzburg.de</a>).</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The number of participants will be kept to a maximum of 12.</span></blockquote><br />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6422938941757513069/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/02/webinar-online-approaches-to-editing.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6422938941757513069"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6422938941757513069"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/02/webinar-online-approaches-to-editing.html"
         title="Webinar: Online Approaches to Editing Greek Literature. The Philosophical Papyri"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
