<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6454168989042251984</id>
   <published>2016-12-14T11:30:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-12-14T11:32:58.346-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Digital Library"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Books from the Cotsen Institute of Archaeology</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.escholarship.org/uc/cioa">Open Access Books from the Cotsen Institute of Archaeology</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Cotsen Institute of Archaeology Press is the academic publishing  division of the Cotsen Institute of Archaeology at UCLA, a premier  research organization dedicated to the creation, dissemination, and  conservation of archaeological knowledge and heritage. The Cotsen  Institute is also home to both the Interdepartmental Archaeology Program  and the UCLA/Getty Master's Program in Archaeological and Ethnographic  Conservation. Since 1975, the Cotsen Institute Press (formerly the  Publications Unit) has served to preserve cultural heritage through the  documentation and publication of scholarly archaeological research.  Specializing in producing high-quality academic titles, our press  publishes approximately 10 volumes per year in nine series, including a  new digital series hosted on eScholarship. Acquisitions are monitored by  an Editorial Board composed of distinguished UCLA and external faculty  and are accepted based on the results of critical peer review. For more  information about our press, please visit our Web site <a href="http://www.ioa.ucla.edu/publications/introduction" target="_blank">http://www.ioa.ucla.edu/publications/introduction</a>.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.escholarship.org/uc/search?entity=cioa_cda">Cotsen Digital Archaeology series</a></span></h3><div id="divcioa_cda" style="display: block;"><blockquote><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0 0 0 75px; position: relative;"><a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/1r6137tb"></a><br /><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Kansa, Eric C.; Kansa, Sarah Whitcher; Watrall, Ethan: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/1r6137tb">Archaeology 2.0: New Approaches to Communication and Collaboration</a>, 2011<br /><b>Abstract:</b> How is the Web transforming the professional practice of archaeology?  And as archaeologists accustomed to dealing with “deep time,” how can we  best understand the possibilities and limitations of the Web in meeting  the specialized...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Wendrich, Willeke: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/6n42w0rg">The World According to Basketry</a>, 1999<br /><b>Abstract:</b> This book was originally published in 1999 by the Leiden University,  Center of&nbsp;Non-Western Studies. This is an unabridged re-publication of  the 1999 edition,&nbsp;and the one-hour movie that is an integral part of the  book. You...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Wendrich, Willemina: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/7p51v5jz">Who is afraid of basketry</a>, 1991<br /><b>Abstract:</b> A guide to recording basketry and cordage for archaeologists and ethnographers...</span></div></div></blockquote></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.escholarship.org/uc/search?entity=cioa_ciap">Cotsen Institute of Archaeology Press</a></span></h3></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="content"><div class="body pad10"><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0 0 0 75px; position: relative;"><a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/2pm6p3j1"></a><br /><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Rosen, Steven A: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/2pm6p3j1">An Investigation into Early Desert Pastoralism: Excavations at the Camel Site, Negev</a>, 2011</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Bonavia, Duccio: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/7xs9j2zs">The&nbsp;South American Camelids:&nbsp;An Expanded and Corrected Edition</a>, 2009<br /><b>Abstract:</b> One of the most significant differences between the New World’s major  areas of high culture is that Mesoamerica had no beasts of burden and  wool, while the Andes had both. Four members of the camelid...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Bawden, Garth; Blom, Deborah E.; Bourget, Steve; Buikstra, Jane E.; Heckman, Andrea M.; Janusek, John Wayne&nbsp;et al.: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/4fv1g24d">Us and Them: Archaeology and Ethnicity in the Andes</a>, 2005<br /><b>Abstract:</b> This volume brings together a corpus of scholars whose work  collectively represents a significant advancement in the study of  prehistoric ethnicity in the Andean region. The assembled research  represents an outstanding collection of theoretical and...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Watrous, L. Vance; Hadzi-Vallianou, Despoina; Blitzer, Harriet: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/9b59z1np">Plain of Phaistos:&nbsp;Cycles of Social Complexity in the Mesara Region of Crete</a>, 2005<br /><b>Abstract:</b> The volume presents the results on an interdisciplinary regional field  project (1984 - 1987) carried out on the island Of Crete. This volume  traces the changing patterns of settlement and cycles of social  complexity from...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/7wz555xf">Advances in Titicaca Basin Archaeology-1</a>, 2005<br /><b>Abstract:</b> Advances in Titicaca Basin Archaeology-I is the first in a series of  edited volumes that reports on recent research in the south central  Andes. Volume I contains 18 chapters that cover the entire range of...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Beaubien, Harriet F.; Emery, Kitty F.; Henderson, John; Joyce, Rosemary; Longstaffe, Fred L.; Masson, Marilyn A.&nbsp;et al.: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/75h1s16p">Maya Zooarchaeology: New Directions in Method and Theory</a>, 2004</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/2z3733d3">Archaeological Research on the Islands of the Sun and Moon, Lake Titicaca, Bolivia: Final Results from the Proyecto Tiksi Kjarka</a>, 2004<br /><b>Abstract:</b> Beginning in 1994, the Proyecto Tiksi Kjarka conducted a complete  survey of the Islands of the Sun and Moon in southern Lake Titicaca,  along with test excavations of important Inca, Tiwanaku, and  pre-Tiwanaku sites. This...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Iannone, Gyles; Connell, Samuel V: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/29z0c6dj">Perspectives on Ancient Maya Rural Complexity</a>, 2003<br /><b>Abstract:</b> Settlement archaeology in the Maya area has focused much of its  attention on the polar extremes of the settlement continuum. As a result  of this urban/rural bias, a whole range of complex rural settlements  remain...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/77c3f20h">Prehistoric Sitagroi: Exavations in Northeast Greece, 1968-1970 Volume 2: The Final Report</a>, 2003<br /><b>Abstract:</b> Volume 2 presents the concluding research on Sitagroi, a prehistoric  settlement mound in northeastern Greece, excavated between 1968 and  1970. This volume offers a detailed report on the plant remains along  with a full treatment...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/7w73x6d5">Yeki bud, yeki nabud: Essays on the Archaeoogy of Iran in Honor of William M. Sumner</a>, 2003<br /><b>Abstract:</b> This volume is a collection of essays by colleagues, friends, and  students of William M. Sumner in appreciation of his outstanding  contribution to Iranian archaeology, especially to our archaeological  knowledge of Fars, a center of...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Arnold, Jeanne E.; Bradford, Katherine; Boyd, Brian F.; Conlee, Christina A.; Dowdall, Katherine M.; Erlandson, Jon M.&nbsp;et al.: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/9j5806h3">Catalysts to Complexity</a>, 2002<br /><b>Abstract:</b> When the Spanish colonized it in AD 1769, the California Coast was  inhabited by speakers of no fewer than 16 distinct languages and an  untold number of small, autonomous Native communities. These societies  all survived...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Brown, Linda A.; Gillepsie, Susan D.; Grove, David C.; Manzanilla, Linda; McAnany, Patricia A.; Plunket, Patricia&nbsp;et al.: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/82s3x2bh">Domestic Ritual in Ancient Mesoamerica</a>, 2002<br /><b>Abstract:</b> Although the concepts and patterns of ritual varied through time in  relation to general sociopolitical transformations and local historical  circumstances in ancient Mesoamerica, most archaeologists would agree  that certain underlying themes and structures modeled the...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Hirth, Kenneth; Andrews, Bradford: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/5n22p8rf">Pathways to Prismatic Blades: A Study in Mesoamerican Obsidian Core-Blade Technology</a>, 2002<br /><b>Abstract:</b> The obsidian prismatic blade is one of the sharpest cutting implements  ever produced in the prehistoric world. This volume explores the social  and economic processes involved in its manufacture in ancient  Mesoamerica. Contributors examine the...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Beaudry-Corbett,  Marilyn; Begley, Christopher Taylor; Bove, Frederick J.; Boxt, Matthew  A.; Dillon, Brian D.; Fowler, William R.&nbsp;et al.: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/5jp891m6">Early Scholars' Visits to Central America</a>, 2000</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Anderson, Patricia C: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/6k10g0nv">Prehistory of Agriculture: New Experimental and Ethnographic Approaches</a>, 1999</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Greenwood, Roberta S.: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/2p51h066">Down by the Station: Los Angeles Chinatown 1880-1933</a>, 1996<br /><b>Abstract:</b> In 1933, the demolition of the thriving Los Angeles Chinatown for the  construction of Union Station sealed the remains of this intact  community 14 feet below the railroad tracks. The planning and  construction of the...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Loring, J. Malcolm; Loring, Louise: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/2m27f1gp">Pictographs &amp; Petroglyphs of the Oregon Country, Parts I &amp; II</a>, 1996</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Lass, Barbara: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/62j0c23c">Hawaiian Adze Production and Distribution: Implications for the Development of Chiefdoms</a>, 1994<br /><b>Abstract:</b> Using a study of stone adzes of the precontact period on the island of  Hawai'i, Lass examines the role of a material resource in the  development of cultural complexity. Archaeological evidence is used to  analyze...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Sease, Catherine: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/8ft6488x">A Conservation Manual for the Field Archaeologist</a>, 1994<br /><b>Abstract:</b> Conservation treatments and techniques for the archaeologist in the  field, emphasizing how to conserve an excavated object before it is  taken to a trained conservator offsite. Safety procedures and  conservation supplies and materials are recommended....</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/75z9q032">Pottery of Prehistoric Honduras: Regional Classification and Analysis</a>, 1993</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Luedtke, Barbara E.: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/7j8387sj">An Archaeologist's Guide to Chert and Flint</a>, 1992<br /><b>Abstract:</b> For at least 2.5 million years, humans have been using tools, and until  just a few thousand years ago their most important tools were of stone.  The single most important and widely used stone in...</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/09x3c981">Hunter-Gatherers of Early Holocene Coastal California</a>, 1991</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 75px; position: relative;"><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Costello, Julia G.; Maniery, Mary L.: <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/8167k5g2">Rice Bowls in the Delta: Artifacts Recovered from the 1915 Asian Community of Walnut Grove, California</a>, 1988</span></div></div><div style="height: 130px; padding: 0 0 0 75px; position: relative;"><a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/38t6f3m0"></a><br /><div style="padding-left: 10px;"><a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/38t6f3m0">Excavations at Sitagroi: A Prehistoric Village in Northeast Greece Volume 1</a>, 1986<br /><b>Abstract:</b> The first of 2 volumes reporting on excavations at a middle neolithic  to early bronze age site in northeast Greece. Vol. 1 presents the full  sequence of culture exposed by excavation of this settlement mound,...</div></div></div></div></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: small;">And see also <a href="http://www.ioa.ucla.edu/publications/backdirt">Backdirt: Annual Review of the Cotsen  Institute of Archaeology at UCLA</a></span></blockquote></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6454168989042251984/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/04/open-access-books-from-cotsen-institute.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6454168989042251984"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6454168989042251984"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/04/open-access-books-from-cotsen-institute.html"
         title="Open Access Books from the Cotsen Institute of Archaeology"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
