<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3342890733281930904</id>
    <published>2015-02-12T15:53:00.001-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-12T15:53:18.182-05:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="numismatics"/>
    <title type="text">Nomisma.org News</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a
      href="http://numishare.blogspot.com/2015/02/new-nomismaorg-framework-has-been.html">New
      Nomisma.org framework has been released</a><br /> <div class="post-header">
      </div><div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"><blockquote
      class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">After much work, the new <a
      href="http://nomisma.org/">Nomisma.org</a> framework has been launched into
      production. Not only is this a major architecture migration (moving the public UI from Apache
      Cocoon into <a href="http://www.orbeon.com/">Orbeon</a>), but a data migration. We
      have implemented a new data model for IDs that conforms to the <a
      href="http://nomisma.org/ontology">Nomisma ontology</a> that Karsten Tolle has been
      working on for at least two years. IDs have a more stable system of classes that will improve
      the predictability of queries. There are presently 16 classes by which IDs are defined--most of
      them in the nmo: (<a
      href="http://nomisma.org/ontology#">http://nomisma.org/ontology#</a>) namespace, but
      we are using the W3C Organziation ontology for expressing roles of people and organizations
      (under foaf:). The ontology is still evolving, but has a carefully curated set of properties
      and classes that pertain to numismatics. Certain URIs (like nm:mint), will never again be used
      simultaneously as classes and properties. In fact, all of the URIs that were used as classes
      and properties have been made instances of nmo:NumismaticTerm. Instances of mints (like Rome or
      Athens) are an nmo:Mint, and nmo:hasMint is the property to use for linking a coin or coin type
      to a mint URI. The ontology and data conform to standards established by the semantic web and
      computer science communities.<br /><br />Data dumps from museum collections (like
      the ANS and Berlin) have been migrated into the Nomisma ontology, as have RDF exports from
      online type corpora, like <a href="http://numismatics.org/ocre/">OCRE</a> and <a
      href="http://numismatics.org/crro/">CRRO</a>. This involved updating Numishare's code
      to export in the new ontology (see <a
      href="http://nomisma.org/documentation/contribute">http://nomisma.org/documentation/contribute</a>
      for example), as well as update SPARQL queries and the XSLT for reading latitude and longitude
      in the new model for mints. Mints are now reckoned as concepts (carrying the skos:Concept
      class, as well as nmo:Mint) that may or may not have a spatial feature, linked with
      geo:location. The object links by the geo:location is a geo:SpatialThing which may either have
      a latitude and longitude or have <a href="http://geojson.org/">geoJSON</a>
      encapsulated in the osgeo:asGeoJson property. Complex shapes, represented as geoJSON, can be
      drawn in Nomisma's XForms-based editing interface (powered by Orbeon). geoJSON objects created
      in OpenLayers in the editing interface are extracted by Javascript and incorporated into the
      XForms engine.<br /><br />The new features of this framework are almost two
      numerous to mention, but here is a synopsis:<br /><br /></span><ul
      style="text-align: left;"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">IDs are
      available in their native RDF/XML, but also serialized into Turtle and JSON-LD. IDs for regions
      that may contain complex geoJSON polygons are exported in <a
      href="http://geojson.org/vocab">geoJSON-LD</a>. These serializations are linked from
      the ID page. Data dumps of all IDs are available in these three serializations as
      well.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="http://numishare.blogspot.com/2014/12/extending-nomisma-for-spatial-queries.html">Spatial
      queries</a> are supported by extending Fuseki to interact with a Solr
      index.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Much improved
      browse interface allows for additional filtering by roles of people/organizations and sorting.
      These filters can be applied to the Atom feed as
      well.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Content
      negotiation is supported for IDs, the SPARQL endpoint, and the browse page. See <a
      href="http://nomisma.org/apis#access">http://nomisma.org/apis#access</a> for more
      information about interacting with IDs and Solr. The SPARQL endpoint supports
      <i>text/html</i>, <i>text/csv</i>, <i>text/plain</i>,
      <i>application/sparql-results+json</i>, and
      <i>application/sparql-results+xml</i>.</span></li><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">RIC and RRC ids have been deprecated by Nomisma, as OCRE and
      CRRO maintain up-to-date and better quality versions. HTTP 303 See Other redirects are
      established for any ID that contains a dcterms:isReplacedBy property that links to something
      else. See <a
      href="http://nomisma.org/id/rrc-44.5">http://nomisma.org/id/rrc-44.5</a>.&nbsp;</span></li><li><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">We have begun documenting the model and <a
      href="http://nomisma.org/documentation/sparql">example SPARQL queries</a>. The
      documentation will evolve to become more comprehensive in the coming months.
      </span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">The system in general
      is far more stable and efficient now that RDF/XML has replaced XHTML documents. It reduces the
      need for additional transformation when delivering web services. More than 90% of HTTP requests
      for Nomisma content comes from machines (about 30,000 per
      day).</span></li></ul></blockquote></div>]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3342890733281930904/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/02/nomismaorg-news.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3342890733281930904"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3342890733281930904"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/02/nomismaorg-news.html"
         title="Nomisma.org News"/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
