<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6222802231092122393</id>
   <published>2015-02-22T10:35:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-02-22T16:24:56.000-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CHS"/>
   <title type="text">Now Online from the CHS – Helots and The Masters in Laconia and Messenia: Histories, Ideologies, Structures</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://edited by Nino Luraghi and Susan E. Alcock">Now Available Online – Helots and The Masters in Laconia and Messenia: Histories, Ideologies, Structures, edited by Nino Luraghi and Susan E. Alcock</a><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://kleos.chs.harvard.edu/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Luraghi-Alcock-cover.jpeg"><img alt="Luraghi-Alcock cover" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3799" src="http://kleos.chs.harvard.edu/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Luraghi-Alcock-cover.jpeg" height="267" style="float: left; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 10px;" width="200" /></a>The <b>Center for Hellenic Studies</b> is pleased to announce the online publication of&nbsp;<a href="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:hul.ebook:CHS_LuraghiN_AlcockS_eds.Helots_and_Their_Masters.2003">Helots and The Masters in Laconia and Messenia: Histories, Ideologies, Structures</a>, eds. <b>Nino Luraghi</b> and <b>Susan E. Alcock</b>,&nbsp;on the <b>CHS</b> website.</span> </blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The name “Helots” evokes one of the most famous peculiarities of  ancient Sparta, the system of dependent labor that guaranteed the  livelihood of the free citizens. The Helots fulfilled all the functions  that slaves carried out elsewhere in the Greek world, allowing their  masters the leisure to be full-time warriors. Yet, despite their crucial  role, Helots remain essentially invisible in our ancient sources and  peripheral and enigmatic in modern scholarship.</span> </blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">This book is devoted to a much-needed reassessment of Helotry and of  its place in the history and sociology of unfree labor. The essays deal  with the origins and historical development of Helotry, with its  sociological, economic, and demographic aspects, with its ideological  construction and negotiation.</span> </blockquote><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Susan E. Alcock</b> writes on the introductory chapter of this volume:</span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">It is unlikely that the helots will ever shed that  quality of Rorschach test, and indeed it might be a shame, given their  evocative history, that they ever should. Still, this volume directs us  towards new ways of analyzing and of envisioning these people. In part,  this involves the nature of our questions: accepting our lack of detail  about helots and helot life should discourage grand and totalizing  narratives. Instead, the way forward seems to be through encouragement  of alternative methodologies, such as the use of comparative data sets  or of archaeology, to unpick more nuanced questions, in more localized  fashions. Perhaps most fundamental of all is the need to reconsider our  own starting assumptions, to grant the helots both capacities and hopes  that the usual suspects of our sources have steadfastly denied to them.</span> </blockquote></blockquote><blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">Such reconsideration—recasting the terms of debate about helots and  helotage— was the point of the original workshop organized by the  editors, and remains the point of this volume. It is certainly a  methodological puzzle. It is inescapably a political challenge. It is  arguably a moral obligation.</span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="promo_scroll" class="aligncenter" src="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/dImage?bdco=450&amp;bdc=12" height="5" title="promo_scroll" width="33" /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Nino Luraghi</b>&nbsp;is Professor of the Classics at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.harvard.edu/">Harvard University</a>.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Susan E. Alcock</b>&nbsp;is John H. D’Arms Collegiate Professor of Classical Archaeology and Classics at the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.umich.edu/">University of Michigan</a>.</span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">Have you taken the <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/02/ancient-world-online-user-survey.html">AWOL User Survey</a>?</div><div style="text-align: center;">And See AWOL's List of <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/09/open-access-publications-of-center-for.html" target="_blank">Open Access Publications of the Center for Hellenic Studies</a> </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6222802231092122393/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/02/now-available-online-helots-and-masters.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6222802231092122393"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6222802231092122393"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/02/now-available-online-helots-and-masters.html"
         title="Now Online from the CHS – Helots and The Masters in Laconia and Messenia: Histories, Ideologies, Structures"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
