<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5474774771559129228</id>
   <published>2014-01-28T06:32:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2014-01-28T06:40:31.486-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Classics"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="History"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Philology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Aegean"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greece"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Electryone - `Hλεκτρυώνη</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.electryone.gr/">Electryone - `Hλεκτρυώνη</a><br />ISSN: 2241-4061<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.electryone.gr/wp-content/themes/piggie-bank/img/header.gif" class="decoded" src="http://www.electryone.gr/wp-content/themes/piggie-bank/img/header.gif" height="103" width="400" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Electryone is an English-language, peer reviewed online journal  devoted to ancient historical and philological issues covering the  period between the 2nd and 1st millennia BC&nbsp; and the Roman period A.D.&nbsp;  Electryone welcomes articles between 4,000 and 8.000 words, shorter  notes, responses, etc. up to 2,500 words, and book reviews. It also  welcomes presentations of new publications, announcements for  conferences and information about research programs.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Electryone focuses on the Mediterranean region and on matters  referring to interactions of the Mediterranean with neighboring areas,  but presents an international forum of research, innovative  interpretations, critical reviews, analyses of ancient text sources,  comparative studies, mythological issues, archive research reports,  interaction of ancient history with topography and archaeology, and  applied new technologies on historical and classical studies.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Electryone covers the full range of classical studies (i.e. 2nd  millennium to late Rome) but is particularly interested in classical  antiquity and its relationship to other cultures.</span><br /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 1 Issue 2</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.electryone.gr/?p=480" title="1. M. Aguirre, “Deukalion and Pyrrha: Re-reading the Greek Flood myth”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss. 2, pp. 1-12">1. M. Aguirre, “Deukalion and Pyrrha: Re-reading the Greek Flood myth”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss. 2, pp. 1-12</a></strong><br />In recent years the most common way to interpret the Greek myth of the  Flood has been through a comparative approach in the context of the  relationship between Greek and Near Eastern cultures and the influences  of the Near East on Greek traditions, literature, religion and myth. My  article does not intend to re-examine the conclusions of this research,  but, without diminishing the obvious importance of the comparative  approach, to focus on the most ‘canonical’ Greek version of the myth and  to highlight some aspects of it which in my view have not been so  deeply explored.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.electryone.gr/?p=482" title="2. N. Panagiotakis, M. Panagiotaki, A. Sarris,”The Earliest Communication System in the Aegean” (2013) Vol. 1, Iss 2,  pp. 13-27">&nbsp;2.  N. Panagiotakis, M. Panagiotaki, A. Sarris,”The Earliest Communication  System in the Aegean” (2013) Vol. 1, Iss 2,&nbsp; pp. 13-27</a></strong><br />A communication system based on fire signals was identified in Crete by  the field archaeologist Nikos Panagiotakis, during an archaeological  survey he conducted in the Pediada region in central Crete (from 1982 to  1989), covering more than 800 sq. km. The Pediada lies between the  Bronze Age palatial sites of Knossos and Malia (from west to east) and  extends south and southeast of modern Heraklion. The communication  system was used during the Minoan period, especially between 1900-1700  BC. It worked by means of codified fire signals sent from the top of  large, man-made constructions (in the shape of a truncated cone), built  on the tops of hills or ridges. The network with its interconnecting  visual contact could keep a close watch over, and so control natural  passes and routes, covering the whole countryside and the coasts.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.electryone.gr/?p=506" title="3. Ι. Deraj, “Xenophon’s Representation of Socratic διαλέγεσθαι” (2013) Vol. 1, Iss. 2, pp.28-38">3. Ι. Deraj, “Xenophon’s Representation of Socratic διαλέγεσθαι” (2013) Vol. 1, Iss. 2, pp.28-38</a></strong><br />This paper deals with the problem of Xenophon’s representation of  Socratic διαλέγεσθαι (dialogic conversation). The author analyzes  selected examples of its use by Xenophon in his adaptation of the  Socratic ethics in Memorabilia and compares it with Plato’s use of  διαλέγεσθαι in his early dialogues. The main hypothesis of this paper is  that the Socratic use of διαλέγεσθαι should not be identified with  Socrates’ use of elenchus (ἔλεγχος). The author suggests an implication  of this hypothesis is that the question-answer turn-taking form of  διαλέγεσθαι is not its essential feature. He attempts to demonstrate  that what constitutes the essence of both Socrates’ use of διαλέγεσθαι  in Xenophon’s Memorabilia 4 and of Odysseus’ use of persuasive speech in  Antisthenes’ Odysseus or on Odysseus is the purpose of examining and  transforming one’s individual ethos (ἦθος).</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.electryone.gr/?p=486" title="4. T. Samuels, “Denise Eileen McCoskey, Race: Antiquity and its Legacy” (2013) Vol. 1, Iss. 2, pp.39-43">4. Review: T. Samuels, “Denise Eileen McCoskey, Race: Antiquity and its Legacy” (2013) Vol. 1, Iss. 2, pp.39-43</a></strong></span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 1 Issue 1</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.electryone.gr/?p=314" title="1. K. Wrenhaven, “Barbarians at the Gate: Foreign Slaves in Greek City-States”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss.1, pp. 1-17">1. K. Wrenhaven, “Barbarians at the Gate: Foreign Slaves in Greek City-States”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss.1, pp. 1-17</a></strong><br />This article considers the relationship between interconnectivity and  Greek slavery, in particular, the slave trade and the geographical  sources of slaves in Greek city-states. Since there exists no extant  treatment of the slave-trade from Greek antiquity, most of the evidence  is indirect and focuses primarily upon the Classical period. A variety  of source material is examined, including Greek drama, art,  historiography, and inscriptions. Of specific interest is the often  problematic nature of the evidence for the slave trade and the ethnicity  of slaves. Although it is clear that the Greeks traded in foreign  slaves, how most slaves were acquired and from where are questions that  continue to confound modern scholars. This article does not seek to  provide a definitive answer to these questions, but aims to further the  discussion through a consideration of why the Greeks preferred foreign  slaves, how slaves were procured and from where, how we might determine  the ethnicity of slaves through indirect evidence (such as names), and  the presence of foreign slaves in Attica, where most of the source  material originates.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.electryone.gr/?p=355" title="2. R. Covino, “Stasis in Roman Sicily”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss. 1, pp. 18-28">2. R. Covino, “Stasis in Roman Sicily”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss. 1, pp. 18-28</a></strong><br />This article seeks to examine the evidence for three instances of  stasis-prevention efforts from the period of Roman dominion known to us  through the medium of Cicero’s Verrines. In doing so, it will build on  the work of Berger who examined the phenomenon of stasis in Sicily and  Southern Italy during preceding eras and of Eilers who examined the  Roman patrons of Greek cities. The article establishes a timeline for  the Romans’ efforts and then draws conclusions about the people involved  in stasis-prevention in the province and the Romans’ hands-off approach  to civic government in Sicily during the Republic.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.electryone.gr/?p=361" title="3. M. Melotti, “Αrchaeological tourism and economic crisis. Italy and Greece”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss. 1, pp. 29-53">3. M. Melotti, “Αrchaeological tourism and economic crisis. Italy and Greece”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss. 1, pp. 29-53</a></strong><br />Before the recent economic crisis, both in Greece and in Italy there was  an extraordinary development in various kinds of urban activities. Some  of them have considerably affected museums and archaeological sites and  have made them more attractive to the new post-modern tourism of  sensory and emotional character. The new Acropolis Museum in Athens was  almost a symbol of this change, but also the new exhibition spaces in  commercial centres and underground stations must be taken into account.  In Italy a similar change occurred in some of its major towns, such as  Rome, Turin, Naples, Cagliari and Reggio Calabria. The outbreak of the  crisis has subsequently brought to a halt the proliferation of these  initiatives and has induced critical reflections on what has happened  and what may yet happen. Urban policies, gentrification and  beautification processes must be reconsidered. It is no longer time for  archaeology without finds and atmosphere without contents, accordingly  to the post-modern model. However, the de-intellectualization of today’s  societies obliges even the most serious scholars to take into account  the potential of some forms of edutainment, such as living history and  re-enactment, which up-to-now have been under-evaluated and despised by  archaeologists and historians.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.electryone.gr/?p=365" title="4. M. Porubjak, “Theognis and the Social Role of Measure.”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss. 1, pp. 54-65">4. M. Porubjak, “Theognis and the Social Role of Measure.”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss. 1, pp. 54-65</a></strong><br />The paper deals with the beginnings of the Greek ethical discourse in  elegies of an archaic lyric poet Theognis of Megara. In the introduction  author shortly discusses the question of origin and influence of the  Theognidea. Then he gradually follows and interprets the occurrences of  the expression “μηδὲν ἄγαν” (Nothing in excess), of the words σωφροσύνη  (soundness of mind), σάοφρων (temperate), μέτρον (measure) and μέτριος  (moderate), according to the problem of ἀρετή (excellence). On the basis  of symposium description in the Theognidea and its functions, author  shows the crucial social dimension of researched capabilities. He also  tries to show how Theognis grasps the wisdom as a quality that has to be  tried for and cared for. In the end author states that for Theognis the  excellences such as wisdom, justice, sound mind and proper measure are  conditio sine qua non for functioning of all social relations – from  erotic relations through symposium to polis itself.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.electryone.gr/?p=368" title="5. Review: M. El-Nowieemmy, “Virgil: The Aeneid, translated into Arabic with notes by various hands, revised by A. Shaarawi”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss. 1, pp.66-68">5.  Review: M. El-Nowieemmy, “Virgil: The Aeneid, translated into Arabic  with notes by various hands, revised by A. Shaarawi”, (2013) Vol. 1 Iss.  1, pp.66-68</a></strong></span></blockquote><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a> </span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5474774771559129228/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/02/new-open-access-journal-electryone-h.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5474774771559129228"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5474774771559129228"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/02/new-open-access-journal-electryone-h.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Electryone - `Hλεκτρυώνη"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
