<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-965854546659534692</id>
   <published>2014-10-02T11:34:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2014-10-02T11:34:13.931-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Announcement/Call for Contributions: Perseus Open Publication Series</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://sites.tufts.edu/perseusupdates/2014/10/02/perseus-open-publication-series/">Perseus Open Publication Series</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">October 2, 2014<br />University of Leipzig, Germany<br />Tufts University, USA</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Initial Call for Contributions:</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Greek and Latin Editions<br />Modern Language Translations<br />Commentaries<br />Contributions to the Ancient Greek and Latin Dependency Treebanks.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Perseus Digital Library at Tufts University and the Open  Philology Project at the University of Leipzig announce plans for the  Perseus Open Publication Series (POPS), a new venue for open access and  open data publications in any format and in any language that the  Perseus Digital Library can support. The Perseus Digitary Library  attracted 390,000 visitors in August 2014 while its contents are now  prominent digital collections for two universities, one in Germany and  one in the United States, each of which maintains its own repository.  The Perseus Open Publication Series thus provides a visible,  non-exclusive publication medium for those who wish their content to  reach the widest possible audience and to be preserved as a part of the  Perseus Digital Library.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Development of POPS will take place in stages and will ultimately  include content in any format and on any subject within the Perseus  Digital Library. This initial call is aimed at those who are producing,  wish to produce, or who have already produced, well-understood forms of  publication such as editions, commentaries, modern language  translations, as well as the Greek and Latin Dependency Treebanks, and  other resources that shed light upon sources in Greek and Latin and  where the content can be reviewed with fairly traditional editorial  processes. If you have published a digitized Greek or Latin edition or a  new translation on a website or as a PDF file, and if you want to see  this work also published as a part of the Perseus Digital Library,  please let us know. You can continue to keep making your material  available on your website and giving it to others to publish.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">We expect the range of materials that we accept to expand in the  coming years. We particularly encourage translations, both in English  and in other languages — the ability to identify qualified reviewers  provides the critical limiting factor on how much material we can  assess. We encourage authors to produce their own TEI XML, using  materials already in the Perseus Digital Library as templates and we  will offer training for the most committed potential contributors and  editors in producing EpiDoc TEI XML and/or creating morphological and  syntactic annotations of Greek and Latin. This training can take place  either at Leipzig or in other countries. We currently support training  in Croatian, English, French, German, and Italian, with plans to expand  to other languages. Where particularly important material already exists  in HTML, Word, PDF or some other format, we will consider helping with  the conversion into XML.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">New contributions will be published initially as part of a new  repository for Greek and Latin textual materials and accompanying  annotations, based upon the Canonical Text Services Architecture. The  CTS architecture will provide the backend for the next generation of the  Perseus Digital Library website.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Our strategy to make the system itself is based upon making all  content available under an appropriate Creative Commons license via the  Perseus.org web site, while charging for services that make that content  more convenient (e.g., a subscription that provides constantly updated  versions of the Perseus texts in e-book format). All content and  software that we produce will be open and others will be able — as they  are already — to create their own versions and services based upon the  Creative Commons licenses that authors select. Authors will be free to  publish their materials in as many other venues as they choose (e.g.,  PDF representations of their materials might appear in Academia.edu or  ResarchGate) and store their materials in additional repositories.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">We have formed a steering committee to accomplish the following  goals: (1) to identify potential authors and existing content; (2) to  participate actively and constructively in planning the on-going  development of the Perseus Open Publication&nbsp;Series.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Those interested in contributing send inquiries <a href="mailto:perseus-pops@elist.tufts.edu">here</a>.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Steering Committee (as of October 1, 2014)<br />Bridget Almas, Tufts and Alpheios.net<br />Alison Babeu, Tufts<br />Marie Claire Beaulieu, Tufts<br />Christopher Blackwell, Furman University<br />Monica Berti, Leipzig<br />Federico Boschetti, CNR, Pisa<br />Michèle Brunet, Lyon<br />Giuseppe G. A. Celano, Leipzig<br />Lisa Cerrato, Tufts<br />Harry Diakoff, Alpheios.net<br />Reinhard Foertsch, German Archaeological Institute, Berlin<br />Greta Franzini, Leipzig (Goettingen, as of 2015)<br />Neven Jovanovic, Zagreb<br />Thomas Koentges, Leipzig<br />Matt Munson, Leipzig<br />Charlotte Schubert, Leipzig<br />Neel Smith, College of the Holy Cross, Worcester MA<br />Simona Stoyanova, Leipzig</span><br /></blockquote><br />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/965854546659534692/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/10/announcementcall-for-contributions.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/965854546659534692"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/965854546659534692"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/10/announcementcall-for-contributions.html"
         title="Announcement/Call for Contributions: Perseus Open Publication Series"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
