<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1802770230409069826</id>
    <published>2015-05-21T17:26:00.000-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-21T17:26:54.222-04:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <title type="text">CDLI News: Detroit Institute of Arts (DIA)</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/?q=news/detroit-institute-arts%E2%80%94cuneiform-too">Detroit
      Institute of Arts—Cuneiform too!</a><br /><div class="field field-name-body
      field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><div class="field-items"><div
      class="field-item even"> <blockquote class="tr_bq"><div><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">The <a href="http://www.dia.org/">Detroit Institute of
      Arts</a> (DIA), and the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation-supported research project “Creating
      a Sustainable Digital Cuneiform Library (CSDCL),” are delighted to announce the addition of new
      resources to the web in support of online research and of the digital preservation of shared
      world cultural heritage. Under the general direction of the Cuneiform Digital Library
      Initiative (CDLI), an international research project based at the University of California, Los
      Angeles, an initial agreement of cooperation was reached in December of 2013 between Prof.
      Robert K. Englund, CDLI Principal Investigator, and Lina Meerchyad, DIA Collection Research
      Associate, who managed communication, catalogued objects, compiled and shared photographs, and
      translated texts of DIA cuneiform objects. With the generous support of the Department of
      Collections Management and the Department of the Arts of Asia and the Islamic World at the DIA,
      the collection was scanned in May of 2014 by CDLI member and UCLA graduate student Michael
      Heinle, working closely with Lina Meerchyad in Detroit. The results of that collaboration have
      now been added to the CDLI website, viewable <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/search/search_results.php?SearchMode=Text&amp;requestFrom=Search&amp;MuseumNumber=dia+">here</a>;
      they can also be viewed via the project’s <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/search/">search
      page</a> (type DIA in “Collection
      number”).&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">The DIA is one of the top art museums in the United States. In addition to having
      great collections of famous artworks, the Museum also possesses <a
      href="http://www.dia.org/art/">discoveries</a> from ancient Middle East, Africa,
      Egypt, Europe, Greece, America, etc. The art of <a
      href="http://www.dia.org/art/search-collection.aspx?department=Ancient+Near+Eastern+Art">Ancient
      Middle East collection</a> consists of significant archaeological artifacts from the
      early civilizations of Mesopotamia, Iran, and the Arabia. Within the collection is a group of
      34 administrative cuneiform clay tablets, cones, and bullae that were formerly in the
      collection of Prof. Albert T. Clay, Yale University, donated to the museum by Henry Glover
      Stevens in 1919. The objects date back to the Sumerian kings of the Third Dynasty of Ur,
      Shulgi, Amar-Sin, Shu-Sin, and Ibbi-Sin, and were mostly found at Puzrish-Dagan, Umma, and
      Girsu (ca. 2112-2004 BC). Among them are documents from the time of Sin-kashid of the Early Old
      Babylonian (ca.1790 BC), as well as from the Old, Middle, and neo-Babylonian periods, dated
      from the 19th-6th centuries BC. Other inscribed objects are neo-Assyrian <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/search/search_results.php?SearchMode=Text&amp;ObjectID=P427111,P480679">reliefs
      of Assurnasirpal II</a> (883-859 BC), a <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P469533">brick of Shalmaneser III</a> (858-824 BC), a <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P450210">relief from the Palace of Tiglath-pileser III</a>
      (744-727 BC), all from Nimrud, and a <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P232285">statue of
      Gudea</a>, the governor of Lagash (ca. 2150-2125 BC). Three publications in the
      <em>Bulletin of the Detroit Institute of Arts</em> on the latter objects can be
      viewed <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/files/diacuneiform_jstor.pdf">here</a>.</span></div><div><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">With the goals of ensuring the long-term digital preservation of
      ancient inscriptions on cuneiform text artifacts, of furthering Humanities research, and of
      providing free international access to all objects data, we hope that the DIA-CDLI
      collaboration will be welcomed by Assyriologists, scholars of related fields, and all those
      generally interested in the history of the ancient Near East. We look forward to their
      investigation of the DIA digital content, and are grateful for their corrections and interest
      in our catalogue and in publishing unedited texts in the collection. For publication purposes,
      any inquiries about the cuneiform collection should be directed to the <a
      href="mailto:curators@dia.org?subject=DIA%20cuneiform">Detroit Institute of
      Arts</a>.</span></div><div><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">For the Detroit Institute of Arts:</span></div><div><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">Lina H. M. Meerchyad, Collection Research Associate, Collections
      Management, DIA</span></div><div><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">For the Cuneiform Digital Library
      Initiative:</span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">Robert
      K. Englund, Director, CDLI, and Professor of Assyriology,
      UCLA</span></div></blockquote></div></div></div>]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1802770230409069826/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/05/cdli-news-detroit-institute-of-arts-dia.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1802770230409069826"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1802770230409069826"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/05/cdli-news-detroit-institute-of-arts-dia.html"
         title="CDLI News: Detroit Institute of Arts (DIA)"/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
