<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1353768229985105694</id>
   <published>2015-02-16T16:23:00.002-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-02-16T16:23:33.352-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Islam"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Geography"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Atlas"/>
   <title type="text">al-Thurayyā Gazetteer, Ver. 02</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://maximromanov.github.io/2014/11-20.html">al-Thurayyā Gazetteer, Ver. 02</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://maximromanov.github.io/images/althurayya_02_01.png" class="decoded" height="125" src="http://maximromanov.github.io/images/althurayya_02_01.png" width="200" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This is our first usable demo of <strong>al-Thurayyā Gazetteer</strong>. Currently it includes over 2,000 toponyms and almost as many route sections georeferenced from Georgette Cornu’s <em>Atlas du monde arabo-islamique à l'époque classique: IXe-Xe siècles</em> (Leiden: Brill, 1983). The gazetteer is searchable (upper left corner),  although English equivalents are not yet included; in other words, look  for Dimashq/دمشق, not Damascus. </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span>  <span style="font-size: x-small;">You can browse the Gazetteer by clicking on any toponym marker. The  popup will show the toponym both in Arabic script and transliterated. We  are&nbsp;using a slightly modified transliteration system that facilitates  conversion between fully transliterated, transliterated, and Arabic  forms of toponyms. It should be easily understandable. There may be  typos, because of the nature of how the data has been generated, so  please, let us know if something should be corrected. The popup also  offers a selection of possible sources on a toponym in question. You can  check <em>Arabic Sources</em>: currently, al-Samʿānī’s <em>Kitāb al-ansāb</em> and Yāqūt’s <em>Muʿjam al-buldān</em>.  Currently, the Gazetteer will only check for exact matches, which means  that in some cases there will not be any entry at all, while in other  cases there may be more than one and they may refer to other places with  the same name. Improving the precision of this lookup is on our to-do  list. You can also check if there is information on a toponym in  question in Brill's <em>Encyclopaedia of Islam</em>, <em>Pleiades,</em> and <em>Wikipedia</em>.</span><br />  <h2 id="credits-&amp;-acknowledgments"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Credits <em>&amp;</em> Acknowledgments</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Many thanks to Adam Tavares (programmer @ Perseus Project, Tufts)  and, particularly, Cameron Jackson (senior, double-majoring in Arabic  and Computer Science, Tufts) for the technical development; to Vickie  Sullivan (Chair, Classics Department), Gregory Crane and the entire  Perseus team on the both sides of the Atlantic for support and  inspiration.</span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">And see AWOL's <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/09/roundup-of-resources-on-ancient.html">Roundup of Resources on Ancient Geography</a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1353768229985105694/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/02/al-thurayya-gazetteer-ver-02.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1353768229985105694"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1353768229985105694"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/02/al-thurayya-gazetteer-ver-02.html"
         title="al-Thurayyā Gazetteer, Ver. 02"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
