<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6749843442356940493</id>
   <published>2016-01-13T14:19:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-01-13T14:19:44.775-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Bibliography"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#"
             term="Corpus Inscriptionem Graecarum"/>
   <title type="text">Classics Librarian on Finding CIG Citations</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: small;"><a href="https://classicslibrarian.wordpress.com/2016/01/13/finding-cig-citations/">Finding CIG Citations</a></span><br />             <span style="font-size: small;">January 13, 2016&nbsp;</span><br /><small><span style="font-size: small;">Reposted with permission from <a href="https://classicslibrarian.wordpress.com/">Classics Librarian</a>&nbsp; by </span></small><small><span style="font-size: small;">Phoebe Acheson </span></small><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">For&nbsp;the&nbsp;<strong>Corpus Inscriptionem Graecarum (CIG)</strong>, all  you need to know to find the inscription you want is its unique number,  and this is just what most citations will give you. Inscriptions are  numbered continuously starting at CIG 1 and continuing through all  volumes and parts (ending at CIG 9926). </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">So, the inscription CIG 284 is 284th from the beginning of the set (it happens to appear in volume 1 part 2). </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">At the <a href="https://www.libraries.uc.edu/classics.html">University of Cincinnati’s Burnam Classical Library</a>, some&nbsp;friendly librarian of yore helpfully labeled the volumes with the CIG numbers contained therein:<br /> <a href="https://classicslibrarian.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/24049452260_70d3aa08c5_o.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-1155"><img alt="photo of spines of CIG volumes" class="wp-image-1155 size-medium alignleft" height="300" src="https://classicslibrarian.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/24049452260_70d3aa08c5_o.jpg?w=466&amp;h=616" width="225" /></a><br /> <ul><li>Volume 1: CIG 1-1792</li><li>Volume 2: CIG 1793-3809</li><li>Volume 3: CIG 3810-6816</li><li>Volume 4: CIG 6817-9926</li></ul><br /><br /> <strong>Story version:</strong><br /> I got a message (on Facebook!) from a friend who is a first-year  graduate student in Classics, with a background heavy on philology and  light on history/archaeology.<br /> <blockquote>I have a CIG number for an inscription (CIG 284) but I have no idea how to find what volume this would be in.<br /> I’ve been staring at a shelf for like five minutes and I can’t figure  out which one would be relevant and/or correct. How do I find this out?</blockquote>My friend already knew that CIG stood for <strong>Corpus Inscriptionem Graecarum</strong> (<a href="http://www.worldcat.org/title/corpus-inscriptionum-graecarum/oclc/4852589">WorldCat record, including volume and parts listings</a>), published by <a href="https://viaf.org/viaf/37048283/">August Bockh</a> between 1828 and 1877. She was standing in front of the print volumes,  which are generally next to the much more voluminous volumes&nbsp;of <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inscriptiones_Graecae">Inscriptiones Graecae</a></strong> (IG), which was created as a continuation of CIG, which I suspect is  what perplexed my friend so thoroughly. Note that this, like many 19th  century German reference works,&nbsp;is entirely in latin as that was the  contemporary&nbsp;<em>lingua franca</em> for the scholarly community.<br /> Since the CIG volumes are old enough to be&nbsp;no longer in copyright, they <a href="https://www.scribd.com/collections/2637277/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-1828-1877">are available as downloadable .pdf files at Scribd</a>. Many thanks to the communal effort of the group&nbsp;<a href="https://www.scribd.com/publisher/31832601/Patrologia-Latina-Graeca-et-Orientalis#">Patrologia Latina Graeca et Orientalis</a>&nbsp;(<a class="site-description" href="http://plgo.org/">plgo.org</a>)  which made these available! I have not checked these thoroughly for  accuracy but in my random perusings have found them to be complete and  fully accurate. Links to individual .pdfs at Scribd follow:<br /> <ul><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/38042967/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-I-Pt-1-Pt-2-Bockh-BOA-1828">Vol. 1,&nbsp;Pars I (Tituli antiquissima scripturae forma insigniores); Pars II&nbsp;(Inscriptiones atticae).</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/38042970/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-I-Pt-2-Pt-6-Bockh-BOA-1828">Vol.  1, Pars II&nbsp;(Inscriptiones atticae); Pars III (Inscriptiones megaricae);  Pars IV&nbsp;(Inscriptiones peloponnesiacae); Pars V&nbsp;(Inscriptiones  boeoticae); Pars VI&nbsp;(Inscriptiones phocicae, locricae, thessalicae).</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/46510268/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-II-Pt-7-Pt-12-Sec-VI-Bockh-BOA-1843">Vol.  2,&nbsp;Pars VII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Acarnaniae, Epiri, Illyrici); Pars  VIII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Corcyrae et vicinarum insularum); Pars IX&nbsp;(Tituli  aliquot locorum in Graecia incertorum); Pars X&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Macedoniae  et Thraciae); Pars XI&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Sarmatiae cum Chersoneso Taurica  et Bosporo Cimmerio); Pars XII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones insularum Aegaei maris cum  Rhodo, Creta, Cypro) through section VI.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/46510262/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-II-Pt-12-Sec-VII-Pt-13-Bockh-BOA-1843">Vol.  2,&nbsp;Pars XII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones insularum Aegaei maris cum Rhodo, Creta,  Cypro) from section VII on; Pars XIII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Cariae).</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/46515272/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-II-Pt-13-Pt-14-Bockh-BOA-1843">Vol. 2,&nbsp; Pars XIII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Cariae); Pars XIV&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Lydiae).</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/46515273/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-II-Pt-15-Pt-16-Bockh-BOA-1843">Vol. 2,&nbsp;Pars XV&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Mysiae); Pars XVI&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Bithyniae).</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/38042974/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-III-Pt-17-Pt-32-Bockh-BOA-185">Vol.  3,&nbsp;Pars XVII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Phrygiae); Pars XVIII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones  Galatiae); Pars XIX (Inscriptiones Paphlagoniae); Pars XX&nbsp;(Inscriptiones  Ponticae); Pars XXI&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Cappadociae); Pars  XXII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Lyciae); Pars XXIII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Pamphyliae); Pars  XXIV&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Pisidiae et Isauriae); Pars XXV&nbsp;(Inscriptiones  Ciliciae); Pars XXVI (Inscriptiones Syriae); Pars XXVII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones  Mesopotamiae et Assyriae); Pars XXVIII (Inscriptiones Mediae et  Persidis); Pars XXIX&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Aegypti); Pars XXX&nbsp;(Inscriptiones  Aethiopiae supra Aegyptum); Pars XXXI&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Cyrenaicae); Pars  XXXII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Siciliae cum Melita, Lipara, Sardinia).</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/53346011/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-III-Pt-32B-Bockh-BOA-1853">Vol. 3, Pars XXXII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Siciliae cum Melita, Lipara, Sardinia) B.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/53346014/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-III-Pt-33A-Bockh-BOA-1853">Vol. 3,&nbsp;Pars XXXIII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Italiae) A.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/53346016/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-III-Pt-33B-Bockh-BOA-1853">Vol. 3, (Pars XXXIII. Inscriptiones Italiae) B.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/53346017/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-III-Pts-34-38-Addenda-et-corrigenda-Bockh-BOA-1853">Vol.  3,&nbsp;Pars XXXIV&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Galliarum); Pars XXXV&nbsp;(Inscriptiones  Hispaniae) Pars XXXVI (Inscriptiones Brittanniae) Pars  XXXVII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Germaniae);&nbsp;Pars XXXVIII&nbsp;(Inscriptiones Pannoniae,  Daciae, Illyrici); Addenda et Corrigenda.&nbsp;</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/38042978/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-IV-Pts-39-40-Bockh-BOA-1877">Vol. 4,&nbsp;Pars XXXIX&nbsp;(Inscriptiones locorvm incertorvm) Pars XL&nbsp;(Inscriptiones christianae).</a></li><li><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/38042979/Corpus-Inscriptionum-Graecarum-Vol-IV-Fasc-3-Indices-Bockh-BOA-1877">Vol. 4, Indices.</a></li></ul>The inscription CIG 284 turns out to be the Shield of Alkamenes,  which has been owned by the British Museum since 1805 (item number <a href="http://www.britishmuseum.org/research/collection_online/collection_object_details.aspx?objectId=459498&amp;partId=1&amp;searchText=shield+of+alkamenes&amp;page=1">1805,0703.232</a>), and they have a very nice online catalog of objects. The entry has an image AND bibliographic citations!<br /> <a href="https://classicslibrarian.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/24049458240_b2cd1fa267_o-e1452698473173.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-1157"><img alt="24049458240_b2cd1fa267_o" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1157" height="338" src="https://classicslibrarian.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/24049458240_b2cd1fa267_o-e1452698473173.jpg?w=900&amp;h=676" width="450" /></a><br /> Note, as for this inscription, many things originally published in  CIG have been subsequently republished in IG, so to be thorough you may  need to look up a given inscription in multiple reference works –  perhaps a future post will tackle the complexities of&nbsp;IG citations!<br /><small><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp; </span></small></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6749843442356940493/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/01/classics-librarian-on-finding-cig.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6749843442356940493"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6749843442356940493"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/01/classics-librarian-on-finding-cig.html"
         title="Classics Librarian on Finding CIG Citations"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
