<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7954257462985122837</id>
   <published>2015-04-19T09:01:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-04-19T09:01:24.410-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Recently Published at Archaeopress: Open Access</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/defaultAll.asp?OpenAccess=Y&amp;intro=true"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Recently Published at<span> Archaeopress: Open Access</span></span></span></a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><div style="text-align: center;"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner" style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/F9A356EA5C754F7E885F44E2F25CC46D%5CA.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Setting  the Scene:   The deceased and regenerative cult within offering table  imagery of the Egyptian Old to Middle Kingdoms   (c.2686 – c.1650 BC)</b> by Barbara O’Neill. 123 pages.  <em>Archaeopress Egyptology </em>. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ancient Egyptian offering table scenes have been explored  from chronological and art historical perspectives over the past  century of Egyptological research. This descriptive overview has usually  centred on the diachronic evolution of philology and food offerings,   focussing less frequently on offering table images as discrete elements  of highly codified information. The exploration into offering&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner" style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner" style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/B3FCE613F1E647058AABFB8B0D237662%5C9781784911003.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>CAA2014. 21st Century Archaeology</b> <i>Concepts,  methods and tools. Proceedings of the 42nd Annual Conference on  Computer Applications and Quantitative Methods in Archaeology</i> edited  by F. Giligny, F. Djindjian, L. Costa, P. Moscati and S. Robert. vi+649  pages; illustrated throughout in colour and black &amp; white.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This volume brings together a selection of papers proposed for the <i>Proceedings of the 42nd Computer Applications and Quantitative Methods in Archaeology conference (CAA)</i>,  hosted at Paris 1 Panthéon-Sorbonne University from 22nd to 25th April  2014. The program was divided into different themes and this structure  has been maintained in the arrangement of articles in the various  chapters of this book. Chapter headings include: Historiography; Field  and Laboratory Data Recording; Ontologies and Standards; Internet and  Archaeology; Archaeological Information Systems; GIS and Spatial  Analysis; Mathematics and Statistics in Archaeology; 3D Archaeology and  Virtual Archaeology; Multi-Agent Systems and Complex System Modelling. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>CAA2014 is also available in paperback, priced £75.00. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B30A17C9B-F191-4734-9FD8-74C3F7002F88%7D">Click here for more information.</a></b></span>&nbsp;</div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/788EB8DC0A1849C790D6F1B28CFBFF7A%5CCover.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Roman Barrows by Velika Gorica, Croatia, and Pannonian Glazed and Samian Pottery Production</b> by Rajka Makjanić and Remza Koščević. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Description of Roman Barrows from the first and second  centuries AD excavated in the 1980s  in the forest of Turopoljski Lug  near Velika Gorica (Zagreb), Croatia. Special attention is given to a  luxurious lead-glazed relief bowl found on the funeral pyre of Barrow V,  probably from a local Pannonian workshop, with decoration inspired by  western Samian ware.</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/42B78E7188754F449EF665A161576937%5CArthur%20Evans%20in%20Dubrovnik%20and%20Split%20%281875-82%29.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Arthur Evans in Dubrovnik and Split (1875-1882)</b> by Branko Kirigin. ii+14 pages; illustrated throughout in colour and black &amp; white.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Thanks to the biography by Joan Evans, sister of Arthur  Evans, the research of John J. Wilkes and the new biography by Silvia L.  Horwitz, we know much about Arthur Evans’s work in the Balkans prior to  his discoveries on Crete. This work will not repeat here the  achievements Evans has made for archaeology, ethnography and cultural  history of the region including his remarkable journalistic work where  he showed deep knowledge of regional politics and admiration towards the  Slav freedom movement ‘against Turks, Austrians, Russians, or any  others – including Englishmen – who refused them their right to  self-determination’. This work presents some details on the everyday  life of Arthur Evans in Dubrovnik and Split as seen by the local people  who wrote about him in newspapers, journals or books, material that is  not easily available to those interested in Evans’s pre-Knossos period.</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/10FA1F93DCD54865B0FA63C2BD5DF3A4%5C9781784910600.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>The Origins and Use of the Potter’s Wheel in Ancient Egypt (VIDEO)</b> by Sarah K. Doherty. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">A sequence of video's from Sarah K. Doherty to compliment her publication <i><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B62A0CB01-F9AA-4A8B-800C-2B61E76FF3D0%7D">Archaeopress Egyptology 7: The Origins and Use of the Potter’s Wheel in Ancient Egypt.</a></i><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Hand-building Cooking Pot, El Nazla Pottery</b><br /><br />See the incredible hand building process using the paddle and anvil  technique. This is still the traditional method of creating water jars  in Egypt, unusually the potter is male. <br /></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Throwing Pottery with a Replica Ancient Egyptian Potter's Wheel</b><br /><br />This is the results of my experiments in creating an ancient Egyptian  potter's wheel and making replica Old Kingdom (4th dynasty c2600 BC)  pottery. The wheel head is wooden, the base comprises a socket and pivot  of basalt or limestone. <br /></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Throwing on a kick wheel at El Nazla, Faiyoum, Egypt</b><br /><br />This shows the quick throwing and coiling process used by the potters of El Nazla, Faiyoum, Egypt. <br /></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Electric Wheel Throwing compared to ancient</b><br /><br />Compare the actions of wheel throwing using a modern electric wheel. Notice how I use both hands to throw. <br /></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /><br />Sarah K. Doherty's publication <i>The Origins and Use of the Potter’s Wheel in Ancient Egypt</i> is available now priced £29.00. <b><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B62A0CB01-F9AA-4A8B-800C-2B61E76FF3D0%7D">View description and full contents listings here.</a></b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/557A18DBA4984EE9992D8E818C666563%5C9781784910839.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Die Anfänge des kontinentalen Transportwesens und seine Auswirkungen auf die Bolerázer und Badener Kulturen</b> by Tünde Horváth. iv+77 pages; illustrated throughout in colour and black &amp; white. German text.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The earliest finds of wheeled vehicles in northern and  central Europe date to 3900-3600 BC. However finds (3400–3300 BC) from  the Boleráz sites of Arbon/Bleiche 3 and Bad Buchau/Torwiesen II, linked  to pile-dwelling settlements, indicate methods of transport typical for  higher altitudes (slides, sleds, etc.). The Boleráz and Baden cultures  overlap in the Carpathian Basin between 3300–3000 BC and this period  seems to have produced transport models that parallel finds in today’s  Austria, Slovakia, Hungary, and other regions. These suggest that  generally the Boleráz settlers inside the Carpathian Basin did not know,  or use, the wheel in the fullest sense. Cart and wheel forms are  indicated only from Grave 177 at Budakalász (2800–2600 BC). The  Hungarian Baden finds follow the Danube and to the East there are no  certain vehicle remains. It is difficult to tell whether the Boleráz  finds are linked to the wider Alpine zone, and the Baden finds are  perhaps associated with the mixed-culture sites along the eastern slopes  of the Carpathians. The four-wheeled wagon was a development linked to  the plains and the Steppes (Cucuteni–Tripolje, Pre-Yamnaja, Yamnaja).  The nature of the finds relating to vehicles associated with lake and  riverine settlements reveal technical and material features: there is  evidence of a high degree of carving, if not decoration, and these  communities pointed the way for future skills and developments in wheel  and cart/wagon manufacture.</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/7B701A0B009440DFA07F21C7DF79F963%5C9781784910242.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Bell Beaker in Eastern Emilia (Northern Italy)</b> <i>Taken from <b>Around the Petit-Chasseur Site in Sion (Valais, Switzerland) and New Approaches to the Bell Beaker Culture</b></i> by Nicola Dal Santo, Alessandro Ferrari, Gabriella Morico and Giuliana Steffè. Pages 205-236.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This paper presents recent pre-Bell Beaker groups and  other groups contemporary to Bell Beaker, such as the final stages of  Spilamberto Group, the Castenaso facies and the Marzaglia facies,  recently recognised after rescue excavations. New Bell Beaker  settlements and some aspects of recent and final Bell Beaker Culture are  discusssed. In Emilia Romagna the final stages of Beaker phenomenon,  here called Late Bell Beaker, are well documented and they are  contemporary to the development of Early Bronze Age communities in the  southern fringe of central Pre-Alps (Polada Culture). <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Around the Petit-Chasseur Site in Sion  (Valais, Switzerland) and New Approaches to the Bell Beaker Culture:  Proceedings of the International Conference (Sion, Switzerland – October  27th – 30th 2011)</i> edited by Marie Besse, Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BA632C561-3DE9-43A4-B1A2-DEA258F87703%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/744EDA4D9BD442268C2E1F0BFCBE7EC8%5C9781784910266.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Occlusal macrowear, antemortem tooth loss, and temporomandibular joint arthritis at Predynastic Naqada</b> <i>Taken from <b>Palaeopathology in Egypt and Nubia: A century in review</b></i> by Nancy C. Lovell. Pages 95-106.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This paper is based on the results of an examination of  crania and mandibles from three cemeteries at Predynastic Naqada, which  were excavated by Petrie in 1895. These remains are curated as part of  the Duckworth Collection at the University of Cambridge. Patterns of  occlusal macrowear, antemortem tooth loss, and lesions of the  temporomandibular joint (TMJ) are described, and are discussed in the  contexts of diet and the biomechanics of mastication. The incomplete  nature of most of the dentitions restricted the assessment of the  pathological conditions, but no statistically significant differences  were observed in the prevalence of TMJ arthritis between males and  females, nor between elite and non-elite cemetery samples. Furthermore,  antemortem tooth loss and occlusal wear were not associated with TMJ  lesions. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Palaeopathology in Egypt and Nubia: A century in review</i> edited by Ryan Metcalfe, Jenefer Cockitt and Rosalie David,  Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or  download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B35B24F22-A438-422E-83F4-F4E3BBAF8B77%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/E86DFEF6626547AABC65C0DC6433DA8E%5COA%20cover.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Terra Sigillata / Samian Ware found in Siscia (Sisak, Croatia) now at the Archaeological Museum in Zagreb</b> by Rajka Makjanić. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Publication of Samian ware from the Archaeological Museum  in Zagreb, found in Roman Siscia. The assemblage includes Italian,  Gaulish, African, Pannonian, Moesian and other pottery. It also  incorporates a study on some types of North Italian Sigillata and their  distribution in Pannonia. First published in BAR S621.</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/7A8F3D67B71647A098FCAEF8C2DC00EF%5CShipwrecks%20and%20Global%20%27Worming%27%20-%20cover.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Shipwrecks and Global ‘Worming’</b> by P. Palma and L.N. Santhakumaran. ii+62 pages; illustrated in full colour throughout.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Marine borers, particularly the shipworms, as destroyers  of timber, par excellence, are well known from very ancient times. They  attacked the wooden hulls of ships with such intensity that the weakened  bottom planks broke up even due to a mild impact caused by hitting a  rock or any floating objects inducing shipwrecks. Even the survival of  sunken ships as wrecks depends on the mercy of wood-destroying  organisms, which may turn these ‘port-holes’ to history into meaningless  junks. The silent saboteurs, involved in several early shipwrecks, are  the molluscan and crustacean borers, aided by bacteria and fungi. <br /><br />This paper presents an account of the marine wood-borers, together with a  historical review of literature on their depredation on wooden ships,  and on protective methods adopted from antiquity to modern times. The  seriousness with which early mariners faced the problem of  bio-deterioration and the fear the wood-borers created in their minds  have been brought to light with, in some cases, excerpts from their  journals and books. The anxiety and concern for protecting the ships  from the ravages of wood-borers and for their own safety, as evidenced  from their accounts, are discussed. Classification of various groups of  marine wood-borers with notes on characters of systematic value and a  complete list of species so far recorded in literature have been  included under Appendix I and II. Methods employed to prevent damage to  the boats included deep-charring, coating with pitch, coal-tar, whale  oil and mustard oil with lime; scupper nailing (‘filling’); sheathing  with animal skin, hair, tarred paper, wooden boards (untreated or soaked  in coal tar, Ferrous sulphate, Copper sulphate or Lead monoxide);  sheathing with metals (Lead or Copper sheets); plastic, neoprene coated  ply-woods; and painting with Copper oxide, Pentachlorophenol or  phenylarsenious oxide. None of these imparts complete protection. Recent  archaeological investigations carried out in British waters, especially  on ‘Mary Rose’, are also summarised. It is suggested that, though  borers are instrumental in inducing ship-wrecks thereby enriching the  materials for archaeological studies, excavations at known ship-wreck  sites should be augmented to unearth valuable historical data, before  they are lost to satisfy the insatiable appetite of these pests.</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/1DE16914A0A045E88254AADA07D06F1B%5C9781784910365.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Alternative Trajectories in Bronze Age Landscapes and the ‘Failure’ to Enclose: A Case Study from the Middle Dunajec Valley</b> <i>Taken from <b>Settlement, Communication and Exchange around the Western Carpathians</b></i> by Tobias L. Kienlin, Marta Korczyńska and Klaus Cappenberg. Pages 159-200.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Drawing on current archaeological work in the  surroundings of the Bronze Age hilltop-settlement of Janowice on the  middle part of the Dunajec valley in this paper we want to highlight  some shortcomings in the traditional modelling of Bronze Age landscapes.  Instead of focusing on political power and the control of trade and  exchange along the Dunajec valley, it is asked in what other sense the  hilltop-settlement of Janowice with its long history of occupation from  broadly the Middle Bronze Age to the Early Iron Age could have been  ‘central’ for the development of this micro-region. GIS applications are  used to integrate the spatial data obtained and to improve our  understanding of local environment, choices of site location and  subsistence economy. In a wider perspective, attention is drawn to the  variability in Bronze Age landscapes – even along the course of the same  river valley. In broadly the same cultural and natural setting there  were different ‘solutions’ or strategies available to communities in  order to cope with external restraints and cultural notions how social  life should be organised. The development of these communities was  contingent upon numerous factors beyond even the most sophisticated  attempt at geographical modelling. In consequence, we must not mistake  any notions we may hold on the development of Bronze Age society for a  model of general applicability. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Settlement, Communication and Exchange around the Western Carpathians</i> edited by T. L. Kienlin, P. Valde-Nowak, M. Korczyńska, K. Cappenberg  and J. Ociepka, Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to read the full  paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B8EF3F10A-FF69-4B35-91F6-69A5297D331D%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/E49BA1DE81934233B621E52B7FE07855%5C9781784910365.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>New Geophysical Data on the Internal Structure of the Gáva Sites of Andrid-Corlat and Căuaş-Sighetiu in North-Western Romania</b> <i>Taken from <b>Settlement, Communication and Exchange around the Western Carpathians</b></i> by Tobias L. Kienlin and Liviu Marta. Pages 381-403.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Over the past years there has been an intensification of  archaeological research on fortified settlements of the Late Bronze Age  Gáva culture in the lowlands or marshes of the Tisza river and its  tributaries. Unlike fortified sites on the hilltops along the mountain  ranges of the Carpathians, that traditionally attracted archaeological  research, much less is known on their lowland counterparts. It is in the  context of this group of fortified lowland sites that Căuaş-Sighetiu  and Andrid-Corlat have to be seen, which are located on islands in the  swamps of the Romanian Ier valley. Fortified sites of the Gáva culture  and its neighbouring groups, that may reach substantial size, are  interpreted everything from the proto-urban centres of hierarchical  societies, via the focal points of tribal groups, to refuges in times of  crisis or enclosures for livestock. In fact, little still is known on  the occupation of such sites. Our work at Căuaş- Sighetiu and  Andrid-Corlat is one step towards a better understanding of such sites  in terms of their internal organisation and their function in a wider  settlement network. Drawing on data from a joint project of the Muzeul  Judeţean Satu Mare and the Institut für Ur- und Frühgeschichte,  Universität zu Köln, in this paper we will focus on the spatial  organisation of the settlement remains. New magnetometer data is  available that allows for the first time a comparison of both sites and  their internal organisation. It is shown, that even in the same  micro-region and during broadly the same period, there may be  considerable variability. Our data indicate that both sites were  occupied by closely comparable household units. Between them, however,  they show indications of rather different notions how social space  should be organised. It is an important task for future work to  understand why such differences occurred, and how such sites relate to  smaller neighbouring sites in chronological and functional terms. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Settlement, Communication and Exchange around the Western Carpathians</i> edited by T. L. Kienlin, P. Valde-Nowak, M. Korczyńska, K. Cappenberg  and J. Ociepka, Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to read the full  paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B8EF3F10A-FF69-4B35-91F6-69A5297D331D%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp; </b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/86A3E5C794B547F4BC7F651112929738%5C9781784910365.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Tard-Tatárdomb: An Update on the Intensive Survey Work on the Multi-Layer Hatvan and Füzesabony Period Settlement</b> <i>Taken from <b>Settlement, Communication and Exchange around the Western Carpathians</b></i> by Klára P. Fischl, Tobias L. Kienlin, Tamás Pusztai, Helmut Brückner,  Simone Klumpp, Beáta Tugya and György Lengyel. Pages 341-379.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">In this paper the results of an intensive survey  programme are discussed carried out on the Early to Middle Bronze Age  site of Tard-Tatárdomb on the foothills of the Bükk mountains. This work  is part of a joint project that seeks to provide more detailed  information on the multi-layer tell or tell-like sites of the Hatvan and  Füzesabony periods in northern Hungary than was hitherto available.  Starting on the micro-level it is our aim to explore the inner structure  of these settlements, to establish the location and the structure of  households, to establish if there are settlement parts with specialised  function, and to compare the architecture and activity patterns of the  various parts of these sites. On a macro-level an attempt is made to  define the factors that determined the choice of site location and to  understand the spatial organisation of settlement in environmental,  economic and social terms. In the long-run, it is asked what role the  sites examined had to play in the settlement network of the Hatvan and  Füzesabony cultures, and an attempt will be made at comparing the land  use, economy and society of both groups. To this end, our current  research is based mainly on intensive archaeological survey, aerial  photography, topographical measurements and magnetometer survey that  provide important data both on the intra- and off-site level. In this  paper we discuss the spatial data obtained by aerial photography and  magnetometry as well as the results of our intensive surface survey  including aspects of lithic raw material procurement and the evidence  from animal bone finds. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Settlement, Communication and Exchange around the Western Carpathians</i> edited by T. L. Kienlin, P. Valde-Nowak, M. Korczyńska, K. Cappenberg  and J. Ociepka, Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to read the full  paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B8EF3F10A-FF69-4B35-91F6-69A5297D331D%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/0685F66B3A834E4F9C7420564DA7B8FE%5C9781784910242.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Megaliths of Easter Island</b> <i>Taken from <b>Around the Petit-Chasseur Site in Sion (Valais, Switzerland) and New Approaches to the Bell Beaker Culture</b></i> by Nicolas Cauwe. Pages 321-330.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">In 1992, a thesis came to light, sustaining the collapse  of Easter Island’s culture after a change in the landscape. This idea  was more than a simple hypothesis: the demonstration of the  deforestation of the island was the basis of this reflection. The  solution presented here appears radically contradictory; however it is  not more than an amendment of the previous one: twenty years ago,  understanding of environmental change contributed fundamentally to  knowledge; since then, the dossier has been enriched with the history of  the island’s monuments. Now we know that the statue platforms never  were destroyed, but conscientiously dismantled and converted into  necropolis. Likewise it is demonstrable that the volcano-quarry (Rano  Raraku), where the moai were sculpted, was not abandoned in  mid-operation, but voluntarily turned into an assembly of human figures.  The absence of great famines on Rapa Nui during the 17th and the 18th  centuries is shown by precise analyses. The very scarce presence of  weapons of war is a fact deduced from technological studies. Finally,  critical examination of the myths and legends shows that these texts do  not record historical events, but the view which Easter Islanders at the  end of the 19th century took of their past, after they had been  irredeemably cut off from it by circumstances beyond their control. It  is therefore incontestable that the last generations of Rapanui before  the arrival of the white man had begun a deep re-structuring of their  politico-religious system. Starting from this new documentary basis, we  must look for new hypotheses. That one proposed here, namely a  globalisation of island’s society giving new visibility to the god  Makemake to the detriment of the traditional pantheon, which was placed  under a taboo, seems provisionally the most credible, since it accounts  for all the elements recorded so far. This mutation of Rapanui’s society  was in progress at the time of the arrival of the 18th century  explorers. They were not aware of it, but no one could have been on  first discovering a hitherto unknown people. The first step of new  arrivals is to describe the present; the underlying dynamic can only be  discerned later, with hindsight. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Around the Petit-Chasseur Site in Sion  (Valais, Switzerland) and New Approaches to the Bell Beaker Culture:  Proceedings of the International Conference (Sion, Switzerland – October  27th – 30th 2011)</i> edited by Marie Besse, Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BA632C561-3DE9-43A4-B1A2-DEA258F87703%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/6CE34B501EB446AB98639C0D332BBA5F%5C9781784910181.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>‘Metal  makes the wheel go round’: the development and diffusion of  studded-tread wheels in the Ancient Near East and the Old World</b> <i>Chapter 18 from <b>ΑΘΥΡΜΑΤΑ: Critical Essays on the Archaeology of the Eastern Mediterranean in Honour of E. Susan Sherratt</b></i> by Simone Mühl. Pages 159-176.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">As emphasized by the image on the cover of Stuart  Piggott’s book Ancient Europe (1965), the wheel is, perhaps, one of  humanity’s greatest inventions. The ingenuity and simplicity of its idea  and the forms we know today are the result of a long process that  involved several stages of construction, testing and cumulative  improvement. Developments in wheel technology were, of course, related  to the emergence of different categories of vehicles – including  different forms of carts, wagons, or chariots – each representing a  response to changing needs in agriculture, elite representation and  warfare. One of these modifications was the ‘studded-tread wheel’ and  this will form the focus of this paper. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>ΑΘΥΡΜΑΤΑ: Critical Essays on the Archaeology of the Eastern Mediterranean in Honour of E. Susan Sherratt</i> edited by Yannis Galanakis, Toby Wilkinson and John Bennet,  Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or  download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BB6639BAB-9C10-4FB3-86AF-EE5801E1C89C%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/DC2B7AF0AD7E475785E68CF8F28379A6%5C9781784910181.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Arthur Evans and the quest for the “origins of Mycenaean culture”</b> <i>Chapter 11 from <b>ΑΘΥΡΜΑΤΑ: Critical Essays on the Archaeology of the Eastern Mediterranean in Honour of E. Susan Sherratt</b></i> by Yannis Galanakis. Pages 85-98.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>It is hard to say what chance had first drawn his  attention to the unknown island; it seems as if a thousand tiny facts  and things had drifted like dust and settled to weigh down the scales of  his decision</i> (J. Evans 1943: 299)<br /><br />What were these “thousand tiny facts and things”, that Joan Evans  alluded to in her influential biographical history, that attracted  Arthur Evans to Crete? An answer to this question may be gleaned from a  series of clues in the Evans story, which are described as pivotal and  decisive for the development of Aegean archaeology; namely his  transformation from a museum director and collector of antiquities  interested in history, art and archaeological research, to one of the  most influential figures in the – still nascent in those days – field of  Aegean archaeology. It is his quest for clues of a pre-alphabetic  writing system in this area of the Mediterranean that is now pinpointed  by scholars as the critical moment which led to the “dramatic  fulfillment” of Evans’s “most sanguine expectations”: the discovery at  Knossos, in various deposits, of materials inscribed with pre-alphabetic  writing. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>ΑΘΥΡΜΑΤΑ: Critical Essays on the Archaeology of the Eastern Mediterranean in Honour of E. Susan Sherratt</i> edited by Yannis Galanakis, Toby Wilkinson and John Bennet,  Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or  download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BB6639BAB-9C10-4FB3-86AF-EE5801E1C89C%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/F469B462030740A0A7EBD08CDF48CD5A%5C9781905739394.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>The Middle Helladic Large Building Complex at Kolonna. A Preliminary View</b> <i>Taken from <b>Our Cups Are Full: Pottery and Society in the Aegean Bronze Age</b></i> by Walter Gauß, Michael Lindblom and Rudolfine Smetana. Pages 76-87.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This paper introduces the so-called Large Building  Complex at Kolonna, Aegina for the first time in a comprehensive way.  The “Large Building Complex” is the thus far largest building found at  Kolonna, except the fortification wall. The Building was constructed at  the beginning of the Middle Helladic period (MH I/II) and remained in  use until the beginning of the Late Helladic period (LH I/II ). Within  its long history, it underwent a series of changes and modifications.  Size and dimensions as well as the rich finds from its interior clearly  indicate that the “Large Building Complex” is the unambiguous  residential building from Middle Helladic Kolonna.</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/3CDD63AFD5E5422693D097F4F05D9E4E%5C9781784910082.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Late  Classic Ceramic Technology and Its Social Implications at Yaxuná,  Yucatán: A Petrographic Analysis of a Sample of Arena Group Ceramics</b> <i>Chapter 19 from <b>The Archaeology of Yucatán: New Directions and Data</b></i> by Tatiana Loya González and Travis W. Stanton. pages 337-362.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This chapter represents an effort to interpret the social  and cultural aspects of ceramic technology and how they relate to the  political economy of the site of Yaxuná, Yucatán during the Late Classic  (A.D. 600-700/750, Yaxuná III) (see also Loya González 2008; Loya  González and Stanton 2013). We begin by introducing the reader to the  archaeology of Yaxuná, with an emphasis on the Late Classic period and a  diagnostic pottery group – Arena – that only appears during this time.  We then describe the Arena Group ceramics in more detail and the role  they have played in defining power struggles and control over central  Yucatán in the archaeological literature. Focusing on a petrographic  analysis of a sample of Arena Group ceramics from Yaxuná conducted  during spring of 2009 at the Center for Material Research in Archaeology  and Ethnology (CMRAE) at MIT we then discuss the implications of  tempers found in the Yaxuná vicinity and those used in the making of the  Arena Group vessels. Finally, we discuss the economic relationship between the sites of  Yaxuná and Cobá – two cities that were connected by a 100 km long raised  causeway during the Late Classic. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>The Archaeology of Yucatán: New Directions and Data</i> edited by Travis W. Stanton, Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://www.archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BA9ED36D9-0CF2-46C5-BA60-F89AE5B6BEC2%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/65B138FEC11042029DEB26CB44E8ADEE%5C9781905739844.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Pilgrimage to Binsey: Medieval and Modern</b> <i>Taken from <b>Binsey: Oxford's Holy Place</b></i> by Lydia Carr. Pages 81-88.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Binsey’s holy well, with its literary and spiritual  overtones, represents a key attraction of the little church for the  modern visitor. In this brief essay, the broad history of pilgrimage in  England is considered before approaching Binsey’s own post-Reformation  history. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Binsey: Oxford’s Holy Place - Its saint, village, and people</i> edited by Lydia Carr, Russell Dewhurst and Martin Henig, Archaeopress  2014. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to  your device. <a href="http://www.archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B3F7AE7AD-5ACA-473F-871D-C9EE553B99D9%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/63A9E64428E14E6CB2826587BC2B778C%5C9781905739141.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>The Archaeology of the North Sea Palaeolandscapes</b> <i>Chapter 9 from <b>Mapping Doggerland: The Mesolithic Landscapes of the Southern North Sea</b></i> by Simon Fitch, Vincent Gaffney and Kenneth Thomson. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>From the introduction:</i> The map data generated as  part of this project represents one of the largest samples of a,  potentially, well preserved early Holocene landscape surviving in Europe  and it is essential that some consideration of the archaeological  context of the mapped remains is presented here. The European cultural  period associated with this landscape is the Mesolithic which lasts  between c. 10,000 BP and c. 5,500 BP, dependent on geographic position.  Tremendous environmental change forms the backdrop to cultural events  throughout this period. Sea level rise, associated with climate change,  resulted in the loss of more than 30,000 km2 of habitable landscape  across the southern North Sea basin during the Mesolithic alone, and the  inundation of this immense area has essentially left us with a ‘black  hole’ in the archaeological record for northwestern Europe as a whole.  This situation is made worse by the fact that finds from the region only  rarely possess an accurate provenance or context (Koojimans 1971;  Verhart 2004). <i>View pdf to continue…</i><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Mapping Doggerland: The Mesolithic Landscapes of the Southern North Sea</i> edited by Vincent Gaffney. Kenneth Thomson and Simon Finch,  Archaeopress 2007. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or  download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BEC757A43-6A67-4817-8FA1-B7CA0418D6A4%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/5F15BF683AD24D42AB6C3B26AE8ACD1B%5C9781784910020.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Gods at all hours: Saite Period coffins of the ‘eleven-eleven’ type</b> <i>This paper is taken from <b>Body, Cosmos and Eternity: New Trends of Research on Iconography and Symbolism of Ancient Egyptian Coffins</b></i> by Jonathan Elias and Carter Lupton. 122-133.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">A distinct coffin style known as the Eleven-Eleven,  featuring a lid format with processions of eleven gods on the right and  left sides, came into prominence in the later Saite Period (likely after  630 BC). It is a style found in multiple regions throughout Upper  Egypt. Examples have been found at Akhmim, Thebes and Edfu. The current  study presents new findings arising from analysis of an Eleven-Eleven  coffin manufactured around 600 BC for the funerary preparer Djed-hor son  of Padiamon and Neshmut-Renenutet from Akhmim (Milwaukee Public Museum  A10264). Critical information relating to how the Eleven-Eleven was  intended to function symbolically comes from a little known container  fragment found at the end of the 19th century by Naville at the Delta  site of Tell el-Baklieh (Hermopolis Parva). It shows that the twenty-two  gods of the Eleven-Eleven style had protective functions linked to the  Day- and Night-hour goddesses of the Stundenwachen tradition. The  twenty-two deities served as guardians of the deceased during the eleven  divisions between the twelve hours of Day- and the eleven divisions  between the twelve hours of Night. With full hours and inter-hourly  divisions properly supervised by deities, all aspects of time were  therefore protected as the transformation of the deceased into a  resurrected being occurred. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Body, Cosmos and Eternity: New Trends of Research on Iconography and Symbolism of Ancient Egyptian Coffins</i> edited by Rogério Sousa, Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BE745BFE4-FAAB-4221-85B3-413A6E3E9276%7D">The full volume is available in paperback or pdf eBook here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/63D6D5053F114FA29AE784B9E44EF61E%5CPSAS%2044%20cover.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Investigating the orientation of Hafit tomb entrances in Wādī Andām, Oman</b> <i>This paper is taken from <b>Proceedings of the Seminar for Arabian Studies 44 (2014)</b></i> by William M. Deadman. 139-152.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This paper presents the results and analysis of a small  research project exploring the orientation of Hafit tomb entrances in  Wadi Andam, Oman. Measurements were taken at three sites along the  course of the wadi: Fulayj in the northern mountains, Khashbah in the  foothills, and ΚUyun on the plains to the south. The clear similarity  between the collective tomb entrance orientation data and the annual  variation in the position of the sunrise suggests that the path of the  sun was of great significance to the Hafit population of Wadi Andam, and  that it was recorded in their tomb architecture. Variation in the tomb  entrance data between the three sites suggests that the population was  nomadic and moved between areas of Wadi Andam according to season. These  results are discussed in the context of the distribution of Hafit tombs  and the terrain of Wadi Andam in order to explore how, where, and when  this seasonal migration could have occurred. Ethnographic studies of the  modern nomadic pastoralists of Oman and the UAE are examined to provide  potential parallels and to obtain a better understanding of the driving  force behind the Hafit seasonal nomadism. The tomb entrance orientation  measurements from Wadi Andam are also presented alongside the available  published data, revealing a possible east/west regional divide in the  Hafit funerary architecture of the northern Oman peninsula. The results  of this research suggest that the Hafit population of Wadi Andam was  nomadic, and migrated from the southern plains in the summer to the  mountains and foothills when the rains came in the winter, moving  through the terrain along the major watercourses and building tombs on  nearby elevated areas as they were needed, with entrances pointing  towards the sunrise. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Proceedings of the Seminar for Arabian Studies 44</i> edited by Robert Hoyland &amp; Sarah Morriss, Archaeopress 2014. Click  on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B91C93B3F-118C-4322-8450-EAED3C063323%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/8D4063D66173410CB1DC43D9688C691D%5CPSAS%2044%20Supplement%20cover.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Towards a Hadramitic lexicon: lexical notes on terms relating to the formulary and rituals in expiatory inscriptions</b> <i>This paper is taken from <b>Languages of Southern Arabia: Supplement to the Proceedings of the Seminar for Arabian Studies Volume 44 (2014)</b></i> by Alessia Prioletta. 101-110.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Although the corpus of Hadramitic inscriptions is highly  fragmented both chronologically and geographically, its grammatical  system and above all its lexicon display unique traits that make it of  particular interest to scholars. These traits are especially well  defined in the textual genre of the expiatory inscriptions since they  display a distinctive formulary and ritual lexicon compared to the  textual counterparts in the other South Arabian kingdoms. The study  focuses, in particular, on the lexical analysis of some key terms that  appear in the fixed formulas within which these inscriptions are  structured. The lexicon of these texts is characterized by many unique  features compared to the other ASA languages and, on a broader level,  combines isoglosses with the Southern Semitic languages, archaisms that  recall Akkadian, and a more typically Central Semitic lexicon. These  elements still await full analysis and systematic organization into a  comparative Hadramitic lexicon that will allow scholars to pursue  broader studies on the position of Hadramitic within the Ancient South  Arabian and Semitic in general. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Languages of Southern Arabia: Supplement to the Proceedings of the Seminar for Arabian Studies Volume 44</i> edited by Orhan Elmaz and Janet C.E. Watson, Archaeopress 2014. Click  on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B1F2BDBC1-B536-4AD9-A42D-4590D43E27A1%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/B3754DCB016E4863B8E9D7E657B492A1%5C9781905739950.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Maritime activity and the Divine: an overview of religious expression by Mediterranean seafarers, fishermen and travellers</b> <i>Chapter 1.1 from <b>Ships, Saints and Sealore: Cultural Heritage and Ethnography of the Mediterranean and the Red Sea</b></i> by Timmy Gambin. 3-12.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Over the past decades, modern technologies such as  electronic navigational aids, improved ship designs and accurate weather  forecasts have all contributed to making maritime activity safer.  However, even today the undertaking of a journey by sea or even a  fishing trip involves varying degrees of danger. Over the centuries,  those involved with earning a living at sea, as well as those simply  travelling by ship, have invoked specific rituals and developed  particular superstitions. These could be aimed at alleviating fears,  supplication for a safe journey or simply to plea for a bumper catch.  The relationship between seafarers and the divine is not limited to a  particular chronological period, religion or geographical zone. The aim  of this paper is to illustrate broadly how the maritime-divine link has  manifested itself through time. The presentation has been divided into a  number of themes that include ritual, iconography and the deities  themselves.<br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Ships, Saints and Sealore: Cultural Heritage and Ethnography of the Mediterranean and the Red Sea</i> edited by Dionisius A. Agius, Timmy Gambin and Athena Trakadas with  contributions by Harriet Nash, Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to  read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B76BBDDA5-640E-4DE5-B47C-95492058EFA0%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/2663E5E18F2944069025B7B7EEB3EA4F%5C9781905739950.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Sailing the Red Sea: ships, infrastructure, seafarers and society</b> <i>Chapter 5.1 from <b>Ships, Saints and Sealore: Cultural Heritage and Ethnography of the Mediterranean and the Red Sea</b></i> by Cheryl Ward. 115-123.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Sailing along the coast reinforces the benefits of  long-established Indian Ocean monsoon and trade patterns that extended  into the Red Sea. Vastly profitable and culturally significant  expeditions and fleets channelled people and exotic animals from  giraffes to elephants, Chinese porcelains, coffee, incense, textiles and  other goods into a durable, if episodic, infrastructure of coastal  sites in a pattern that endured for thousands of years. The acquisition  and influx of exotic materials established economic and social  interactions illuminated by recent archaeological exploration of  anchorages, harbours, shipwrecks and other installations. New data from  Red Sea sites offer a basis for examining the development of extensive  maritime systems from the middle of the third millennium BCE through the  early modern era. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Ships, Saints and Sealore: Cultural Heritage and Ethnography of the Mediterranean and the Red Sea</i> edited by Dionisius A. Agius, Timmy Gambin and Athena Trakadas with  contributions by Harriet Nash, Archaeopress 2014. Click on the PDF to  read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B76BBDDA5-640E-4DE5-B47C-95492058EFA0%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/D752FDD766EC49F7ACD602122603BFD0%5C9781905739752.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>The Boudica Code: recognising a 'symbolic logic' within Iron Age material culture</b> <i>Taken from <b>Landscapes and Artefacts: Studies in East Anglian Archaeology Presented to Andrew Rogerson</b></i> by John Davies. 27-34.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The material culture of the Iceni carries a wealth of  imagery and symbols. It is apparent that a number of these  representations were repeatedly chosen and, by implication, that they  carried meaning for the Iceni. The deep significance of symbols and  imagery in material culture can be observed in relation to other tribal  societies, such as the plains Indians of North America, whose objects of  everyday use possessed deep symbolic importance to them.<br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>Landscapes and Artefacts: Studies in East Anglian Archaeology Presented to Andrew Rogerson</i> edited by Steven Ashley and Adrian Marsden, Archaeopress 2014. Click on  the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B2CFF3438-93D0-4857-9310-1BE6B1EE57BE%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/674151BB21194C7DBBBDE85B72572007%5C9781905739462.JPG" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>A note on the development of Cypriot Late Roman D forms 2 and 9</b> <i>Taken from <b>LRFW 1. Late Roman Fine Wares. Solving problems of typology and chronology. A review of the evidence, debate and new contexts</b></i> by Paul Reynolds. 57-65.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The development and evolution of LRD 2 into LRD 9 through  the 5th to 7th centuries is traced and illustrated through a revision  of the evidence presented in Late Roman Pottery (Hayes 1972) and finds  from new contexts excavated in Beirut. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>LRFW 1. Late Roman Fine Wares. Solving problems of typology and chronology. A review of the evidence, debate and new contexts</i> edited by Miguel Ángel Cau, Paul Reynolds and Michel Bonifay,  Archaeopress 2012. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or  download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B1916F63B-0A20-48B5-8164-BC42F9FA6EC6%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/46B2F7634EA04FE68C8B0E9C290AB445%5C9781905739462.JPG" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>An initiative for the revision of late Roman fine wares in the Mediterranean (c. AD 200-700): The Barcelona ICREA/ESF Workshop</b> <i>Taken from <b>LRFW 1. Late Roman Fine Wares. Solving problems of typology and chronology. A review of the evidence, debate and new contexts</b></i> by Miguel Ángel Cau, Paul Reynolds and Michel Bonifay. 1-13.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This paper summarises both the evolution and the results  of the Barcelona ICREA/ESF workshop on late Roman fine wares. A brief  guide to what we agreed were the principal Mediterranean contexts for  the dating of fine wares, as well as a summary of the principal  conclusions on the dating and sources of ARS, LRC and LRD forms are  presented. Plans for the publication of the workshop and its results, as  well as future collaborative projects are outlined. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>LRFW 1. Late Roman Fine Wares. Solving problems of typology and chronology. A review of the evidence, debate and new contexts</i> edited by Miguel Ángel Cau, Paul Reynolds and Michel Bonifay,  Archaeopress 2012. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or  download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B1916F63B-0A20-48B5-8164-BC42F9FA6EC6%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/B29B1F9454F944EEAF9362BB903FAF49%5C9781905739462.JPG" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Ceramica e contesti nel Quartiere Bizantino del Pythion di Gortina (Creta): alla ricerca della “complessità” nella datazione</b> <i>Taken from <b>LRFW 1. Late Roman Fine Wares. Solving problems of typology and chronology. A review of the evidence, debate and new contexts</b></i> by Enrico Zanini and Stefano Costa. 33-44. Italian text.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The paper explores some critical points in the dating of  fine tableware found in occupation deposits and contexts of late Antique  and early Byzantine sites in the Mediterranean. The refinement of the  typological-chronological seriation of artifacts, the availability of  increasingly sophisticated stratigraphic sequences and the awareness of  the multiplicity of possible cognitive approaches create the conditions  for a methodological reflection on the complexity of dating. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This paper is taken from <i>LRFW 1. Late Roman Fine Wares. Solving problems of typology and chronology. A review of the evidence, debate and new contexts</i> edited by Miguel Ángel Cau, Paul Reynolds and Michel Bonifay,  Archaeopress 2012. Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or  download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B1916F63B-0A20-48B5-8164-BC42F9FA6EC6%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/CD893D7ACC974D67A3764A54DA3AC61C%5C9781905739462.JPG" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Sigillatas  africanas y orientales de mediados del VI d. C. procedentes de los  rellenos de colmatación de una cisterna de Hispalis (Sevilla) Los  contextos de la Plaza de la Pescadería</b> <i>Taken from <b>LRFW 1. Late Roman Fine Wares. Solving problems of typology and chronology. A review of the evidence, debate and new contexts</b></i> by Jacobo Vázquez Paz and Enrique García Vargas. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /><br />The public works carried out on the road network of  Seville (Spain) uncovered a structural complex of Roman date for the  storage and redistribution of water. According to some </span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7954257462985122837/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/04/recently-published-at-archaeopress-open.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7954257462985122837"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7954257462985122837"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/04/recently-published-at-archaeopress-open.html"
         title="Recently Published at Archaeopress: Open Access"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
