<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2783660150660465751</id>
   <published>2015-12-26T15:48:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-12-26T15:48:34.762-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Year End News from CDLI</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[As we near the end of the year, I'd like to report on a few additions to  CDLI content and functionality that might be of interest to some in  cuneiform studies and related fields. These additions resulted in large  measure from the project Creating a Sustainable Cuneiform Digital  Library (CSCDL)–phase 3, under the general management of CDLI at UCLA,  and generously funded by the Mellon Foundation, by UCLA's Humanities  Division (supported by its Center for Digital Humanities), and by Oxford  University.<br /><br />The first is a technical improvement achieved by  Émilie Pagé-Perron of the University of Toronto. Her implementation of a  CDLI search-renderer feed of an online viewer now accommodates the RTI  images of cuneiform artifacts that Oxford co-PI Jacob Dahl and research  associate Klaus Wagensonner (now at the Free University of Berlin)  created, working in the collections of the Ashmolean Museum and the  Louvre, and in smaller numbers in those of Oslo (Schøyen), Manchester  (JRL) and Philadelphia (UPenn); Bruce Zuckerman's West Semitic Research  Project at USC also imaged for us the Khorsabad reliefs of the Oriental  Institute Museum (Chicago). These files currently document 2,279  surfaces of 1,085 individual artifacts—in 8,570,000 discrete jpg's. Our  use of this online viewer, written by Gianpaolo Palma as a  sub-initiative of the cultural heritage capture technologies being  developed at the Visual Computing Lab of CNR-ISTI (Pisa), is described  at &lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT76_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT79_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/?q=rti-images" target="_blank">http://cdli.ucla.edu/?q=rti-images</a></span></span>&gt;.  The viewer does not pretend to replace the higher-level capabilities of  such powerful RTI viewers as InscriptiFact (WSRP) running on local  workstations, but it does offer some of the strengths of RTI image files  in a true online environment. In these, treated artifact surfaces are  presented for immediate browser view; for instance, three artifacts at  &lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT77_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT80_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/search/search_results.php?SearchMode=Text&amp;ObjectID=P215173,P345806,P416821" target="_blank">http://cdli.ucla.edu/search/search_results.php?SearchMode=Text&amp;ObjectID=P215173,P345806,P416821</a></span></span>&gt;,  a Sargon II lamassu in the OIM, an Ashmolean prism with Sumerian  literary texts, and an Old Akkadian account from the Louvre, each  hyperlink to several RTI images. Users may click on one of these links  after "View RTI" above the entry thumbnail, and then on the light bulb  found in the tool box at the upper left. Clicking, holding and moving  your cursor round about the image determines the light source and raking  angle, while the magnifying glass (or scroll ball/tracking pad in your  mouse) allows you to enlarge the image up to and down from pixelation.  It does not require as much practice as some of your <span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT78_com_zimbra_date" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT81_com_zimbra_date" role="link">Christmas</span></span>  toys to become expert at the use of this simple viewer. We are now  discussing making the much more cumbersome full RTI files available for  download to and viewing on local computers, using whatever full viewer  users might have available to them.<br /><br />Other additions to CDLI are in the realm of content: <br /><br />To begin, &lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT82_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT89_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://tinyurl.com/zelrw7e" target="_blank">http://tinyurl.com/zelrw7e</a></span></span>&gt;  displays, in groups of 2,000 entries per scroll view, the now full  Louvre catalogue completed as a component of the Agreement of Scientific  Cooperation signed by the Louvre and UCLA in <span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT83_com_zimbra_date" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT90_com_zimbra_date" role="link">March 2013</span></span> (&lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT84_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT91_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/?q=news/louvre-and-cdli" target="_blank">http://cdli.ucla.edu/?q=news/louvre-and-cdli</a></span></span>&gt;, and see &lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT85_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT92_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/collections/louvre/louvre_fr.html" target="_blank">http://cdli.ucla.edu/collections/louvre/louvre_fr.html</a></span></span>&gt;).  In a collaborative effort among Louvre staff and Klaus Wagensonner,  then at Oxford, this initial full inventory of Louvre cuneiform  artifacts resulted in a total of 12,550 entries, of which some 4,300  remain, so far as we see, unpublished. Wagensonner has, further, added  nearly 1,000 new fatcross image files for online view (&lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT86_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT93_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://tinyurl.com/hhx44wr" target="_blank">http://tinyurl.com/hhx44wr</a></span></span>&gt;),  including large numbers of unpublished Ur III accounts and receipts,  significant witnesses of Sumerian literary texts, and the DP tablets  heretofore only available in the 1913 hand copies of Allotte de la Fuÿe.  Through this initiative, and following the drive of Jacob Dahl, the  proto-Elamite texts from Susa have achieved the photographic  documentation that so evidently deserve (&lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT87_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT94_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://tinyurl.com/gog2hec" target="_blank">http://tinyurl.com/gog2hec</a></span></span>&gt;).  Quite frankly, it is difficult to overstate the importance to the  research of archaic Iran that is represented by the quality of images  presented at &lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT88_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT95_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P008126" target="_blank">http://cdli.ucla.edu/P008126</a></span></span>&gt;—not so much the dumb images really, as the text annotation that they facilitate.<br /><br />&lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT96_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT97_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://tinyurl.com/q567ho4" target="_blank">http://tinyurl.com/q567ho4</a></span></span>&gt;  are a final set of new British Museum images, also nearly 1,000 in  number. These are largely the result of digital camera photography done  by staff working under Jonathan Taylor, Assistant Keeper of the Museum's  Middle East Department, during CSCDL phase 2 and deposited as raw files  at CDLI/UCLA for final fatcrossing. More than half of these entries are  currently listed as unpublished; we are, as ever, grateful for any  feedback from specialists that would assist us in the many text  identifications we have certainly missed.<br /><br />&lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT98_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT100_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://tinyurl.com/gnz6n4b" target="_blank">http://tinyurl.com/gnz6n4b</a></span></span>&gt;  is the now complete set of cuneiform text artifacts located in the  collection of the Royal Ontario Museum of Archaeology, Toronto. ANE  Curator Clemens Reichel has kindly allowed us to make public, here,  images of all located artifacts, including ROM's 460+ unpublished 2nd  and 1st millennium texts. Permission to publish these texts should be  arranged through Dr. Reichel. For an overview of the collection, see  &lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT99_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT101_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/collections/rom/rom.html" target="_blank">http://cdli.ucla.edu/collections/rom/rom.html</a></span></span>&gt;.<br /><br />In  the past year, we have added substantial numbers of fatcrosses of  tablets in the collection of the Princeton Theological Seminary &lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT102_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT103_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/collections/pts/pts.html" target="_blank">http://cdli.ucla.edu/collections/pts/pts.html</a></span></span>&gt;.  UCLA graduate student Michael Heinle has recently undertaken CSCDL's  final capture mission to the PTS, and is processing our archival images  to complete work on their 2,900 texts. We were, unfortunately, not given  permission to access the largely unpublished Princeton University  Library collection of some 1,250 cuneiform texts.<br /><br />Now finally,  those whose interest in proto-cuneiform has never flagged will have  noted that the ongoing conflict in and around Baghdad shelved the final  volumes in the ATU series planned for Iraq National Museum texts, while  at the same time heavy numbers of Late Uruk texts have become available  to research in the aftermath of the two US-led wars against Iraq. Faced  with the unlikelihood of achieving a completed paper publication of  proto-cuneiform artifacts from Uruk, Hans Nissen determined that all  such data created in preparation for those volumes (ATU 8-9), as well as  all records of proto-cuneiform artifacts generally, should be made  available online so as to facilitate ongoing and future research. CDLI,  as successor host to the online components of ATU, has therefore  endeavored to gather and process for web dissemination all available  proto-cuneiform documentation, regardless of the origin of such data. As  a modest homage to Nissen's Archaische Texte aus Uruk project, to his  personal commitment to all facets of Uruk excavations, and as a living  extension of the ATU series, we completed in the past months a score  generator of all pertinent archaic lexical lists published in ATU 3.  Clicking on Q000002 under the first entry at &lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT104_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT107_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://tinyurl.com/zb2m3ol" target="_blank">http://tinyurl.com/zb2m3ol</a></span></span>&gt;,  for instance, brings up the composite version and all currently known  Late Uruk witnesses to the list known as Archaic Lu2 A (the notorious  Professions List; click on "Download transliterations" to see the exact  form of such transliterations with score-generating tags), while  clicking on "score" brings up the same texts in the full-score version  taught to all Sumerology students in Germany (and entering the Oracc  pages of Niek Veldhuis’ DCCLT site, for instance at &lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT105_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT108_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/dcclt/Q000002/score" target="_blank">http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/dcclt/Q000002/score</a></span></span>&gt;).  These scores include the numerous new witnesses in the Norwegian  Schøyen collection, and are a part of a growing number of such compendia  entering CDLI pages at &lt;<span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT106_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT109_com_zimbra_url" role="link"><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/tools/scores/partitur-index.html" target="_blank">http://cdli.ucla.edu/tools/scores/partitur-index.html</a></span></span>&gt;.<br /><br />Bob Englund<br />Director, CDLI<br />UCLA]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2783660150660465751/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/12/year-end-news-from-cdli.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2783660150660465751"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2783660150660465751"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/12/year-end-news-from-cdli.html"
         title="Year End News from CDLI"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
