<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-971545180685433335</id>
   <published>2015-12-08T13:22:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-12-08T13:24:54.740-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Italy"/>
   <title type="text">Pompeii Bibliography and Mapping Project</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://digitalhumanities.umass.edu/pbmp/" rel="home" title="Pompeii Bibliography and Mapping Project">Pompeii Bibliography and Mapping Project</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Pompeii Bibliography and Mapping Project is working to create a  unique resource that binds two resources in a responsive online user  interface. The first component is an exhaustive <a href="http://digitalhumanities.umass.edu/pbmp/?page_id=1298" target="_blank" title="The Bibliography">database of citations</a> and full-text repository relating to the ancient city of Pompeii.&nbsp; The second component is a <a href="http://digitalhumanities.umass.edu/pbmp/?page_id=1258" target="_blank" title="The Map">Geographical Information System (GIS) map </a>of  that ancient city. &nbsp;Both of these components are available in their  beta formats. The online interface planned will allow a user to navigate  the bibliographic database and repository via the GIS map or,  conversely, to illustrate places in the GIS map found in a search of the  database or repository. These components are described in greater  detail in the following sections.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://umasscreative.com/biblio/pomptest/"><img alt="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-95" src="http://digitalhumanities.umass.edu/pbmp/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/notMap1.png" height="223" title="Biblio" width="230" /></a></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i></i></span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Bibliographic Database – </i>Based on the 14,596 references detailed &nbsp;in L. García y García’s landmark publication,&nbsp;<i>Nova Bibliotheca Pompeiana</i>,&nbsp;the bibliographic database is designed as an &nbsp;exhaustive database of all works related to Pompeii. Although the <i>Nova &nbsp;Bibliotheca Pompeiana</i> is the core of the database, works produced &nbsp;after 1998 when the <i>Nova Bibliotheca Pompeiana </i>was published will also be incorporated. Automated means to capture future citations on Pompeii are also being developed.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Full-Text Repository – </i>The PBMP’s full-text, text-searchable  repository incorporates the extant digital resources in the public  domain and builds upon them by capturing all other similarly available  works. A census of the <a href="http://www.archive.org/" target="_blank">Internet Archive</a>’s  catalog combined with our own digitization efforts shows that as much  as 25% of the out-of-copyright titles have already been digitized. The  collections of the <a href="http://www.hathitrust.org/" target="_blank">Hathi Trust</a> and <a href="http://books.google.com/" target="_blank">Google Books</a> will raise the number of works initially available. While the project  has already invested in its own digitization equipment and staff,  partnerships with the groups just mentioned will be sought to fill the  full-text repository. This means that only the smallest portion of the  project’s efforts will involve digitization. Where possible, use of  in-copyright works will be negotiated through the agreements and  policies of the University of Massachusetts libraries. Full-Text  documents are connected to citations in the bibliographic database and  together form a full subject repository.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.mainstreetmaps.com/ITALY/Pompeii/"><img alt="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-101" src="http://digitalhumanities.umass.edu/pbmp/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/map.png" height="220" title="map" width="219" /></a></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i></i></span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Geographical Information System</i> (<i>GIS) – </i>The online  GIS is a dynamic map of the places and objects in ancient Pompeii. Its  most basic function is to allow a user to navigate the physical  landscape of the ancient city. The current GIS is exceptionally robust:  more than 15,000 objects and properties are contained in over 400 files.  In the next iteration, ESRI’s ArcServer platform will be used to  display and deliver these files online and its advanced functionalities –  including an integrated timeline feature and the ability to check-out  (download), check-in (upload) and track the changes to the map’s base  files – make it an ideal choice for this project. Users will be able to  download the base files and perform more advanced analyses and/or modify  their geometry based on new archaeological interpretations and then  upload those new files back into the versioning archive for the online  GIS for use (navigation or download by others) of those alternate  interpretations.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Interface – </i>These components will be accessed via an online  user interface. Users will be able to begin their search via the GIS map  or the bibliographic database, a choice that will determine the search  environment. For example, as the user selects a place or places in the  map, the right side of the interface will display all available  information for that place, from simple citations to full-text  documents. In this way, using the GIS interface can be imagined as  moving the map over the top of a pyramid, to the apex of a unique and  structured set of citations and references that lead down to a vast  repository of articles, books, and images. Should the user prefer to  explore the bibliographic database and full-text repository, the  interface will adjust to provide more space for standard bibliographic  and full-text search tools. When a search is conducted and records are  selected, relevant locations appear highlighted in the reduced sized GIS  map. In this way, the metaphorical topical landscapes within the  scholarship on Pompeii can be not only expressed as a list, but also can  be visualized and given physical structure in the map. The act of  searching the subject repository thus creates an instant gazeteer of the  results that can be used with the list of citations.</span> </blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">And see AWOL's <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/09/roundup-of-resources-on-ancient.html">Roundup of Resources on Ancient Geography</a> </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/971545180685433335/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/12/pompeii-bibliography-and-mapping-project.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/971545180685433335"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/971545180685433335"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/12/pompeii-bibliography-and-mapping-project.html"
         title="Pompeii Bibliography and Mapping Project"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
