<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5042596216588827225</id>
   <published>2017-01-17T19:36:00.002-05:00</published>
   <updated>2017-01-17T19:36:41.275-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Resources for Teaching Ancient Geography</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://sarahemilybond.wordpress.com/resources-for-teaching-gis-mapping-and-ancient-geography/">Resources for Teaching Ancient&nbsp;Geography</a><br />From <a href="https://sarahemilybond.wordpress.com/" rel="home">History From Below</a>: Musings on Daily Life in the Ancient and Early Medieval Mediterranean By Sarah E. Bond<br /><div class="site-branding">		</div><br />  	 		<blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Making Maps</strong></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://awmc.unc.edu/wordpress/alacarte/" target="_blank">Antiquity À-la-carte</a>:&nbsp;</strong>“The <a href="http://awmc.unc.edu/awmc/applications/alacarte/" target="_blank">Antiquity À-la-carte application</a> is a&nbsp;web-based GIS interface and&nbsp;interactive digital atlas of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_history" target="_blank">ancient world</a>, featuring accurate historical, cultural, and geographical data produced by the <a href="http://awmc.unc.edu/">AWMC</a>&nbsp;in addition to the&nbsp;entire <a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/">Pleiades Project</a> feature set. The map is completely searchable with customizable features, allowing for the creation of any map covering&nbsp;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Archaic_Greece">Archaic Greece</a> to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Late_Antiquity">Late Antiquity</a> and beyond. AWMC welcomes feedback from community members on the  experience of using the application and welcomes suggestions and  comments.&nbsp;Click&nbsp;<a href="http://awmc.unc.edu/awmc/applications/alacarte/" target="_blank">here&nbsp;.</a>..&nbsp;to launch the map application. This application works best with <a href="http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/" target="_blank">Firefox</a>, <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en/chrome/browser/" target="_blank">Chrome</a>, or <a href="http://www.apple.com/safari/" target="_blank" title="Safari">Safari</a>.&nbsp;All site content and maps are released here under the&nbsp;<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/" title="license">Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 3.0 Unported (CC BY-NC 3.0)</a>&nbsp;license.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.lib.uiowa.edu/bam/" target="_blank"><strong>Big Ancient Mediterranean:</strong></a>&nbsp;A  project that marries texts, network analysis, and ancient geography. It  currently allows you to see the people and places in the Book of Luke  within the module Terra Biblica–built to house texts connected to early  Christianity–and to explore a map of Latin authors. Project PIs are  Sarah Bond, Paul Dilley, and Ryan Horne.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="https://cartodb.com/signup?plan=academy" target="_blank">CartoDB:</a></strong><a href="https://cartodb.com/signup?plan=academy" target="_blank">&nbsp;</a>“is a <a class="mw-redirect" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_as_a_Service" title="Software as a Service">Software as a Service</a> (SaaS) <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing" title="Cloud computing">cloud computing</a> platform that provides <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geographic_information_system" title="Geographic information system">GIS</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_mapping" title="Web mapping">web mapping</a> tools for display in a web browser. CartoDB users can use the company’s free platform or deploy their own instance of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_source" title="Open source">open source</a> software. CartoDB is offered as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freemium" title="Freemium">freemium</a> service, where accounts are free up to a certain size. For larger accounts, a fee is applied.<sup class="reference" id="cite_ref-1"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CartoDB#cite_note-1">[1]</a></sup> It was first released in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_release_life_cycle" title="Software release life cycle">Beta</a> at FOSS4G in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denver" title="Denver">Denver</a> in September 2011,<sup class="reference" id="cite_ref-2"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CartoDB#cite_note-2">[2]</a></sup> and officially debuted as a final release at Where2.0 in April 2012.” (Description via Wikipedia)</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.gpsvisualizer.com/about.html" target="_blank">GPS Visualizer</a>:&nbsp;</strong>“GPS  Visualizer is do-it-yourself mapping, for both beginners and power  users. Its strengths are its simplicity and flexibility in terms of  input, and its enormous number of options regarding the output. When you  upload your GPS data, GPS Visualizer will automatically detect what  kind of file it is and process it accordingly. The output can be in the  form of <a href="http://www.gpsvisualizer.com/map_input">Google Maps</a>, <a href="http://www.gpsvisualizer.com/map_input?form=googleearth">KML files for Google Earth</a>, <a href="http://www.gpsvisualizer.com/map_input?form=jpg">JPEG maps</a>, <a href="http://www.gpsvisualizer.com/map_input?form=svg">SVG drawings</a>, <a href="http://www.gpsvisualizer.com/profile_input">elevation profiles</a>, <a href="http://www.gpsvisualizer.com/convert_input">plain-text tables</a> with all your raw data, or <a href="http://www.gpsvisualizer.com/convert_input?convert_format=gpx">GPX files</a> that can be used with many other GPS-related applications. Moreover,  all of the maps and profiles can be adjusted in innumerable ways using  the options on the input forms: you can change the size, the colors, the  background map, etc. In the case of Google Maps, there is even more you  can do to edit your map after it’s been created, if you’re comfortable  with HTML and/or JavaScript.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="https://www.google.com/earth/" target="_blank">Google Earth and Google Earth Pro:&nbsp;</a></strong>Google  Earth reads and produces a file called KML. “KML, or ‘Keyhole Markup  Language’, is an XML grammar and file format for modeling and storing  geographic features such as points, lines, images, polygons, and models  for display in Google Earth, <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps">Google Maps</a> and other applications. You can use KML to share places and information  with other users of these applications. You can find example KML files  on the KML Gallery and <a href="http://bbs.keyhole.com/" target="_blank">Google Earth Community site</a> that describe interesting features and places.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://worldmap.harvard.edu/maps/new" target="_blank"><strong>Harvard World Map:&nbsp;</strong></a>“WorldMap  is an open source web mapping system that is currently under  construction. It is built to assist academic research and teaching as  well as the general public and supports discovery, investigation,  analysis, visualization, communication and archiving of  multi-disciplinary, multi-source and multi-format data, organized  spatially and temporally.&nbsp;The first instance of WorldMap, focused on the  continent of Africa, is called AfricaMap. Since its beta release in  November of 2008, the framework has been implemented in several  geographic locations with different research foci, including metro  Boston, East Asia, Vermont, Harvard Forest and the city of Paris. These  web mapping applications are used in courses as well as by individual  researchers.”</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://leafletjs.com/download.html" target="_blank">Leaflet:</a></strong><a href="http://leafletjs.com/download.html" target="_blank">&nbsp;</a>“Leaflet is a modern open-source JavaScript library for mobile-friendly interactive maps. It is developed by <a href="http://agafonkin.com/en">Vladimir Agafonkin</a> with a&nbsp;team of dedicated <a href="https://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet/graphs/contributors">contributors</a>. Weighing just about <abbr title="33 KB gzipped — that's 123 KB minified and 218 KB in the source form, with 10 KB of CSS (2 KB gzipped) and 11 KB of images.">33 KB of JS</abbr>, it has all the <a href="http://leafletjs.com/features.html">features</a> most developers ever need for online maps.&nbsp;Leaflet is designed with <em>simplicity</em>, <em>performance</em> and <em>usability</em> in mind. It works efficiently across all major desktop and mobile  platforms out of the box, taking advantage of HTML5 and CSS3 on modern  browsers while still being accessible on older ones. It can be extended  with a huge amount of <a href="http://leafletjs.com/plugins.html">plugins</a>, has a beautiful, easy to use and <a href="http://leafletjs.com/reference.html" title="Leaflet API reference">well-documented API</a> and a simple, readable <a href="https://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet" title="Leaflet GitHub repository">source code</a>&nbsp;that is a&nbsp;joy to <a href="https://github.com/Leaflet/Leaflet/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md" title="A guide to contributing to Leaflet">contribute</a> to.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="https://www.buildwithchrome.com/" target="_blank">LEGO Build with Chrome:&nbsp;</a>“</strong>is a web application that allows users to explore and build a world of digital <strong><a href="http://lego.wikia.com/wiki/LEGO" title="LEGO">LEGO</a> </strong>creations. A collaboration between <strong><a class="external text" href="https://www.google.com/chrome/" rel="nofollow">Google Chrome</a> and <a href="http://lego.wikia.com/wiki/The_LEGO_Group" title="The LEGO Group">The LEGO Group</a>, </strong>Build with Chrome was originally developed by a team of<strong> <a class="external text" href="https://www.google.com.au/" rel="nofollow">Google Australia</a>&nbsp;</strong>developers for the LEGO Festival of Play. In January 2014, <a class="external text exitstitial" href="http://chrome.blogspot.com/" rel="nofollow">the Google Chrome team</a> opened up Build with Chrome to everyone and added features such as the ability to sign in with a<strong> <a class="external text" href="https://plus.google.com/" rel="nofollow">Google Plus</a> </strong>account to help you find builds that people in your circles have created, a new categorization system for completed builds, and<strong> <a class="external text" href="https://www.buildwithchrome.com/buildacademy" rel="nofollow">Build Academy</a></strong>.” (Pulled from <span class="skimlinks-unlinked">Lego.Wikia</span>)</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="https://www.mapbox.com/" target="_blank">MapBox:</a>&nbsp;“</strong>is one of the biggest providers of custom online maps for major websites such as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foursquare" title="Foursquare">Foursquare</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pinterest" title="Pinterest">Pinterest</a>,<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evernote" title="Evernote">Evernote</a>, the Financial Times and <a class="mw-redirect" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uber_Technologies" title="Uber Technologies">Uber Technologies</a>.<sup class="reference" id="cite_ref-WashingtonPost_2-0"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mapbox#cite_note-WashingtonPost-2">[2]</a></sup> Since 2010, it has rapidly expanded the niche of custom maps, as a  response to the limited choice offered by map providers such as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Maps" title="Google Maps">Google Maps</a>.<sup class="reference" id="cite_ref-WashingtonPost_2-1"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mapbox#cite_note-WashingtonPost-2">[2]</a></sup> Mapbox is the creator of, or a significant contributor to many popular  open source mapping libraries and applications, including the MBTiles  specification, the TileMill cartography IDE, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leaflet_%28software%29" title="Leaflet (software)">Leaflet</a> JavaScript library, the CartoCSS map styling language and parser, and the <span class="skimlinks-unlinked">mapbox.js</span> JavaScript library.” (Description via Wikipedia)</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://pelagios.org/maps/greco-roman/"><strong>Pelagios Project</strong></a>:  A great tool for geography and for finding material culture for a  certain area. It plugs you into the linked open data network for  antiquity–e.g. inscriptions, ceramics, coins, and archaeological  remains. Via the Pelagios Blog: “The aim of [the] work with Pelagios has  been to create a static (non-layered) map of the ancient places in the  Pleiades dataset with the capacity to serve as a background layer to  online mapping applications of the Ancient World. Because it is based on  ancient settlements and uses ancient placenames, our map presents a  visualisation more tailored to archaeological and historical research,  for which modern mapping interfaces, such as Google Maps, are hardly  appropriate; it even&nbsp;includes non-settlement data such as the Roman  roads network, some aqueducts and defence walls (<em>limes</em>, city  walls). Thus, for example, the tiles can be used as a background layer  to display the occurrence of find-spots, archaeological sites, etc.,  thereby creating&nbsp;new opportunities to put data of these kinds in their  historical context.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Tools</strong></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://dirtdirectory.org/categories/mapping?field_platform_value=web&amp;field_cost_value=All&amp;term_node_tid_depth=All&amp;sort_by=title&amp;sort_order=ASC" target="_blank"><strong>DIRT: Digital Research Tools</strong>:&nbsp;</a>“The  DiRT Directory aggregates information about digital research tools for  scholarly use. It evolved from “Bamboo DiRT”, a version of the directory  developed by <a href="http://www.projectbamboo.org/">Project Bamboo</a>,  which itself developed out of Lisa Spiro’s DiRT wiki. The DiRT  Directory makes it easy for digital humanists and others conducting  digital research to find and compare resources ranging from content  management systems to music OCR, statistical analysis packages to  mindmapping software.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/fusiontablestalks/stories" target="_blank">Google Fusion Tables:</a>&nbsp;</strong>“Fusion Tables is an experimental data visualization web application to gather, visualize, and share data tables.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://storymaps.arcgis.com/en/" target="_blank"><strong>Esri’s StoryMap</strong>:&nbsp;</a>A <strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CCNVX4mQVlo" target="_blank">video tutorial</a></strong> for using Esri’s Story Maps. Check out Odysseus’ Journey <strong><a href="http://esripm.maps.arcgis.com/apps/MapTour/index.html?appid=4fc9153f4d9248b9bab7011e3950b552&amp;webmap=962ca9da38bf4c5e9439a6acf3dd1b3e" target="_blank">HERE.&nbsp;</a></strong></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.worldatlas.com/aatlas/findlatlong.htm" target="_blank">World Atlas: Find Longitude and Latitude:</a></strong><a href="http://www.worldatlas.com/aatlas/findlatlong.htm" target="_blank">&nbsp;</a>Find  longitude and latitude coordinates quickly. Caveat internetor: Ancient  places are not this Atlas’ strong point. Go with the Pleiades data.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Free Data&nbsp;</strong></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><strong><a href="http://catalog.data.gov/dataset" target="_blank">Data.gov</a>:&nbsp;</strong></strong>Downloadable data from the US government.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.eurogeographics.org/" target="_blank">Eurogeographics:&nbsp;</a></strong>“EuroGlobalMap is a 1:1 million scale topographic dataset covering 45 countries and territories in the European region.<a href="http://www.eurogeographics.org/form/topographic-data-eurogeographics">It is now available as opendata.</a>&nbsp;EuroGlobalMap  is perfect for use as background to many applications from planning,  monitoring and network analysis to presenting environmental policies.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/downloads" target="_blank">Pleiades:</a>&nbsp;“</strong>Get complete and regular shapshots of all Pleiades resources, available in multiple formats including CSV, KML, and RDF.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://nationalmap.gov/small_scale/atlas-ftp-global-map.html" target="_blank"><strong>USGS: The National Map</strong></a>:&nbsp;“The  Global Map is an international effort by national mapping organizations  to produce consistent and accurate mapping data of the world at a scale  of 1:1,000,000. The 1997-2014 Edition of the National Atlas of the  United States originally supplied all American data to the Global Map.  The National Map will continue to publish two data collections at one  million-scale: one for Global Map users and one for National Map users.  In terms of vector geometry, the lines, points, and areas in these data  collections are identical. The difference is in the attributes assigned  to these features. The Global Map edition includes just the data fields  and attribute values in the Global Map Specifications Version 2.2.  National Map vector data includes all of the Global Map data fields and  attributes plus those in the National Map data dictionary.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>GIS Classes (Some Free, Some Not So Free)</strong></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.esri.com/training/main" target="_blank"><strong>ESRI Virtual Campus Courses:</strong></a>&nbsp;<strong>“</strong>online,  self-paced, step by step lessons that cover a variety of topics related  to GIS applications and technology. Currently there are 40+ course  selections to choose from that are included with our standard  subscription, and many more seminars are available that are free to the  public.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/maps" target="_blank">Coursera: “Maps and the Geospatial Revolution”</a>: </strong>“This  course brings together core concepts in cartography, geographic  information systems, and spatial thinking with real-world examples to  provide the fundamentals necessary to engage with Geography beyond the  surface-level. We will explore what makes spatial information special,  how spatial data is created, how spatial analysis is conducted, and how  to design maps so that they’re effective at telling the stories we wish  to share. To gain experience using this knowledge, we will work with the  latest mapping and analysis software to explore geographic problems.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Classroom Activities&nbsp;</strong></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/?pli=1" target="_blank"><strong>Google Editable Map</strong></a>:  Ask students to contribute to an editable map and place information  about themselves on it. This is a great way to start off a class and  introduce spatial thinking, maps, layers, and data sharing.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1iARIcFWTzypi8eW_ZON5jFNLIcV7z0tKf4zG4LCOP_Q/edit" target="_blank"><strong>Serpent Column</strong></a>: This activity explore the monument of the <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Serpent_Column" target="_blank">“serpent column”</a></strong> and how we can represent inscriptions and other textual sources geographically using <span class="skimlinks-unlinked">Pleiades.stoa.org</span>. The full Pleiades workshop video with this activity is available for viewing <strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hVuPAAAAoso" target="_blank">HERE.</a></strong></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/news/blog/mapping-spartacus" target="_blank">Mapping Spartacus</a>:</strong> Using <span class="skimlinks-unlinked">Pleiades.stoa.org</span> in order to teach the Third Servile War (i.e. The Spartacan War).</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Finding Digital Humanities Projects</strong></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.dhcenternet.org/">Centernet:</a> </strong>Find Digital Humanities Centers.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.hastac.org/">HASTAC</a></strong></span></blockquote><span style="font-size: small;"><br /></span><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;">And see AWOL's <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/09/roundup-of-resources-on-ancient.html">Roundup of Resources on Ancient Geography</a></span> </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5042596216588827225/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2017/01/resources-for-teaching-ancient-geography.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5042596216588827225"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5042596216588827225"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2017/01/resources-for-teaching-ancient-geography.html"
         title="Resources for Teaching Ancient Geography"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
