<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5052392724311558557</id>
   <published>2015-11-16T19:08:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-11-16T19:08:46.675-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open CFP: Digital Approaches and the Ancient World</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://spaghetti-os.blogspot.com/2015/11/open-cfp-digital-approaches-and-ancient.html">Open CFP: Digital Approaches and the Ancient World</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">More publicity!<br /><br />*Digital Approaches and the Ancient World*<br />A themed issue of the _Bulletin of the Institute of Classical Studies_<br /><br />Editors:<br />Gabriel Bodard (University of London) gabriel.bodard@sas.ac.uk<br />Yanne Broux (KU Leuven) yanne.broux@arts.kuleuven.be<br />Ségolène Tarte (University of Oxford) segolene.tarte@oerc.ox.ac.uk<br /><br />Call for papers:<br />We invite colleagues all around the world and at all stages of their careers to submit papers on the topic of “Digital Approaches and the Ancient World” to a themed issue of the Bulletin of the Institute of Classical Studies. The topic is to be construed as widely as possible, to include not only the history, archaeology, language, literature and thought of the ancient and late antique Mediterranean world, but also of antiquity more widely, potentially including, for example, South and East Asian, Sub-Saharan African or Pre-Columbian American history. Digital approaches may also vary widely, to include methodologies from the digital humanities and information studies, quantitative methods from the hard sciences, or other innovative and transdisciplinary themes.<br /><br />Papers will be fully peer reviewed and selected for inclusion based not only on their research quality and significance, but especially on their ability to engage profoundly both with classics/history academic readers, and scholars from digital or informatic disciplines. We are keen to see papers that clearly lay out their disciplinary and interdisciplinary methodological approaches, and present and interpret the full range of scholarly and practical outcomes of their research.<br /><br />We encourage the use of and direct reference to open online datasets in your papers. BICS is not currently an open access publication, but self-archiving of pre-press papers is permitted, and the editors believe in the transparency and accountability that comes with basing scientific work on open data.<br /><br />To submit an article to this themed issue, please send your full paper of 4,000–8,000 words in Microsoft Word doc, docx or rtf format, to &lt;gabriel.bodard@sas.ac.uk&gt;, along with a 150 word abstract, by January 31, 2016. You do not need to follow BICS style for the initial submission, but please note that the final version of accepted articles will need to be formatted to adhere to our style guide (http://www.icls.sas.ac.uk/sites/default/files/files/STYLE-V15.pdf).<br /><br />If you have any questions about this issue, please feel free to contact any of the editors informally.<br /><br />Please, oh please, oh please, circulate anywhere you think is appropriate!</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5052392724311558557/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/open-cfp-digital-approaches-and-ancient.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5052392724311558557"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5052392724311558557"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/open-cfp-digital-approaches-and-ancient.html"
         title="Open CFP: Digital Approaches and the Ancient World"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
