<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5072602003423778183</id>
   <published>2016-08-09T16:43:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-08-09T16:43:49.194-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Recently Published at Archaeopress: Open Access</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/defaultAll.asp?OpenAccess=Y&amp;intro=true">Recently Published at Archaeopress: Open Access</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="shop_Title">Reinterpreting chronology and society at the mortuary complex of Jebel Moya (Sudan)</span></span><br /><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="height: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="vertical-align: top;">     	<table id="Table2">		<tbody><tr>			<td>			<table><tbody><tr><td><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/4E3C48AF9AD64B518B64C6F52EDA8EA9%5C9781784914318.jpg"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/4E3C48AF9AD64B518B64C6F52EDA8EA9%5C9781784914318.jpg" style="max-width: 200px;" width="150" /></a></span></td></tr></tbody></table></td>		</tr></tbody></table></td><td class="productDetailsText"><span style="font-size: x-small;">    Author: Michael Jonathan Brass.   <em>Cambridge Monographs in African Archaeology 92</em>. ISBN 9781784914325. <br /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><br />The  Jebel Moya massif is situated in the relatively under-explored southern  Gezira Plain in the Sudan, approximately 250km south south-east of  Khartoum and ca. 30km west of Sennar. The massif has a perimeter of ca.  11km. Its north-eastern valley was excavated by (later Sir) Henry  Wellcome, the founder of the Wellcome Trust, over four field seasons  from 1911 – 1914. Around a fifth of the estimated 10.4 hectares of the  valley floor was excavated over four seasons, yielding a recorded 3135  human burials from 2791 graves. It is by far the largest and most  intensively excavated cemetery anywhere in sub-Saharan Africa. <br /><br />The archaeological and bioanthropological reports were published in 1949  and 1955 respectively. The vast majority of extant assemblages and the  expedition records are curated at different institutions in the United  Kingdom. The excavation cards and extant skeletal assemblages at the  Duckworth Laboratory (University of Cambridge) together with a field  diary from the second season’s field director, geological reports from  the third and fourth seasons, a topographical survey map, Addison’s  correspondences, plans of some of the burials excavated during the  fourth and final season, cards describing artefacts and the photographic  archive at the Griffiths Institute (Oxford) and the pottery samples at  the British and Petrie Museums comprise the key materials curated in the  United Kingdom. They have not been comprehensively re-evaluated,  subsequent to the original reports, to determine the nature of social  evolution at Jebel Moya.  <br /><br />Developments in archaeological inference and techniques provide a unique  opportunity to re-orientate the published and extant material evidence  within an updated interpretive framework on mortuary social organisation  at Jebel Moya. The present work places the site’s different phases of  occupation in secure temporal contexts to allow for informed social  analysis of change over time. In particular, it focuses on questions of  social organization and evaluates the nature of socio-political order in  the southern Gezira Plain.</span><div class="productBox3TextHighlight">      <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span>               <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/viewReviews.asp?id=%7B9334676E-3BBC-4D52-BF46-96F92045E02A%7D">View Reviews</a></span>         	    </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"> &nbsp; <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/download.asp?id=%7B0D367A52-873B-4664-8701-1FCD9DD874A2%7D" target="_blank">Download (pdf)</a> &nbsp;      </span><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">	    <tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong style="color: #535c5a;">These downloads are single-user and for your own personal use only.</strong></span></td></tr></tbody></table></td></tr></tbody></table><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;<span class="shop_Title">Tell Barri/Kahat (al Hassake)</span></span><br /><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="height: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="vertical-align: top;">     	<table id="Table2">		<tbody><tr>			<td>			<table><tbody><tr><td><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/7FA6A9F09E0948E8A3B5EC74F2D2F100/Benoit%20OA%20cover.jpg"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/7FA6A9F09E0948E8A3B5EC74F2D2F100/Benoit%20OA%20cover.jpg" style="max-width: 200px;" width="141" /></a></span></td></tr></tbody></table></td>		</tr></tbody></table></td><td class="productDetailsText">     <span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Taken from <b>A History of Syria in One Hundred Sites</b></i> by Raffaella Pierobon Benoit. Pages 304-308.<br /><br />Tell  Barri is located in western Jazira, on the left bank of the river  JaghJagh, a tributary of the Habur. The river was fully navigable in  antiquity and permitted easy communications as far as the Euphrates. The  river supplied water, used not only for drinking but for crops and  artisanal activities; cuneiform tablets provide evidence that fishing  was also practised. This part of the Jazira was, in any case, favourable  to settlements thanks to sufficient rainfall for the development of  semi-arid agriculture. Its products, especially grains, combined with  intense animal husbandry, notably sheep, formed the mixed economy that  seems to have characterized all phases of the life of the site. <b>Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BE656951E-527C-4A52-8B6D-09660D88E11F%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span><div class="productBox3TextHighlight">      <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span>               <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/viewReviews.asp?id=%7BDE93B38A-E017-41D1-B054-AD2F96CB842B%7D">View Reviews</a></span>         	    </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"> &nbsp; <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/download.asp?id=%7B61FAAD31-0636-4FF1-9CC2-980D542C67B2%7D" target="_blank">Download (pdf)</a> &nbsp;      </span><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">	    <tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong style="color: #535c5a;">These downloads are single-user and for your own personal use only.</strong></span></td></tr></tbody></table><div class="text">     	<table id="Table2">		<tbody><tr>			<td>			 			<span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td>		</tr></tbody></table></div></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;<span class="shop_Title">Middle  to Late Neolithic animal exploitation at UAQ2 (5500–4000 cal BC): an  Ubaid-related coastal site at Umm al-Quwain Emirate, United Arab  Emirates</span></span><br /><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="height: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="vertical-align: top;">     	<table id="Table2">		<tbody><tr>			<td>			<table><tbody><tr><td><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/3A51134E58924065820ADF35F1E73BC9/MaskourOA%20cover.jpg"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/3A51134E58924065820ADF35F1E73BC9/MaskourOA%20cover.jpg" style="max-width: 200px;" width="160" /></a></span></td></tr></tbody></table></td>		</tr></tbody></table></td><td class="productDetailsText">     <span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Taken from <b>Proceedings of the Seminar for Arabian Studies 46 (2016)</b></i> by Marjan Mashkour, Mark Jonathan Beech, Karyne Debue, Lisa Yeomans,  Stéphanie Bréhard, Dalia Gasparini &amp; Sophie Méry. Pages 195-210.<br /><br />The  subsistence strategies of coastal Neolithic groups in eastern Arabia,  reliant upon the exploitation of marine and terrestrial animal  resources, are not yet fully understood. A central question in relevant  literature is the issue of mobility. This is the reason for excavations  in Umm al-Quwain (UAQ2), UAE, from 2011 by the French Archaeological  Mission. UAQ2 is a site with obvious potential, occupied for 1500 years  from the mid-sixth millennium BC. It has an area of approximately 6 ha  with 3.2 m or more of imposing and unusual stratigraphy. A large  quantity of faunal remains, including terrestrial and marine  vertebrates, was recovered from UAQ2. The terrestrial mammals are  composed mainly of domestic herbivores including caprines, cattle, and  dogs. The most striking feature is the number of newly born and young  animals among the small herbivores, a clear indication of occupation  during late winter/spring. As for the fish bones, the following taxa  were identified: requiem sharks, shark-suckers, marine catfish,  needlefish, jacks/trevallies, milkfish, mojarra, emperors, snappers,  mullet, flatheads, shortfin flounders, parrotfish, kawakawa, tuna,  groupers, sea bream, barracuda, puffer, and tripod fish. These indicate  that most fishing was carried out in the shallow lagoon area, but some  fishing for tuna may have been carried out in the open seas beyond the  local lagoon. Besides fish were also the remains of cuttlefish and  swimming crabs. This assemblage provides new information on the mixed  exploitation of inland and marine resources during the sixth to fifth  millennium BC. The integrated study of the faunal remains contributes to  the proposal of a possible year round residency, not excluding coastal  mobility. <a href="http://www.archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B7C5532BA-8357-46D8-9C54-9BA1F202C409%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</span><div class="productBox3TextHighlight">      <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span>               <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/viewReviews.asp?id=%7B2D978E68-A546-4F39-8282-3EB1CB9D2C0F%7D">View Reviews</a></span>         	    </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"> &nbsp; <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/download.asp?id=%7B2639BD5B-BB3A-4CCA-AEC7-C9C5B0725F50%7D" target="_blank">Download (pdf)</a> &nbsp;      </span><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">	    <tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong style="color: #535c5a;">These downloads are single-user and for your own personal use only.</strong></span></td></tr></tbody></table><div class="text">     	<table id="Table2">		<tbody><tr>			<td>			 			<span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td>		</tr></tbody></table></div></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;<span class="shop_Title">Ubaid-related sites of the southern Gulf revisited: the Abu Dhabi Coastal Heritage Initiative</span></span><br /><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="height: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="vertical-align: top;">     	<table id="Table2">		<tbody><tr>			<td>			<table><tbody><tr><td><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/AF033850A2D14DEFB76146B139E861A0%5CMarkBeechOA.jpg"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/AF033850A2D14DEFB76146B139E861A0%5CMarkBeechOA.jpg" style="max-width: 200px;" width="160" /></a></span></td></tr></tbody></table></td>		</tr></tbody></table></td><td class="productDetailsText">     <span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Taken from <b>Proceedings of the Seminar for Arabian Studies 46 (2016)</b></i> by Mark Jonathan Beech, Kristian Strutt, Lucy Blue, Abdulla Khalfan  al-Kaabi, Waleed Awad Omar, Ahmed Abdulla al-Haj El-Faki, Anjana Reddy  Lingareddy &amp; John Martin. Pages 9-23.<br /><br />The Coastal Heritage  Initiative of the Abu Dhabi Tourism and Culture Authority (TCA Abu  Dhabi) aims to investigate the rich maritime history of Abu Dhabi  Emirate. Since the establishment of TCA Abu Dhabi in February 2012, a  new phase of archaeological research has been carried out. Systematic  mapping of sites, their integration into the Abu Dhabi geographic  information system (GIS geodatabase of archaeological sites for the  Emirate), as well as further investigations of key sites by both  geophysical prospection and excavation have been undertaken. Recent work  has concentrated on the Ubaid-related coastal sites on both Dalma  Island (Jazīrat Dalmā) and Marawah Island (Jazīrat MarawaΉ). A  combination of both magnetometry and ground-penetrating radar (GPR)  geophysical surveys, as well as follow-up excavations are discussed.  These shed new light on the structure of Ubaid-related coastal  settlements between the mid-sixth and early fifth millennium BC. <a href="http://www.archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B7C5532BA-8357-46D8-9C54-9BA1F202C409%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</span><div class="productBox3TextHighlight">      <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span>               <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/viewReviews.asp?id=%7B304B5B23-A18D-46B6-97E1-7550BB78FDC0%7D">View Reviews</a></span>         	    </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"> &nbsp; <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/download.asp?id=%7BFC2CC1FE-AEAD-468B-98DB-3AE0EEC74E57%7D" target="_blank">Download (pdf)</a> &nbsp;      </span><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">	    <tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong style="color: #535c5a;">These downloads are single-user and for your own personal use only.</strong></span></td></tr></tbody></table></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="shop_Title">CAMERA KALAUREIA</span></span><br /><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="height: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="vertical-align: top;">     	<table id="Table2">		<tbody><tr>			<td>			<table><tbody><tr><td><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/87C463CC50C84BEB840936622023E70A%5C9781784914127.jpg"><img border="0" height="160" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/87C463CC50C84BEB840936622023E70A%5C9781784914127.jpg" style="max-width: 200px;" width="200" /></a></span></td></tr></tbody></table></td>		</tr></tbody></table></td><td class="productDetailsText">     <span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>An Archaeological Photo-Ethnography | Μια αρχαιολογική φωτο-εθνογραφία</i> by Yannis Hamilakis &amp; Fotis Ifantidis. 170 pages; illustrated in full colour throughout. Full text in English and Greek. <span style="color: blue;"><b> Available both in print and Open Access</b></span>.ISBN 9781784914141. <br /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><br />How can we find alternative, sensorially rich and affective ways of engaging with the material past in the present? <br /><br />How can photography play a central role in archaeological narratives, beyond representation and documentation? <br /><br />This photo-book engages with these questions, not through conventional  academic discourse but through evocative creative practice. The book is,  at the same time, a site guide of sorts: a photographic guide to the  archaeological site of the Sanctuary of Poseidon in Kalaureia, on the  island of Poros, in Greece. <br /><br />Ancient and not-so-ancient stones, pine trees that were “wounded” for  their resin, people who lived amongst the classical ruins, and the  tensions and the clashes with the archaeological apparatus and its  regulations, all become palpable, affectively close and immediate. <br /><br />Furthermore, the book constitutes an indirect but concrete proposal for  the adoption of archaeological photo-ethnography as a research as well  as public communication tool for critical heritage studies, today. <br /></span><span style="color: red; font-size: x-small;"><b> Also available in hardback and paperback printed editions:</b></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BC8881B14-2108-4138-A0ED-FF92F2987A3B%7D">Click here to purchase paperback edition priced £30.00.</a></b></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BE6E41971-8691-4F25-9666-308FF2F585CF%7D">Click here to purchase hardback edition priced £55.00.</a></b><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/" rel="license"><img alt="Creative Commons License" src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/4.0/88x31.png" style="border-width: 0px;" /></a><br />This work is licensed under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License</a>. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Note for downloading: PDF displays best in Chrome. For best results  right-click 'Download (pdf)' below and use the option 'Save link as...'  to save a local copy to your computer/device.</b></span><div class="productBox3TextHighlight">      <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span>               <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/viewReviews.asp?id=%7B5795E01E-3C43-4204-8335-9F80F493023C%7D">View Reviews</a></span>         	    </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"> &nbsp; <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/download.asp?id=%7BF2813CA2-A44A-410F-9C6A-669DD030AC01%7D" target="_blank">Download (pdf)</a> &nbsp;      </span><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">	    <tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong style="color: #535c5a;">These downloads are single-user and for your own personal use only.</strong></span></td></tr></tbody></table></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;<span class="shop_Title">A Dignified Passage through the Gates of Hades</span></span><br /><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"><tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="height: 10px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></td></tr><tr><td style="vertical-align: top;">     	<table id="Table2">		<tbody><tr>			<td>			<table><tbody><tr><td><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/5ECE7815FC314DABB82BBB19CF4F9B8E%5C9781784913830.jpg"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/5ECE7815FC314DABB82BBB19CF4F9B8E%5C9781784913830.jpg" style="max-width: 200px;" width="148" /></a></span></td></tr></tbody></table></td>		</tr></tbody></table></td><td class="productDetailsText">     <span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>The Burial Custom of Cremation and the Warrior Order of Ancient Eleutherna</i> by Anagnostis P. Agelarakis. 24pp; illustrated throughout in colour. <span style="color: blue;"><b> Available both in print and Open Access</b></span>.ISBN 9781784913847. <br /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><br />Archaeological  excavations at the Eleuthernian burial ground of Orthi Petra continue  to yield significant elements of the archaeo-anthropological record, the  subject matter of continuous interdisciplinary research, outreach,   national and international acclaim.  Among a plethora of features  discovered, unearthing components of a unique nexus to the  Geometric-Archaic Periods, was an unspoiled time capsule in astonishing  contextual preservation, a hand carved tomb with a <i>drómos</i> into  the softer bedrock material of Orthi Petra.  Designated in short as  contextual association A1K1, the tomb as a funerary activity area  yielded a remarkable collection of jar burials in complex internal tomb  stratification, containing cremated human bones accompanied by a most  noteworthy assembly of burial artifacts of exquisite wealth, along a  multitude of traces of “fossilized” behavior left resolutely behind by  the ancients in their transactions on the paths of their perceived  realities and obligations of life norms, but also of the arcane matters  of afterlife.  Such evidentiary data of funerary behavior in conjunction  with the rest of the archaeo-anthropological record afford the  opportunity to document where possible and deduce where pertinent  aspects of the transitional period, overlapping the end of life’s  journey and the unfolding of death in light of a number of the  principles, the values, and the modes that guided the lives of the  ancients as mortuary habits may have the transcending power to be  revealing of certain codes of <i>ante mortem</i> conduct, of main  beliefs, of ideologies and viewpoints, characteristic of their  ideational world and hence of their attitudes toward, and expectations  of, <i>post mortem</i> life. Such understandings, based on critical and  deductive thinking combined with the data offered through the scope of  anthropological archaeology and forensics by the decoding of traces  permanently recorded on bone and dental surfaces, construct a persuasive  dialectic, regarding important facets of the human condition in  Eleutherna from Geometric through Archaic times. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><a href="http://www.archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BA2E2FAD7-072C-489E-8E3E-B254A9EB46ED%7D">This book is also available to buy in paperback priced £8.00.</a></b><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Access Archaeology:</b> <i>Our newest imprint is designed to make  archaeological research accessible to all and to present a low-cost (or  no-cost) publishing solution for academics from all over the world.  Material will range from theses, conference proceedings, catalogues of  archaeological material, excavation reports and beyond. We will provide  type-setting guidance and templates for authors to prepare material  themselves designed to be made available for free online via our Open  Access platform and to supply in-print to libraries and academics  worldwide at a reasonable price point. <b><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/defaultAll.asp?displayPage=Publish+in+Access+Archaeology">Click here to learn more about publishing in Access Archaeology.</a></b></i><br /><br /></span><div class="productBox3TextHighlight">      <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span>               <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/viewReviews.asp?id=%7B3CAA9BF6-0D13-4EDA-B351-09516C9F8A55%7D">View Reviews</a></span>         	    </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"> &nbsp; <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/download.asp?id=%7B8F88FE87-9259-4AB8-A0CE-83F77C38F42D%7D" target="_blank">Download (pdf)</a> &nbsp;      </span><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">	    <tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong style="color: #535c5a;">These downloads are single-user and for your own personal use only.</strong></span></td></tr></tbody></table></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Halaf Settlement in the Iraqi Kurdistan: the Shahrizor Survey Project</b> <i>Taken from <b>The Archaeology of the Kurdistan Region of Iraq and Adjacent Regions</b></i> by Olivier Nieuwenhuyse, Takahiro Odaka and Simone Mühl. Pages 257-266.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The archaeology of the Halaf period has seen a very  significant increase over the past decades. This recent work almost  exclusively focussed on Northern Syria and Southeastern Turkey, or Upper  Mesopotamia (Akkermans and Schwartz 2003; Nieuwenhuyse et al. 2013). As  scholarship returns to Iraqi Kurdistan, prehistorians bring implicit  expectations and assumptions that are shaped to a large extent by the  latest work in Upper Mesopotamia. At the same time, the various new  projects are taking up the challenge of adapting the existing models to  local expressions of the Halaf cultural idiom (Altaweel et al. 2012;  Bonacossi and Iamoni 2015; Gavagnin et al. (forthcoming); Nieuwenhuyse  et al. 2016; Saber et al. 2014; Tsuneki et al. 2015; Ur et al. 2013).  For the Halaf period, it is necessary to develop a fine-tuned  chronological system that is sensitive to local internal sub-divisions  in order to assess the significance of fluctuating site densities  through time. The coarsegrained chronological framework currently  available only permits a generalized slicing-up of later prehistory into  ‘Pre-Halaf’, ‘Halaf’ and ‘Ubaid’. Such broad chronological boundaries  may well turn out to be less significant if these long periods can be  split into more nuanced images of change and continuity. The ultimate  aim is to develop local frameworks based on explicitly described  parameters so as to facilitate inter-regional comparisons (Ball et al.  1989; Dittmann 1992; Ur 2010, 214-5; Wilkinson and Tucker 1995). <b>Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BFD3630F4-AC74-42C6-A089-7737CD60911D%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b> </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/7A4BF88F9E814CA0A2D67DC1040240FF/Current%20Investigations%20into%20the%20Early%20Neolithic%20of%20the%20Zagros%20Foothills%20of%20Iraqi%20Kurdistan.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Current Investigations into the Early Neolithic of the Zagros Foothills of Iraqi Kurdistan</b> <i>Taken from <b>The Archaeology of the Kurdistan Region of Iraq and Adjacent Regions</b></i> by Roger Matthews, Wendy Matthews, Kamal Rasheed Raheem and Kamal Rauf Aziz. Pages 219-228.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">One of the most significant transformations in history  took place after the last Ice Age, from c. 12,000 BC (all dates  calibrated BC), when human communities changed from being mobile  hunter-foragers to more settled farmers and stock-keepers, with  domesticated crops and animals. This Neolithic transformation was a  fundamental development in the human condition across much of the world  and led ultimately, through surplus accumulation and social  differentiation, to the emergence of towns, cities, and empires, shaping  the modern world. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BFD3630F4-AC74-42C6-A089-7737CD60911D%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</span></div></div></blockquote><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/5FA63F46919F4AFFBABAFA89C6847758/In%20the%20Neo-Assyrian%20Border%20March%20of%20the%20Palace%20Herald.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>In  the Neo-Assyrian Border March of the Palace Herald: Geophysical Survey  and Salvage Excavations at Gird-i Bazar and Qalat-i Dinka (Peshdar Plain  Project 2015)</b> <i>Taken from <b>The Archaeology of the Kurdistan Region of Iraq and Adjacent Regions</b></i> by Karen Radner, Andrei Ašandulesei, Jörg Fassbinder, Tina Greenfield,  Jean-Jacques Herr, Janoscha Kreppner and Andrea Squitieri. Pages  353-367.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Peshdar Plain is situated in the province of  Sulaymaniyah, district of Raniyah (also known as Raparin district), in  the Kurdish Autonomous Region of Iraq, directly at the border with Iran  on the upper reaches of the Lower Zab. The regional centre is the town  of Qaladze (Qalat Dizeh), in the northwest of the plain, whose  impressive settlement mound (36° 11’ 7” N, 45° 6’ 53” E) demonstrates  that the site has held this position since antiquity. The Peshdar Plain  Project was inaugurated in 2015 with the goal of investigating the  region in the Neo-Assyrian period and focuses on two sites: tiny Gird-i  Bazar (36° 8’ 18” N, 45° 8’ 28” E; henceforth Bazar), a shallow mound  (altitude: 539 m) of only 1.5 ha situated in the plain, and the more  impressive Qalat-i Dinka (36° 8’ 12” N, 45° 7’ 57” E; henceforth Dinka),  looming high over the Lower Zab on the imposing terminal outcrop of a  crescent-shaped mountain range along the northern river bank. This first  report will briefly detail the geophysical survey (section 1) and the  excavations (section 2) conducted in 2015 before introducing the  bioarchaeological sampling strategy (section 3) and presenting a first  assessment of the sites and more generally of the significance of our  work in the regional setting of the Peshdar Plain and within the  Neo-Assyrian Empire and its client states (section 4). <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BFD3630F4-AC74-42C6-A089-7737CD60911D%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.&nbsp;</span></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/B70B0BFD9E004D7181A8319975EF44D1/Magnetic%20investigations%20in%20the%20Shahrizor%20Plain.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Magnetic investigations in the Shahrizor Plain: Revealing the unseen in survey prospections</b> <i>Taken from <b>The Archaeology of the Kurdistan Region of Iraq and Adjacent Regions</b></i> by Simone Mühl and Jörg Fassbinder. Pages 241-248.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Prospection by magnetometer in urban environments outside  the limits of excavation offers the possibility to unveil the layout of  entire settlements, including street networks and residential and other  architectural features, without the use of a spade. Questions about  city planning, the use of built and open space and the organization of  religious and other architecture at sites can all be addressed (cf.  Fassbinder 2002; Fassbinder et al. 2005; Benech 2007). Magnetic  prospections of sites in the Shahrizor Plain, which have been conducted  since October 2013, have the potential to provide insights into the  diachronic use of rural space in the region. This paper will focus on  the results of investigations which were carried out at Gird-i Shatwan  (bečuk – ‘the small mound Shatwan’; SSP-51 &amp; 52), a small Parthian  site in the rural environment of Wadi Shamlu in the center of the  Shahrizor Plain. <b>Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BFD3630F4-AC74-42C6-A089-7737CD60911D%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b>&nbsp;</span></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/7F4350A4819C40369D4DCC85073B6825/Palmyra,%2030%20Years%20of%20Syro-German-Austrian%20Archaeological%20Research.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Palmyra, 30 Years of Syro-German/Austrian Archaeological Research (Homs)</b> <i>Taken from <b>A History of Syria in One Hundred Sites</b></i> by Andreas Schmidt-Colinet, Khaled al-As‘ad and Waleed al-As‘ad. Pages 339-348.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The temple- or house-like tomb no. 36 is situated in the  centre of so-called ‘Valley of the Tombs’. With about 18m length from  edge to edge and about 300 graves (loculi), it is the largest  representative of this palace-like type of tombs at Palmyra. The  architectural decoration of the building allows a dating to about 210 to  230 AD. Furthermore the tomb can be attributed probably to the family  of the famous Iulius Septimius Aurelius Vorodes. The documentation of  the more than 700 fallen blocks of the ruin enables us to draw an exact  reconstruction of the building. The architecture documents a fusion of  different traditions as well as the grandiose will of the buildings  commissioner: The palace-like facade of the entrance contrasts with the  square, two-storey and uncovered peristyle courtyard in the centre of  the structure. Design and metrology of the building reveal at every  point Roman principles of design, brought into line with oriental taste.  The themes and the stylistic evidence of the architectural sculpture  prove close relations with foreign sarcophagi workshops on the Syrian coast and their connections to Roman art:  Dionysos-Baalshamin sitting in the vineyards, nereids and erotes riding  on dolphins, seamonsters holding a shell between them, victories,winged  Medusas, tragic masks. On the other hand, the exceptionally rich  architectural decoration of highest quality was worked out by local  workshops and enables us to reconstruct pattern books which partly can  be traced back to native textile patterns. <b>Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BE656951E-527C-4A52-8B6D-09660D88E11F%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b>&nbsp;</span></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBoxHover"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/C84AE9000BC94822A7C75755B9415580/Satu%20Qala.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Satu Qala: an Assessment of the Stratigraphy of the Site</b> <i>Taken from <b>The Archaeology of the Kurdistan Region of Iraq and Adjacent Regions</b></i> by Cinzia Pappi. Pages 297-307.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The view of historical developments within the area of  Idu, identified with Sâtu Qalâ on the Lower Zāb in Iraqi Kurdistan (Van  Soldt 2008), and its hinterland have so far been closely connected to  available information on the imperial expansion of Assyria in the  region. Through the support of the Directorate of Antiquities of the  Kurdish Regional Government of Iraq, an international team consisting of  the universities of Leiden (2010-12), Leipzig (2010-14), the Salahaddin  University of Erbil (2010-12), and the University of Pennsylvania  (2013) was able to conduct several seasons of fieldwork at Sâtu Qalâ.  Data from this fieldwork can now provide a much wider historical  sequence for the settlement. <b>Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BFD3630F4-AC74-42C6-A089-7737CD60911D%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b>&nbsp;</span></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/08397CB548F0473083A332740C211FB9/Tell%20el-Kerkh.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Tell el-Kerkh (Idlib)</b> <i>Taken from <b>A History of Syria in One Hundred Sites</b></i> by Akira Tsuneki. Pages 61-64.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Tell el-Kerkh is a large tell-complex located in the  south of the Rouj Basin, Idlib province. It was occupied for long  periods from the Neolithic to the Byzantine, however we concentrated our  excavations on the Neolithic period. It is the oldest Neolithic  settlement in northwest Syria, dating back to the middle of the 9th  millennium BC. Therefore, the site provided us with data on how farming  villages appeared in this region. Based on the excavated plant remains  and animal bones, the subsistence of the people who first settled at  Tell el-Kerkh seemed to follow the path from hunter-gatherers to  farmer-herders. <b>Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BE656951E-527C-4A52-8B6D-09660D88E11F%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b></span></div></div></blockquote><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/1ABB730D350D4D029CE3E6CA9AA5225B/Early%20Iron%20Age%20metal%20circulation%20in%20the%20Arabian%20Peninsula.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Early Iron Age metal circulation in the Arabian Peninsula: the oasis of Tayma as part of a dynamic network (poster)</b> <i>Taken from <b>Proceedings of the Seminar for Arabian Studies 46 (2016)</b></i> by Martina Renzi, Andrea Intilia, Arnulf Hausleiter &amp; Thilo Rehren. Pages 237-246.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The oasis of Tayma, located in north-western Arabia,  between the Hijaz mountains and the great Nafud desert, was  strategically situated on one of the branches of the main trade routes  that connected southern Arabia and the Mediterranean Sea during the  first millennium BC. During archaeological excavations at this site — a  project carried out by a Saudi Arabian-German team — an architectural  complex of public character dated to the Early Iron Age (eleventh–ninth  centuries BC) was investigated in Area O, in the southwestern section of  the ancient settlement. Among other finds, a significant concentration  of luxury goods (i.e. objects made of ivory, wood, bone, and faïence)  was discovered there, together with a few iron and several copper-based  artefacts. Of this assemblage, fifty-eight copper-based objects have  been analysed by portable X-ray fluorescence (pXRF), while sixteen have  undergone trace element and lead isotope analyses. The objects chosen to  be analysed included everyday items, such as rivets and fragments of  rods, three small metal lumps, and a bracelet. The data on their  elemental composition and lead isotope signatures combined to indicate  that different metal sources were used, suggesting the existence of a  highly dynamic metal trade in the wider region during the Early Iron  Age. <a href="http://www.archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B7C5532BA-8357-46D8-9C54-9BA1F202C409%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.&nbsp;</span></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/A85AC257040840BDA81AA10E79776E19/Iron%20Age%20metallurgy%20at%20Salut.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Iron Age metallurgy at Salūt (Sultanate of Oman): a preliminary note (poster)</b> <i>Taken from <b>Proceedings of the Seminar for Arabian Studies 46 (2016)</b></i> by Michele Degli Esposti, Martina Renzi &amp; Thilo Rehren. Pages 81-88.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Extensive excavations at the Iron Age site of Salūt, near  Bisyā in central Oman, revealed a complex architecture, allowing the reconstruction of a long history of building activities and  rearrangements. Among the discovered structures, none can clearly be  associated to metal production, although a small vertical furnace could  be tentatively interpreted as a metallurgical structure, possibly used  for small-scale copper/bronze remelting. The presence of charcoalrich  deposits, metal scraps, and stored broken objects in its vicinity also  points in this direction. A selection of these items, together with some  plano-convex ingots from other contexts within the site, has been  analysed and the preliminary results are outlined here. The significance  of this work is underlined by the current dearth of data on Iron Age  metallurgy in the Oman peninsula, compared to comprehensive studies of  Bronze Age metal production, when the land of Magan was widely renowned  for its wealth of copper ores. <b>Click on the PDF to read the full paper online, or download to your device. <a href="http://www.archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B7C5532BA-8357-46D8-9C54-9BA1F202C409%7D">The full volume is available in paperback here</a>.</b>&nbsp;</span></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/29B8F86C5F3D4FD28F2CA5BFCAFAF30C/The%20Crowded%20Desert.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>The Crowded Desert: a multi-phase archaeological survey in the north-west of Qatar</b> <i>Taken from <b>Proceedings of the Seminar for Arabian Studies 46 (2016)</b></i> by Jose C. Carvajal Lopez, Laura Morabito, Robert Carter, Richard  Fletcher &amp; Faisal Abdullah al-Naimi. Pages 45-62.ISBN 9781784913632.  <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This paper introduces the conception, development, and  results of the first campaign of the Crowded Desert Project, an  archaeological survey of the area of Mulayhah (aka Mleiha), Umm al-Ma in  north-west Qatar. The project </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"></blockquote><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;<b>CAA2015. Keep The Revolution Going</b> <i>Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Conference on Computer Applications and Quantitative Methods in Archaeology</i> edited by Stefano Campana, Roberto Scopigno, Gabriella Carpentiero and Marianna Cirillo. 1160 pages, illustrated throughout.  <span style="color: blue;"><b> Available both in print and Open Access</b></span>. 229 2016. ISBN 9781784913389. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This volume brings together all the successful  peer-reviewed papers submitted for the proceedings of the 43rd  conference on Computer Applications and Quantitative Methods in  Archaeology that took place in Siena (Italy) from March 31st to April  2nd 2015. <br /></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B503CFE7A-870C-42F1-86FD-E179E5DAE726%7D">This book is also available to buy in paperback priced £129.00.</a></b><br /><br /><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/0B30A310B9A04426A97065DD8586ABC7%5C9781784913229.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Off the Beaten Track. Epigraphy at the Borders</b> <i>Proceedings of 6th EAGLE International Event (24-25 September 2015, Bari, Italy)</i> edited by Antonio E. Felle and Anita Rocco. vi+154 pages; illustrated throughout in colour and black &amp; white.  <span style="color: blue;"><b> Available both in print and Open Access</b></span>.ISBN 9781784913236. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This volume contains the papers presented during the  Meeting ‘Off the Beaten Track – Epigraphy at the Borders’, the sixth in a  series of international events planned by the EAGLE, Europeana network  of Ancient Greek and Latin </span></blockquote><br /><br /><br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Access Archaeology:</b> <i>Our newest imprint is designed to make  archaeological research accessible to all and to present a low-cost (or  no-cost) publishing solution for academics from all over the world.  Material will range from theses, conference proceedings, catalogues of  archaeological material, excavation reports and beyond. We will provide  type-setting guidance and templates for authors to prepare material  themselves designed to be made available for free online via our Open  Access platform and to supply in-print to libraries and academics  worldwide at a reasonable price point. <b><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/defaultAll.asp?displayPage=Publish+in+Access+Archaeology">Click here to learn more about publishing in Access Archaeology.</a></b></i><br /></span><br /><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/797C8A3F8CBF470A98B5CED8EBA16097%5C9781784912727.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Structured Deposition of Animal Remains in the Fertile Crescent during the Bronze Age</b> by José Luis Ramos Soldado. vi+58 pages; illustrated throughout in colour and black &amp; white.  <em>Access Archaeology </em>. ISBN 9781784912697. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Although most of the animal remains recorded throughout  the archaeological excavations consist usually of large assemblages of  discarded and fragmented bones, it is possible to yield articulated  animal skeletons in some cases. Most of them have been usually picked up  from sacred and/or funerary contexts, but not all of them might fit  necessarily in ritual and symbolic interpretations, and not all of the  structured deposit of animal remains may be explained due to anthropic  factors. In addition, zooarchaeology has traditionally focused on animal  domestication, husbandry and economy, and species identification above  all, shutting out further discussion about these type of findings.  Moreover, the limited condition of the data is also another issue to  bear in mind. Thus, the aim of this paper has been to draw up a  literature review of the structured deposits of animal remains during  the third and second millennia BC in the Ancient Near East for its  subsequent classification and detailed interpretation. In this survey it  has been attested that not only most of the articulated animal remains  have been found in ritual and/or funerary contexts but also that all  species recorded– but some exceptions–are domestic. Hence, I argue in  this paper that there is a broad religious attitude towards the main  domesticated animals of human economy in the Ancient Near East, based on  the closeness of these animals to the human sphere. Therefore, it seems  that domesticated animals were powerful constituents in the cultural  landscape of these regions, never simply resources.<br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7B9D65E50D-09B2-47F2-B2D8-DD7D3F0FD53A%7D">This book is also available to buy in paperback priced £20.00.</a></b><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Access Archaeology:</b> <i>Our newest imprint is designed to make  archaeological research accessible to all and to present a low-cost (or  no-cost) publishing solution for academics from all over the world.  Material will range from theses, conference proceedings, catalogues of  archaeological material, excavation reports and beyond. We will provide  type-setting guidance and templates for authors to prepare material  themselves designed to be made available for free online via our Open  Access platform and to supply in-print to libraries and academics  worldwide at a reasonable price point. <b><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/defaultAll.asp?displayPage=Publish+in+Access+Archaeology">Click here to learn more about publishing in Access Archaeology.</a></b></i><br /></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/C88FCCB5456E422EA8A4B78EB0533EE5%5CCover.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Proceedings of ArcheoFOSS</b> <i>Free, libre and open source software e open format nei processi di ricerca archeologica: VIII Edizione Catania 2013</i> edited by Filippo Stanco e Giovanni Gallo. viii+274 pages. Illustrated  throughout in black &amp; white. Papers in Italian with English  Abstracts. <span style="color: blue;"><b> Available both in print and Open Access</b></span>.ISBN 9781784912604. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The VIII Workshop ArcheoFOSS, Free, Libre and Open Source  Software e Open Format for archeological research, has been held in  Catania, at The Department of Mathematics and Informatics of Catania  University, on June 18-19, 2013. The workshop has been attended by about  60 Italian  scientists and specialists of open source technology for  cultural heritage and archaeology. During the workshop, several original  contributions have been presented in well attended talks, followed by  lively Q&amp;A and open discussion among the attenders. The Workshop  sessions have been organized around general themes: Usage and  application of Geographical Information Systems; 3D modeling; Data  Management. The papers related to oral contribution have been expanded, revised,  peer reviewed and collected here according to the same themes. The contributed talks have been also complemented by 3D modeling and  digital visual effects tutorials. A lively barcamp by covering the main  issues related with the main topics of the conference has concluded the  meeting. To organize and coordinate the event has been a gratifying experience  for us. We have been much enriched by the long and constructive  discussions and exchanges during the workshop as well before it, with  all members of the Scientific Committee. Our hope is that the present  collection of papers will provide readers and experts useful ideas and  research perspectives beyond the people attending the workshop.</span></div></div></blockquote><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" height="200" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/7BC90C56796545ADA38F5A1D4B193915%5C9781784912284.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="141" /><b>About the Oldest Known Christian Buildings in the Extreme South of Lusitania</b> <i>The Case of Quinta De Marim (Olhão, Algarve, Portugal)</i> by Carlos Pereira. iii+23 pages; 8 plates, 2 in colour.ISBN 9781784912284. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Quinta de Marim (Algarve, Portugal) always aroused the  interest of researchers, but the ignorance on this site insists on  staying. We can confirm much of what has already been written and come  up with new interpretations that provide a new understanding of the  archaeological site, particularly on the Christianisation of the current  Algarve region. The fourth century represents the pinnacle moment in  which villae spaces become liable to be Christianized, motivating the  construction of religious buildings, including examples found in Quinta  de Marim, serving, perhaps, funerary purposes.</span></div></div></blockquote><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" height="200" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/5DFA36446D1743C58D0835796DD1173E%5C9781784912277.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="141" /><b>The Roman Necropolis of Algarve (Portugal)</b> <i>About the Spaces of Death in the South of Lusitania</i> by Carlos Pereira. iv+21 pages; 8 plates, 6 in colour.ISBN 9781784912277. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">We intend to disclose some of the results of the analysis  of the spaces of death from Roman times that were excavated in Algarve  for over a century. The conclusions obtained do not fit, as it is  understandable, in a summary article on the topic. However, it is  important to disclose some that denounce the status and religion of the  people who inhabited the South of the Roman province of Lusitania. <br /><br />We have particularly emphasised the problems related to the transition  from the cremation rite to the rite of inhumation of the corpse and the  possible visibility of the first signs of Christianity in the tombs of  these necropoleis. Arguments that favour and refute either situation  were weighed, which cannot be fully expressed here, but are better  exposed in the doctoral thesis of the author.</span></div></div></blockquote><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" height="200" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/98E4D1E8A9E34B20AB5CA673AE917D62%5C9781784911621.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="140" /><b>Best Practices of GeoInformatic Technologies for the Mapping of Archaeolandscapes</b> edited by Apostolos Sarris. iv+269 pages; illustrated throughout in colour and black &amp; white.ISBN 9781784911638. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">New geoinformatic technologies have recently had a  transformative effect on landscape archaeology, particularly by  facilitating the high resolution acquisition and analysis of data over  large areas. These techniques have fundamentally changed the nature and  scope of questions that can be addressed </span></div></div></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5072602003423778183/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/08/recently-published-at-archaeopress-open.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5072602003423778183"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5072602003423778183"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/08/recently-published-at-archaeopress-open.html"
         title="Recently Published at Archaeopress: Open Access"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
