<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8743929039972619365</id>
   <published>2016-06-14T03:16:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-06-14T03:49:32.504-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Canada"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Classica"/>
   <title type="text">New (Forthcoming) Open Access Monograph Series: Teiresias Supplements Online</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://teiresias-supplements.mcgill.ca/index">Teiresias Supplements Online</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="Journal Homepage Image" src="http://teiresias-supplements.mcgill.ca/public/journals/1/homepageImage_en_US.jpg" height="200" width="154" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: #9d2127;"><b>Teiresias Supplements Online&nbsp;</b></span>(ISBN) is an open access venue for the publication of high-end research in Classical Studies. Supplementing the journal <a href="http://www.teiresias-journal.org/" target="_blank">Teiresias Online Review and Bibliography of Boiotian Studies</a>,  the mission of the series is to foster research on Central Greece and  its core region Boiotia. At the same time, the supplements have a wider  geographical range, branching out into the history and culture of the  Greek mainland and the Peloponnese, from the Bronze Age to Late  Antiquity.&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Publications&nbsp;appear as peer-reviewed monographs or  edited volumes, with extensive coverage of scholarship in Ancient  History, Classical Philology, Archaeology, and Epigraphy. The series  also invites submissions in related special disciplines such as, for  instance, Historical Topography, Onomastics, Prosopography, or  Environmental History.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp; </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The journal&nbsp;Teiresias&nbsp;continues to be  distributed free of charge ever since its inception and, since 1991, has  also been made available electronically.&nbsp;<span style="color: #9d2127;"><b>Teiresias Supplements Online </b></span>is  faithful to this spirit of knowledge advancement. The series makes a  bold, pioneering move in the publication of specialized Humanities  research. Available in the <a href="https://doaj.org/" target="_blank">Directory of Open Access Journals (DOAJ)</a> and maintaining the highest standard of peer-review, the supplement  series reduces price barriers and delays in the production process,  while allowing authors to maintain copyright over their intellectual  output. This includes the upload of contributions to academic platforms  such as academia.edu, if authors wish to do so. Click <a href="http://teiresias-supplements.mcgill.ca/about/editorialPolicies#sectionPolicies" target="_blank">here</a>&nbsp;for further copyright information. Participating in the DOAJ also ensures that publications in&nbsp;<span style="color: #9d2127;"><b>Teiresias Supplements Online </b></span>are  indexed and searchable on platforms like Google scholar. As open access  supplements, the series embraces a sustainable publishing model that  benefits researchers and their multiple audiences.&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: #9d2127;"><b>Teiresias Supplements Online</b></span>&nbsp;is  a publication out of McGill University in Montreal. It offers a swift  two-step reviewing process. A detailed proposal will be examined in the  first instance by the advisory board, and, if successful, the editors  will welcome the submission of the whole manuscript for peer-reviewing.  All inquiries and submissions should be directed to the <a href="http://teiresias-supplements.mcgill.ca/manager/setup/%3Ehttp:/teiresias-supplements.mcgill.ca/about/" target="_blank">series editors</a>.</span></blockquote><h2 style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-weight: normal;"><span class="style3">And see AWOL's <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/06/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">Alphabetical List of Open Access Monograph Series in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></span></span></h2>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8743929039972619365/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/06/new-forthcoming-open-access-momograph.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8743929039972619365"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8743929039972619365"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/06/new-forthcoming-open-access-momograph.html"
         title="New (Forthcoming) Open Access Monograph Series: Teiresias Supplements Online"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
