<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-590125092966267143</id>
    <published>2014-11-12T18:22:00.000-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-11-12T18:22:36.961-05:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <title type="text">CDLI News: Free Library of Philadelphia cuneiform collection</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Mellon-funded digitization of the Free Library of Philadelphia cuneiform
      collection<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">We are delighted to announce a successful digitization collaboration between the
      Free Library of Philadelphia (<a href="http://freelibrary.org/">FLP</a>) and the
      Andrew W. Mellon Foundation-supported research project "Creating a Sustainable Cuneiform
      Digital Library" (CSCDL).<br /><br />Under the general direction of the Cuneiform
      Digital Library Initiative (<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/">CDLI - Los
      Angeles/Berlin/Oxford</a>), CSCDL is dedicated to the digital capture, persistent
      archiving and web dissemination of major collections in the US, Europe and the Middle East. The
      2916 cuneiform artifacts of the FLP represent a very substantial, yet still only partially
      published American collection. Janine Pollock, then Head of FLP’s Rare Book Department,
      provided the CDLI with a full concordance of the collection, and Los Angeles staff began in
      August of 2012 with preparations for its digitization. In January of 2013, CDLI postdoctoral
      associate Lance Allred initiated scanning work in Philadelphia, followed by subsequent missions
      undertaken by graduate student researcher Michael Heinle and research associate Stephen Hughey.
      All three were aided in no small part by the dedicated efforts of the Rare Book Department’s
      staff. Following fatcross-processing of the raw images by Heinle and Hughey, these files have
      been posted to the CDLI website, and can be viewed in search at &lt;<a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/search/">http://cdli.ucla.edu/search/</a>&gt;, and in
      overview at &lt;<a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/collections/flp/flp.html">http://cdli.ucla.edu/collections/flp/flp.html</a>&gt;.
      In the interest of a speedy exposure of the full collection, we have done only preliminary work
      on the nearly 1400 texts currently registered as "unpublished unassigned”; and a final short
      mission to the FLP by UCLA staff is planned to correct or supplement some of our online files.
      All inquiries regarding further publication of the FLP collection should be directed to the
      <a href="mailto:erefrbd@freelibrary.org">Rare Book Department</a>; we welcome
      corrections or additions to our files, sent to<a href="mailto:cdli@ucla.edu">
      CDLI</a>.<br /><br />In opening cuneiform collections to world-wide
      inspection, the FLP joins other cultural heritage and research institutions in CDLI's "extended
      family" who support efforts to permanently archive, and to make available to the public all
      artifacts of shared world history that are in their immediate, or indirect care.<br
      /><br />Janine Pollock, Assistant Chief, Central Public Services Division, Free
      Library of Philadelphia<br />Robert K. Englund, Director, CDLI (Los
      Angeles)</span></blockquote><br />]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/590125092966267143/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/11/cdli-news-free-library-of-philadelphia.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/590125092966267143"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/590125092966267143"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/11/cdli-news-free-library-of-philadelphia.html"
         title="CDLI News: Free Library of Philadelphia cuneiform collection"/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
