<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5919634521364297501</id>
   <published>2014-09-16T13:50:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2014-09-16T13:50:54.709-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="History"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greece"/>
   <title type="text">From the Archivist's Notebook: Essays Inspired by Archival Research in Athens Greece</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://nataliavogeikoff.com/">From the Archivist's Notebook</a>: Essays Inspired by Archival Research in Athens Greece<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="http://nataliavogeikoff.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/cropped-notebooks1.jpg" class="decoded" height="81" src="http://nataliavogeikoff.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/cropped-notebooks1.jpg" width="320" /></span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">My name is Natalia Vogeikoff-Brogan – archivist, archaeologist, historian, wife and mother. These are pages from my notebook.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">I studied Classical Archaeology in Greece (University of  Thessaloniki) and the United States (Bryn Mawr College), and have  conducted field work in East Crete for many years. Since 1994, I have  served the American School of Classical Studies at Athens as head of its  archives, from which I draw inspiration for most of my writings in this  blog. Together with Jack L. Davis, I recently co-edited a volume titled  <em>Philhellenism, Philanthropy, or Political Convenience? American Archaeology in Greece</em>, <em>Hesperia</em> 82:1, Princeton 2013. Jack, Vivian Florou, and I have another edited  volume in preparation; we are publishing papers from a colloquium that  the American School and the J.F. Costopoulos Foundation&nbsp; co-organized,  in May 2013, to remember Carl and Elizabeth Blegen. The volume carries  the provisional title, <em>Carl W. Blegen: Personal and Archaeological Narratives.</em></span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em></em>The book is scheduled to appear before the end of 2014 and it can already be pre-ordered at: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Carl-W-Blegen-Archaelogical-Narratives/dp/1937040224/ref=sr_1_4?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1409506771&amp;sr=1-4&amp;keywords=vogeikoff" rel="nofollow">http://www.amazon.com/Carl-W-Blegen-Archaelogical-Narratives/dp/1937040224/ref=sr_1_4?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1409506771&amp;sr=1-4&amp;keywords=vogeikoff</a></span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Unlike other blogs which have a casual tone and are published almost  on a daily basis, “From the Archivist’s Notebook” will appear once a  month (on the 1st), occasionally twice (then also on the 15th) if there  is a guest contribution. My intention is not to flood my followers’  e-mails with daily “announcements” —it doesn’t take much to run a good  thing into the ground, as my son says!</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Here you will also will find essays contributed by guest authors who  are involved in similar kinds of archival research: viz., the history of  institutions and the role of individual agency in them. These essays  will include their musings on books, articles, and exhibition catalogs  relevant to their research interests. Until now, guest bloggers Jack  Davis, Jacquelyn Clements, Liz Ward Papageorgiou, and Vivian Florou have  written on a variety of themes.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Jack Davis has contributed four great stories: “Barbarians at the  Gate” examined the history of the entrance exams to the American School  (and provoked strong reactions!); “An Archival Paradox, the Expédition  de Morée and a Mysterious Love Affair” explored the literary activities  of their members of the&nbsp; Expédition de Morée including Jack’s recent  discovery of an unknown epistolary novel by one otheir members,  Jacques-Louis Lacour; the unexpected retrieval of Marion Rawson’s  diaries prompted him to write about his favorite topic, Carl Blegen and  the Pylos excavations, in a story titled ” ‘I Once was Lost but Now I’m  Found': The Search for Missing Archives, Marion Rawson, and the  Excavations of the Palace of Nestor”; and in the September 2014 post,  Jack will be contributing an essay about the non-archaeological&nbsp;pastimes  of some of the American School’s most distinguished past members,  including Carl Blegen, Emily Vermeule, Rhys Carpenter, Oscar Broneer,  and Dorothy Burr Thompson.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Jacquelyn Clements composed a fun essay about living in Greece in the  early 1910s. “Letters from a New Home: Early 20th Century Athens  Through the Eyes of Zillah Dinsmoor” draw inspiration from the letters  that a young bride, Zillah Pierce Dinsmoor (the wife of the well-known  architect William Bell Dinsmoor), sent from Athens to her mother in  America.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">In “That Unspeakable Stoa” Liz Ward Papageorgiou wrote about Nancy  Mitford’s visit to the Athenian Agora during the re-construction of the  Stoa of Attalos in 1955. Unhappy with the building, Mitford, one of the  famous Mitford sisters, wrote acidic comments about it in the press as  well as to the Director of the Agora Excavations, Homer A. Thompson.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The July 2014 post featured Vivian Florou’s essay about&nbsp; high-society  Greek women in the decades between the two world wars. The traditional  festive costumes that they wore on their social outings defined the  aspirations of their class.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Finally, opinions on From the Archivist’s Notebook are those of the  authors. Comments are moderated, but publication of a comment does not  indicate an endorsement of the opinions in any comment. Opinions  expressed in comments are those of the individuals making the comments.</span></blockquote><br /><div id="logo">		</div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5919634521364297501/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/09/from-archivists-notebook-essays.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5919634521364297501"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5919634521364297501"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/09/from-archivists-notebook-essays.html"
         title="From the Archivist's Notebook: Essays Inspired by Archival Research in Athens Greece"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
