<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7486880142961624087</id>
   <published>2017-01-26T10:04:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2017-01-26T10:15:19.620-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="UK"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egyptology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Museum Catalogue"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egypt"/>
   <title type="text">UCL Petrie Collection Online Catalogue</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://petriecat.museums.ucl.ac.uk/default.aspx">UCL Petrie Collection Online Catalogue</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="Engraved tablet in the Petrie Museum" src="http://petriecat.museums.ucl.ac.uk/images/petrie/tn_DSCN6005.jpg" height="200" width="150" /> </blockquote></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This is the searchable dataset for all 80,000 artefacts  preserved in  the Petrie Museum of Egyptian Archaeology, with one photograph for each  item. To start searching right away, click on 'Search' above.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Museum houses one of the largest  archaeological collections in the world for Egypt and Sudan. It is named  after William Matthew Flinders Petrie (1853-1942), appointed in 1892 as  first UCL Edwards Professor of Egyptian Archaeology and Philology. Over  three-quarters of the material comes from excavations directed or  funded by Petrie, or from purchases he made for university teaching.  More information about the museum itself can be found at the Petrie  Museum homepage.</span><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Completeness of the Catalogue</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Like any museum inventory, the Petrie  Museum online catalogue is a hybrid of research publication and  public/research access project. The following short history of the  registration may help users to know what to expect from the contents.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>1. Petrie and the Collection</i><br />                                Petrie himself kept no accession  register, preferring to concentrate on publications for research and  teaching, with simple inventories for each type or technology: from 1914  to 1937, he personally saw to publication volumes including Objects of  Daily Use, Stone and Metal Vases, Weights and Measures, Scarabs, and  Amulets – others were published posthumously from his notes, mainly by  his widow Hilda.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>2. Seventy Years Registering the Collection</i><br />                                Comprehensive registration began only in  1935, under his successor as Professor Stephen Glanville, who  introduced the single-number “University College” sequence starting at  UC001.  In the following seven decades, broken only by the Second World  War, dozens of staff and volunteers with different levels of research  training, and varying amounts of time, contributed to the cataloguing  project. From 1999 to 2002 the last 40,000 objects were registered and  the whole collection put online with government funding through the  Designation Challenge Fund. In 2005 six hundred items on loan to the  National Museum of Science and Industry returned to be registered,  taking the collection to UC80604.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">As a result of the number of  individuals and different levels of expertise involved, all information  should be treated as a starting-point rather than an end in discovering  more about the objects in the collection. Arguably, museums deliver  exact data in only two areas: measurements, and date of acquisition –  all other key fields, from material to dating to depend on unstated  levels of research and subjective interpretation. For example,  laboratory analysis is expensive, and so, as in most collections, the  identification of material usually follows only quick inspection and  general expectations: specific identifications are often given for stone  and metal, but will need checking by analysis, while specific types of  wood are rarely given, awaiting a larger research project of analyses.  In this way, the process of revising the database can lead to important  new research projects of scientific and historical research. The Petrie  Museum curator is responsible for the updating of information, from  research at UCL and worldwide, including the discovery of new parallels  in fresh excavations in Egypt and Sudan. To keep this research in view,  the web catalogue is regularly updated.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Many fields of information have not  been entered yet, as research continues, particularly for the fields on  inscriptions and the history of acquisition. The Museum also preserves  important archives for material from Petrie excavations and purchases.  Continuing research and conservation into these archival holdings is  also contributing to the online catalogue.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="activetab" id="MainTabs1_tabIntro">    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://petriecat.museums.ucl.ac.uk/default.aspx" id="MainTabs1_HyperLinkIntro" title="Go to the introduction page"><span>Introduction</span></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="tab" id="MainTabs1_tabSearch">    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://petriecat.museums.ucl.ac.uk/search.aspx" id="MainTabs1_HyperLinkSearch" title="Go to the search form"><span>Search</span></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="tab" id="MainTabs1_tabResults">    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a disabled="disabled" href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="MainTabs1_HyperLinkResults" title="Go to the result view"><span>Results</span></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="tab" id="MainTabs1_tabDetails">    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a disabled="disabled" href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="MainTabs1_HyperLinkDetails" title="Go to the detail view"><span>Details</span></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="tab" id="MainTabs1_tabSelection">    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a disabled="disabled" href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="MainTabs1_HyperLinkSelection" title="Go to the selection page"><span>Selection</span></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="tab" id="MainTabs1_tabHistory">    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a disabled="disabled" href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="MainTabs1_HyperLinkHistory" title="Go to the search history page"><span>Search&nbsp;History</span></a></span></div></blockquote><h2></h2>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7486880142961624087/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2017/01/ucl-petrie-collection-online-catalogue.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7486880142961624087"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7486880142961624087"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2017/01/ucl-petrie-collection-online-catalogue.html"
         title="UCL Petrie Collection Online Catalogue"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
