<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7479577914349100426</id>
    <published>2014-11-27T09:31:00.000-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-11-27T12:17:33.386-05:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <title type="text">CDLI search</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[CDLI has recently implemented at &lt;<a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/search">http://cdli.ucla.edu/search</a>/&gt; a search
      functionality, similar to that for transliterations, for lines of translation and comment that
      form a part of our core text annotation files. While only a fraction of the numbers of
      translations available through the Oracc consortium, there are, still, currently some 54,000
      lines of translated cuneiform text in CDLI files, mostly in English, but including some
      instances in German, French, and even Catalan; 14,700 lines of interlinear annotation, from
      comment on sign preservation up to calculations that underlie numbers in accounts and
      metrological-mathematical texts, and 88,000 lines of (usually formulaic) comment to text
      structure. The bulk of current CDLI translations is comprised of those created by Dan Foxvog
      for the Mesopotamian Royal Inscriptions component of the website (nearly 30,000 lines in 1550
      texts; see &lt;<a
      href="http://tinyurl.com/mdhzlrg">http://tinyurl.com/mdhzlrg</a>&gt; and
      &lt;<a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/projects/royal/royal.html">http://cdli.ucla.edu/projects/royal/royal.html</a>&gt;),
      and we anticipate more translation content of Sumerian literary texts as ETCSL migrates to
      CDLI; but 13,600 lines in 1530 administrative texts are also now in some form of translation
      (&lt;<a
      href="http://tinyurl.com/kjkcut4">http://tinyurl.com/kjkcut4</a>&gt;). For the
      record, CDLI restricts translation of texts liable to appear in multiple witness artifacts to
      their artificial composite entries. As with transliteration search, the exact string of
      searched characters in translations and comments are highlighted in blue to facilitate their
      discovery within the displayed texts. Exact string in these instances means that, for example,
      a search for “pig” will display that string as a discrete word, but also all uses of “pigs,”
      “pigherder,” and so on. Only “pig” will be highlighted. Please note that the search engine
      results pages only report numbers of texts found, not individual references to a given search
      string. Thus a search for “calculation:” in comment results in 228 texts found, but altogether
      1026 uses of “calculation:”. As with transliteration search, users can enter multiple character
      strings in a field, each separated by a comma, for instance "lukalla,account” in translation
      (currently just six hits, at &lt;<a
      href="http://tinyurl.com/pegtatb">http://tinyurl.com/pegtatb</a>&gt;), but unlike
      transliteration these searches are always of full texts and cannot be restricted to single
      line, and are not case sensitive, neither of which seemed to us to contribute materially to
      search strategies.<br /><br />Bob Englund<br />UCLA]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7479577914349100426/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/11/cdli-search.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7479577914349100426"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7479577914349100426"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/11/cdli-search.html"
         title="CDLI search"/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
