<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7192775827534557686</id>
    <published>2014-11-04T16:21:00.000-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-11-04T16:21:27.951-05:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Bibliography"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ugaritic"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Grammar"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Hebrew"/>
    <title type="text">A BIBLIOGRAPHY OF UGARITIC GRAMMAR AND BIBLICAL HEBREW GRAMMAR IN THE
      TWENTIETH CENTURY</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a
      href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html">A BIBLIOGRAPHY OF
      UGARITIC GRAMMAR AND BIBLICAL HEBREW GRAMMAR IN THE TWENTIETH CENTURY</a> <br />By
      Mark S. Smith <br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="Section1"><div
      align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 12.5pt; margin-bottom: .0001pt;
      margin-bottom: 0in; margin-left: .5in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 3.0pt;
      mso-line-height-rule: exactly; mso-outline-level: 1; text-align: center; text-indent:
      -.5in;"><span style="font-size: x-small; text-transform:
      uppercase;"><b>Introduction</b></span></div><div
      class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 12.5pt; margin-bottom: .0001pt; margin-bottom: 0in;
      margin-left: .5in; margin-right: 0in; margin-top: 3.0pt; mso-line-height-rule: exactly;
      mso-outline-level: 1; text-indent: -.5in;"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><b>Purpose</b></span>
      </div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div
      class="Section1"><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 12.5pt; margin-top: 3.0pt;
      mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align: justify; text-indent: .25in;"><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">At present, a beginning course on Ugaritic might use either D.
      Sivan, <i>A Grammar of the Ugaritic Language</i> (HdO 1/28; Leiden: Brill, 1997),
      J. L. Cunchillos and J. A. Zamora, <i>Gramática Ugaritica Elemental</i> (Madrid:
      Ediciones Clásicas, 1995), or J. Tropper, <i>Ugaritisch. Kurzgefasste Grammatik mit
      Übungstexten und Glossar</i> (Elementa Linguarum Orientis 1; Münster: Ugarit-Verlag,
      2002). These books will be joined shortly by Joel H. Hunt and William M. Schniedewind's work,
      <i>A Primer for Ugarit: Language, Culture and Literature</i>(in preparation), which
      will be particularly suitable for beginning students. J. Tropper's <i>Ugaritische
      Grammatik</i>(AOAT 273; Münster: Ugarit-Verlag, 2000) is a research grammar appropriate
      for advanced courses and research. For an advanced course on Biblical Hebrew, one might consult
      N. Waldman's reference work, <i>The Recent Study of Hebrew: A Survey of the Literature
      with Selected Bibliography</i> (Bibliographica Judaica 10; Cincinnati: Hebrew Union
      College Press; Winona Lake, IN: Eisenbrauns, 1989). Readers will find good bibliography (as
      well as direction) in B. Waltke and M. P. O'Connor's study, <i>An Introduction to
      Biblical Hebrew Syntax</i>(Winona Lake, IN: Eisenbrauns, 1990). Building on these works
      and others, this work of mine is offered as a resource for the study of Ugaritic grammar and
      the grammar of Biblical Hebrew. Although such a bibliography may appear tedious, scholars
      cannot afford to work in a bibliographical vacuum. The linguist E. H. Sturtevant made this
      point over five decades ago when he wrote that "a writer who neglects the work of his
      predecessors and contemporaries is wasting his time and the time of his readers."<a
      href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1"
      style="mso-footnote-id: ftn1;" title=""><span class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span
      style="mso-special-character:
      footnote;">[1]</span></span></a></span><br
      /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 12.5pt; mso-line-height-rule:
      exactly; text-align: justify; text-indent: .25in;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">I
      have had misgivings about compiling a bibliography on Ugaritic grammar with bibliography of
      Biblical Hebrew grammar. After all, Ugaritic is not the only West Semitic source to provide
      important information for the background of Hebrew (especially "archaic Hebrew" and "classical
      Hebrew"). Indeed, readers will note from the organization of section one that Ugaritic and
      Hebrew are preceded by -- and therefore located bibliographically within -- their larger
      context of general linguistics and Semitics. This bibliography generally reflects the overall
      weight given to Ugaritic and Biblical Hebrew over and against other West Semitic material;
      these, too, are included but to a lesser degree. Missing from the listings for the West Semitic
      corpora is Aramaic, which deserves a treatment in its own right; readers may turn to J. A.
      Fitzmyer and S. A. Kaufman, ed., <i>An Aramaic Bibliography, Part I: Old, Official, and
      Biblical Aramaic</i>(Baltimore: Johns Hopkins, 1992).&nbsp;</span><br
      /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 12.5pt; mso-line-height-rule:
      exactly; text-align: justify; text-indent: .25in;"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">The weight given to Ugaritic and Biblical Hebrew may be justified based on the
      relative distribution of texts that currently survive in the West Semitic languages of the
      second and first millennia. For continuous texts, Ugaritic and Hebrew clearly enjoy a
      disproportionately superior place among the attested corpora. Readers may find it nonetheless
      misleading to juxtapose Ugaritic and Hebrew material in parallel sections, as if to suggest
      that Ugaritic is a direct antecedent to Hebrew. In order to be clear on this point, I would
      refer to the balanced view expressed by Anson Rainey over thirty years
      ago:</span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 12.5pt;
      mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align: justify; text-indent: .25in;"><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">Ugaritic is <i>not</i> Hebrew; it is not an older
      stage of Hebrew; it must even be differentiated from the dialect(s) reflected in the Amarna
      glosses. Its closest relative is undoubtedly Phoenician; but there are marked differences
      between them. One might agree that Ugaritic is a North-West Semitic language, evidently
      standing alongside Phoenician, Hebrew, Moabite and the Amarna glosses over against
      Aramaic.<a href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftn2"
      name="_ftnref2" style="mso-footnote-id: ftn2;" title=""><span
      class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span style="mso-special-character:
      footnote;">[2]</span></span></a></span><br
      /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 12.5pt; mso-line-height-rule:
      exactly; text-align: justify; text-indent: .25in;"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">As this statement suggests, Ugaritic and Hebrew belong to a larger group within
      the West Semitic languages. As the Ugaritic and Hebrew texts comprise the two largest corpora
      within this group, comparison of their grammatical features has often proved illuminating
      despite considerable differences between the two languages. A word about the listing for
      Hebrew: delineating the boundaries of what constitutes bibliography pertinent to the historical
      development of biblical Hebrew, or "Hebrew historical grammar," is not always obvious, and what
      I have provided perhaps tends toward the more inclusive end of the spectrum (with the
      exceptions of introductory grammars and dictionaries, which are not included
      here).</span><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height:
      12.5pt; mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align: justify; text-indent: .25in;"><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">In order to make this bibliography more "user friendly," I have
      presented it in the order of topics found in a grammar. The order here is largely traditional
      (with the customary division of phonology, morphology and syntax), although since the 1960s
      linguists have paid a great deal of attention to the interface between these levels of
      grammar.<a href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftn3"
      name="_ftnref3" style="mso-footnote-id: ftn3;" title=""><span
      class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span style="mso-special-character:
      footnote;">[3]</span></span></a> In section 15, the organization for
      syntax gives precedence of text linguistics before the syntax of clauses and their subunits,
      reflecting the current view that the sentence does not constitute the largest unit of
      grammatical analysis.<a
      href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftn4" name="_ftnref4"
      style="mso-footnote-id: ftn4;" title=""><span class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span
      style="mso-special-character: footnote;">[4]</span></span></a> One might
      go further and present syntax as theoretically prior to, and the context for, situating
      morphology, and, by extension, phonology as well; however, the traditional order of grammars is
      retained here for the sense of familiarity that it affords readers.
      </span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 12.5pt;
      mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align: justify; text-indent: .25in;"><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">I have included bibliography for the alphabet (under section 2),
      although properly speaking the alphabet is not a grammatical topic but a matter of the graphic
      representation of languages.<a
      href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftn5" name="_ftnref5"
      style="mso-footnote-id: ftn5;" title=""><span class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span
      style="mso-special-character: footnote;">[5]</span></span></a> However,
      the alphabet's historical importance for the study of West Semitic languages dictates its
      inclusion here. I have included some entries for Hebrew phonology or morphology with little or
      no mention of Ugaritic, in part to be more inclusive in these areas and in part to promote such
      work in the study of Ugaritic. Also included are entries for the syntax of particles (under
      9.2) and for the verb (under 10.2.1) as well as some select individual verbal roots (under
      14.11 and following). The bibliography in section 16 includes both basic and illustrative
      entries in the areas of lexicography, loanwards and semantics as well as personal names, but
      listings for dictionaries and lexica for Biblical Hebrew have not been included.<a
      href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftn6" name="_ftnref6"
      style="mso-footnote-id: ftn6;" title=""><span class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span
      style="mso-special-character: footnote;">[6]</span></span></a> As this
      discussion and the many entries in 1.1.1 and 1.1.2 illustrate (not to mention specific
      references in many other sections), the study of ancient Hebrew has benefited from the
      application of modern linguistics more than Ugaritic. The borders between some areas of grammar
      and other subjects are not always simple to delineate. For example, some bibliography for
      grammatical aspects of Hebrew poetry are included (word-order and semantics), but other aspects
      of Hebrew poetry are not. Some entries are listed more than once when they pertain to multiple
      grammatical topics. Standard abbreviations have been used (see the list in the final section of
      this introduction); these are found also in <i>Ugarit-Forschungen</i> and
      <i>Journal of Biblical Literature</i>).</span><br /></div><div
      class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 12.5pt; mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align:
      justify; text-indent: .25in;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This bibliography is
      not comprehensive. As a work in progress, it contains omissions and mistakes. Moreover, some of
      terms or words in foreign language fonts as well as some diacritical marks have not come
      through. I trust that the contexts where these terms or words appear will indicate what foreign
      words (mostly in Hebrew) they refer to. For words spelled in Hebrew I have substituted English
      spellings in square brackets. As a result of working on this project at different times, I have
      produced other inconsistencies of format as well. I hope to correct these flaws in future
      revisions; in the meantime, I hope this bibliography will nonetheless serve the
      field.</span><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height:
      12.5pt; margin-top: 12.0pt; mso-line-height-rule: exactly; mso-outline-level: 1;"><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Origins and
      Acknowledgments</b></span><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal"
      style="line-height: 12.5pt; mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align: justify; text-indent:
      .25in;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This bibliography originated in the early
      1980s during my studies at Yale University. In the summer of 1981, Marvin Pope hired me to
      produce a general bibliography regarding Ugaritic mythological texts. The following year Robert
      R. Wilson put into my hands a basic bibliography for a reading course on Hebrew historical
      grammar that he had inherited from his own teacher at Yale, S. Dean McBride. Professor Wilson's
      bibliography as well as the bibliographical learning gained under Professor Pope were useful
      later for courses that I offered. I have also found it useful to maintain the bibliography as a
      resource for my own research and for course readings. A couple of years ago I made this
      bibliography available to interested scholars and students in the form of xerox copies. At that
      time, it was suggested to me that this bibliography should be published. Despite the flaws of
      this edition and despite some misgivings, I have decided to proceed with this e-version so that
      the bibliography can be made more widely available.</span><br /></div><div
      class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 12.5pt; mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align:
      justify; text-indent: .25in;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">I am indebted in
      particular to the students who went through courses with me. The bibliography was advanced
      through the labors of the interlibrary office of Drexel Library of Saint Joseph's University. I
      am grateful also to the Simor Bible Bibliographical Computer Service, which provided me with a
      printout of its listings for Ugarit and Ugaritic. A number of colleagues kindly provided help
      with references: Professors S. A. Fassberg, J. Huehnergard, T. Muraoka, F. H. Polak, G. A.
      Rendsburg and G. Rubio. John Huehnergard generously shared his bibliography with me. I thank
      Charles E. Jones, Research Archivist and Bibliographer, and Thomas G. Urban, Senior Editor,
      both of the Oriental Institute, for their time and energy in preparing this work for the
      web.</span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><br
      /></div></div><div style="mso-element: footnote-list;"><hr align="left"
      size="1" width="33%" /><div id="ftn1" style="mso-element: footnote;"><div
      class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 11.5pt; margin-top: 4.0pt; mso-line-height-rule: exactly;
      text-align: justify;"><a
      href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1"
      style="mso-footnote-id: ftn1;" title=""><span class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span
      style="font-size: 9.0pt;"><span style="mso-special-character:
      footnote;">[1]</span></span></span></a><span style="font-size:
      9.0pt;"> Sturtevant, <i>An Introduction to Linguistic
      Science</i></span><span style="font-size: 9.0pt;"> (New Haven/London: Yale,
      1947) 2 (cited by A. Hurvitz, "The Relevance of Biblical Hebrew Linguistics for the Historical
      Study of Ancient Israel," <i>Proceedings of the Twelfth World Congress of Jewish Studies.
      Division A: The Bible and Its World</i></span><span style="font-size:
      9.0pt;"> [Jerusalem: World Union of Jewish Studies, 1999] 24* n.
      6).</span></div></div><div id="ftn2" style="mso-element:
      footnote;"><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 11.5pt; margin-top: 4.0pt;
      mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align: justify;"><a
      href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftnref2" name="_ftn2"
      style="mso-footnote-id: ftn2;" title=""><span class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span
      style="font-size: 9.0pt;"><span style="mso-special-character:
      footnote;">[2]</span></span></span></a><span style="font-size:
      9.0pt;"> Rainey, "Observations on Ugaritic Grammar,"
      <i>UF</i></span><span style="font-size: 9.0pt;"> 3 (1971) 153 (Rainey's
      italics).</span></div></div><div id="ftn3" style="mso-element:
      footnote;"><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 11.5pt; margin-top: 4.0pt;
      mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align: justify;"><a
      href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftnref3" name="_ftn3"
      style="mso-footnote-id: ftn3;" title=""><span class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span
      style="font-size: 9.0pt;"><span style="mso-special-character:
      footnote;">[3]</span></span></span></a><span style="font-size:
      9.0pt;"> For example, see E. Benveniste, "Les niveaux de l'analyse linguistique,"
      <i>Proceedings of the Ninth International Congress of Linguists, Cambridge, Mass., August
      27-21, 1962</i></span><span style="font-size: 9.0pt;"> (ed. H. G. Lunt; Janua
      Linguarum, series maior XII; London/The Hague/Paris: Mouton, 1964) 266-75, with responses on
      275-93; and J. Kurylowicz, "The Notion of Morpho(pho)neme," <i>Directions for Historical
      Linguistics: A Symposium</i></span><span style="font-size: 9.0pt;">(ed. W. P.
      Lehmann and Y. Malkiel; Austin/London: University of Texas, 1968)
      65-81.</span></div></div><div id="ftn4" style="mso-element:
      footnote;"><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 11.5pt; margin-top: 4.0pt;
      mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align: justify;"><a
      href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftnref4" name="_ftn4"
      style="mso-footnote-id: ftn4;" title=""><span class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span
      style="font-size: 9.0pt;"><span style="mso-special-character:
      footnote;">[4]</span></span></span></a><span style="font-size:
      9.0pt;"> See the response of K. Pike to E. Benveniste, "Les niveaux de l'analyse
      linguistique," <i>Proceedings of the Ninth International Congress of Linguists,
      Cambridge, Mass., August 27-21, 1962</i></span><span style="font-size:
      9.0pt;"> (ed. H. G. Lunt; Janua Linguarum, series maior XII; London/The Hague/Paris: Mouton,
      1964) 266-75, on p. 283. See more recently J. Joosten, "The Indicative System of the Biblical
      Hebrew Verb and Its Literary Exploitation," <i>Narrative Syntax and the Hebrew Bible:
      Papers of the Tilburg Conference 1996</i></span><span style="font-size:
      9.0pt;"> (ed. E. van Wolde; Biblical Interpretation Series 29; Leiden: Brill, 1997) 54; M.
      O'Connor, "Discourse Linguistics and the Study of Biblical Hebrew," <i>Congress Volume:
      Basel 2001</i></span><span style="font-size: 9.0pt;"> (ed. A. Lemaire; VTSup
      92; Leiden/Boston: Brill, 2002) 26.</span></div></div><div id="ftn5"
      style="mso-element: footnote;"><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 11.5pt;
      margin-top: 4.0pt; mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align: justify;"><a
      href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftnref5" name="_ftn5"
      style="mso-footnote-id: ftn5;" title=""><span class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span
      style="font-size: 9.0pt;"><span style="mso-special-character:
      footnote;">[5]</span></span></span></a><span style="font-size:
      9.0pt;"> See the response of J. Lee to J. V. Walsh, "Linguistic Factors in the Evolution of
      the Alphabet," <i>Proceedings of the Ninth International Congress of Linguists,
      Cambridge, Mass., August 27-29, 1962</i></span><span style="font-size:
      9.0pt;"> (ed. H. G. Lunt; Janua Linguarum, series maior XII; London/The Hague/Paris: Mouton,
      1964) 519-20.</span></div></div><div id="ftn6" style="mso-element:
      footnote;"><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 11.5pt; margin-top: 4.0pt;
      mso-line-height-rule: exactly; text-align: justify;"><a
      href="http://oi-archive.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.html#_ftnref6" name="_ftn6"
      style="mso-footnote-id: ftn6;" title=""><span class="MsoFootnoteReference"><span
      style="font-size: 9.0pt;"><span style="mso-special-character:
      footnote;">[6]</span></span></span></a><span style="font-size:
      9.0pt;"> For recent discussions, see M. O'Connor, "Semitic Lexicography: European
      Dictionaries of Biblical Hebrew in the Twentieth Century,"
      <i>IOS</i></span><span style="font-size: 9.0pt;"> 20 (2002) =
      <i>Semitic Linguistics: The State of the Art at the Turn of the
      21<sup>st</sup> Century</i></span><span style="font-size:
      9.0pt;"> (ed. S. Izre'el; Winona Lake, IN: Eisenbrauns, 2002) 173-212; and G. J. Van
      Steenbergen, "Hebrew Lexicography and Worldview: A Survey of Some Lexicons,"
      <i>JSem</i></span><span style="font-size: 9.0pt;"> 12/2 (2003)
      268-313.</span></div></div></div><hr align="center" size="5"
      width="100%" /><span style="font-size: x-small;">This first on-line version is
      presented courtesy of the Research Archives at the Oriental Institute, the University of
      Chicago. The full text of the bibliography is available in three formats.
      </span></blockquote><blockquote></blockquote><ul><li><blockquote><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">For a .pdf version [610K] <a
      href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.pdf" target="_BLANK">Click
      Here</a></span></blockquote></li></ul><blockquote></blockquote><ul><li><blockquote><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">For a .doc version [673K] <a
      href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.doc" target="_BLANK">Click
      Here</a></span></blockquote></li></ul><blockquote></blockquote><ul><li><blockquote><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">For an .rtf version [852K] <a
      href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/OI/DEPT/RA/bibs/BH-Ugaritic.rtf" target="_BLANK">Click
      Here</a></span></blockquote></li></ul>]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7192775827534557686/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/11/a-bibliography-of-ugaritic-grammar-and.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7192775827534557686"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7192775827534557686"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/11/a-bibliography-of-ugaritic-grammar-and.html"
         title="A BIBLIOGRAPHY OF UGARITIC GRAMMAR AND BIBLICAL HEBREW GRAMMAR IN THE TWENTIETH CENTURY"/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
