<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-718742867352646869</id>
   <published>2015-09-17T16:04:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-09-17T16:04:21.085-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dissertation"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egyptology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egypt"/>
   <title type="text">The Egyptian Ouroboros: An Iconological and Theological Study</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/t0jv5bgp9sfgfb2/DISSERTATION.pdf">The Egyptian Ouroboros: An Iconological and Theological Study</a><br />by Dana Michael Reemes<br />Doctor of Philosophy in Near Eastern Languages and Cultures<br />University of California, Los Angeles, 2015<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This  study  examines  a  well-established  idea  in  normative  Egyptological  discourse,  that  there exists  in  the  inventory  of  Egyptian  symbolism  a  distinct  and  unique  symbol  called sed-em-ra(„tail-in-mouthʼ)  in  Egyptian,  though  usually  referred  to  today  by  the  Greek  term ouroboros („tail-devouringʼ), being  the image of a serpent arranged in a  circle with the tip of its tail in its mouth, and expressive of specific meanings such as “endless time” and “eternity,” among others. However,  a  close  examination  of  relevant  iconographic  and  textual  sources  reveals  that  this Egyptological  ouroboros  is  largely  an  illusion,  and  one  that  distorts  understanding  of  Egyptian material  by  importing  into  it  ideas  that  properly belong  to  the  history  of  the  post-pharaonic reception  of  the ouroboros  icon, such as  the idea  that  the ouroboros  was primarily  a  symbol  of the recurrent  solar  year,  which  had  its  origin  with  Latin  authors,  or  the idea  that  the ouroboros symbolizes time andeternity, which is a tradition no older than the Italian Renaissance. Yet it is this latter ouroboros of the Renaissance iconographers and emblem books, an unquestioned part of the intellectual environment in which the discipline of Egyptology historically  emerged, that induced   nineteenth   and   twentieth   century   Egyptologists   to   unhesitatingly   single   out   the ouroboros for special notice as the “serpent of eternity,” an interpretation not supported by Egyptian   sources.   A   fresh   hermeneutical   approach   requires the   abandonment   of   such preconceptions,  starting  with  rejection  of  the  idea  that  the  Egyptian  ouroboros  is  a  distinct symbol with specific meanings attached. Once the term „ouroborosʼ is used only in a limited and purely  descriptive  sense,  it  becomes  possible  to  understand  what  the  icon  may  be  intended  to express  within  the  larger  conceptual  and  iconographic  context  in  which  occurrences  are embedded. This approach makes it clear that the icon was never a discrete symbol in Egypt, but rather  a  possible  variant  amongst  related  iconography  that  might  convey  similar  meanings.  A detailed  reassessment  of  relevant  primary  sources  shows  that  the  icon  is  primarily  associated with  the  idea  of  protective  enclosure,  conceived  of  as  a  divine  forcefunctioning  on  multiple levels: cosmic, solar, funereal, and individual.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/718742867352646869/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/09/the-egyptian-ouroboros-iconological-and.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/718742867352646869"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/718742867352646869"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/09/the-egyptian-ouroboros-iconological-and.html"
         title="The Egyptian Ouroboros: An Iconological and Theological Study"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
