<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4779054062977628683</id>
   <published>2015-09-28T13:50:00.003-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-09-28T13:50:37.646-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <title type="text">SURVEY ON FIELD SAFETY (2015): MIDDLE EAST, NORTH AFRICA, AND MEDITERRANEAN BASIN </title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://uarizona.co1.qualtrics.com/SE/?SID=SV_bNHSjX0MTkFqKnb"><span style="font-size: 16px;">SURVEY ON FIELD SAFETY (2015): MIDDLE EAST, NORTH AFRICA, AND MEDITERRANEAN BASIN</span></a><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span> </span></span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"><strong>Introduction and thanks: &nbsp;</strong></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Thank you for your interest in this survey, and for taking the time to participate in it. &nbsp;The original </span><em style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Survey on Field Safety: Middle East, North Africa, and Mediterranean Basin</em><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"> was circulated a year ago (mid-2014), and you may have seen it – and  even taken it – at that time.&nbsp; It is being circulated again (mid-2015),  with two goals.&nbsp; The first goal is to reach individuals who might not  have seen the survey the first time, or who might have seen the survey  but not taken it and would like to do so now.&nbsp; The second goal is to  follow up, for those who have participated in field projects since they  took the 2014 survey.&nbsp; The results from this survey will provide insight  into field culture for 2015 and over a more extended period of time.  &nbsp;These results are critical both <span>for identifying problems, and for developing methods to remediate problems in archaeological field culture.</span></span><br />&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"><strong>IF YOU HAVE NOT PREVIOUSLY TAKEN THIS SURVEY:</strong><br />When taking this survey, you may also include information about your  2014 fieldwork experience. &nbsp;Doing so will facilitate comparisons between  the two field seasons.&nbsp;</span></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><strong style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">IF YOU ALREADY TOOK THIS SURVEY IN 2014:</strong><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"><br />When taking this survey, you may also incl</span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">ude  information about your 2014 fieldwork experience, even if you already  reported about it in 2014. &nbsp;Doing so will facilitate comparisons between  the 2014 and 2015 field seasons.&nbsp;</span></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">About the survey:</strong><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">The </span><em style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Survey on Field Safety: Middle East, North Africa, and Mediterranean Basin</em><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">&nbsp;is designed to</span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"> understand the ways in which archaeological fieldwork does – or does  not – provide a setting that is safe and secure from intimidation,  harassment and violence based on gender, sexual orientation, and/or  gender identity for all project participants. &nbsp;Beyond documenting and  quantifying experiences,&nbsp;goals include determining those factors that  contribute to safe and unsafe fieldwork environments; identifying areas  in which further research is necessary; determining best practices and  the means by which to implement them; developing standards, policies and  protocols designed to educate and inform all participants in  archaeological excavations about ethics and laws in the field and on  research projects; and, under the auspices of the American Schools of  Oriental Research (ASOR),&nbsp; offering online trainings and access to  relevant documents for excavation leaders, staff, volunteers, and  employees.&nbsp; Collaboration among a broad spectrum of professional  societies and institutes is essential for meeting these goals.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><strong style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">PLEASE SUBMIT YOUR RESPONSE BY OCTOBER 15, 2015.</strong></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><strong style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">To take the survey:</strong><br /><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">All individuals  taking this survey must be 18 years or older. &nbsp;By clicking on the  "NEXT" (right-facing) arrows at the bottom of this page, you give  informed consent to participate in this research study "</span></span><em style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Survey on Field Safety.</em><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">"&nbsp;  Please answer the questions to the best of your ability.&nbsp; You may stop  taking the survey at any time, and you may decide not to answer every  question.&nbsp;</span></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><strong style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Confidentiality:&nbsp;</strong></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Your  responses will remain anonymous.&nbsp; The University of Arizona server on  which this survey and all responses to it are stored is data-encrypted.  At no time, whether in presentations or in online or print publications  will your name, place of study or employment, field project/s or other  identifying information be made public.&nbsp; Only the Principal Investigator  will know your identity.&nbsp; Unless you indicate interest in a follow-up  interview, you will not be contacted about the survey and your responses  to it.<br /><br />In order to ensure that participants fill out the survey only once, you  will be asked to provide your email address.&nbsp; The confirmation you will  receive upon completion of the survey is the only communication that  will be sent to your email address, unless you indicate interest in a  follow-up interview.&nbsp;</span></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">&nbsp;</span></span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">If your responses indicate an on-going situation in which reporting to authorities is legally mandated (such as, for <span>example, on-going sexual abuse of minors), then such a report will be made, as required by law.</span></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Optional follow-up interview:</strong></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">If you  indicate, by checking the appropriate box at the end of the survey, that  you would like to participate in a follow-up interview, then you will  be contacted for scheduling at your email address.&nbsp; As with the survey,  no personal or project identifiers will be made public, whether in  presentations or in online or print publications.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Risks and benefits:</strong></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Participation  in this survey may trigger difficult and troubling memories.&nbsp;&nbsp;If you are  concerned that sharing these memories might be too painful, please do  not continue with the survey.&nbsp;&nbsp;If, however, you are able to share your  expe<span>riences, then be assured that the  information you provide (concerning both positive and negative  experiences) will be used to make archaeological fieldwork safer and  more secure for all participants.&nbsp;</span></span></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">An  Institutional Review Board responsible for human subjects research at  The University of Arizona reviewed this research project and found it to  be acceptable, according to applicable state and federal regulations  and University policies designed to protect the rights and welfare of  participants in research.</span></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"><br /></span></span></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">For further information:</strong></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">If  you have any questions about this project, please contact the principal  investigator, Beth Alpert Nakhai, Ph.D., R.P.A.,&nbsp;Associate Professor,  Arizona Center for Judaic Studies and School of Anthropology, The  University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ (520-626-5762;  bnakhai@email.arizona.edu).</span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"><br /></span></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">If  you have questions about your rights as a participant in this survey,  or if you have concerns or complaints, please contact The University of  Arizona Institutional Review Board (520) 626-6721 or  www.orcr.arizona.edu/hspp</span></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"><br /></span></span></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Thank you for your willingness to participate in this project.</span></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"><br /></span></span></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Sincerely,</span></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;">Beth Alpert Nakhai, Ph.D., R.P.A.</span></span></span><br />  <br />&nbsp;  <span style="font-size: 13px;"><span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"><br /></span></span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4779054062977628683/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/09/survey-on-field-safety-2015-middle-east.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4779054062977628683"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4779054062977628683"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/09/survey-on-field-safety-2015-middle-east.html"
         title="SURVEY ON FIELD SAFETY (2015): MIDDLE EAST, NORTH AFRICA, AND MEDITERRANEAN BASIN "/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
