<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4764410421831062928</id>
   <published>2016-01-06T23:30:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-01-06T23:30:20.386-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Penn Libraries’ OPenn Manuscript Portal Launched</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="tr_bq"><a href="http://schoenberginstitute.org/2016/01/06/penn-libraries-openn-manuscript-portal-to-host-the-countrys-largest-regional-collections-of-digitized-medieval-manuscripts/">Penn Libraries’ OPenn Manuscript Portal to Host the Country’s Largest Regional Collections of Digitized Medieval&nbsp;Manuscripts  </a></div><header class="single-entry-header">   <a href="http://schoenberginstitute.org/2016/01/06/penn-libraries-openn-manuscript-portal-to-host-the-countrys-largest-regional-collections-of-digitized-medieval-manuscripts/" rel="bookmark" title="4:07 pm"><time class="entry-date" datetime="2016-01-06T16:07:52+00:00" pubdate="">January 6, 2016</time></a><span class="byline"> </span><span class="comments-link"></span>     <br />  </header>         <div class="wp-caption alignright" data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_1123" style="width: 229px;"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><a href="https://schoenberginstitute.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/mca0071162.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-1123"><img alt="Free Library of Philadelphia Lewis E 7, Processional, f. 116v (http://libwww.freelibrary.org/medievalman/ecw.cfm?ItemID=mca0071162)" class="size-medium wp-image-1123" height="200" src="https://schoenberginstitute.files.wordpress.com/2016/01/mca0071162.jpg?w=438&amp;h=600" width="146" /></a></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="wp-caption-text"><span style="font-size: xx-small;">Free Library of Philadelphia Lewis E 7, Processional, f. 116v (<a href="http://libwww.freelibrary.org/medievalman/ecw.cfm?ItemID=mca0071162" rel="nofollow">http://libwww.freelibrary.org/medievalman/ecw.cfm?ItemID=mca0071162</a>)</span></div></blockquote></div><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Philadelphia, PA, January 6th, 2016—</strong>The Penn  Libraries is proud to announce their role as online host and one of the  leaders in a partnership that will create the country’s largest regional  collection of digitized medieval manuscripts. This role is made  possible through a grant of almost $500,000 awarded to <em>Bibliotheca Philadelphiensis,</em> a new project organized by the<a href="http://pacscl.org/"> Philadelphia Area Consortium of Special Collections Libraries (PACSCL)</a> and funded by the<a href="http://www.clir.org/"> Council on Library and Information Resources</a> (CLIR) with generous support from The Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The project, involving a total of 15 partner institutions, and led by  the Penn Libraries, the Free Library of Philadelphia, and Lehigh  University, will complete the digitization and online presentation of  virtually all of the region’s medieval manuscripts – a total of almost  160,000 pages from more than 400 individual volumes. PACSCL first  showcased the variety and depth of Philadelphia collections in a 2001  exhibition, “<a href="http://archives.pacscl.org/leaves/">Leaves of Gold: Manuscript Illumination from Philadelphia Collections,</a>”  at the Philadelphia Museum of Art. &nbsp;The exhibition and its associated  catalogue drew heavily upon the manuscripts to be digitized in this  project and sparked a surge in scholarly interest in the Philadelphia  collections.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The manuscripts in this project range from simple but functional  texts intended for the students of science, philosophy, and religion to  jewel-like works of art in the collections of such institutions as Bryn  Mawr College, the Philadelphia Museum of Art, and the Free Library of  Philadelphia’s Rosenbach Museum.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>Bibliotheca Philadelphiensis’</em> images and metadata will be hosted by the Penn Libraries’ manuscript portal, OPenn (<a href="http://openn.library.upenn.edu/">http://openn.library.upenn.edu</a>).  The images will be released into the public domain at high resolution  and available for download (by the page, manuscript, or collection) with  descriptive metadata. “Penn Libraries is thrilled to be collaborating  with the Philadelphia Area Consortium of Special Collections Libraries  to create data on the Middle Ages for the twenty-first century from  American collections,” remarked William Noel, Director of the Kislak  Center for Special Collections, Rare Books and Manuscripts at the Penn  Libraries.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The project participants include the following area libraries and  museums: Bryn Mawr College, Chemical Heritage Foundation, College of  Physicians of Philadelphia, Franklin and Marshall College, Free Library  of Philadelphia (lead contributor and co-principal investigator)  Haverford College, Lehigh University (principal investigator, fiscal  agent, and dark archive), Library Company of Philadelphia, Philadelphia  Museum of Art, Rosenbach Museum and Library, Swarthmore College, Temple  University, University of Delaware, University of Pennsylvania (OPenn  host and lead imaging/metadata center), Villanova University.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4764410421831062928/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/01/penn-libraries-openn-manuscript-portal.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4764410421831062928"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4764410421831062928"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/01/penn-libraries-openn-manuscript-portal.html"
         title="Penn Libraries’ OPenn Manuscript Portal Launched"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
