<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4741579518830671893</id>
   <published>2016-12-20T14:15:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-12-20T14:15:08.796-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Job: Research Fellow: Cataloging Open Access Classics Serials (COACS)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.jobs.london.ac.uk/displayjob.aspx?jobid=665"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Job: Research Fellow: <span>Cataloging Open Access Classics Serials (COACS)</span></span></span></a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span><img alt="University of London" height="63" src="https://www.jobs.london.ac.uk//clientimages/logo.jpg" width="185" /> </span></span></span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span>The Institute of Classical Studies is  running a one-year pilot project Cataloging Open Access Classics Serials  (COACS), in collaboration with the Combined Library of the ICS and of  the Hellenic and Roman Societies, and colleagues in the UK, Germany and  the USA.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><span>INSTITUTE OF CLASSICAL STUDIES</span></strong></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span>The Institute of Classical Studies  (ICS) is the national centre for the promotion and facilitation of  research into Classics and related disciplines. Founded in 1953 by the  University of London and the Hellenic and Roman Societies, it now  provides an internationally renowned research library used by scholars  from universities throughout the world. It also runs seminar series,  conferences and other events aimed at making the results of new research  into Greek and Roman Antiquity available to the widest possible  audience.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><span>The COACS Project&nbsp;</span></strong></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span>The Institute of Classical Studies  (ICS) is running a one-year pilot project, Cataloguing Open Access  Classics Serials (COACS), in collaboration with the Combined Library of  the ICS and of the Hellenic and Roman Societies, and colleagues in the  UK, Germany and the USA. This project will leverage the various sites  that list or index open access (OA) publications, especially journals  and serials in classics and ancient history in the first instance, so as  to produce a resource that subject libraries may use to automatically  catalogue the publications and articles therein.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><span>The Role&nbsp;</span></strong></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span>The Institute of Classical Studies is  seeking an engaged and active Developer to work on the COACS project.  The primary function of this role is to assess several databases of open  access journals in ancient studies and formulate an intermediate  metadata format for recording and sharing the serial and article  records; build code to help with cataloguing and indexing the contents,  and ingest the results into the library catalogue. &nbsp;The role also  requires acting as point of contact for academic project partners and  other libraries working with the data and code we create.</span></span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span>Candidates will required a PhD or other  postgraduate qualification (awarded or close to completion) in  Classical Studies, Digital Humanities, Computer Science, Information and  Library Studies or related discipline or equivalent professional  experience in the library and information sector. You will have an  understanding of the workings of specialist research libraries and a  familiarity with metadata formats used in libraries especially MARC,  MODS, XML, JSON. Candidates will require proficiency in a high-level  programming language (preferably Python, but e.g.. also Javascript, PHP,  Perl) and strong English Language and communication skills.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: 14px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">For an informal discussion on this position, please contact Dr Gabriel Bodard on <strong>gabriel.bodard@sas.ac.uk</strong>. For any recruitment issues or enquiries please contact the recruitment team on ulrecruit@london.ac.uk </span></span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4741579518830671893/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/12/job-research-fellow-cataloging-open.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4741579518830671893"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4741579518830671893"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/12/job-research-fellow-cataloging-open.html"
         title="Job: Research Fellow: Cataloging Open Access Classics Serials (COACS)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
