<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6525455210634920349</id>
   <published>2014-12-15T09:01:00.003-05:00</published>
   <updated>2014-12-15T09:01:54.231-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">News from the Freer|Sackler: Entire collection in a digital asset management system</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://bento.si.edu/from-the-collections/open-fs-digital-zero/" target="_blank">Open F|S: Digital Zero</a><br />            <div class="entry-content">   <div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_8277" style="width: 610px;"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><a href="http://bento.si.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/DZ_01_lg.jpg"><img alt="Composite of 700 images from the Freer Ramayana." class="size-large wp-image-8277" height="98" src="http://bento.si.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/DZ_01_lg-1024x337.jpg" width="200" /></a></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="wp-caption-text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Composite of 700 images from the Freer Ramayana.</span></div></blockquote></div><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>Courtney O’Callaghan is chief digital officer at&nbsp;the&nbsp;Freer|Sackler.</em></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">We’ve reached an important milestone at the Freer|Sackler, an effort  we’re calling Digital Zero. As of this writing, we’ve become the first  Smithsonian museums to digitize their&nbsp;collections. This is a great  opportunity for scholars and researchers as well as our everyday virtual  visitors to have 24/7 access to our works of art.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">What exactly is Digital Zero? For the Freer|Sackler, it means that  we’ve photographed and uploaded our entire collection into a digital  asset management system—more than&nbsp;40,000 objects and almost twice as  many images,&nbsp;from Whistler’s <em><a href="http://www.asia.si.edu/exhibitions/current/PeacockRoom.asp" target="_blank" title="Peacock Room">Peacock Room</a></em> to the tiniest unnamed ceramic sherd. We have examined the rights  information on every object and marked them appropriately. We have  reviewed records, both complete and incomplete, and deemed them  acceptable to make public.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">On January 1, 2015, we will finally share all of our objects and  accompanying data with the public. We will make available&nbsp;40,000+  works&nbsp;as high-resolution images with (often) detailed metadata,  available for <a href="http://www.si.edu/content/pdf/about/sd/SD609.pdf" target="_blank">non-commercial use</a> by anyone.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Digital Zero gives us the freedom to begin the rapid prototyping of  digital offerings. It allows&nbsp;us to focus on how our visitors want to  interact with our collection. And it enables our creative allies to  peruse our objects and form&nbsp;their own endlessly variable takes on the  Freer|Sackler legacy.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">But this&nbsp;is simply the base from which we begin our digital journey.  As our curators and their collaborators discover new insights, new  connections, and new interpretations of our storied holdings, we must  acknowledge&nbsp;the fact that our work is on shifting sands. Our  understanding of our own collection continually evolves and changes.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">We hope that by releasing this information, we will encourage others  to join our journey of discovery and help us fill in the gaps, share  stories, and think of new ways to envision and enliven these objects. As  we move from the idea of museums as spaces for the static delivery of a  monolithic point of view into ones&nbsp;where our objects inspire communal  storytelling, and where we share&nbsp;diverse perspectives that are alive and  changing, we will be able to engage our visitors in ways that we cannot  yet imagine.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">This is only the first phase. If you are interested in being part of our adventure, email us at <a href="mailto:openfs@si.edu" target="_blank">openfs@si.edu</a> and we will include you in our plans.</span><br /> <div class="wb_fb_bottom"> </div></blockquote><div class="wb_fb_comment"><br /></div></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6525455210634920349/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/12/news-from-freersackler-entire.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6525455210634920349"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6525455210634920349"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/12/news-from-freersackler-entire.html"
         title="News from the Freer|Sackler: Entire collection in a digital asset management system"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
