<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6098055993434963245</id>
   <published>2015-03-13T13:00:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-03-13T13:03:39.579-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">A new feature to the onomastic database of Trismegistos People: Network</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;<span><span class="title"><span><span>Have you taken the <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/02/ancient-world-online-user-survey.html">AWOL User Survey</a>?</span></span></span></span></span></div><br /><a href="http://www.trismegistos.org/ref/about_networks.php">A new feature to the onomastic database of Trismegistos People: Network</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.trismegistos.org/img/tm_logo_web2.png" class="transparent" src="http://www.trismegistos.org/img/tm_logo_web2.png" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">An onomastic network on the basis of genealogical relations&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Networks are ways to map connections between elements, in this case  names. Each name is represented by a node (the dots), and each  connection is shown as an edge (or link or tie: the lines between the  dots).</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />The nature of the connection can be chosen freely. In this network there  is a link between name A and name B if a person with name A chose name B  for his or her son or daughter. If more people with name A have opted  for name B, the link will be tighter (and the line visualising it  thicker). The networks of the more popular names resemble 'spaghetti  monsters', as they are connected with many other names. To see where the  name itself is, hover over the transcription in the information pane to  the right of the window.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />There are many network measures to describe the features of the network  as a whole, as well as those of individual nodes and ties: betweenness  centrality, Eigenvector, density, modularity, ... Here we have limited  the information to degree centrality, which is how many other names a  name is connected to. Since the network is directed (meaning that there  is a direction from parent to child), we distinguish between out-degree  (how many different names are chosen by parents with that name) and  in-degree (how many different names are attested for the parents of  children with that name).<br />E.g. When the name <a href="http://www.trismegistos.org/name/1397">Thotortaios</a> has a degree of 184, this means he occurs in 184 different parent -  child pairs. The out-degree of 85 means that Thotortaios is the father's  name of children with 85 different names. The name's in-degree of 99  implies that 99 different fathers' or mothers' names are attested.&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The names are coloured according to their linguistic origin, as follows:</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="indent">Blue = Egyptian<br />Green = Greek<br />Yellow = hybrid (combining elements from two or more languages and traditions)<br />Orange = Latin<br />Turquoise = Semitic<br />Pink = Other (e.g. Macedonian, Thracian, Gallic, ...)<br />Grey = Unknown</span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="indent"><br /></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In principle the shape of the network is irrelevant: as long as nodes  are connected, they can be placed anywhere. But as humans have  difficulty seeing the 69,860 edges between the 17,182 nodes (names in  this case), programs like <a href="http://gephi.github.io/">Gephi</a>  can adapt the visual representation of the network according to specific  layout algoritms. In this case we have used 'ForceAtlas 2". <a href="http://www.trismegistos.org/img/names%20new.mp4">The 47-second video below shows </a>this process, which in fact took the MacBook  Air over 22 minutes. </span></blockquote><hr />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6098055993434963245/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/03/a-new-feature-to-onomastic-database-of.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6098055993434963245"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6098055993434963245"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/03/a-new-feature-to-onomastic-database-of.html"
         title="A new feature to the onomastic database of Trismegistos People: Network"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
