<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-756578398383734158</id>
    <published>2014-12-02T07:44:00.000-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-12-02T07:44:52.375-05:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Latin"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Pedagogy"/>
    <title type="text">Sequential Latin</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: x-small;"><a
      href="http://sequentiallatin.wordpress.com/">Sequential Latin</a> </span><br
      /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Sequential Latin
      is a proj<span class="text_exposed_show">ect that is in the very early stages of
      development. The main impetus of this project is to create a free online Latin language course,
      an accompanying yet separate Latin web-comic, and a rich Latin language and Classics
      community.</span></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size:
      x-small;">The Course:</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size:
      x-small;">The course will be self-paced and designed for the absolute beginner. It will
      focus specifically on developing an ability to read Latin, though spoken and written Latin will
      also be crucial elements. The methodology employed will immerse the reader in lots of Latin
      text (“synthetic”, edited and authentic), but will also provide a thorough understanding of
      grammatical and syntactical concepts, as well as general down-to-earth reading practices,
      seeking to provide a broad but flexible set of skills for students to draw upon when reading
      Latin. Included in this skill-set will be cultural context, as the course also aims to be a
      full-on exploration of Classical Culture and History.</span><br /><br />
      <span style="font-size: x-small;">Images and Comics forms will be used heavily. Indeed,
      this is the inspiration for the project title, as the incomparable Will Eisner called comics
      “Sequential Art.” I do believe that comics is an ideal medium for foreign language studies, as
      it depends heavily upon reader involvement, from all their senses. As comics artist Scott
      Mcloud says, “…human imagination takes two separate images [that is, two separate panels of a
      comic] and transforms them into a single idea. Nothing is seen between the two panels, but
      experience tells you something must be there! …within these panels, we can only convey
      information visually, but between panels, none of our senses are required at all, which is why
      all of our senses are engaged.”*</span><br /><br /> <span
      style="font-size: x-small;">Readers will follow a continuous narrative tale called the
      Cloeliad, which follows the legendary Roman heroine Cloelia on a series of adventures
      throughout the Classical world (she is cursed by Chronos to be transported to different times
      and places on a regular basis…). Many other “synthetic” Latin texts will be written which do
      not tell a continuous tale, but focus on specific topics from the Classical world (for example,
      a conversation between two senators, a roman youth heading to school, and that sort of thing).
      Authentic Latin will also be a large part of the
      lessons.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/756578398383734158/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/12/sequential-latin.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/756578398383734158"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/756578398383734158"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/12/sequential-latin.html"
         title="Sequential Latin"/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
