<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6090657231273372484</id>
   <published>2017-02-07T13:46:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2017-02-07T13:46:36.587-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ARCE"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egyptology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#"
             term="American Research Center in Egypt"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egypt"/>
   <title type="text">HISTORY OF EGYPTOLOGY - A SERIES OF VIDEOS</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://arce.org/main/EducationalResources/HistoryofEgyptology"><span style="color: #7f3701;">HISTORY OF EGYPTOLOGY - A SERIES OF VIDEOS</span></a><br /><span style="color: #046380;"> </span><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Land of the Pharaohs. Birthplace of Christian monasticism. One of the  earliest civilizations. Egypt has been called many things and captured  western imagination for the past 2000 years. This fascination with the  land of the Nile continues today. Tours from around the world flock to  Egypt to explore its antiquities. And iconic images, such as  Tutankhamun's burial mask, can be found everywhere from China to  America.</span><br /><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: #046380;"><strong>Click on the images to watch videos.</strong></span></span><br /><br />  <div class="alignLeft" style="width: 150px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iwfNM8kJJq0&amp;feature=plcp"><img alt="" src="http://arce.org/files/user/page335/1.jpg" style="height: 148px; width: 150px;" /></a> <span style="color: #046380;">Episode 1 - Early Greeks giving gifts to Pharaoh</span></span><br /> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iwfNM8kJJq0&amp;feature=plcp">Episode 1</a>:</strong> This first episode in the series, <em>The History of Egyptology</em>,  explores ancient Egypt's contact with the wider, ancient world, through  trade and cultural exchange with the city-states of Greece and the  Roman Empire. Most of the ancient history that’s taught to us in North  American schools is the history of Greece and Rome; the birth of  democracy and philosophy, wars, centurions, and Caesars. But this  ancient world had nothing on the countries on the other side of the  Mediterranean. To the ancient peoples of Greece and Rome, Egypt was old;  thousands of years older, in fact, than anything they knew. Figuring  out exactly when Greece and Egypt became aware of each other is an  impossible task, but tantalizing images suggest a long history of  interaction.</span><br /><br />  <div class="alignLeft" style="width: 150px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xpAu4-HdYcI"><img alt="" src="http://arce.org/files/user/page335/2a.jpg" style="height: 143px; width: 150px;" /></a> <span style="color: #046380;">Episode 2 - Biblical references ignite interest</span></span><br /> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xpAu4-HdYcI">Episode 2:</a></strong> This second episode continues the story of western interest in Egypt  from the European Middle Ages through the Enlightenment. This episode  touches upon the collapse of the Roman Empire, the spread of  Christianity, the Crusades, Egyptian hieroglyphs, pyramids, temples,  and, of course, Napoleon; all the while charting a continuing desire to  learn more about Egypt. In the fifth century AD, the western half of the  Roman Empire collapsed. Some people still refer to the period that  followed in Europe as the Dark Ages; a time when knowledge and resources  were lost, and people lived in ignorance. In fact, this period was  anything but that. The disintegration of the Roman Empire saw the  different regions it once controlled fragment into their own,  independent units. As the Empire fragmented, these different units held  onto knowledge that had been acquired while it was whole.</span><br /><br />  <div class="alignLeft" style="width: 250px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2FeSXvBhQQQ"><img alt="" src="http://arce.org/files/user/page335/3.jpg" style="height: 151px; width: 250px;" /></a> <span style="color: #046380;">Episode 3 - Napoleon's invasion increased European interest</span></span><br /> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2FeSXvBhQQQ">Episode 3:</a></strong> This third episode continues the story of western interest in Egypt  through the Enlightenment, and into the modern era chronicling Napoleon  Bonaparte's shocking invasion of the Land of the Nile, the early  nineteenth-century's rush of European explorers, the scramble for  antiquities, and the gradual professionalization of Egyptology. A great  deal of popular and academic knowledge on Egypt, including its  antiquities, natural environment, culture and peoples, was available to  Europeans by the end of the 1700s. One of the most famous episodes in  the history of Egyptian exploration, however, occurred on the cusp of  the new century.</span><br /><br />  <div class="alignLeft" style="width: 200px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KqL8Q4R39cU"><img alt="" src="http://arce.org/files/user/page335/4.jpg" style="height: 119px; width: 200px;" /></a> <span style="color: #046380;">Episode 4 - Americans go to Egypt in the late 1700s</span></span><br /> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KqL8Q4R39cU">Episode 4:</a></strong> Next, we shift our focus from Europe to the United Sates.&nbsp; The  increased access to Egypt, and the flurry of research into its ancient  past, mentioned in the last episode only fuelled further western  interest in the Land of the Nile’s history. The increased access to  Egypt, and the flurry of research into its ancient past, mentioned in  the last episode only fueled further western interest in the Land of the  Nile’s history. Exploration into Egypt’s ancient civilization was  viewed as an exploration into the origins of human society itself. Given  both this motivation and the allure that ancient Egypt radiated, it’s  no surprise to find the citizens of a relatively new society interested  in its past.</span><br /><br />  <div class="alignLeft" style="width: 150px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-_5GyUahgc0"><img alt="" src="http://arce.org/files/user/page335/5.jpg" style="height: 170px; width: 150px;" /></a> <span style="color: #046380;">Episode 5 - Tut and Egyptomania</span></span><br /> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-_5GyUahgc0"><span style="color: #046380;"><strong>Episode 5:</strong></span></a> To conclude, we focus on the birth of the American Research Center and  American fascination with all things ancient Egyptian. By the early  1900s, a significant amount of information had been uncovered about the  ancient Land of the Nile. This was partly due to the progress made in  reading hieroglyphs, and partly the result of extensive archaeological  work throughout the country.</span></blockquote><div class="alignLeft" style="width: 150px;"></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6090657231273372484/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2017/02/history-of-egyptology-series-of-videos.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6090657231273372484"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6090657231273372484"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2017/02/history-of-egyptology-series-of-videos.html"
         title="HISTORY OF EGYPTOLOGY - A SERIES OF VIDEOS"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
