<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1262955367985992358</id>
   <published>2016-05-14T06:57:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-05-14T06:57:14.054-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Digital Library"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Bible"/>
   <title type="text">The SBL's International Cooperation Initiative Program (ICI)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">&nbsp;[First posted on AWOL 23 March 2009. Updated 14 May 2016]</span><br /><br /><a href="http://www.sbl-site.org/InternationalCoopInitiative.aspx">The Society of Biblical Literature International Cooperation Initiative (ICI)</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">A strategic vision of the SBL is to “facilitate broad and open  discussion from a variety of perspectives.” But voices from around the  globe are underrepresented, and we are all the poorer for it. In 2007,  to address this issue and facilitate meaningful, international, and  multidirectional scholarly collaboration, the SBL established the  International Cooperation Initiative (ICI). The initiative includes many  projects, more information about which you will find below and in the  quick links to the right. Should you have any questions, please contact  chair of the ICI board <a href="mailto:lcj@sun.ac.za">Louis Jonker</a> or staff liaison <a href="mailto:charles.haws@sbl-site.org">Charlie Haws</a>..&nbsp;</span></div></blockquote>If you visit <a href="http://www.sbl-site.org/publications/onlinebooks.aspx">this page</a> from a domain identifiable as being in a <a href="http://www.sbl-site.org/assets/pdfs/ICIcountries.pdf">qualifying country</a>, you should be able to see links to all the available books.  I would appreciate comment (see below) from those who are able to access these book. This is the current list:<br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>CI Newsletter</strong> (<a href="https://www.sbl-site.org/ICInewsletterArchive.aspx">more info</a>)<br />            Louis C. Jonker, chair of the ICI Board, collects  information about and on behalf of the initiative and distributes it via  email to those interested. Contact <a href="mailto:lcj@sun.ac.za">Louis</a> directly to add your name to the list.&nbsp;</span></blockquote><blockquote>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Online Books</strong> (<a href="https://www.sbl-site.org/publications/onlinebooks.aspx">more info</a>)<br />            This ICI project provides free online PDF files to scholars  and students who may not otherwise have access to these resources. These  resources are available for persons in countries with a per capita GDP  that is substantially lower than the average per capita GDP of the  United States and the European Union. Eligible countries&nbsp;are <a href="https://www.sbl-site.org/assets/pdfs/ICIcountries.pdf" target="_blank">listed here</a>.</span><br />             <span style="font-size: x-small;">Academic presses partnering with SBL Press in this project are&nbsp;<strong>Brown  Judaic Studies, Catholic Biblical Association, Fortress Press, Gorgias  Press, Sheffield Phoenix Press, Westminster John Knox Press&nbsp;</strong>and&nbsp;<strong>Wiley-Blackwell</strong>. SBL thanks these partners for their vision and dedication to fostering biblical scholarship. </span></blockquote><blockquote>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Journal Subscriptions</strong><br />            Institutions located in countries that qualify for the  Online Books also qualify for reduced subscription rates to the <em>Journal of Biblical Literature</em>&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<em>Review of Biblical Literature</em>. With these reduced rates, a print&nbsp;<em>JBL</em>&nbsp;subscription costs $35 plus shipping and a print&nbsp;<em>RBL</em>&nbsp;subscription costs $20 plus shipping. Forms for these reduced rates and free access to recent&nbsp;<em>JBL</em>&nbsp;archives can be found <a href="https://www.sbl-site.org/publications/onlinebooks.aspx">here</a>. </span></blockquote><blockquote>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Open-Access Book Series</strong><br />            Two open-access book series are published through the ICI: <a href="https://www.sbl-site.org/publications/Books_ANEmonographs.aspx">Ancient Near East Monographs</a> (ANEM) and <a href="http://ivbs.sbl-site.org/">International Voices in Biblical Studies</a> (IVBS).</span><br />             <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Teaching Collaboration/Mentoring Program</strong> (<a href="http://www.sbl-site.org/educational/ICITeaching.aspx">more info</a>) </span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">            SBL hosts two databases that allow scholars, students, and  institutions to establish contact and make arrangements for various  types of scholarly exchange. How are SBL members taking advantage of the  ICI Scholarly Exchange program?&nbsp;Kelley N. Coblentz Bautch shares <a href="https://www.sbl-site.org/assets/pdfs/KCB_ICIvideoconferencing.pdf" target="_blank">How Videoconferencing with International Scholars Can Enliven Your Classroom</a> and Jonathan David Lawrence shares how the ICI Scholarly Exchange program provided&nbsp;<a href="https://www.sbl-site.org/assets/pdfs/ICI_FijiFinal.pdf" target="_blank">an opportunity to teach in the South Pacific</a>. </span></blockquote><blockquote>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Liaison Network</strong> (<a href="https://www.sbl-site.org/assets/pdfs/ICI_LiaisonNetworkContacts.pdf">more info</a>)<strong></strong><br />            The goal of the ICI Liaison Network is to establish open  lines of communication that will promote awareness of the resources and  opportunities made available through the ICI to scholars, teachers, and  students and to communicate and develop an awareness of the scholarly  work done in ICI countries. There are liaisons in several countries and  SBL is working to build upon this base and extend the representation to  more areas.&nbsp;</span>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />            The ICI volunteer coordinator is&nbsp;<a href="mailto:tim.langille@gmail.com">Tim Langille</a>.  SBL members in ICI countries who wish to become liaisons or in  countries for which there is already a representative in the Liaison  Network are encouraged to contact Tim to volunteer to further ICI and  its goals. There are opportunities on the local level to coordinate with  the country representatives. All SBL members, regardless of their  country of domicile, are asked to suggest colleagues in ICI countries  who might be willing to participate in this initiative. </span></blockquote><blockquote>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Calendar of Events</strong> (<a href="https://www.sbl-site.org/meetings/events.aspx">more info</a>)<br />            SBL encourages participation in scholarly conferences and  workshops worldwide, including those organized and sponsored independent  of SBL. </span></blockquote><blockquote>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Visa letters for travel to the Annual or International Meetings</strong><br />            In order to facilitate attendance by those in ICI countries at SBL Congresses,&nbsp;<a href="mailto:samantha.spitzner@sbl-site.org">Samantha Spitzner</a>&nbsp;has  been appointed as the SBL visa coordinator. Samantha will advise  members who need visas in order to travel to and participate in the  Annual or International Meetings. She will not prepare applications, but  will be a source of information to aid members in submitting  applications and will provide letters of intent if needed by those  participating in the meeting as presenters or board members. For more  information, please contact Samantha directly. </span></blockquote><blockquote>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>JSTOR Journal Discount Programs</strong> </span>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://about.jstor.org/libraries/african-access-initiative">African Access Initiative</a>:  JSTOR has waived the standard participation fees (the Archive Capital  Fee and the Annual Access Fee) for any not-for-profit institution in a  country on the continent of Africa. </span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">            <a href="http://about.jstor.org/libraries/developing-nations-access-initiative">Developing Nations Access Initiative</a>:  JSTOR has waived or offered reduced participation fees for any academic  or not-for-profit institution in developing countries (and all of  Africa).             </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">.</span><br /><div align="left"></div></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1262955367985992358/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/03/sbls-international-cooperation.html#comment-form"
         title="2 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1262955367985992358"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1262955367985992358"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/03/sbls-international-cooperation.html"
         title="The SBL's International Cooperation Initiative Program (ICI)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
