<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-423167241521559973</id>
   <published>2015-08-29T11:29:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-08-29T11:29:58.666-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Learned Society"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Classics"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="APA"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="USA"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#"
             term="American Philological Association"/>
   <title type="text">New Website of the Society for Classical Studies Launched Today</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://classicalstudies.org/scs-news/launch-new-web-site">Launch of New Web Site</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="https://classicalstudies.org/sites/default/files/logo_scs_main.png" class="transparent" height="82" src="https://classicalstudies.org/sites/default/files/logo_scs_main.png" width="320" />&nbsp;  </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="conflux-sidebar2-scs-row conflux-sidebar2-scs-row-odd conflux-sidebar2-scs-section1 clearfix conflux-row c2grid5 conflux-main"><div class="conflux-sidebar2-scs-row-body conflux-row-body"><div class="conflux-sidebar2-scs-container conflux-container conflux-sidebar2-scs-main-1 panel-panel"><div class="conflux-sidebar2-scs-container-inner conflux-container-inner conflux-sidebar2-scs-main-1-inner panel-panel-inner"><div class="panel-pane pane-page-content"><div class="pane-content"><div class="ds-1col node node-apa-blog node-promoted view-mode-full clearfix"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Thanks to the extraordinary efforts of Information Architect,  Samuel Huskey, and to the programming and web designing skills of  Confluence Corporation, we have launched a new web site with a new URL:&nbsp;  <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/">https://classicalstudies.org/</a>.&nbsp;  Both the site and the URL reflect the Society’s new name and its effort  to be more useful and accessible to both its members and to a wider  audience of people interested in classical antiquity.&nbsp; The site is  easier to navigate and will present more opportunities for featuring and  discussing new work in classics.&nbsp; The site will also include all  Placement Service operations.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">To ensure that the site and our social media outlets are  comprehensive and current, President John Marincola is appointing a new  Communications Committee.&nbsp; Once this Committee begins operations, I will  publish contact information and procedures that members can use to make  suggestions to its members.&nbsp; In the interim, please send comments and  suggestions to me (<a href="mailto:blistein@sas.upenn.edu">blistein@sas.upenn.edu</a>).</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Streamlined Access for SCS Members</b></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">As before, much of the information on the SCS web site will be  available to any visitor.&nbsp; However, the new site will make it easier for  members to become Placement Service candidates and subscribers at no  charge and to enjoy other benefits exclusive to members because it will  permit them to use a single set of credentials for all functions on the  SCS web site <u>and</u> for all SCS-related activities on the Johns  Hopkins University Press (JHUP) web site.&nbsp; Members no longer need to  create multiple online accounts for SCS.&nbsp; Accounts already established  or to be established at the JHUP web site will be the only credentials  you need.</span><br /><br /><div style="margin-left: .5in;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Members with Existing Accounts at JHUP</b>.&nbsp;  If you have ever created an account on the JHUP web site, for example,  to pay your dues via credit card or to view our directory of members,  the username and password associated with that account will now give you  access to the SCS web site as well.&nbsp; If you need a reminder of either  your <a href="https://scs.press.jhu.edu/membership/forgot-username">username</a> or <a href="https://scs.press.jhu.edu/membership/forgot-password">password</a> on the JHUP web site, click on the relevant link to request it.&nbsp;</span><br /></div><div style="margin-left: .5in;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Members Needing to Create an Account at JHUP</b>.&nbsp; <a href="https://scs.press.jhu.edu/cgi-bin/create_login.cgi">Follow this link to create an online account</a>.&nbsp;  You will need both the e-mail address you gave to Johns Hopkins when  you paid your dues and your member number.&nbsp; If you need a reminder of  your member number, <a href="https://scs.press.jhu.edu/cgi-bin/member_number_lookup.cgi">click here</a>.&nbsp;</span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you need further assistance from staff at Johns Hopkins, they can be reached in the following ways:</span><br /><ul><li>  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><u>Telephone</u>:&nbsp; 800-548-1784 (U.S. and Canada only);&nbsp; 410-516-6987 (other countries)</span></li><li>  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><u>FAX</u>:&nbsp; 410-516-3866</span></li><li>  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><u>E-mail</u>:&nbsp; <a href="mailto:jrnlcirc@press.jhu.edu">mailto:jrnlcirc@press.jhu.edu</a></span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you call JHUP and reach an answering machine, be sure to  leave a message that includes a suggested time to call you back.&nbsp; This  will enable staff to follow up with you as soon as they can.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Site Navigation</b></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Two menus appear at the top of every page on the site.&nbsp; In the higher  of the two, note especially the links for member log-in and for “SCS  News”.&nbsp; The former gives members access to the portions of the site that  are set aside for them, and the latter (as the APA Blog did before)  contains announcements of Society activities and other information for  anyone interested in classics.&nbsp; Clicking on SCS News will generate a  list of the most recent announcements of all kinds, but the drop-down  menu and search box above the first item on the list permit the user to  obtain a specific range of entries.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The second menu, in white type on a blue background, gives links to  the most commonly used functions on our site.&nbsp; Each of these links  contains a drop-down menu leading to a specific subtopic.&nbsp; Clicking on  the white text will also take the user to an introductory page where the  links in the drop-down menu appear on the right hand side of the  screen.&nbsp; The menu on the right appears on many related interior pages as  well.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Below the image on the main page only are four links to “landing  pages”.&nbsp; On these four pages we have attempted to place links to the  information that we think will be most useful for our four overlapping  constituencies:&nbsp; members, professional classicists, classics students,  and enthusiasts for classics. &nbsp;For that reason some links appear on more  than one landing page.&nbsp; Underneath these four links are an additional  link for the annual meeting, the most recent letter from the President,  and a number of other useful links for the field.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Further down the main page, we have also added a Member Spotlight  that will feature information about a new member every few weeks.&nbsp; To  begin this new feature we have asked (first) Sara Forsdyke and (in a few  weeks) Matt Roller, both of whom rotated off the Board last January as  at-large Directors, to write about their service to the Society.&nbsp;  Members with suggestions for this new feature should write to me (<a href="mailto:blistein@sas.upenn.edu">blistein@sas.upenn.edu</a>) for transmission to the new Communications Committee.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Members Only Page</b></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Members Only page contains links to the Directory of Members, to <i>TAPA </i>online,  and to discounts on various publications and resources including our  GreekKeys software.&nbsp; To reach that page, first log in to the SCS web  site, and then click on the drop-down menu under “Membership” or click  on “Membership” itself.&nbsp; You will then see a link labeled “For Members  Only”.&nbsp; Note that this link will not appear unless you are logged in.&nbsp;  Finally, if the resource you are seeking is on the <a href="https://scs.press.jhu.edu/membership/join">Johns Hopkins site</a> rather than our own (the Directory and <i>TAPA</i> are examples), you will need to enter your membership credentials again.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Placement Service</b></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The 2015-2016 Placement Service is now open.&nbsp; Before registering for  the service, please read the information below about new features this  year.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">As President Marincola <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/scs-news/presidents-letter-travel-awards-and-placement-fees">announced in his most recent letter</a>,  SCS members may enroll as candidates or subscribers to the Placement  Service at no charge for 2015-2016.&nbsp; The Finance Committee and Board of  Directors took this step enthusiastically as part of the Society’s  efforts to provide as much assistance as possible to those members who  have the least resources.&nbsp; If you register, note that “candidates” have  access to the full range of services provided to job-seekers, including  the scheduling of interviews at the annual meeting.&nbsp; We offer  “subscriber” status to members who are not on the job market themselves  but who want to monitor that market, usually because they are advising  candidates in some capacity.&nbsp; Nonmembers can again purchase either  service for $55.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Candidates and subscribers should note carefully the information  above about verifying membership before registering for the Service.&nbsp; If  you are not yet a member of the Society or if your dues are not  current, the fastest way to gain access to a free subscription is <a href="https://scs.press.jhu.edu/membership/join">to pay dues online</a>, and then log in to the Placement Service using the credentials you create during the payment.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In part to recover some of the revenue that will be lost by offering  candidates and subscriber services to members at no charge, the Society  has increased the fees for institutions for the first time in several  years.&nbsp; Institutions purchasing Comprehensive Service (which includes  facilities for conducting interviews at the annual meeting) will pay  $475.&nbsp; The fee for institutions simply placing an advertisement will be  $200 until January 9 and $175 thereafter.&nbsp; If you are purchasing an  institutional service, note that individual or departmental membership  is <b>not</b> required, and that membership brings no reduction in institutional fees.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you have used the Service in previous years, you know that  candidates, subscribers, and comprehensive institutions used to receive  an e-mail each night if we had approved any new job listings that day.&nbsp;  The e-mail list serve will operate in a slightly different manner this  year.&nbsp; A day or two after you register for the Service, you will receive  an e-mail confirming your addition to the Placement list serve.&nbsp; While  your e-mail subscription will not be active immediately, you will have  access to all published jobs by visiting the Placement Service pages  once you are logged in and clicking on a link entitled “Recent  Advertisements (Not Public)”.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In addition, once your e-mail subscription is active, you will  receive an e-mail immediately after each new listing is approved.&nbsp; These  separate individual e-mails will replace the daily summary of jobs  posted sent in previous years.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">To register for the 2015-2016 Service, go to <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/">classicalstudies.org</a> and then click on “Placement Service” in the menu with the blue  background.&nbsp; Scroll down to find either Services for Candidates and  Subscribers or Services for Institutions, and click on the appropriate  link.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Over the last two weeks, we published new job advertisements for  2015-2016 on last year’s Placement site.&nbsp; Now that that site is offline,  <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/scs-news/interim-listing-positions-advertised-july-and-august-2015">I have posted those listings again in SCS News</a> and will continue to make them available there for about a week.&nbsp; We  ask that the institutions posting those advertisements now register for  the Service and post them <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/placement-service">in the new online system</a>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Conclusion</b></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">I hope you will enjoy the new site.&nbsp; Please send comments and reports of broken links to me (<a href="mailto:blistein@sas.upenn.edu">blistein@sas.upenn.edu</a>).</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Adam D. Blistein</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Executive Director</span></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">- See more at: https://classicalstudies.org/scs-news/launch-new-web-site#sthash.NswUEis0.dpuf </span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/423167241521559973/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/08/new-website-of-society-for-classical.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/423167241521559973"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/423167241521559973"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/08/new-website-of-society-for-classical.html"
         title="New Website of the Society for Classical Studies Launched Today"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
