<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4290575945391258068</id>
   <published>2015-09-21T18:02:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-09-21T18:02:13.709-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Late Antiquity"/>
   <title type="text">Late Antiquity and the New Humanities: An Open Forum</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/late-antiquity-and-the-new-humanities-an-open-forum/">Late Antiquity and the New Humanities: An Open Forum</a><br /><a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/">The <em>Marginalia Review of Books</em></a> <br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">&nbsp;<img alt="http://marginalia.wpengine.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/marginalia-larb.jpg" height="44" src="http://marginalia.wpengine.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/marginalia-larb.jpg" width="320" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">                            <br /><div id="main">                 <div class="post-heading">                 <span class="heading-date">September 16, 2015</span>          </div><div class="post-entry">           <div class="shareaholic-canvas shareaholic-ui shareaholic-resolved-canvas ng-scope" data-app-id="6744048" data-app="share_buttons" data-link="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/late-antiquity-and-the-new-humanities-an-open-forum/" data-summary="" data-title="Late Antiquity and the New Humanities: An Open Forum" id="shr_canvas2"><div class="ng-scope">     <div class="shareaholic-share-buttons-container shareaholic-ui flat round mini    right-align" style="top: 15%;">    <div class="shareaholic-share-buttons-wrapper shareaholic-ui">                 </div></div></div></div></div></div><div class="shareaholic-canvas shareaholic-ui shareaholic-resolved-canvas ng-scope" data-app-id="6744048" data-app="share_buttons" data-link="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/late-antiquity-and-the-new-humanities-an-open-forum/" data-summary="" data-title="Late Antiquity and the New Humanities: An Open Forum" id="shr_canvas2"><div class="ng-scope"><div class="shareaholic-share-buttons-container shareaholic-ui flat round mini    right-align" style="top: 15%;"><div class="shareaholic-share-buttons-wrapper shareaholic-ui">     </div></div></div></div><h2 class="Normal1" style="line-height: normal;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/contributing-editors/ellen-muehlberger/">Ellen Muehlberger</a>&nbsp;introduces the forum on Late Antiquity and the New Humanities</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The</span> five essays in this forum developed from remarks in a panel  organized by Heidi Marx-Wolf (University of Manitoba) at the May 2015  International Congress on Medieval Studies in Kalamazoo titled “Late  Antiquity and the New Humanities.” The panel reflected on the field of  “late antiquity” as a whole: we gauged the changes in scholarship on  late antiquity in the context of the shifts taking place in the  humanities overall. What new questions were scholars asking, and what  new questions could they answer? </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">We advertised widely the call for panelists, and we certainly got a  wide range of responses. The essays you read here assess “late  antiquity” from such divergent viewpoints that it is hard to  characterize them as a group. Catherine Chin’s fantastical essay speaks  of the effects of style on the representation of the past, and then  tries out some of the best tools available in her retelling of a  well-known historical event. Mira Balberg astutely places her finger on a  problem that has troubled the study of late antiquity as well as the  study of the middle ages, namely, that these fields almost by definition  exclude Jewish materials. She then calls scholars to go beyond the easy  first step (identifying late ancient Jewish texts that are familiar  because they are similar to other late ancient materials) and to let the  truly different texts change what we think of when we speak of “late  antiquity.” Anthony Kaldellis describes the distinct emphasis that  scholars of late antiquity place on concepts like identity and cultural  negotiation, then asks his readers to consider what may be lost by such a  methodology. Philip Rousseau speaks of the twists and turns, over the  last several decades, in the organization and self-understanding of the  field of “late antiquity” and points to an emerging paradigm that might  replace it: the study of the first millennium. My own essay describes a  structural limitation in the field of late antiquity, especially in  research on early Christianity, namely, our reliance on the author as a  category of analysis and organization...</blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><br /><div class="Normal1" style="line-height: normal; text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">※</span></div><div class="Normal1" style="line-height: normal; text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Chaterine Chin" class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-7882" height="150" src="http://14chrg47qoru3d1nk6pwnf5v.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Chaterine-Chin-150x150.jpg" width="150" /></span></div><div class="Normal1" style="line-height: normal; text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/pro-nobis-fabula-narratur-late-antiquity-as-art-and-fantasy-by-catherine-m-chin">Catherine M. Chin,</a> “<em>Pro nobis fabula narratur</em>: Late Antiquity as Art and Fantasy”</span></div><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">What might such non-argumentative production look like?  Here I would like to move into a different mode, with an example of what  I think is somatically and intellectually engaged storytelling that  does not rely on stereotypical academic argumentation. The story I will  tell is famous: <a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=_qQsA7gE6UoC&amp;printsec=frontcover#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false">Ambrose</a>, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00PXGNQ7K/marginalia0c-20/">Symmachus</a>,  and the altar of Victory. I am interested in how words can suggest the  density of aesthetic, somatic, and temporal experience that the story of  the altar evokes. This is how such a story might be told.</span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">※</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="balberg_2015" class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-7888" height="150" src="http://14chrg47qoru3d1nk6pwnf5v.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/balberg_2015-150x150.jpg" width="150" /></span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/late-ancient-judaism-beyond-border-lines-by-mira-balberg/">Mira Balberg</a>, “Late Ancient Judaism: Beyond Border Lines”</span></div><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The integration of late ancient Jewish literature into  our library, then, forces us to rethink some of the fundamental  categories and distinctions — of language, authorship, and genre —  through which we approach the period of late antiquity and its texts.  This in itself is a worthwhile and desired development: as more and more  scholars now contend, these categories and distinctions&nbsp;<em>need&nbsp;</em>to  be rethought, challenged, and expanded — not only to include materials  beyond the Greek-Roman canon but also to include a plethora of  uncategorized materials that defy clear pigeon-holing (literary,  religious, doctrinal or other), like magical texts, apocalyptic visions,  dedicatory inscriptions, collections of sayings, etc.</span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">※</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="kaldellis.1" class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-7894" height="150" src="http://14chrg47qoru3d1nk6pwnf5v.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/kaldellis.1-150x150.jpg" width="150" /></span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/late-antiquity-dissolves-by-anthony-kaldellis/">Anthony Kaldellis</a>, “Late Antiquity Dissolves”</span></div><blockquote><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The field, I claimed above, was defined as  much by methodology as by time and place, and I will explain that claim  below. But the methodology goes hand-in-hand with a set of topics too.  The study of the later Roman Empire used to be dominated by the  reconstruction of political events and institutions on the one hand and  the disembodied (“view from nowhere”) study of theology on the other.  With the making of late antiquity, this dead-end combination gave way to  a set of more theoretically challenging “soft” topics such as holiness,  authorship, gender, sexuality, group identity, worship, social  relations, and private life. These were taken to be constructed and  changing social forms that were — to use the field’s favorite terms of  art — “negotiated” through “discourse,” and mostly Christian discourse  at that.</span></div></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">※</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="rousseau2" class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-7900" height="150" src="http://14chrg47qoru3d1nk6pwnf5v.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/rousseau2-150x150.jpg" width="150" /></span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/can-late-antiquity-be-saved-by-philip-rousseau/">Philip Rousseau</a>, “Can ‘Late Antiquity’ Be Saved?”</span></div><blockquote><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">I confess I’ve sometimes wondered whether  we shouldn’t abandon the term “late antiquity.” I’m equally ready to  admit it can’t be a serious suggestion. There does remain, even so, a  confusing doubt in my mind as to what “late antiquity” really means. I  agree with my colleagues who suggest it may have something to do with  differing senses of period. Medieval and Byzantine historians, and even  Islamicists, have been at times disturbed by an apparent late antique  encroachment upon their supposed territory; and the situation has been  exacerbated more recently by a growing attachment to the “early’” Middle  Ages, “early” Byzantium and “early” Islam, the earliness of which is  often difficult to limit or define.</span></div></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">※</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Ellen Muehlberger" class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-7013" height="150" src="http://14chrg47qoru3d1nk6pwnf5v.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/IMG_2644-150x150.jpg" width="150" /></span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/on-authors-fathers-and-holy-men-by-ellen-muehlberger">Ellen Muehlberger</a>, “On Authors, Fathers, and Holy Men”</span></div><blockquote><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">What this long-term, informal archival  process has given us is a collection, not of evidence, but of authors.  That is, our archive represents to us a selection of the fraction of the  people from the past who happened to be in a social position to produce  texts and to have their names permanently associated with what they  produced. Practically speaking, we are already lacking any way to  understand an overwhelming amount of late ancient Christianity: the  ideas, motivations, habits, creative products, and innovations of those  who were not authors are just not available to us.</span></div></blockquote></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4290575945391258068/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/09/late-antiquity-and-new-humanities-open.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4290575945391258068"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4290575945391258068"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/09/late-antiquity-and-new-humanities-open.html"
         title="Late Antiquity and the New Humanities: An Open Forum"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
