<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4294266886051261544</id>
   <published>2016-08-16T21:45:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-08-16T21:47:19.121-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text"> Rediscovering Scholarly Newsletters: A Challenge </title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="post-title entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-weight: normal;">Back in 2009, Andrew Reinhard, then at <a href="http://www.bolchazy.com/">Bolchazy-Carducci Publishers, Inc.</a>&nbsp; serialized the republication online of&nbsp; <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/02/pompeiiana-newsletter-online-open.html">The Pompeiiana Newsletter:</a></span></span></span></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Pompeiiana Newsletter was created and edited by Bernard Barcio and  ran from 1974 through 2003. Pompeiiana offered a place for Latin  students to publish comics, stories, games, and articles, and was a  beloved resource for Latin teachers. In 2008, Barcio granted  Bolchazy-Carducci Publishers the rights for all of Pompeiiana. This blog  will make all 229 issues freely available to Latin teachers, students,  and others interested in Classics, one issue per day. </span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size: small;">In August 2013, the <a href="https://medievalsaiproject.wordpress.com/">Medieval Sai Project: The Greek Norwegian Archaeological Mission to Sudan</a> began the serialized republication of the 22 issues of <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/08/open-access-journal-nubian-letters.html"><i>Nubian Letters</i></a> published between 1983 and 1994:</span><br /></span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/08/open-access-journal-nubian-letters.html"><i>Nubian Letters</i></a> in an  independent biannual bulletin for Nubian history and archaeology,  published under the auspices of the International Society for Nubian  Studies and the Department of Early Christian Art at the University of  Leiden, the Netherlands.<br /><br />Edited by Elizabeth de Ranitz and Karel Inemmée.</span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size: small;">I'm really pleased to see these newsletters in general circulation. They  represent a form of semi-formal scholarly communication which was common in the  second half of the 20th century (and earlier), but which was never  properly collected by libraries. Even those which have made the leap to  digital media (and you can find many be searching the keyword  "newsletter" in <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/">AWOL</a>),  remain mostly poorly curated or uncollected in libraries. They are  nevertheless an extraordinarily important resource for the history of  the disciplines they cover and the institutions and projects they  represent.<br /><br />In the Summer of 2014<span style="background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: &quot;georgia&quot; , serif; line-height: 20px;">&nbsp;Oriental Institute Research Archivist, Bibliographer Foy Scalf, began to scan the hard copies of the <i>Oriental Institute Staff Newsletter</i> (63 issues&nbsp;</span><span style="background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: &quot;georgia&quot; , serif; line-height: 20px;">edited by me which appeared between February 1998 and March 2005)</span><span style="background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: &quot;georgia&quot; , serif; line-height: 20px;">&nbsp;and  upon discovering that they were incomplete, urged me to try to recover  the lost files from a ten year old laptop. As a consequence we now have a  complete set available. So a small piece of Oriental Institute  microhistory is now recovered and preserved. They are available at</span><span style="background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: &quot;georgia&quot; , serif; line-height: 20px;">&nbsp;<span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/04/open-access-journal-oriental-institute.html" style="color: #999999; text-decoration: none;"><i>Oriental Institute Staff Newsletter</i></a></span>, and further information is at the <a href="http://oihistory.blogspot.com/2009/02/oi-staff-newsletter.html">OI History Blog</a>.</span></span></span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: &quot;georgia&quot; , serif; line-height: 20px;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Beginning in February 1998, with the encouragement and support of Gene Gragg  who was then Director of the Oriental Institute, I compiled, edited and  distributed by email an internal newsletter for the staff of the  Oriental Institute.  It chronicled the activities of the departments of  the OI, and of individual scholars and senior students at the OI.  It  was distributed widely in the University of Chicago community by means  of a listhost mailing list, but its archive was not publicly available.&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /><span style="font-size: small;">Many scholars keep files of these things, which they get by virtue of  memberships in societies or organization, or association with projects,  and in other ways. Likewise, many projects, association, and societies  hold files of them in their archives, or in their archives of their  successor or sponsoring institutions. If you have a files of one of  these inaccessible newsletters, or know of one, I challenge you to  follow in the footsteps of <i><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/02/pompeiiana-newsletter-online-open.html">The Pompeiiana Newsletter</a>,</i><i> </i><i><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/08/open-access-journal-nubian-letters.html"><i>Nubian Letters</i></a>, and </i></span></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size: small;"><i><u><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="background-color: white; line-height: 20px;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/04/open-access-journal-oriental-institute.html" style="text-decoration: none;"><i>The Oriental Institute Staff Newsletter</i></a></span></span></u> </i>and make it available<i> </i>to your colleagues and the world at large.<i> </i>It is simple<i> </i>to  set up a blog at Blogger, Wordpress or Tumblr (or one of many other comparable tools), to scan an issue a day, and post them online. Please make sure  that you get, or make a good faith effort to get, permission from the  organization or person who published the newsletter in the first place.<i> </i>&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size: small;">Since then a couple of additional newsletters have emerged: </span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: small;">This past year I scanned and posted <i><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/open-access-journal-pirradazis-bulletin.html">Pirradazi<span class="st">š: Bulletin of Achaemenian Studies</span></a></i> I produced in the 1990s<i>.</i></span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Pirradazi<span class="st">š (Pirradazish) [</span><span class="st"><a href="http://www.worldcat.org/title/pirradazis-newsletter-of-achaemenian-studies/oclc/863381899">OCLC Number:          863381899</a>] is a newsletter produced by Charles E. Jones at the Oriental Institute Chicago. Eight issues appeared between 1990 and 1994.</span></span></span></blockquote><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span></span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Pirradaziš seeks to gather information, primarily bibliographical, which relates to the study of the Achaemenid Persian empire, as well as relevant material on the periods immediately preceding and following it.  Each issue will cover the material seen by the editor during the six months (more or less) prior to the date of issue. </span></span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i></i></span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /><span style="font-size: small;">Also in 2015, colleagues at the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World scanned and made available copies of the orphaned<i> </i></span></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size: small;"><i><a class="external-link" href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/ancientworld/search/?q=newsletter&amp;page=1" target="_self" title="">Circle of&nbsp; Inner Asian Art and Archaeology Newsletter</a></i> as a component of the relaunched <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/10/ancient-world-digital-library.html">Ancient World Digital Library</a>. </span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size: small;">Please let me know if you can participate, and what and where you efforts appear so I can include it in AWOL's <span class="brödtext"><span class="titol"><span class="text"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies.</a></span></span></span><br /><br /></span></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="brödtext"><span class="titol"><span class="text"><span style="font-size: small;">And I'll happily offer advice and assistance in how to go about doing it If you'd rather have me do it, and can supply the hard copy, I'll gladly make that happen as well.</span></span></span></span></span>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4294266886051261544/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/08/rediscovering-scholarly-newsletters.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4294266886051261544"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4294266886051261544"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/08/rediscovering-scholarly-newsletters.html"
         title=" Rediscovering Scholarly Newsletters: A Challenge "/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
