<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7654401881204325730</id>
   <published>2015-03-07T09:30:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-03-07T18:13:48.240-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Language. Concordance"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greek"/>
   <title type="text">CLAROS. Concordancia de Inscripciones griegas</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;<span class="title">Have you taken the <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/02/ancient-world-online-user-survey.html">AWOL User Survey</a>?</span></span></div><br /><a href="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/cnc/cnc.htm">CLAROS. Concordancia de Inscripciones griegas</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/logodge1.gif" src="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/logodge1.gif" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The editors of the Diccionario Griego-Español (DGE) are pleased to announce the new release of CLAROS, the online concordance of Greek inscriptions, that can be accessed at &lt;<a href="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/cnc/cnc.htm">http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/cnc/cnc.htm</a>&gt;.<br /><br />CLAROS is a part of the DGE project. It is an electronic database containing the successive publications of epigraphical Greek texts re-edited during the last 125 years (and before). Users of CLAROS can consult the data relative to the edition of Greek inscriptions (name and date of publication, and the editor's name; but not the epigraphic text itself). More interestingly, users can retrieve the concordance BETWEEN inscriptions, that is, the different editions of the same inscription. In addition to the bibliographical reference to the main editions of an epigraphical text, CLAROS contains reference to numerous corpora of translations of the same Greek texts.<br /><br />This new release of CLAROS contains more than 605,000 concordances between inscriptions published (in text or translation) in about 6,300 publications. This data was collected through the inspection of about 1000 epigraphical collections (including SEG and Bulletin Epigraphique). The main contribution of this upgrade, apart from 150.000 new concordances, is the introduction of almost 180.000 external links that connect the results of bibliographical searches with digital versions of publications. There are three kinds of links, each of them in a different color:<br /><br />The red links connect with PDF papers in subscription platforms, which require some kind of payment for consulting complete papers, like JStor or Periodicals Archive Online.<br /><br />The green links connect with hard copies (journals or books) in PDF or JPG format that may be consulted without restrictions in all kinds of platforms or repositories (École Française d'Athènes, Köln Universität, Gallica, Universitätsbibliothek Heidelberg, Persée, Revues.org, Internet Archive, etc.).<br /><br />The blue links connect with digital editions of inscriptions, including both original editions (The Princeton Project on the Inscriptions of Anatolia in Searchable Greek Inscriptions, Inscriptions of Aphrodisias Project, Inscriptions of Israel / Palestine, etc.) and digital versions of corpora simultaneously or previously published (Inscriptiones Graecae, Monumenta Asiae Minoris Antiqua XI, Inscriptions of Roman Tripolitania, etc.).<br /><br />The database can be consulted in Spanish, French and English at<br />&lt;<a href="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/cnc/cnc.htm">http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/cnc/cnc.htm</a>&gt; Here you can learn more about the editions used, the criteria for the inclusion in the data base, and a full list of the bibliographical abbreviations. The editors of CLAROS would appreciate any suggestion for the improvement and enlargement of the data base. Please, send your letters to<br />juan.rodriguez@cchs.csic.es.&nbsp; </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><br /><dd><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: x-small;">Quienes trabajan en epigrafía griega saben lo laborioso que resulta    a veces rastrear la bibliografía generada por una inscripción    o una serie concreta de inscripciones a lo largo de los años. El propósito    de la base de datos CLAROS es facilitar la tarea de localizar nuevas ediciones    de inscripciones griegas aparecidas a lo largo del último siglo. Está    pensada para servir de ayuda tanto a los especialistas en epigrafía griega    como a los historiadores, lingüistas y filólogos en general, menos    habituados que aquellos a desenvolverse en la jungla bibliográfica en    que se ha convertido esta disciplina.<br />  <br /></span></dd><dd><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: x-small;">El origen de esta base de datos se remonta al año 1990, cuando una    parte del equipo del <i>DGE</i> empezó a recoger en una versión previa    bajo entorno MSDOS este tipo de información con el fin de servir de ayuda    en la tarea de revisión del material epigráfico incluido en el    diccionario. Su filosofía es la misma que la de otras secciones de esta    página web: poner a disposición de los investigadores información    de uso interno del <i>DGE</i> que difícilmente vería la luz de    otro modo.<br />  <br /></span></dd><dd><span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: x-small;">Esta Base de Datos en modo alguno pretende ser exhaustiva, ni aspira a recoger    todas las ediciones de cada inscripción citada. Es sencillamente una    suma de las concordancias que aparecen al final de numerosas colecciones epigráficas    publicadas en los últimos cien años, más o menos. A ello    se añade un cierto número de concordancias preparadas por los autores    del <i>Supplementum Epigraphicum Graecum</i> para volúmenes que carecían    de ella o la tenían incompleta y, por último,    un buen número de concordancias realizadas por nosotros directamente    para volúmenes que igualmente carecían de ella. Entre estos últimos pueden citarse por ejemplo colecciones como    <i>GVI</i>, <i>ICr</i>., <i>Hell</i>., <i>IGR</i>, <i>INomima</i>, <i>ISE</i>,    <i>ISic.MG</i>, <i>RDGE</i>, <i>Schwyzer</i> o <i>Sokolowski</i>...</span></dd></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img src="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/buttn15c.gif" height="6" width="6" /> <a href="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/cnc/cnc.htm" target="_parent">Presentación</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img src="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/buttn15c.gif" height="6" width="6" /> <a href="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/claros.htm" target="_parent">Base de Datos</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img src="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/buttn15c.gif" height="6" width="6" /> <a href="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/cnc/cnc2.htm" target="_parent">Colecciones</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img src="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/buttn15c.gif" height="6" width="6" /> <a href="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/cnc/cnc4.htm" target="_parent">Ayuda</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><center><span style="color: #008040; font-size: x-small;"><b>Abreviaturas</b></span></center><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img src="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/buttn15c.gif" height="6" width="6" /> <a href="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/cnc/cnc3.htm" target="_parent">Lista</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img src="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/buttn15c.gif" height="6" width="6" /> <a href="http://www.dge.filol.csic.es/claros/cnc/cnc5.htm" target="_parent">Búsqueda</a></span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7654401881204325730/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/03/claros-concordancia-de-inscripciones.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7654401881204325730"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7654401881204325730"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/03/claros-concordancia-de-inscripciones.html"
         title="CLAROS. Concordancia de Inscripciones griegas"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
