<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5435000055788919376</id>
   <published>2015-04-30T08:00:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-04-30T08:39:50.785-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text"> New Book from the Oriental Institute: Household Studies in Complex Societies: (Micro) Archaeological and Textual Approaches</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="column" id="content" role="main"><span style="font-size: small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/publications/ois/ois-10-household-archaeology-complex-societies">OIS 10. <cite>Household Studies in Complex Societies: (Micro) Archaeological and Textual Approaches</cite></a></span>             <br /><article class="node-3949 node node-publication view-mode-full clearfix"><div class="content-inner one-column"><div class="content-inner-left"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Edited by Miriam Müller</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;<a class="publication ss-standard ss-download btn" href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/sites/oi.uchicago.edu/files/uploads/shared/docs/ois10.pdf">Download</a> <a class="publication" href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/electronic-publications-initiative-oriental-institute-university-chicago">Terms of Use</a></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/sites/oi.uchicago.edu/files/styles/narrow/public/uploads/shared/docs/Publications/ois10-Muller-cover-web.jpg?itok=M90Vs1Hs" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img alt="Household Archaeology in Complex Societies cover" border="0" class="imgrt" src="http://oi.uchicago.edu/sites/oi.uchicago.edu/files/styles/narrow/public/uploads/shared/docs/Publications/ois10-Muller-cover-web.jpg?itok=M90Vs1Hs" height="200" title="Household Archaeology in Complex Societies cover" width="137" /></a>The volume is the result of the ninth annual University of Chicago  Oriental Institute Postdoc Seminar, held on March 16-17, 2013. Twenty  scholars specialized in the Old and New World from all over Europe and  the U.S. came together to find new approaches in the study of households  in complex societies. The papers in this volume present case studies  from the Near East, Egypt and Nubia, the Classical World, and  Mesoamerica, including three comparative responses from the perspective  of the different disciplines. By combining the archaeology record,  scientific data, and written documents, the papers examine and  contextualize different approaches and techniques in uncovering  household behavior from the material record and discuss their  suitability for the respective region and site. Building on the  methodological groundwork laid out in a number of recent publications on  household archaeology, the volume contributes to the methodological and  theoretical discussion, expands on the topics of society, identity, and  ethnicity in household studies, and opens up new avenues of research  such as the perception of space in this innovative field. At the same  time the papers reveal problems and disparities with which household  archaeology is still struggling. It is hoped that the variety of case  studies presented in this volume will further inspire the interested  reader to establish new research agendas and excavation strategies that  contribute to the development of the field in the various regions  covered in the different papers and beyond.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Table of Contents</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Introduction: Household Studies in Complex Societies: (Micro) Archaeological and Textual Approaches. Miriam Müller</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">PART I: Method and Theory<br />1. Investigating Traces of Everyday Life in Ancient Households: Some Methodological Considerations. Lynn Rainville<br />2. Activity-area Analysis: A Comprehensive Theoretical Model. Peter Pfälzner<br />3. How to Reconstruct Daily Life in a Near Eastern Settlement:  Possibilities and Constraints of a Combined Archaeological, Historical,<br />and Scientific Approach. Adelheid Otto<br />4. Ancient Egyptian Houses and Households: Architecture, Artifacts, Conceptualization, and Interpretation. Kate Spence<br />5. Artifact Assemblages in Classical Greek Domestic Contexts: Toward a New Approach. Lisa C. Nevett</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">PART II: Perception of Space<br />6. Interaction between Texts and Social Space in Mesopotamian Houses: A Movement and Sensory Approach. Paolo Brusasco<br />7. Clean and Unclean Space: Domestic Waste Management at Elephantine. Felix Arnold<br />8. Creating a Neighborhood within a Changing Town: Household and Other Agencies at Amara West in Nubia. Neal Spencer<br />9. Crucial Contexts: A Closer Reading of the Household of the Casa del Menandro at Pompeii. Jens-Arne Dickmann</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">PART III: Identity and Ethnicity<br />10. Private House or Temple? Decoding Patterns of the Old Babylonian Architecture. Peter A. Miglus<br />11. Hybrid Households: Institutional Affiliations and Household Identity in the Town of Wah-sut (South Abydos). Nicholas Picardo<br />12. Living in Households, Constructing Identities: Ethnicity, Boundaries, and Empire in Iron Ii Tell en-Nasbeh. Aaron J. Brody<br />13. Micro-archaeological Perspectives on the Philistine Household throughout the Iron Age and Their Implications. Aren M. Maeir</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">PART IV: Society<br />14. Property Title, Domestic Architecture, and Household Lifecycles in Egypt. Brian P. Muhs<br />15. Late Middle Kingdom Society in a Neighborhood of Tell el-Dabʿa/Avaris. Miriam Müller<br />16. Family Structure, Household Cycle, and the Social Use of Domestic Space in Urban Babylonia. Heather D. Baker<br />17. Reconstructing Houses and Archives in Early Islamic Jēme. Tasha Vorderstrasse</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">PART V: Responses<br />18. Social Conditions in the Ancient Near East: Houses and Households in Perspective. Elizabeth C. Stone<br />19. Multifunctionality and Hybrid Households: The Case of Ancient Egypt. Nadine Moeller<br />20. A Mesoamerican Perspective on Old World Household Studies in Complex Societies. Cynthia Robin</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Oriental Institute Seminars 10</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Chicago: The Oriental Institute, 2015</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">ISBN 978-1-61491-023-7</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Pp. xlii + 470; 208 illustrations</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="pubprice">$25.95</span></span></li></ul></blockquote></div></div></article>          </div><br /><div style="text-align: center;">For an up to date list of all Oriental Institute publications available online see:</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/10/oriental-institute-open-access.html">The Oriental Institute Open Access Publications</a><br /></div><div style="text-align: center;">See <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/03/open-access-monographic-series-oriental.html">Open Access Monograph Series: Oriental Institute Seminars (OIS)</a><br />&nbsp; <br />  <br />And see the <a class="GCUXF0KCPB" href="http://oihistory.blogspot.com/2014/11/chronological-lists-of-oi-publications.html">Chronological Lists of OI Publications</a> </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5435000055788919376/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/04/new-book-from-oriental-institute.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5435000055788919376"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5435000055788919376"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/04/new-book-from-oriental-institute.html"
         title=" New Book from the Oriental Institute: Household Studies in Complex Societies: (Micro) Archaeological and Textual Approaches"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
