<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6288538328655505546</id>
   <published>2016-04-06T17:07:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-04-06T17:07:48.570-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Art History"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Pedagogy"/>
   <title type="text">Smarthistory</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">[First posted in AWOL 24 October 2012, updated 6 April 2016] </span><br /><br /><a href="http://smarthistory.org/">Smarthistory</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="Back Home" class=" attachment-6445" src="http://smarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/LogoOnly@2x.png" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">What is Smarthistory?</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Smarthistory is a leading resource for the study of art and cultural  heritage. Our growing collection of videos and essays are designed to be  engaging and conversational and cover art that ranges from the  paleolithic to the present. Everything on Smarthistory is completely  free and our content is offered with no advertising. We are a tiny  non-profit organization based in New York, but we reach millions of  learners around the world.</span><br /> <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Who is Smarthistory?</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Smarthistory is a collaboration of more than <a href="http://smarthistoryblog.org/contributors-and-contributing-editors/" target="_blank" title="Contributors and Contributing Editors">200</a> art historians, archaeologists, curators and other specialists who want  to make the highest-quality art history learning content freely  available to a global audience.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Dr. Beth Harris</strong>&nbsp;is co-founder and executive editor  for Smarthistory and faculty emeritus at Khan Academy. Previously, she  was dean of art and history at Khan Academy. She works with leading  museums to bring their content to new global audiences and acquires,  edits, and publishes short essays on art and history by leading  academics. She was the first director of digital learning at The Museum  of Modern Art, where she started MoMA Courses Online and co-produced  educational videos, websites and apps. Before joining MoMA, Beth was  Associate Professor of art history and director of distance learning at  the Fashion Institute of Technology where she taught both online and in  the classroom. She has co-authored, with Dr. Steven Zucker, numerous  articles on the future of education and the future of museums, topics  she regularly addresses at conferences around the world. She received  her Master’s degree from the Courtauld Institute of Art in London, and  her doctorate in Art History from the Graduate Center of the City  University of New York. Email: beth.harris@gmail.com</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><br />Dr. Steven Zucker&nbsp;</strong>is co-founder and executive editor for  Smarthistory and faculty emeritus at Khan Academy. Previously, he was  dean of art and history at Khan Academy. He produces short-form videos  on art and history viewed by millions of people around the world. He  works with leading museums to bring their content to new global  audiences and acquires, edits, and publishes short essays on art and  history by leading academics. He was chair of history of art and design  at Pratt Institute where he strengthened enrollment and led the renewal  of curriculum across the Institute. Before that, he was dean of the  School of Graduate Studies at the Fashion Institute of Technology, SUNY  and chair of their art history department. He has taught at The School  of Visual Arts, Hunter College, and at The Museum of Modern Art. Dr.  Zucker is a recipient of the SUNY Chancellor’s Award for Excellence in  Teaching. He has co-authored, with Dr. Beth Harris, numerous articles on  the future of education and the future of museums, topics he regularly  addresses at conferences around the world. Dr. Zucker received his Ph.D.  from the Graduate Center of the City University of New York. Email:  drszucker@gmail.com</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6288538328655505546/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/smarthistory.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6288538328655505546"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6288538328655505546"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/smarthistory.html"
         title="Smarthistory"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
