<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6298624713807045227</id>
   <published>2015-11-17T18:17:00.002-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-11-17T18:17:59.274-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Crowd Source"/>
   <title type="text">SAVE LATIN AND GREEK ON ALPHEIOS!</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/save-latin-and-greek-on-alpheios#/"><span style="font-size: small;">SAVE LATIN AND GREEK ON ALPHEIOS!</span></a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">(<i>and help extend its support to other classical languages</i>) </span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>THE PURPOSE</b></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Many of the most important books ever written, the most profound and  the most beautiful, were written in one of the ancient languages no  longer spoken. <sup>1</sup> Translations can convey some part of what their authors intended, but by no means all.&nbsp;</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Traditionally it was necessary to devote prolonged study to each  language, preferably with a knowledgeable teacher, before ever  confronting the original text itself. Today, a variety of online tools  can help anyone begin to appreciate the original language whenever they  wish. The Alpheios Project was created to bring the latest technology to  this task, and already has tens of thousands of users around the world  with its reading support tools for Latin, Greek, and classical Arabic  and Chinese. The software was designed to permit new languages to be  added easily, and there are plans underway for its extension to other  classical languages such as Persian, Sanskrit and several others.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">In keeping with its mission to bring texts in the classical languages  to the widest possible audience, Alpheios has always made its tools  available for free and has kept its code open source for use by any  other non-profit initiative.&nbsp; </span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>THE CRISIS</b></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">However, at the moment, not only the expansion but even the survival  of the present Alpheios functionality is threatened by impending changes  to the Firefox browser, which is currently the only platform on which  Alpheios runs. &nbsp;Significant modifications of our code will be needed,  and at the moment we do not have the resources to make the changes in  the required time frame. </span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>THE APPEAL</b></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">We are consequently making our first public funding appeal. We are  hoping to raise between fifty and one hundred thousand dollars so that  we can employ professional programmers in an accelerated timeframe.  Since we are a registered 501(c)3 non-profit organization, all  contributions are tax-deductible in the United States. </span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you consider this initiative worthwhile, please let others know about it, whether or not you are able to contribute yourself. </span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">At this point we don't anticipate any insuperable technical  challenges since the requirements are quite clearly defined and all the  original developers of Alpheios remain available for consultation. &nbsp;We  just need competent hands to do the work before the clock runs out on  Alpheios. </span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>THE HOPE &nbsp;&nbsp;</b></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">In addition to maintaining Alpheios on Firefox, the changes to the  code that must be made will greatly facilitate porting Alpheios to other  browsers and to mobile devices, among the most frequent requests from  our users. They should also help bring an expanded Alpheios reading  environment to other classical languages and provide a more convenient  platform for the deployment of a greater variety of language learning  games. &nbsp;We believe that the supreme importance of the classical  languages, and their immediate relevance to our present world, &nbsp;can only  be fully appreciated when they can all be studied with similar tools in  a common reading environment.&nbsp;</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">-------</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span>(1) (Perhaps the best known of  these "classical languages" are ancient Greek, Latin, Sanskrit and  classical Chinese, Persian, Arabic and Hebrew, but there are many more,  including Old Norse and Old English, Old French and the Langue d'oc, Old  Spanish and Old and Middle High German, not to mention the great  languages of the ancient middle east, such as Egyptian, Sumerian,  Akkadian, Hittite, Classical Armenian, Syriac and Aramaic, or the  classical Japanese of the Man'yōshū.</span></span><br /> </div></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6298624713807045227/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/save-latin-and-greek-on-alpheios.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6298624713807045227"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6298624713807045227"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/save-latin-and-greek-on-alpheios.html"
         title="SAVE LATIN AND GREEK ON ALPHEIOS!"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
