<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-628569442147137787</id>
   <published>2016-06-17T03:32:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-06-17T03:32:23.255-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="dissertations"/>
   <title type="text">ETHoS:  Electronic Thesis Online Service: The UK’s national thesis service</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://ethos.bl.uk/Home.do">ETHoS:  Electronic Thesis Online Service</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img border="0" height="54" src="http://ethos.bl.uk/ethos/images/bl/ethosbanner.jpg" title="EThOS - Electronic Theses Online Service" width="400" /></span> </blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;"></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">EThOS is the UK’s national thesis service which aims to maximise the  	        visibility and availability of the UK’s doctoral research theses.<br /><br />	         	        It demonstrates the quality of UK research, and supports the UK Government’s 	        open access principle that publications resulting from publicly-funded research 	        should be made freely available for all researchers, providing opportunities 	        for further research. EThOS helps institutions to meet the expectation of the 	        UK Research Councils that PhDs supported by a Research Council Training Grant 	        should be made freely available in an open access repository, as indicated 	        in its <a href="http://www.rcuk.ac.uk/funding/grantstcs/" target="_blank">Training Grant Terms &amp; Conditions</a> (Paragraph 104). 	       </span>	       <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />	        	       EThOS aims to provide: 	       </span><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">A national aggregated <b>record</b> of all doctoral theses awarded   	                by UK Higher Education institutions</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Free access to the <b>full text</b> of as many theses as possible  	                for use by all researchers to further their own research.</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">	        There are approximately 400,000 records relating to theses awarded by  	        over 120 institutions. Around 160,000 of these also provide access to the  	        full text thesis, either via download from the EThOS database or via links  	        to the institution’s own repository. Of the remaining 240,000 records dating  	        back to at least 1800, three quarters are available to be ordered for scanning  	        through the EThOS digitisation-on-demand facility. 	        </span>        	<span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />        	         	Records are held for all UK PhD-awarding institutions, but we do not (yet)              hold <i>all</i> records for <i>all</i> institutions. Every month around 3000 new records are              added and an additional 2000 full text theses become accessible. Access routes              to the full text are determined by the individual institution and may depend              on:             </span>                         <ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Mandatory electronic deposit of newly awarded theses by its students</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Availability of its theses in the institutional repository</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Its level of repository development</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Digitisation priorities for its print theses</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">                         The digitisation on demand facility is a unique feature of  EThOS and brings              new e-born theses and older print content together into a  single place. Users              ordering a copy through digitisation on demand may  experience a turnaround time             of up to 6 weeks. There may also be a charge for the  scanning process (currently  £45.40 + VAT £9.08 = Total £54.48). Details  are              provided within each record.             </span>	        <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />	         			EThOS continues to be developed to benefit both participating institutions and users. 			In June 2015 new data started to be added: <a href="http://orcid.org/" target="_blank">ORCID</a>  			and <a href="http://www.isni.org/" target="_blank">ISNI</a> are two international author systems which provide  			unique identity profiles for any researcher or author to support the visibility and re-use of their works.  			Digital Object Identifiers (<a href="http://www.doi.org/" target="_blank">DOIs</a>) are unique persistent identifiers for research works increasingly issued and  			required by publishers and should be used to cite or link to the work wherever possible. 			All three identifiers are now being embraced by universities for their students, academics, PhD theses and other works.  			 	        </span>	        <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />			The <a href="http://ethostoolkit.cranfield.ac.uk/" target="_blank">EThOS Toolkit</a> provides further information about all aspects of the service. 	        </span>	        <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span>	         	        <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="tk" href="http://ethos.bl.uk/HEIList.do">View a list of participating institutions</a>	        </span>	        </blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://ethos.bl.uk/AdvancedSearch.do">Search ETHoS</a>  (and note that you can limit your search to items available for immediate download)</span><br /><a href="https://draft.blogger.com/null" id="data:post.url" name="data:post.title" onclick="return addthis_sendto()" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onmouseover="'return"></a>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/628569442147137787/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/04/ethos-electronic-thesis-online-service.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/628569442147137787"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/628569442147137787"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/04/ethos-electronic-thesis-online-service.html"
         title="ETHoS:  Electronic Thesis Online Service: The UK’s national thesis service"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
