<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6297812229532449992</id>
   <published>2016-03-02T14:42:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-03-02T14:45:33.279-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Atlas"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Maps"/>
   <title type="text">The Digital Archaeological Atlas of the Holy Land</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">[First posted in AWOL 11 August 2011, updated 2 March 2016]</span><br /><br /><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/">The Digital Archaeological Atlas of the Holy Land</a><br /><div class="figureRight"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: center;"><div style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img class="brdr" src="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/GMAPS.jpg" height="167" width="200" /></div></div></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><br /></span></div></div><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Digital Archaeological Atlas of the Holy Land (DAAHL) is an  international project that brings together experts in information  technology including Geographic Information Systems (GIS) and the  archaeology of the Holy Land (modern Israel, Palestine, Jordan, southern  Lebanon, Syria and the Sinai Peninsula) to create the first on-line  digital atlas of the region held sacred to the three great monotheistic  faiths - Judaism, Christianity and Islam.  Using the power of spatial  information systems such as Google Maps and Google Earth, GIS, the tens  of thousands of recorded archaeological sites for the region - from the  remote prehistoric periods to the early 20th century - will be entered  into a comprehensive database along with site maps, photographs and  artifacts.   The historical and archaeological content for this project  will be developed by a team of over 30 international scholars working in  the region, helping to provide the data used to create the Atlas.  This  website and its content will serve as the prototype "knowledge node" of  a more comprehensive Digital Archaeological Atlas Network for the  Mediterranean region.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="headerlinks" href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/" target="_top">Home </a> |            <a class="headerlinks" href="http://medarchnet.org/" target="_blank"> MedArchNet </a> |            <a class="headerlinks" href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/GML.php" target="_top"> Empires </a> |            <a class="headerlinks" href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/Periods.php" target="_top"> Archaeological Periods </a> |            <a class="headerlinks" href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/Shishak.php" target="_top"> Shishak's Campaign </a> |            <a class="headerlinks" href="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/#"> Case Studies </a> |  	  <a class="headerlinks" href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/AboutAtlas.php" target="_top"> About the Atlas </a> |  	  <a class="headerlinks" href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/PEFMaps.php" target="_top"> PEF Maps </a> |  	  <a class="headerlinks" href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/DaahlGESearch.php" target="_blank"> Database Search </a> |            <a class="headerlinks" href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/GMPiPDigitizer.php" target="_top"> Spatial Search </a> |            <a class="headerlinks" href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/ComponentMaps.php" target="_blank"> Make Maps </a> |  	  <a class="headerlinks" href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/Preservation.php" target="_top"> Site Preservation </a> |           <a class="headerlinks" href="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/#"> Contributors </a> |           <a class="headerlinks" href="http://terrawatchers.org/" target="_blank"> TerraWatchers</a></span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The site now contains a variety of Google Maps interfaces that let  you explore the region and the archaeological resources it contains. <b>The link bar under the DAAHL header provides access to the main functions currently available in the website.</b> These include:</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><br /><div class="figureRight"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://medarchnet.org/" target="_top"><img class="brdr" height="100" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/MEDARCNT.jpg" width="125" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <a href="http://medarchnet.org/" target="_top"><b>Mediterranean Archaeological Network</b></a> or MedArchNet is one of the first attempts to create 'Portal Science'  for archaeologists and the interested public.  Consequently, a major  goal of MedArchNet is to make archaeological data from the Mediterranean  lands accessible to various communities, including school teachers,  tourists and travel agents, university students and professors,  researchers, and public policy makers.  MedArchNet taps into the  fast-growing field of 'portal science' and will serve researchers and  explorers as a platform for international collaboration, while also  allowing the general public to share in the excitement of archaeology  and discovery. This link takes you to the MedArchNet homepage.  </span><br /><div class="figureLeft"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/GML.php" target="_top"><img class="brdr" height="125" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/ALEX.jpg" width="100" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/GML.php" target="_top"><b>Empires</b></a> presents one set of examples of Global Moments in the Levant. On this  page the DAAHL includes an interactive Google Maps interface that  presents the rise and fall of empires in the ancient world.  The map can  be animated to display the empires across time; individual empires can  be selected to display summary information, and archaeological sites  extant during the empire's time span can be displayed and queried on the  map.  </span><br /><div class="figureRight"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/Periods.php" target="_top"><img class="brdr" height="125" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/EBCLUST.jpg" width="100" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/Periods.php" target="_top"><b>Archaeological Periods</b></a> organize over 17,000 sites in the DAAHL database by more than 60 time  periods from the Lower Paleolithic, more than 2 million years ago, to  the Late Ottoman period, which ended in 1918. A Google Maps interface  lets the user animate site clusters through time, and explore the  distribution of archaeological sites in the Levant during any of these  periods.  Short introductions to the time periods are included as well.  </span><br /><div class="figureLeft"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/Shishak.php" target="_top"><img class="brdr" height="125" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/SHESHONQ.jpg" width="100" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/Shishak.php" target="_top"><b>Shishak's Campaign</b></a> presents information related to the Egyptian Pharoah Sheshonq I (known  in the Hebrew Bible as Shishak) and his military expedition into  southwestern Asia. His invasion of Judah and Israel is documented on the  south wall of the Temple of Amun Ra at Karnak, and described in the  Bible (1 Kings 11:40; 14:25; 2 Chronicles 12:2-9).  The DAAHL uses the  latest "tour" capability in the Google Earth API to track some of the  movements of Shishak's army.  </span><br /><div class="figureRight"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/#"><img class="brdr" height="100" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/COPPER.jpg" width="125" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/#"><b>Case Studies</b></a> are specialized, in depth explorations of different subjects in the  atlas.  Tom Levy's exploration of the Edomite Lowlands during the Iron  Age, which is accompanied by an interactive Google Maps display, is a  prime example. Other case studies are presented as online Powerpoint or  HTML presentations.  </span><br /><div class="figureLeft"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/AboutAtlas" target="_top"><img class="brdr" height="100" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/GML-group.jpg" width="125" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/AboutAtlas.php" target="_top"><b>About the Atlas</b></a> displays information about the main research partners who are  developing the atlas. The Atlas is an international project that brings  together experts in information technology and Levantine archaeology to  create the first on-line digital atlas of the region held sacred to the  three great monotheistic faiths - Judaism, Christianity and Islam.  </span><br /><div class="figureRight"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/PEFMaps.php" target="_top"><img class="brdr" height="100" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/PEF.jpg" width="125" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/PEFMaps.php" target="_top"><b>PEF Maps</b></a> are maps produced for the Palestine Exploration Fund by Claude R.  Conder of the British Ordanace Survey in the 1870s and 1880s. These  classic maps contain more than 10,000 place names, and are an important  resource for Late Ottoman period Palestine.  The GAIA Lab at Arizona  State University converted the map sheets into more than 50,000 tiles in  an interactive Google Maps display that can be zoomed and panned to  show the maps in the background, with the DAAHL archaeological sites  superimposed.  </span><br /><div class="figureLeft"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/DaahlGESearch.php" target="_blank"><img class="brdr" height="100" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/DAAHL.gif" width="128" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/DaahlGESearch.php" target="_blank"><b>Search Database</b></a> opens a page in the website where users can query the database by such  things as site name, time period, site type, site conditions, etc.   Queries are submitted to the DAAHL web server and the results are  returned to the user as dynamic kml, which opens on the user's computer  in Google Earth.  All sites displayed in the result sets are  "backlinked" to the DAAHL database, so they can be explored indiviually  by following their links. See the video below for an example of a time  period search.  </span><br /><div class="figureRight"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/GMPiPDigitizer.php" target="_top"><img class="brdr" height="100" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/DIGPROJ2.jpg" width="125" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/GMPiPDigitizer.php" target="_top"><b>Spatial Search</b></a> link opens a page with in interactive Google Maps display.  The user  can draw an irregular region of interest on the map and perform a search  for all the sites in the DAAHL database that fall within one kilometer  of the search region.  Like the database search, results are displayed  as points in Google Earth; the user can determine the point display  style, and all search results are back-linked to the Atlas.  </span><br /><div class="figureLeft"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/ComponentMaps.php" target="_blank"><img class="brdr" height="100" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/MMapThm.jpg" width="125" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">Use the <a href="http://gaialab.asu.edu/DAAHL/ComponentMaps.php" target="_blank"><b>Make Maps</b></a> function to make queries of sites by time period and/or site/feature  type, and display the results on a Google Maps interactive map that  includes site clusters and individual sites. Clusters can be clicked to  zoom to the next level, displaying smaller clusters and individual  sites. &nbsp;Hover over site points to see the site name. &nbsp;Use your  computer's screen copy function to copy the map; then paste it into a  graphics editing program and crop it to the map--then you can use the  map in presentations or documents.  </span><br /><div class="figureRight"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/Preservation.php" target="_top"><img class="brdr" height="100" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/AMCLIP.jpg" width="125" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/Preservation.php" target="_top"><b>Site Preservation</b></a> links to a page in the DAAHL website that displays two film clips.  The  first shows how the Spatial Search is done, and illustrates how this  function can be used to help preserve archaeological sites by minimizing  the impact of development projects through avoiding sites.  The second  film clip is a trailer to a movie that discusses the danger to one of  Jordan's most significant Early Bronze Age sites posed by expanding  gravel quarries.  </span><br /><div class="figureLeft"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/#"><img class="brdr" height="100" src="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/images/CONTRIB.jpg" width="125" /></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://daahl.ucsd.edu/DAAHL/#"><b>Contributors</b></a> to the DAAHL project have come from many countries, universities, and  research institutions.  All sites and project data that are contributed  to the DAAHL are "branded" with the contributor's information and  cross-linked to their websites.  The DAAHL database safeguards our  contributor's information and drives website traffic to their research  projects.</span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;And see AWOL's <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/09/roundup-of-resources-on-ancient.html">Roundup of Resources on Ancient Geography</a></span> </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6297812229532449992/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/08/digital-archaeological-atlas-of-holy.html#comment-form"
         title="1 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6297812229532449992"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6297812229532449992"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/08/digital-archaeological-atlas-of-holy.html"
         title="The Digital Archaeological Atlas of the Holy Land"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
