<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1157776229829063325</id>
   <published>2014-11-05T17:41:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-02-23T07:09:25.292-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Religion"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ancient"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal:  Entangled Religions: Interdisciplinary Journal for the Study of Religious Contact and Transfer</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/about">Entangled Religions: Interdisciplinary Journal for the Study of Religious Contact and Transfer</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div align="justify"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Entangled Religions</i> (ER) is a peer reviewed online periodical that complements the book series “Dynamics in the History of Religions” (<a href="http://www.khk.ceres.rub.de/en/publications/dhr-series/" target="_blank" title="DHR">DHR</a>) published with Brill. <i>Entangled Religions</i> is dedicated to channeling research on religious contact and transfer  in past and present times into a single journal to open up innovative  ways of conceptualizing the history of religions. It aims at  contributing to a better understanding of the interdependence of  religious traditions, of processes of religious transfer as well as of  formally and semantically varying borders between religion and other  societal fields.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The so-called world religions and  other religious traditions are not, and have hardly ever been,  homogeneous. Nor have they formed or evolved in isolation. The study of  Religions, however, has been split into different fields for contingent  reasons.This is a disadvantage especially with regard to topics relating  to cross- and trans-religious processes whose research requires the  joined expertise of different philologies and area studies. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div align="justify"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Here, <i>Entangled Religions</i> offers common ground: It provides a platform which brings together  scholars of various academic specializations – ranging from philologies  to the social sciences – and incorporates historical as well as  contemporary research.</span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">With the objective of overcoming cultural stereotypes and their ideological abuse, the journal <i>Entangled Religions</i> focuses on the crucial role of mutual encounters for the origins,  development and internal differentiation of religious traditions. We  also examine interactions with other societal fields such as politics,  economics, law, arts, medicine, and social care. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The studies published in <i>ER</i> are conducted in an interplay of theory-building and empirical studies, of object language and meta-language. <i>ER</i> aims at bridging academic meta-discourses on religion with religious  discourses and religious self-descriptions. Thus, both scholarly  theorizing disconnected from empirical data and atheoretical or naïve  positivism can be avoided. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">We set out to  scrutinize interconnected processes of self-perception and perception by  others, as well as phenomena of adaption and demarcation. Contributions  to our journal examine how these phenomena become important factors in  the historical dynamics of both the regional and the increasingly  globalized religious fields, whose outer borders are constituted by both  distinctions from and relations with other societal rationalities. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div align="justify"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Presenting  research on dynamics resulting from the interaction of idealtypically  conceptualized religious traditions and their manifestations in the  self-imagination of these traditions, the journal <i>Entangled Religions</i> creates systematic reference points which allow for the integration of  diachronically and synchronically compared material into a general  history of religions.</span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="float: left; width: 100%;"><div id="issue" style="clear: left;">   <h4><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-weight: normal;"><a href="http://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/issue/view/39">Vol 2 (2015)</a></span></span></h4><span style="font-size: x-small;">     </span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">       </span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">                         </span><h4><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-weight: normal;"><a href="http://er.ceres.rub.de/index.php/ER/issue/view/32">Vol 1 (2014)</a></span></span></h4></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1157776229829063325/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/coming-soon-entangledreligions-er.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1157776229829063325"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1157776229829063325"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/coming-soon-entangledreligions-er.html"
         title="Open Access Journal:  Entangled Religions: Interdisciplinary Journal for the Study of Religious Contact and Transfer"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
