<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1794166069237006877</id>
   <published>2016-10-19T11:10:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-10-19T11:10:27.699-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Mediterranean"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Trade"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Geography"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Maps"/>
   <title type="text">Proxeny Networks of the Ancient World  (a database of proxeny networks of the Greek city-states)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://proxenies.csad.ox.ac.uk/places/home">Proxeny Networks of the Ancient World</a>&nbsp;  (a database of proxeny networks of the Greek city-states)<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">About</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">PNAW is a database of evidence for a particular kind of social  networking between Greek city-states in the Ancient Greek world, known  as proxeny (Greek: proxenia). It enables this material to be used to  visualise the highly-fragmented political geography of the ancient world  during the Archaic, Classical, and Hellenistic periods, and to get a  sense of how densely and intensely interconnected were the states which  made it up.  </span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Context</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Before its unification under a Roman emperor, the ancient Mediterranean  world constituted the most fragmented state system in recorded history.  More than a thousand distinct Greek city-states (poleis), and many other  kinds of actor, such as dynasts, federations, and kings, made up a  vibrant and dynamic ecosystem of self-governing states. The interactions  of these states were mediated through a highly developed system of  institutions. Proxeny is the best attested of these institutions, and  was probably the most widely used. It enabled cities to maintain  substantial and often widespread networks that connected them with other  cities.  </span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Proxeny</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Proxeny was an institution of interstate relations in the ancient Greek  world. A city-state granted proxeny to the citizen of another community,  the status of being their proxenos within that individual's home city.  The role of the proxenos was to facilitate interaction between the two  political communities, most often by performing services of different  kinds for visiting citizens of the first state (termed here the  'granting city'). These services could take various forms - including  hospitality, introductions to magistrates, prominent men, or merchants,  and help negotiating local legal institutions in the case of contractual  disputes. Collectively these services helped to enable citizens of the  granting community in question to overcome the political fragmentation  of this world and function, whether as official representatives of their  own city, or as merchants, tradesmen, or even as tourists, in other  communities where they did not have the privileged status of citizen.  Proxeny networks, therefore, reflect and allow us to trace patterns of  political, economic, and social interactions between city states, and to  trace the horizons of different political communities.  </span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">PNAW</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">PNAW presents an overview of our evidence for these relationships of  proxeny in the ancient world, including those recorded in the literary  sources as well as the more than two thousand texts inscribed on stone.  It accompanies the recent study of this institution published by Oxford  University Press, <a alt="Proxeny and Polis book" href="http://ukcatalogue.oup.com/product/9780198713869.doi" title="Proxeny and Polis book">Proxeny and Polis</a> and its purpose is to make this material available in an accessible  format which can be corrected and updated as new evidence is published.  It makes use of GIS mapping to enable the evidence of links between  different communities which this data presents to be explored in an  intuitive way. In order to make the search function useable, results are  presented in a condensed view with further information available in the  form of mouseover dialogue boxes. To illustrate the potential of the search and mapping functions of this  database, here are some example searches: </span><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="Athenian Proxeny network of the fifth century BC" href="http://proxenies.csad.ox.ac.uk/representatives/search?granting_authority_id=13&amp;DateRange%5B0%5D=4&amp;DateRange%5B1%5D=5" title="Athenian Proxeny network of the fifth century BC">Athenian proxenoi network of the fifth century BC</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="Proxenoi at Athens in the fourth century BC" href="http://proxenies.csad.ox.ac.uk/representatives/search?proxenos_city_id=13&amp;DateRange[0]=6&amp;DateRange[1]=7" title="Proxenoi at Athens in the fourth century BC">Proxenoi at Athens in the fourth century BC</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="The Karthaian catalogue of proxenoi, 360s BC" href="http://proxenies.csad.ox.ac.uk/representatives/search?granting_authority_id=103&amp;DateRange%5B0%5D=6" title="The Karthaian catalogue of proxenoi, 360s BC">The Karthaian catalogue of proxenoi, 360s BC</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a alt="Grants of citizenship (politeia) alongside proxenia" href="http://proxenies.csad.ox.ac.uk/representatives/search?Honours%5B0%5D=3" title="Grants of citizenship (politeia) alongside proxenia">Grants of citizenship (politeia) alongside proxenia</a></span></li></ul><br /><div class="navbar navbar-static" id="navbar-example"><span style="font-size: x-small;">  </span><div class="navbar-inner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">    </span><div class="container" style="width: auto;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">      </span><ul class="nav" role="navigation"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="header_menu" href="http://proxenies.csad.ox.ac.uk/places/home">Home</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="header_menu" href="http://proxenies.csad.ox.ac.uk/about">About</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="header_menu" href="http://proxenies.csad.ox.ac.uk/representatives/search">Search</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="header_menu" href="http://proxenies.csad.ox.ac.uk/evidence">Evidence</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="header_menu" href="http://proxenies.csad.ox.ac.uk/terms">Terms</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="header_menu" href="http://proxenies.csad.ox.ac.uk/credits">Credits</a></span></li></ul></div></div></div></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">And see AWOL's <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/09/roundup-of-resources-on-ancient.html">Roundup of Resources on Ancient Geography</a> </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1794166069237006877/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/10/proxeny-networks-of-ancient-world.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1794166069237006877"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1794166069237006877"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/10/proxeny-networks-of-ancient-world.html"
         title="Proxeny Networks of the Ancient World  (a database of proxeny networks of the Greek city-states)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
