<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6513714759178061727</id>
    <published>2014-05-27T16:17:00.002-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-27T20:56:24.032-04:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <title type="text">CDLI News: The National Museums Scotland</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/?q=news/tablets-scotland"><span
      style="font-size: small;">CDLI News</span></a><br /><blockquote
      class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <a href="http://www.nms.ac.uk/"
      target="_blank">National Museums Scotland (NMS)</a> and the <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/" target="_blank">Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative</a>
      are pleased to announce the addition of the digitized NMS cuneiform corpus to CDLI’s website.
      </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">With approximately 250 objects in storage, the collection of the NMS is the
      largest of its kind in Scotland. It is remarkable due to its diversity, covering various
      periods of Mesopotamian history and beyond. Although a majority of the corpus consists of
      cuneiform artifacts made of clay (mainly tablets and bricks), the collection contains several
      nice examples of <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/search/search_results.php?SearchMode=Text&amp;requestFrom=Search&amp;Collection=national+museums+scotland&amp;MuseumNumber=&amp;order=MuseumNumber&amp;Period=neo-assyrian&amp;ObjectRemarks=relief"
      target="_blank">Neo-Assyrian reliefs</a>&nbsp;as well.</span><br />
      <span style="font-size: x-small;">It is not surprising that administrative records dating
      to the last century of the 3rd millennium BC, the so-called Ur III period, have a fair share in
      this collection. An edition of this still mostly unpublished <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/search/search_results.php?SearchMode=Text&amp;requestFrom=Search&amp;PrimaryPublication=unpublished&amp;Collection=national+museums+scotland&amp;MuseumNumber=&amp;order=MuseumNumber&amp;Period=Ur+III"
      target="_blank">corpus</a> is planned for the near future together with further
      smaller Scottish collections of cuneiform artifacts. Although much of this material consists of
      small receipts, some larger specimens of Ur III accounts are noteworthy, thus the fragment of a
      large <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P453060" target="_blank">Ur III account</a>,
      whose date is unfortunately broken. The account deals with work performed for the house of the
      third king of the Ur III dynasty, Amar-Suen, and mentions a variety of workers (those that are
      present, missing and dead). Similarly significant documents are a <a content="" for=""
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P414092" target="_blank">literary letter</a> addressed to a
      king that is known from several <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/search/search_results.php?order=MuseumNumber&amp;CompositeNumber=Q000573"
      target="_blank">places</a> and that uses sophisticated epithets, and a Sumerian <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P355876" target="_blank">love incantation</a>&nbsp;with
      just one <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P355884"
      target="_blank">duplicate</a>,&nbsp;adding valuable information to the
      understanding of this composition due to its excellent state of
      preservation.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Besides Sumerian
      literary texts, there are quite a few well-preserved legal texts in the NMS dating to the Old
      Babylonian period. Due to such internal criteria as names and places referenced in the records,
      we learn that a substantial number originate from the site of ancient Kish. Others such as
      <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P453133" target="_blank">NMS A.1909.405.28</a> might
      originate from Sippar. Fragments of its original envelope are still preserved. Furthermore,
      there is an Old Babylonian <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P453066"
      target="_blank">letter</a> written in Akkadian dealing with the rights to a field.
      </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">Although there are no texts in the collection from Mesopotamia proper that date to
      the second half of the 2nd millennium BC, there is a <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P464356"
      target="_blank">brick</a> with a Middle Elamite royal inscription by the Shutrukid
      king Shilhak-Inshushinak commemorating the restoration of the temple of Kiririsha-of-Liyan (see
      K. Wagensonner, <i>CDLN</i> <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000045"
      target="_blank">2014:018</a> [forthcoming]).
      </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">Aside from these clay tablets, the most noteworthy objects held by the collection
      are its Neo-Assyrian period (ca. 911-612 BC) <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P426881"
      target="_blank">relief</a>. Among the latest datable texts in the collection are those
      dating to the Neo-Babylonian (ca. 626-539 BC) and the subsequent Achaemenid periods (547-331
      BC). The well-preserved tablet&nbsp;<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P453151"
      target="_blank">NMS A.1909.405.23</a> derives from the vast archive of the Egibi
      family, whose business spanned over five generations (see C. Wunsch, <i>Das Egibi-Archiv
      </i>[=<i>Cuneiform Monographs</i> 20. Groningen&nbsp;2000]). This text,
      from the third year of Darius, testifies to the purchase of a plot of land; it has a duplicate
      in the British Museum (BM 32180 + 33125; see Wunsch <i>op.cit.</i>, no. 199A). Due
      to the better preservation of the Edinburgh tablet, the whole transaction is better understood.
      </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">Noteworthy for this late stage in Mesopotamian history is also a royal inscription
      by the Neo-Babylonian king Nebuchadnezzar II (605-562 BC), inscribed on a clay <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P453135" target="_blank">barrel cylinder</a>. This
      inscription is known from several examples, among others a similar <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P430894" target="_blank">barrel</a> in the John Rylands
      Library (Manchester). Last but not least, one should draw attention to a bilingual version of a
      <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P414095" target="_blank">lamentation</a>, whose copy
      in Edinburgh dates to the second half of the 1st millennium BC as well. A strikingly similar
      text in terms of scribal hand and spacing is a bilingual <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P432447" target="_blank">prayer</a>&nbsp;in the
      Manchester Museum. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">Thanks to the cordial assistance of NMS curators, the results of
      the National Museums Scotland collaboration have now been added to CDLI pages.</span>
      </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Any
      queries regarding the collection should be directed to Margaret Maitland, Curator of the
      Ancient Mediterranean (<a
      href="mailto:m.maitland@nms.ac.uk">m.maitland@nms.ac.uk</a>); any corrections or
      comments on the catalogue and associated online files should be directed to CDLI (<a
      href="mailto:cdli@ucla.edu">cdli@ucla.edu)</a>.
      </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">The imaging in Edinburgh was undertaken by Kathryn Kelley and Klaus Wagensonner
      (University of Oxford). The RTI capture of the <a
      href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/dl/photo/P426881.jpg" target="_blank">Neo-Assyrian
      relief</a> in the collection as well as some chosen cuneiform texts were done by James
      Miles (University of Southampton). Post-capture processing was undertaken by Klaus Wagensonner.
      The NMS digital capture was made possible by funding from the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, and
      is are part of the on-going mission of CDLI to ensure the long-term digital preservation of
      ancient cuneiform inscriptions, and, in furtherance of humanities research, to provide free
      global access to all available text artifact data.
      </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">For the NMS and the
      CDLI:<br />Margaret Maitland, Curator of the Ancient Mediterranean, Department of World
      Cultures, National Museums Scotland<br />Jacob L. Dahl, Associate Professor of
      Assyriology, Faculty of Oriental Studies, University of Oxford</span><br /><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size:
      10pt;"></span></span></blockquote>]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6513714759178061727/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/05/cdli-news-national-museums-scotland.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6513714759178061727"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6513714759178061727"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/05/cdli-news-national-museums-scotland.html"
         title="CDLI News: The National Museums Scotland"/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
