<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2204932130062693261</id>
   <published>2015-12-02T16:43:00.002-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-07-31T09:50:05.240-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Dabiq</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.clarionproject.org/news/islamic-state-isis-isil-propaganda-magazine-dabiq">Dabiq</a><br /><br />The Islamic State's (ISIS, ISIL, Daesh) Magazine. Scans of Dabiq have been made available online by The Clarion Project.<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Islamic State (ISIS) regularly puts out a glossy propaganda magazine  aimed at recruiting jihadists from the West. It is sophisticated,  slick, beautifully produced and printed in several languages including  English...</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">'Dabiq' as it is called, bills itself as "a periodical magazine  focusing on the issues of tawhid (unity), manhaj (truth-seeking), hijrah  (migration), <a class="glossary-item" href="http://www.clarionproject.org/glossary/jihad/">jihad</a> (holy war) and jama'ah (community). It will also contain photo reports,  current events, and informative articles on matters relating to the  Islamic State."</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">It <a href="http://www.clarionproject.org/analysis/islamic-state-selling-message-glossy-english-magazine">portrays the Islamic State</a> as they see themselves:<span style="background-color: white;">&nbsp;</span>boasting  of their victories and painting a romantic image of the restoration of  an Islamic golden age and the heralding of a glorious new <a class="glossary-item" href="http://www.clarionproject.org/glossary/caliphate/">Caliphate</a> based on holy war.&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Dabiq is a place in Syria that is  supposed to be the location for one of the final battles according to  certain Muslim myths about a final apocalypse. Choosing such a name for  the magazine highlights the Caliphate's goals... </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">In order to combat extremist groups,  it is important to understand their underlying ideology. Therefore,  Clarion Project will continue to post the issues of <i>Dabiq</i></span><span style="font-size: 16px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;here as they are released. </span></span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Issues of <i>Dabiq</i> released&nbsp;so far:&nbsp;</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Issue fourteen of the Islamic State’s magazine is entitled <strong><em>The Murtadd Brotherhood</em></strong>, referring to the Egyptian Islamist group the <a class="glossary-item" href="http://www.clarionproject.org/glossary/muslim-brotherhood/">Muslim Brotherhood</a> as apostates. In addition to sections praising the terrorists who carried out the attack on Brussels airport on March 22, <em>Dabiq</em> features a section attacking the legitimacy of the Muslim Brotherhood.  It also exhorts ISIS supporters to kill a slew of Muslim leaders living  in the West, some of whom are linked to the Brotherhood or hold Islamist  views. Regular features boasting of alleged military victories,  praising departed fighters and advertising ISIS videos are also  included.&nbsp;</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.clarionproject.org/docs/Dabiq-Issue-14.pdf">The Islamic &nbsp;State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine:&nbsp;<em>Dabiq -&nbsp;</em>Issue 14</a></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The thirteenth issue of the Islamic State's propaganda magazine is called&nbsp;<strong><em>The Rafidah: From Ibn Sa'ba to the Dajjal.&nbsp;</em></strong>Rafidah  is a pejorative term for Shi'ite while the Dajjal is an antichrist  figure in Muslim eschatology. The magazine opens by praising the San  Bernardino attacks which killed 14 people in California. It goes on to  attack Saudi Arabia's legitimacy and heavily criticize the history of  Shiite Islam in Iran. Jihadi John received a full two page obituary in  the recurring section 'Among the Believers are Men' and the 'To Our  Sisters' section provides advice on the correct way to mourn a martyred  husband.</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.clarionproject.org/factsheets-files/Issue-13-the-rafidah.pdf">Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine: <em>Dabiq - </em>Issue 13&nbsp;</a></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The twelth issue of the Islamic State’s propaganda magazine is entitled <em><strong>Just Terror</strong></em>. It boasts about the terrorist <a href="http://www.clarionproject.org/analysis/three-reactions-isis-hoping-we-will-have">attacks in Paris</a>, the <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/nov/12/beirut-bombings-kill-at-least-20-lebanon" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">double-bombing in Beirut</a>, and the <a href="http://www.clarionproject.org/analysis/russian-plane-downing-turbocharge-isis">downing of a Russian plane in Sinai</a> among other attacks. It spins terrorism in the language of a fairy  story, referring to terrorists as “knights,” acting to defend Muslim  honor. This issue is also striking for the high number of Islamic State  propaganda videos it advertizes, a sign of increased output in that  area. Other pieces continue long-running themes, including attacking the  legitimacy of other Islamist factions, recounting its military  victories and attacking women who oppose polygyny as opposing Islam. &nbsp;</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.clarionproject.org/docs/islamic-state-isis-isil-dabiq-magazine-issue-12-just-terror.pdf"><span>Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine:&nbsp;<em>Dabiq&nbsp;</em>- Issue 12</span></a></span><br /> <br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The eleventh issue of the Islamic State’s propaganda magazine is called <strong><em>From the Battle of Al-Ahzab to the War of Coalitions</em>. </strong>Al-Ahzab refers to a battle in the <a class="glossary-item" href="http://www.clarionproject.org/glossary/quran/">Quran</a> between a coalition of Meccan tribes and the nascent forces of Islam.  ISIS attacks al-Qaeda and castigates the Taliban for concealing the  death of Mullah Omar. ISIS also accuses the Shiite messiah (<a class="glossary-item" href="http://www.clarionproject.org/glossary/mahdi/">Mahdi</a>)  of being the dajjal (devil) in league with the Jews. More is directed  at women, who are urged to have children and care for their jihadi  husbands.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">ISIS also tout their establishment of gold dinars as currency and  boast of having captured a Norwegian and a Chinese hostage, who are  offered up for ransom in full page adverts.</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.clarionproject.org/docs/Issue%2011%20-%20From%20the%20battle%20of%20Al-Ahzab%20to%20the%20war%20of%20coalitions.pdf"><em>Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine: </em><em>Dabiq </em>Issue 11</a></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The tenth issue of the Islamic State's&nbsp;<em>Dabiq&nbsp;</em>magazine is called&nbsp;<em><strong>The Laws of All or the Laws of Men</strong></em>.&nbsp;It&nbsp;opened by praising the deadly simultaneous <a href="http://www.clarionproject.org/analysis/it-doesnt-matter-which-group-carried-out-fridays-attacks">terror attacks in Tunisia, Kuwait and France</a> and the massive casualties caused. <span>It  calls on children to obey Allah (ie. ISIS) before their parents and  wives to leave their husbands who fight ISIS. It also boasts of  expansions in the Caucasus and recruitment in Afghanistan.&nbsp;</span></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Since it is the Ramadan issue, it discusses the historical victories  of some of the early Muslim armies during Ramadan as well as expounding  on the holiness of the month.</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.clarionproject.org/docs/Issue%2010%20-%20The%20Laws%20of%20Allah%20or%20the%20Laws%20of%20Men.pdf"><em>Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine:</em><em> </em><em>Dabiq&nbsp;</em>Issue 10</a></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The ninth issue of the Islamic State's&nbsp;<em>Dabiq&nbsp;</em>magazine is called&nbsp;<strong><em>They Plot and <a class="glossary-item" href="http://www.clarionproject.org/glossary/allah/">Allah</a> Plots</em></strong>,  referring to the central feature of the magazine which argues that  Islamic State supporters should not fear any plans to defeat them since  Allah controls the world. The issue focuses on legitimacy - both  attacking that of its enemies in Syria and the surrounding Arab nations,  and in building up its own, with pieces on the importance of jihad.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Most shockingly this issue ran a lengthy segments admitting to and  justifying sex slavery. It threatens to sell US first Lady Michelle  Obama into sexual slavery for a third of a dinar.&nbsp;</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://media.clarionproject.org/files/islamic-state/isis-isil-islamic-state-magazine-issue%2B9-they-plot-and-allah-plots-sex-slavery.pdf">Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine: <em>Dabiq&nbsp;</em>Issue 9</a></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The eighth issue of the Islamic State's&nbsp;<em>Dabiq&nbsp;</em>magazine is called&nbsp;<em><strong>Shari'ah Alone Will Rule Africa. </strong></em>Like other issues of&nbsp;<em>Dabiq </em>it  focuses on Islamic State successes, leaving out the group's defeats in  strategic areas of Iraq and Syria to focus on Africa. It emphasizes the  pledge of allegiance from Boko Haram in Nigeria and terror attacks in  Libya and Tunisia. It tries to portray an organization with a future by  glorifying its child soldier program and undermining the legitimacy of  Al-Qaeda affiliat Jabhat al-Nusra by attacking its allies as  'nationalists' and therefore un-Islamic.&nbsp;</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://media.clarionproject.org/files/islamic-state/isis-isil-islamic-state-magazine-issue+8-sharia-alone-will-rule-africa.pdf">Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine:&nbsp;<em>Dabiq&nbsp;</em>- Issue 8</a></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The seventh issue of the Islamic State's&nbsp;<em>Dabiq</em>&nbsp;magazine is entitled <strong><em>From Hypocrisy to Apostasy</em></strong>.  It begins with a declaration of war against Japan. Dabiq then boasts  about the murder of the Jordanian pilot by immolation, before going on  to give advice for would be leaders within the Islamic State. It  reiterates their commitments to war, arguing that “Islam is the religion  of the sword.” It then proceeds to tout its successes in Egypt and  Libya. It reiterates its division of the world into two camps and  includes interviews with jihadists and hostage John Cantlie.&nbsp;</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://media.clarionproject.org/files/islamic-state/islamic-state-dabiq-magazine-issue-7-from-hypocrisy-to-apostasy.pdf">Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine:&nbsp;<em>Dabiq -&nbsp;</em>Issue 7</a></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><em style="line-height: 22px;"><strong><br /></strong></em></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The sixth issue of <em>Dabiq</em> is called "<em><strong>Al-Qa'idah of Waziristan: A Testimony From Within</strong>."&nbsp;</em>This  issue begins by taking responsibility for the terrorist attack in  Sydney that killed two at St. Martin's place and again calls on the  Islamic State's supporters worldwide to carry out killings of Westerners  whenever and wherever they can without revealing their intentions by  discussing them. Most of the rest of the magazine focuses on internal  jihadi disputes, criticizing the Islamic State's detractors from within  the jihadi movement. &nbsp;</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://media.clarionproject.org/files/islamic-state/isis-isil-islamic-state-magazine-issue-6-al-qaeda-of-waziristan.pdf">Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine: <em>Dabiq&nbsp;</em>- Issue 6&nbsp;</a></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The fifth issue of <em>Dabiq</em>&nbsp;is named after the Islamic State slogan, '<strong>Remaining and Expanding</strong>.'  In this theme, it announces the expansion of the Islamic State into  Sinai, Libya, Yemen, Algeria and the Arabian Peninsula after accepting  pledges of loyalty (bay'ah) from terrorist groups there. It also  announces the minting of gold dinars and silver dirhams in order to  separate it from the international fiat currency markets and build the  economy of the Islamist state.&nbsp;</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://media.clarionproject.org/files/islamic-state/isis-isil-islamic-state-magazine-issue-5-remaining-and-expanding.pdf">Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine:&nbsp;<em>Dabiq&nbsp;</em>- Issue 5</a></span><br /> <br /> <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The fourth issue of <em>Dabiq</em> is entitled "<strong>The Failed Crusade</strong>."  It focuses on the attempts by the U.S.-led coalition to counter the  Islamic State and mocks what the Islamists regard as a campaign doomed  to fail. They express their certainty saying "This religion is the one  promised with victory." The picture on the cover is of the iconic St.  Peter's Square in Rome, displaying the group's ambitions of world  conquest.</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://media.clarionproject.org/files/islamic-state/islamic-state-isis-magazine-Issue-4-the-failed-crusade.pdf">Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine:&nbsp;<em>Dabiq</em>&nbsp;- Issue 4</a></span><br /> <br /> <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span>The third issue of&nbsp;</span><em>Dabiq, "<strong>The Call to Hijrah"</strong></em><span>&nbsp;focuses on the jihadists' call to Muslims worldwide to move to Iraq and Syria to join the caliphate as soon as possible.&nbsp;</span><em>Hijrah&nbsp;</em><span>is Arabic for</span><em>&nbsp;'</em><span>migration' and refers to the journey of the founder of Islam, Mohammed, and his companions from Mecca to Medinah in 622 C.E.</span><span>&nbsp;The comparison is very deliberate and intended to invoke religious nostalgia.&nbsp;</span></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://media.clarionproject.org/files/09-2014/isis-isil-islamic-state-magazine-Issue-3-the-call-to-hijrah.pdf">Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine:&nbsp;<em>Dabiq</em>&nbsp;- Issue 3</a></span><br /> <br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The second issue of&nbsp;<em>Dabiq</em>, "<em><strong>The Flood</strong>,"</em>&nbsp;uses  the metaphor of the story of Noah to put across a stark message: you  are either with the Islamic State, or against them and doomed to be  destroyed. It calls on all Muslims around the world to pledge loyalty to  the Islamic State and to move there immediately. There is also a  section on the attempts to resolve the disputes between the Islamic  State and other Jihadi factions such as Jabhat al-Nusra by means of&nbsp;<em>mubahalah</em>, an Islamic religious arbitration process.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://media.clarionproject.org/files/09-2014/isis-isil-islamic-state-magazine-Issue-2-the-flood.pdf">Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine:&nbsp;<em>Dabiq</em>&nbsp;- Issue 2</a></span><br /> <br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The first issue of <em>Dabiq</em>, "<strong><em>The&nbsp;</em></strong><em><strong>Return of Khilafah"</strong>&nbsp;</em>is  focused on the declaration of the caliphate and what that means. Some  of the ideology behind the group is explained in an attempt to persuade  more Muslims to join. It also explains the name of the magazine, and  boasts of ISIS' victories.&nbsp;<span>It also talks  about efforts made to build support among local tribal groups, reporting  their pledges of loyalty to Abu Bakr al-Baghadi, the self-appointed  caliph of the Islamic State.</span></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://media.clarionproject.org/files/09-2014/isis-isil-islamic-state-magazine-Issue-1-the-return-of-khilafah.pdf">Islamic State (ISIS, ISIL) Magazine: <em>Dabiq</em> - Issue 1</a></span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span><span><span><span style="font-weight: normal;"><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>S<span>ee AWOL's full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.co.uk/2015/12/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2204932130062693261/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/12/open-access-journal-dabiq.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2204932130062693261"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2204932130062693261"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/12/open-access-journal-dabiq.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Dabiq"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
