<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7346304604330770896</id>
    <published>2015-01-02T11:03:00.002-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-02T11:03:43.551-05:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <title type="text">New Open Access Journal: Frontiers in Digital Archaeology</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a
      href="http://www.frontiersin.org/Digital_Archeology/about">Frontiers in Digital
      Archaeology</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div
      id="ctl00_ctl00_MainContentPlaceHolder_ContentAreaMainContent_divMissionStatementCot"><span
      style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Digital Archeology</i> is a specialty section of
      Frontiers in Digital Humanities.<br /></span> <span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><i>Frontiers in Digital Archaeology</i> is a specialty section of
      Frontiers in Digital Humanities that offers a forum for showcasing, discussing, and developing
      computer and network based approaches to archaeological research, conservation, and
      dissemination. In our quest to understand how humans became who we are, archaeologists have
      always been early adopters of promising new technologies. Computers and the internet have been
      no exception to this rule. The Digital Archaeology specialty section will publish a variety of
      contributions from thought pieces about the direction of Digital Archaeology, to innovations in
      digital field, lab, or curatorial methods, experimental results in computational archaeology,
      and any high quality examples of the application of computer or network based tools to
      archaeological research and education. Scholarship on the Archaeology of the Digital is welcome
      as part of the study of the human past. Through publishing a mix of vision and concrete
      results, we hope to contribute significantly to the development of a truly Digital
      Archaeology.<br /></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Digital
      Archeology</i> welcomes submissions of the following <a
      href="http://www.frontiersin.org/Journal/ArticleType.aspx?name=Digital_Archeology">tier 1
      articles</a>: Book Review, Editorial, General Commentary, Hypothesis &amp; Theory,
      Methods, Mini Review, Opinion, Original Research, Perspective, Review and Technology
      Report.<br /><br /> All manuscripts must be submitted directly to the section
      <i>Digital Archeology</i>, where they are peer reviewed by the associate and review
      editors of the specialty section.<br /><br /> Articles published in the section
      <i>Digital Archeology</i> will be subject to the <a
      href="http://www.frontiersin.org/about/evaluationsystem">Frontiers evaluation
      system</a> after online publication. Authors of published original research with the
      highest impact, as judged democratically by the readers, will be invited by the Chief Editor to
      write a prestigious Frontiers <a
      href="http://www.frontiersin.org/Journal/ArticleType.aspx?name=Digital_Archeology">Focused
      Review</a> - a tier 2 article. This is referred to as "<a
      href="http://www.frontiersin.org/about/tieringsystem">democratic tiering</a>". The
      author selection is based on article impact analytics of original research published in all
      Frontiers specialty journals and sections. Focused Reviews are centered on the original
      discovery, place it into a broader context, and aim to address the wider community across all
      of Digital Humanities.<br /></span></div><div class="clear">
      </div><div class="colTitle_withbg"> <h2> <span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><span
      id="ctl00_ctl00_MainContentPlaceHolder_ContentAreaMainContent_lblOpenAccessStatement">Open
      Access Statement</span></span> </h2></div><span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><span
      id="ctl00_ctl00_MainContentPlaceHolder_ContentAreaMainContent_lblOpenAccessStatementContent"></span></span><br
      /><div id="staticContentWrapp"><div class="float_left w100pc mainPage"><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">Frontiers’ philosophy is that all research is for the benefit of
      humankind. Research is the product of an investment by society and therefore its fruits should
      be returned to all people without borders or discrimination, serving society universally and in
      a transparent fashion.</span> </div></div></blockquote><blockquote
      class="tr_bq"><div id="staticContentWrapp"><div class="float_left w100pc
      mainPage"><span style="font-size: x-small;">That is why Frontiers provides online free
      and open access to all of its research publications. For more information on open access click
      <a href="http://www.frontiersin.org/about/openaccess">here</a>.</span><br
      /> </div></div><br /></blockquote><br /><div
      style="text-align: center;">See the full <a
      href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List
      of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div>]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7346304604330770896/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/01/new-open-access-journal-frontiers-in.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7346304604330770896"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7346304604330770896"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/01/new-open-access-journal-frontiers-in.html"
         title="New Open Access Journal: Frontiers in Digital Archaeology"/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
