<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7823714498430302958</id>
   <published>2016-12-02T14:49:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-12-02T14:49:06.083-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Fayyum"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egypt"/>
   <title type="text">Karanis Housing Project</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://karanishousingproject.org/">Karanis Housing Project</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Karanis was a Greco-Roman town located in Egypt's Fayoum Region. Founded  in the third century BCE, the town remained inhabited until the fifth century CE.  A small population of Roman mercenaries lived in the primarily agrarian town,  where sustenance farmers produced crops such as wheat, barley, olives, figs,  and walnuts. Alexandria, one of the major centers of Roman trade, lay a mere  124 miles to the north of Karanis, making this small, rural town a gateway to  more populated and urban areas.</span><br /><br />                  <span style="font-size: x-small;">The site was primarily excavated by a team from the University of Michigan,  lead by Francis W. Kelsey, in the 1920s. However, Kelsey was not the first  person to show interest in Karanis; local farmers had been obtaining  government permits to remove nitrogen-rich soil from the site to use as  fertilizer (<em>sebbakh</em>) up until the early twentieth century, and the  papyri they inevitably unearthed caught the attention of English scholars  Bernard Pyne Grenfell and Arthur Surridge Hunt, who completed minor  excavations of the site in 1895 before moving to a different site. As a result, Kelsey and his team were forced to work around whole swaths of the town that  had been destroyed by earlier activities -- most notably, an area right in the  center of the Karanis mound. The Michigan team completed a wonderfully thorough excavation of the areas that remained intact, cataloging each artifact and  making careful note of where exactly each item was discovered. This provides  crucial information to archeologists and classicists who wish to consider  artifacts in their original contexts.</span><br /><br />                  <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Karanis Housing Project seeks to bring this valuable information into the  twenty-first century by digitizing the dig and making a comprehensive list  of finds easily accessible and searchable online. While still in its early  stages, the model developed based on data from Karanis will eventually be applied to other excavations, providing a way to analyze finds and query  specific artifacts that is far more user-friendly than sifting through boxes of  field notes. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="collapse navbar-collapse">                    <ul class="nav navbar-nav"><li class="active">                            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://karanishousingproject.org/index.html">Home</a>                        </span></li><li>                            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://karanishousingproject.org/map.html">Map</a></span>                        </li><li>                            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://karanishousingproject.org/pottery.php">Pottery</a></span>                        </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">                            <a href="http://karanishousingproject.org/about.html">About</a></span>                        </li></ul></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">                    </blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7823714498430302958/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/12/karanis-housing-project.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7823714498430302958"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7823714498430302958"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/12/karanis-housing-project.html"
         title="Karanis Housing Project"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
