<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8013897611597124313</id>
   <published>2016-04-25T18:45:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-04-25T18:45:04.589-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Blog"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Latin"/>
   <title type="text">Reading, Writing, Romans: The blog of the Ashmolean Latin Inscriptions Project (AshLI) </title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.ashmolean.org/ashwpress/latininscriptions">Reading, Writing, Romans: The blog of the Ashmolean Latin Inscriptions Project (AshLI</a><a href="http://www.ashmolean.org/ashwpress/latininscriptions">)&nbsp;</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="" height="46" id="header-img" src="http://www.ashmolean.org/ashwpress/latininscriptions/files/2014/01/cropped-black-header-extended-more-copy.jpg" width="400" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Ashmolean Latin Inscriptions Project (AshLI) is a three-way  collaboration between Warwick University, Oxford University and the  Ashmolean Museum, supported by the Arts and Humanities Research Council.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Our Aims</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">We love Latin inscriptions. Really. And we want other people to love  them too. Using the fantastic collection from the Ashmolean Museum,  we’ve set ourselves some challenges, all of which we have to meet before  September 2016:</span><br /> <ol><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">To research and catalogue all the Latin inscriptions in the  Ashmolean Museum. The last person to do this was Richard Chandler when  he wrote <em>Marmora Oxoniensia</em> in 1763. That gives us plenty to do.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">To set up new displays of Latin inscriptions in the Ashmolean. These  will be on themes like death and burial, the Roman army, slaves and  freed-people, literacy in the Roman Empire and the lives of Roman women.  For us, inscriptions are about people, not just letter shapes or  carving techniques.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">To produce teaching resources that can be downloaded from the  Ashmolean Education Department for use in Primary and Secondary schools,  and to devise new museum visits for students who are interested in the  lives of the Romans.</span></li></ol><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>The AshLI Team</strong></span><br /> <ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www2.warwick.ac.uk/fac/arts/classics/staff/alisoncooley/">Professor Alison Cooley</a>, </strong>is  Principal Investigator for the project and Head of Warwick University’s  Department of Classics and Ancient History. Alison is a specialist in  Latin inscriptions, and is taking on the challenge of writing the new  catalogue.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://www.classics.ox.ac.uk/abigailbaker.html">Dr Abigail Baker</a>&nbsp;</strong>is an archaeologist and museologist,&nbsp;based at Oxford’s Centre for the Study of Ancient Documents (<a href="http://www.csad.ox.ac.uk/" target="_blank">CSAD</a>).  She’s responsible for bringing AshLI’s work to the public through  education projects, museum displays and social media. She also works on  the&nbsp;EpiDoc based online catalogue – making the Ashmolean’s inscriptions  accessible&nbsp;for free online.</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">Other members of the team are <strong>Dr Paul Roberts</strong>, the Keeper of Antiquities at the Ashmolean Museum, <strong>Dr Charles Crowther</strong> from Oxford’s Centre for the Study of Ancient Documents, and&nbsp;<strong>Stephanie Lane</strong>, who is studying material from the project as part of her PhD on Roman Literacy.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">AshLI’s access to the Ashmolean’s inscriptions is masterminded by the Antiquities’ Collections Manager <strong>Helen Hovey. </strong>We’ve also had the specialist help of <strong>Ben Altshuler </strong>and <strong>Sarah Norodom </strong>for RTI capture of our more challenging stones.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Former members of the team still keep in touch. <strong><a href="http://www2.le.ac.uk/departments/archaeology/people/academics/masseglia">Dr Jane Masséglia</a></strong>&nbsp;(who  used to work on education and public communication for the project) is  now a lecturer in Ancient History at the University of Leicester.&nbsp;<strong><a href="http://www.icls.sas.ac.uk/about-us/staff">Dr Hannah Cornwell</a>&nbsp;</strong>(who  used to work on the project’s online database, digital images and  podcasts)&nbsp;is now a Leverhulme Early Career Fellow at the Institute of  Classical Studies.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8013897611597124313/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/04/reading-writing-romans-blog-of.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8013897611597124313"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8013897611597124313"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/04/reading-writing-romans-blog-of.html"
         title="Reading, Writing, Romans: The blog of the Ashmolean Latin Inscriptions Project (AshLI) "/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
