<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8072578780794122956</id>
    <published>2014-02-22T08:11:00.000-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-24T09:31:26.908-05:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Online Course"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Bible"/>
    <title type="text">MOOC: The Bible's Prehistory, Purpose, and Political Future</title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/biblefuture">The Bible's
      Prehistory, Purpose, and Political Future</a><br /><div
      class="coursera-course2-instructors-info"><a class="internal-home"
      data-link-type="instructor-name"
      href="https://www.coursera.org/instructor/jacobwright"><span
      class="coursera-course2-instructor-name">Jacob L. Wright</span></a><span
      class="coursera-course2-instructor-university">&nbsp;</span></div><div
      class="coursera-course2-instructors-info"><a class="internal-home"
      data-link-type="instructor-university" href="https://www.coursera.org/emory"><span
      class="coursera-course2-instructor-university">Emory
      University</span></a></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div
      data-user-generated="data-user-generated" style="margin-top: 12px;"><span
      style="font-size: x-small;">How and why was the Bible written? This course synthesizes
      fascinating recent research in biblical studies and presents a powerful new thesis: The Bible's
      primary purpose is not religious but political. Facing catastrophic defeat, the biblical
      authors created a new form of community. Their achievements bear directly on modern questions
      of politics, economics, and theology.</span></div><hr
      class="coursera-full-page-divider-no_padding" style="clear: both;" /><h2
      class="coursera-course-heading" data-msg="coursera-course-about"><span style="font-size:
      x-small;">About the Course</span></h2><div class="coursera-course-detail"
      data-user-generated="data-user-generated"><span style="font-size: x-small;">With its
      walls razed to ground by Babylon’s armies, Jerusalem joined a long line of ancient vanquished
      cities—from Ur and Nineveh and Persepolis to Babylon itself. While some recovered from the
      destruction, others did not.&nbsp; But none responded to political catastrophe by
      fashioning the kind of elaborate and enduring monument to their own downfall that we find in
      the Bible. Most conquered populations viewed their subjugation as a source of shame. They
      consigned it to oblivion, opting instead to extol the golden ages of the past.&nbsp; The
      biblical authors in contrast reacted to loss by composing extensive writings that acknowledge
      collective failure, reflect deeply upon its causes, and discover thereby a ground for
      collective hope. <br /><br />Working through colorful biblical and ancient Near
      Eastern texts, and drawing on an array of comparative examples, the course illustrates the
      thoroughgoing manner with which biblical authors responded to defeat by advancing a demotic
      agenda that places the community at the center. The aim of the biblical authors was to create a
      nation, and they sought to realize this goal via a shared text, which includes stories and
      songs, wisdom and laws. This corpus of writings belongs, without a doubt, to humanity’s
      greatest achievements. Whereas the great civilizations of the Near East invested their energies
      and resources into monuments of stone that could be destroyed by invading armies, the biblical
      authors left a literary legacy that has been intensively studied until the present day. More
      important, these authors’ visionary response to defeat brought to light a radical new
      wisdom:&nbsp; the notion that a people is greater than the state which governs it, and that
      a community can survive collapse when all of its members can claim a piece of the pie and
      therefore have a reason to take an active part in its collective life. <br /><br
      />The objectives of the course are to show: <br />—how the Bible emerged from
      large-scale corporate crisis and rupture;<br />—that in our present state of uncertainty
      and instability we have much to learn from the various strategies the biblical authors adopted
      to create an enduring “people of the book”;<br />—that one doesn’t have to believe in God
      or accept the historicity of the Bible in order to appreciate its profound political
      messages;<br />—that the Bible offers modern societies a model for creating communities
      around a shared collection of texts, songs, and laws;<br />—and that the Bible itself has
      a major role to play in our futures.</span></div><h2
      class="coursera-course-heading" data-msg="coursera-course-syllabus" style="clear:
      both;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Course
      Syllabus</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Week 1: The
      Riddle That Has Yet To Be Solved</b><br />The Bible's Purpose<br />Books in
      Ancient Religions<br />Between "Church and State"<br />Theologies of the
      Bible<br />A Shared Text<br />The Bible as a "Pedagogical Program of
      Peoplehood"<br /><br /><b>Week 2: The Rise and Fall</b><br
      />Israel's Place in the World of the Ancient Near East<br />The Emergence of Two
      Competing Kingdoms<br />Military Triumphs<br />The Onslaught of Imperial
      Powers<br />Defeat and Deportation <br />Conditions of Conquest<br /><br
      /><b>Week 3: The Making of the Bible as a Response to Defeat</b><br
      />Diaspora and Divided Communities<br />Creating a Shared Past and Common
      Ancestors<br />The Pentateuch and Historical Narratives<br />One People with
      Multiple Law Codes<br />Creating a Collection of National Songs and Laments<br
      />Reinterpreting Prophecies<br />Comparative Cases: English and German
      History&nbsp; <br /><br /><b>Week 4: Reinventing the Hero</b><br
      />Martial Valor, Masculinity, and Martyrdom<br />Long Life versus Glorified Heroic
      Death<br />The New Role of the Family<br />From Battles to Building<br
      />Comparatives Cases: From the Crow Nation to Jane Austen<br /><br
      /><b>Week 5: A Wise and Discerning People&nbsp; </b><br />The Role of
      Education<br />National Education Programs: From 19th Century Germany to the Dalai
      Lama<br />From Deuteronomy to Ezra-Nehemiah<br />Freedom of Information and Open
      Access<br />Making Priestly Knowledge Public<br />The Attempts of the State to
      Control Prophets <br />Divine Knowledge for the People, Not Solely the King <br
      />The Reason Why Biblical Writings Survived Catastrophes <br /><br
      /><b>Week 6: Covenant and Kinship</b><br />The Rise of Empires<br
      />One God<br />A New "Political-Theology"<br />Covenantal Ethics of
      Peoplehood<br />The Power of Law<br />Protecting the Individual and Defending
      Difference<br />Caring for the Land<br /><br /><b>Week 7: The Bible's
      Future</b><br />The Bible's Pedagogical and Political Purpose<br />The
      Bible's Radical Theology<br />The Bible as an Attempt to Unify Rival Communities<br
      />The Bible's Impact on Political Identities Throughout the World<br />The Bible's
      Role in the Public Sphere and in Secular Society<br />The Bible as a Model for New Forms
      of Community </span></blockquote>]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8072578780794122956/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/02/open-mooc-bibles-prehistory-purpose-and.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8072578780794122956"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8072578780794122956"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/02/open-mooc-bibles-prehistory-purpose-and.html"
         title="MOOC: The Bible's Prehistory, Purpose, and Political Future"/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
