<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8010871148755570217</id>
   <published>2014-08-26T16:53:00.003-04:00</published>
   <updated>2014-08-26T16:53:42.527-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Jew and Judean: A Forum on Politics and Historiography in the Translation of Ancient Texts</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/jew-judean-forum/">Jew and Judean: A Forum on Politics and Historiography in the Translation of Ancient Texts</a><br /> 					 					<span class="heading-date">August 26, 2014</span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Have scholars erased the Jews from Antiquity?</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Jew or Judean Slider" class="alignleft wp-image-6269 size-medium" height="197" src="http://14chrg47qoru3d1nk6pwnf5v.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Jew-or-Judean-Slider-300x197.jpg" width="300" />The&nbsp;<em>Marginalia Review of Books</em>&nbsp;aims  to host conversations&nbsp;about serious&nbsp;books and important ideas. Taking  advantage of the&nbsp;opportunities supplied by&nbsp;new media, we  are&nbsp;providing&nbsp;space for constructive debates&nbsp;on&nbsp;the questions that shape  how&nbsp;we understand the world.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Adele Reinhartz’s essay in <em>MRB</em>&nbsp;on June 24 set off a vibrant discussion in the comments section and in the&nbsp;<em>MRB</em>&nbsp;editors’  inboxes. The range of responses to the piece dotted the spectrum from  full support to indignation, proving that a sizable readership wanted to  debate these ideas further. The forum is released today only two months  after the Reinhartz essay thanks to the good will and the efficiency of  the participants. The essays, beginning with Reinhartz’s original piece  and concluding with her response to the collection, investigate the  political and historiographical considerations involved in the  translation of ancient texts, in particular how modern translators and  historians ought to deal with the translation of the Greek word <i>ioudaios </i>(<span style="color: #001320;">Ἰουδαῖος</span>).</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Along with the forum,&nbsp;<em>MRB</em> is excited to release an e-book  version of the discussion&nbsp;free for our readers. We hope that you will  read and share with as many people as you wish, and we hope it becomes a  resource for use in seminars, classrooms, and other group settings. You  can download the e-book in <a href="http://db.orangedox.com/H3lgKno1Ax6G92tvtM/Jew%20and%20Judean.epub" target="_blank">epub format</a>&nbsp;(most readers)&nbsp;or in <a href="http://db.orangedox.com/G7DnZoecZkHwtQnWtd/Jew%20and%20Judean.mobi">mobi format</a>&nbsp;(Amazon Kindle). &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;— Timothy Michael Law</span><br /> <div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: black;">※</span></span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Adele Reinhartz</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: black;">I am  alarmed by the growing invisibility of Jews and Judaism in English  translations of ancient texts and scholarship about them. The use of  “Judeans” to translate all occurrences of&nbsp;</span><em style="color: black;">ioudaioi</em><span style="color: black;">&nbsp;achieves  neither the scholarly precision nor the ethical high ground that  scholars claim. On the contrary, the proliferation of Judeans  inadvertently creates confusion and misunderstanding and merely  sidesteps the issue without addressing the anti-Jewish or even  anti-Semitic potential of texts such as the Gospel of John.</span></span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/vanishing-jews-antiquity-adele-reinhartz/">Read more …</a>]</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Steve Mason</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">All humanities disciplines invite us to  explore the possibilities of human existence, but history opens the door  to conditions that have really existed before our time. No one should  be naïve enough, however, to think that we can simply enter the distant  past as it really was, for it does not exist now. The vehicle that takes  us there we construct today. We pose our questions about the past and  gather any surviving evidence that seems relevant.</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">…</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The problem of translating with sensitivity to ancient contexts is basic to the research and teaching of all ancient historians.</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/ancient-jews-judeans-different-questions-different-answers-steve-mason/" title="Ancient Jews or Judeans? Different Questions, Different Answers – By Steve Mason">Read more …</a>]</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Daniel Schwartz</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The question whether we should use “Jew”  or “Judean” when writing about antiquity should, I assume, be approached  no differently than other questions concerning the use of our modern  English vocabulary for ancient phenomena. Just as we normally look at  the evidence concerning antiquity and, when turning to describing what  we see, strive to choose the English words that best correspond to what  we see, so too in this case.</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/different-tasks-translators-historians-daniel-r-schwartz/" title="The Different Tasks of Translators and Historians – By Daniel R. Schwartz">Read more …</a>]</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Annette Yoshiko Reed</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">At first sight, the debate might seem to  pivot on the choice between Mason’s search for the most accurate English  equivalent of the term’s meaning in the first century and Reinhartz’s  concern to tailor its translation to the understanding (and potential  misunderstandings) of present-day readers. Yet the ramifications are  also much wider. Just as Mason shows how the translation of a single  term can engage the very nature of identity in the ancient world, so  Reinhartz also calls us to critical reflection concerning the degree to  which modern historical research can be isolated from its own historical  contexts. Rather than arguing for one side or another, I would thus  like to push further on both fronts — in part by asking what we miss  when we plot the different meanings of&nbsp;<em>ioudaios</em>&nbsp;along a straight line towards the concept of “Judaism” as “religion.”</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/ioudaios-religion-annette-yoshiko-reed/" title="Ioudaios before and after “Religion” – By Annette Yoshiko Reed">Read more …</a>]</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Joan Taylor</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="s1">To say, as Malina does, that a “Jew”&nbsp;</span><span class="s1">is  an anachronistic category in the first century erects a wall between  modernity and antiquity. I do not want to sever Jesus from the  designation “Jew”&nbsp;</span><span class="s1">and insist on it being  relevant only to a later time, because that might sever him from a  Judaism today that embraces diversity within its past. To say that Jesus  was a Jew is not to say that he was a Jew as the rabbis would define  that term but a Jew as one might define him in the first century.</span></span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/judean-jew-jesus-paul/" title="“Judean” and “Jew”, Jesus and Paul – Joan Taylor">Read more …</a>]</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Malcolm Lowe</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">If a word — or some use of that word — is  lacking in ancient sources before a certain date, we should be cautious  both about assuming&nbsp;<i>and</i>&nbsp;about denying that it existed in earlier  times. Moreover, we should beware of assuming that if a word or use of a  word is not found in ancient authors, then those authors did not have  the&nbsp;<i>concept</i>&nbsp;denoted by that word.</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/concepts-words-malcolm-lowe/" title="Concepts and Words – By Malcolm Lowe">Read more …</a>]</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Jonathan Klawans</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Is it really the case that the  translation “Jew” has done great harm? If I am not mistaken, the  question about “Jew” and “Judean” is, as it is taking place here,  primarily an English-language question. Far be it from me to deny the  influence of anti-Semitism in the English-speaking world. But let<span lang="FR">’</span>s  be frank: on the whole, Jews have been and continue to be rather safe  wherever the English language is spoken, even though all the Bibles talk  about Jews.</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/invented-revolution-jonathan-klawans/" title="An Invented Revolution – By Jonathan Klawans">Read more …</a>]</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ruth Sheridan</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">It is not sufficient to say that  subsequent Christian interpreters of the Gospel of John mistakenly  identified the narrative’s “Jews” with real flesh-and-blood Jews living  among them — with disastrously violent consequences — and that they&nbsp;<i>mis</i>interpreted  John’s sense. It is also not enough to claim, on that basis, that the  imperative facing us now is to “restore” the correct meaning (the  entho-geographic one) to the text, translating&nbsp;<i>hoi Ioudaioi</i>&nbsp;as “the Judeans.” This avoids the fact that texts&nbsp;<i>do</i>&nbsp;carry  within them the potential to become loosed from their authorial  moorings and to reach beyond the particularities of their original  reception.</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/hiding-fourth-gospels-tragic-reception-history/" title="Hiding from the Fourth Gospel’s Tragic Reception History – By Ruth Sheridan">Read more …</a>]</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">James Crossley</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The&nbsp;<em>ioudaios</em>&nbsp;debate is an  especially good example of the impossibility of escaping ideology, no  matter how disinterested a given scholar might be and no matter how  unware a scholar might be. We have seen how easy it is to detect what we  might crudely label “pro-Israel” and “anti-Israel” stances, ethical  concerns about anti-Semitism, and a marginalizing of Palestinian  concerns. Of course, there are genuine concerns about the pervasiveness  of ideology for academic research. But we can perhaps calm some of these  fears.</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/difference-translation-makes-ideological-analysis-ioudaios-debate-james-crossley/" title="What a Difference a Translation Makes! An Ideological Analysis of the Ioudaios Debate – By James Crossley">Read more …</a>]</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Adele Reinhartz</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">While not all participants in the Forum  explicitly address anti-Semitism or its seemingly&nbsp;more benign variant,  anti-Judaism, I believe that all recognize that the&nbsp;<em>ioudaios</em>&nbsp;question  does have implications for this sensitive issue. As some of the  responses note, the question of translation may matter less when readers  have ready access to commentaries and more in the case, for example, of  New Testaments that are used liturgically and therefore, in most cases,  without commentary.</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[<a href="http://marginalia.lareviewofbooks.org/response-jew-judean-forum-adele-reinhartz/" title="A Response to the Jew and Judean Forum – By Adele Reinhartz">Read more …</a>]</span></div></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8010871148755570217/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/08/jew-and-judean-forum-on-politics-and.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8010871148755570217"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8010871148755570217"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/08/jew-and-judean-forum-on-politics-and.html"
         title="Jew and Judean: A Forum on Politics and Historiography in the Translation of Ancient Texts"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
