<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6815438520487257166</id>
   <published>2015-01-13T06:21:00.003-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-01-13T11:18:48.179-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Digital resources for research in Near Eastern Studies (Bibliotheca Orientalis 71 3/4 (2014), Jubilee fascicle)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.nino-leiden.nl/publications.aspx?id=10"><i>Bibliotheca Orientalis</i> 71 3/4 (2014), Jubilee fascicle on <b>digital resources for research in Near Eastern Studies</b>:</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.nino-leiden.nl/img/BiOr71-34_cover.jpg" class="shrinkToFit decoded" src="http://www.nino-leiden.nl/img/BiOr71-34_cover.jpg" height="200" width="153" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The year 2014 marks the 75th anniversary of NINO — <i>The  Netherlands  Institute  for  the Near  Eas</i>t. As one of the initiatives to celebrate this event the editorial board of <i>Bibliotheca  Orientalis</i>decided to devote one of the 2014 issues to reviews of web-based resources on the scholarly subjects covered by the journal. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Bibliotheca  Orientalis</i>— <b>BiOr</b>— has for decades been one of the main review journals for (Ancient) Near Eastern Studies, providing comprehensive and prompt information and reviews on published books in the fields of Near Eastern Archaeology, Egyptology, Assyriology, Arabic and Semitic philology and history, and generally studies on the Middle East. The traditional focus on printed works has of recent neglected an increasing mass of web-based resources. These resources of course incorporate digital access or reference to printed materials, but also provide independent data sets and compilations of otherwise scattered information in new integrated configurations. It is surely highly relevant to consider these still fairly new, but fast developing resources, and we have therefore invited a number of experts to submit overview — or review articles on this aspect of their relevant fields. We are grateful for the enthusiastic and constructive responses to this call by the authors of the contributions presented here in conventional printed form, but simultaneously also in open access digital version on the NINO website (<a href="http://www.nino-leiden.nl/">www.nino-leiden.nl</a>), which allows active links to the referenced sites. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">We have deliberately left the authors free to choose the scope and format of their contribution, knowing that comprehensive assessments are impossible for a sphere which witnesses virtually daily additions and readjustments. Matters have moved considerably from the time not so long ago when scholars depended primarily on their own ‘Zettelkasten’ to a situation where much information is now available at our fingertips on the web. The basic importance and obvious convenience of this change are certainly not in doubt, but the organisation and optimal develop- ments, as well as the ‘side effects’, of this brave new situation deserve serious consideration and debate. Both aspects are reflected in the contributions presented here. Generous listings and com- ments of web-based resources will hopefully be of interest and usefulness to many readers, while broader perspectives touched upon may serve as inspiration for further and future debates – also welcome as contributions to new issues of BiOr ... </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="width: 750px;"><thead><tr><td><a href="http://www.nino-leiden.nl/doc/BiOr71-34_I-403.pdf"><b>Articles</b> published in&nbsp;<i>Bibliotheca Orientalis</i> 71 3/4 (2014), Jubilee fascicle on <b>digital resources for research in Near Eastern Studies</b>:&nbsp;</a><br /><ul><li>Les ressources numériques pour l'égyptologie (W. Claes &amp; E. Van Keer)</li><li>Electronic resources for Graeco-Roman and Christian Egypt: a review of the state of the net (A. Delattre &amp; P. Heilporn)</li><li>Ressources assyriologiques sur internet (D. Charpin)</li><li>Web Resources for Hittitology (F. Giusfredi)</li><li>Web-based Resources in the Field of Old Testament Studies (K. Spronk)</li><li>A ‘lean' approach to digital resources for Ancient Near Eastern archaeology (S. Anastasio &amp; F. Saliola)</li><li>Digital Resources in Middle Eastern Studies (B. Kristiansen)<br />Some digital resources for the study of the Middle East (R.E. Kon)</li></ul></td><td></td><td>1.5 MB</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://www.nino-leiden.nl/doc/BiOr71-34_Arabic.pdf"><b>Arabic summaries</b> of three articles published in<i> Bibliotheca Orientalis</i> 71 3/4 (2014):</a><br /><ul><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Les ressources numériques pour l'égyptologie (W. Claes &amp; E. Van Keer)</span></li><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ressources assyriologiques sur internet (D. Charpin)</span></li><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">A ‘lean' approach to digital resources for Ancient Near Eastern archaeology (S. Anastasio &amp; F. Saliola)</span></li></ul></td></tr></thead></table></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6815438520487257166/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/01/digital-resources-for-research-in-near.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6815438520487257166"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6815438520487257166"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/01/digital-resources-for-research-in-near.html"
         title="Digital resources for research in Near Eastern Studies (Bibliotheca Orientalis 71 3/4 (2014), Jubilee fascicle)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
