<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3108056253595029777</id>
   <published>2016-03-03T17:32:00.002-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-03-03T17:32:49.679-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Bibliography"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Corinth"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greece"/>
   <title type="text">Announcing An Open Bibliography in Corinthian and New Testament Studies</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://corinthianmatters.com/2016/03/03/an-open-bibliography-in-corinthian-and-new-testament-studies/">An Open Bibliography in Corinthian and New Testament&nbsp;Studies</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">First a word on the Corinthian Studies library general.&nbsp;The most up  to date&nbsp;bibliography&nbsp;for Corinthian Studies runs to&nbsp;2,758 individual  items&nbsp;and covers&nbsp;subjects from deep prehistory to the modern era. You  can find other useful&nbsp;bibliographic lists of Corinthian Studies online,  but you won’t&nbsp;find a more comprehensive and searchable open library than  this one. You can access the bibliography&nbsp;in two ways:</span><br /> <ol><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">On the web&nbsp;at the Corinthian Studies <a href="https://www.zotero.org/groups/corinthian_studies/items" target="_blank">Group Library</a>&nbsp;hosted  at Zotero.org. Simply&nbsp;search the library as a whole, or search the  collections within the library by keyword.&nbsp;This only&nbsp;requires that you  visit the&nbsp;Corinthian Studies group library&nbsp;and search or browse through  the collections.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">As<a href="https://drive.google.com/open?id=0ByIQ4FOW0YlQeFpNSF9qOXQ2S2M" target="_blank"> a downloadable RIS file</a>, which can be&nbsp;imported into a bibliographic program such as&nbsp;<a href="http://zotero.org/" target="_blank">Zotero</a>, <a href="http://endnote.com/" target="_blank">EndNote</a>, or <a href="http://refman.com/" target="_blank">Reference&nbsp;Manager</a>.</span></li></ol><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you ask me, you should download and and install&nbsp;a reference  managing program such as Zotero. Using software to mine the  bibliography&nbsp;offers much more powerful and complex&nbsp;search&nbsp;capabilities  than the web version. For an introduction to Zotero and further details  about the Corinthian Studies bibliography, see&nbsp;<a href="http://corinthianmatters.com/bibliography/zotero/" target="_blank">this page</a>. Zotero&nbsp;is&nbsp;free and easy to use. Try it.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="PaulCorinth" class="alignleft  wp-image-3890" height="296" src="https://corinthianmatters.files.wordpress.com/2016/03/paulcorinth.jpg?w=622&amp;h=592" width="311" />The  collected&nbsp;bibliography includes nearly a thosand entries related  to&nbsp;ancient Christianity,&nbsp;Judaism, and New Testament&nbsp;Studies. As I noted a  <a href="http://corinthianmatters.com/2014/03/24/a-new-bibliography-for-1-and-2-corinthians/" target="_blank">couple of years ago</a>,&nbsp;there are plenty of select bibliographic lists floating about related to the Pauline mission, or the study of <em>1 and&nbsp;2</em> Corinthians,<em>&nbsp;</em>but  this&nbsp;collection has a number of key&nbsp;strengths that you will not  find&nbsp;elsewhere.&nbsp;Some highlights for someone interested in understanding  &nbsp;scholarship on, say, some passage in&nbsp;<em>1 Corinthians</em> (much of this applies to other subjects as well, of course):</span><br /> <ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Free.&nbsp;</strong>It is completely free and open to public use,&nbsp;not locked inside&nbsp;a pay-to-use database.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Comprehensive</strong>. The bibliography aims to be&nbsp;comprehensive. It includes articles and books from&nbsp;<em><a href="http://www.worldcat.org/title/urban-religion-in-roman-corinth-interdisciplinary-approaches/oclc/56874310&amp;referer=brief_results" target="_blank">Urban Religion in Roman Corinth</a>&nbsp;</em>(2005), <em><a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=WcPFWtWd-fcC" target="_blank">Corinth in Context</a></em> (2010), and<em>&nbsp;<a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=fcveAQAAQBAJ" target="_blank">Corinth in Contrast</a> </em>(2013). It includes all relevant Corinthian studies material&nbsp;listed in the bibliography of <em>Urban Religion in Roman Corinth,&nbsp;</em><em>Corinth in Context,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/pdf/uploads/CorinthBiblioRev.pdf" target="_blank">Corinth Volume XX</a>,&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876615485" target="_blank">Bridge of the Untiring Sea</a>.&nbsp;</em>And it includes&nbsp;works listed in a number of&nbsp;commentaries&nbsp;on&nbsp;<em>1 and 2 Corinthians</em>, and relevant material from JSTOR and WorldCat searches (see <a href="http://corinthianmatters.com/bibliography/zotero/" target="_blank">this page</a> for more information about coverage).</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Current</strong>. The coverage from 2010-2016 is especially  good, and thereby&nbsp;offers up-to-date&nbsp;views of what scholars are saying  today about&nbsp;Corinth and the New Testament situation.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Open</strong>. Many of the entries&nbsp;include links to  articles, books, and material&nbsp;that are partly or fully accessible online  through journal websites, Google Books, Internet Archive, or Academia.  Abstracts are included when available.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Browsable</strong>.&nbsp;The library is divided into three&nbsp;main  collections (I. Archaeology and History, II. New Testament, Judaism, and  Early Christianity, and III. Geology)&nbsp;and tagged accordingly  (.ARCHAEOLOGY AND HISTORY or .CHRISTIANITY &amp; JUDAISM or .GEOLOGY).  These show up as the first three&nbsp;tags in the Tags area to the lower left  of the <a href="https://www.zotero.org/groups/corinthian_studies/items" target="_blank">Zotero Library </a>(expand  the tags if you don’t see them).&nbsp;An item may belong to  multiple&nbsp;categories. You can also view the most recent material  from&nbsp;2015 by looking at the&nbsp;individual folders.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Searchable</strong>.&nbsp;&nbsp;The collection is tagged&nbsp;with keywords  such as&nbsp;“Roman,”&nbsp;“1 Corinthians”, and “2 Corinthians”. Much of the New  Testament material&nbsp;is also tagged by chapter, e.g.,&nbsp;&nbsp;“_1 Cor. 13”. This  is especially useful&nbsp;f you&nbsp;are looking for some discussion of an  enigmatic passage in&nbsp;<em>1</em> <em>Corinthians</em><em>&nbsp;</em>of a&nbsp;recent discussion of the love chapter.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Variety</strong>. &nbsp;The collection includes articles, books, PhD theses, and sermons</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">The bibliography is a work in progress. There are holes and  inaccuracies&nbsp;and the entire collection needs better tagging. But&nbsp;it does  provide a good place to start.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">And it’s worth noting that&nbsp;the bibliography has been created largely  through my own labor, and&nbsp;student help funded through&nbsp;work studies  positions at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.messiah.edu/" target="_blank">Messiah College</a>.&nbsp;If you’re interested in improving&nbsp;the quality of the collection, I’d be glad to have your help or support.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3108056253595029777/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/03/announcing-open-bibliography-in.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3108056253595029777"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3108056253595029777"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/03/announcing-open-bibliography-in.html"
         title="Announcing An Open Bibliography in Corinthian and New Testament Studies"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
