<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4848406741303189917</id>
   <published>2015-11-05T18:23:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-11-05T18:23:33.219-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Digital Library"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="UK"/>
   <title type="text">Cambridge Digital Library</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/">Cambridge Digital Library</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/img/general/introducingCUDL.jpg" height="97" src="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/img/general/introducingCUDL.jpg" width="200" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Over the course of six centuries Cambridge University      Library's collections have grown from a few dozen volumes into one      of the world's great libraries, with an extraordinary accumulation      of books, maps, manuscripts and journals. These cover every      conceivable aspect of human endeavour, spanning most of the world's      cultural traditions. While parts of the Library's manuscript      collections have already been published in print, microfilm and      digital formats, we are now building a substantial online resource      so that our collections can be much more accessible to students,      researchers and the wider public.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>The first phase</b> of our work on the Cambridge Digital      Library, which ran from 2010 to 2014 was made possible through a      lead gift of £1.5m from Dr Leonard Polonsky. This generous support      has enabled the Library to develop its technical infrastructure and      create significant content, particularly in the areas of faith and      science - two areas of strength within our collections. It has also      enabled us to attract funding from other sources, including the      AHRC, NSF, NEH, JISC and other private donors.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <b>Foundations of Faith</b> strand of content includes      important works from many religious traditions, particularly      Judaism, Islam, Christianity and Buddhism. In its initial phase,      the Digital Library has made available some of the <a href="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/collections/islamic">earliest Qur'anic fragments on       parchment</a>, important manuscripts in Hebrew, including one of the      earliest known copies of the Ten Commandments - the second- century      BCE <a href="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/view/MS-OR-00233">Nash Papyrus</a>, and a large      selection of manuscripts from the <a href="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/collections/genizah">Taylor-Schechter       Genizah Collection</a>, considered by many to be a collection as      significant as the Dead Sea Scrolls. Our online Christian holdings      include the <a href="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/view/MS-NN-00002-00041">Codex Bezae       Cantabrigiensis</a> - one of the most interesting of all New Testament      manuscripts, and the remarkable <a href="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/view/MS-II-00006-00032">Book       of Deer</a>. The end of this first phase is also marked by the release      of more than 500 manuscripts from the Library's extensive <a href="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/collections/sanskrit">Sanskrit collection</a>, including      some of the earliest surviving Buddhist manuscripts.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <b>Foundations of Science</b> content draws on the very strong      collections the Library holds relating to the History of Science.      We began with the papers of <a href="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/collections/newton">Isaac       Newton</a> and by the end of this phase have launched the first part      of a major release of Darwin's manuscripts - the <a href="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/collections/darwin_mss">papers and drafts that led to <i>The        Origin of Species</i></a>. We have also released the <a href="http://cudl.lib.cam.ac.uk/collections/longitude">Papers of the Board of Longitude</a>,      a fascinating and substantial archive charting scientific and      technological endeavors in the eighteenth and early nineteenth      centuries.     </span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4848406741303189917/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/cambridge-digital-library.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4848406741303189917"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4848406741303189917"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/cambridge-digital-library.html"
         title="Cambridge Digital Library"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
