<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4109363790167225146</id>
   <published>2016-05-15T21:41:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-05-15T21:42:23.780-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tell Mardikh"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Syria"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Cuneiform"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Prosopography"/>
   <title type="text">The Prosopography of Ebla Online</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">&nbsp;[First posted in AWOL 28 February 2011. Updated 15 May 2016]</span><br /><br /><a href="http://www.sagas.unifi.it/cmpro-v-p-359.html">The Prosopography of Ebla</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img height="160" src="http://www.sagas.unifi.it/upload/sub/eblaweb/ebla_city.jpg" width="320" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;  The administrative and chancery cuneiform texts of the Archives of the   Ebla Palace G (Tell Mardikh, Syria, 24th century BC) offer an   exceptional anthroponomastic corpus relating to the whole of Syria and   part of Mesopotamia. The personal names in the Ebla texts refer first of   all to members of the elites – sovereigns and high-ranking officials   (including priests) and their relatives – in Ebla itself and in the   other great political capitals of the period, as far as Mari, Nagar and   Kiš. Besides these, the texts record the personal names of minor   palatine officials, of those in charge of the small towns and villages,   and of people belonging to other strata of the population, such as   merchants, artisans, farmers and artists.&nbsp;</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The in-depth study of the   political and cultural history of the Near East in the period of the   Ebla Archives requires from the very outset as reliable an   identification as possible of the individual people mentioned in the   texts. Only an accurate prosopographical analysis makes it possible to   distinguish – often despite cases of homonymy – family memberships,   careers, occupations and geographical origins.&nbsp;</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The repertoire of   personal names established by prosopographical analysis, which also   makes it possible to identify graphic variants, forms the basis for the   complementary onomastic study, aimed at providing a linguistic   interpretation of individual names.&nbsp;</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The individual entries in The   Prosopography of Ebla organise the occurrences of the personal names  of  Ebla according to criteria that enable an initial identification of   those people whose existence and activity were recorded by the Palace G   scribes. Some characteristics are particularly privileged, such as   relations of kinship and dependence, names of functions and professions,   and geographical origins, but some activities are also highlighted.   When possible, each personal name is analysed linguistically. In   addition, a comment on the individual personal names explains the   reasons for disambiguating the occurrences, outlines the political and   social importance of the individual people identified, and provides   basic bibliographical information.&nbsp;</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Prosopography of Ebla  provides further materials useful for research, such as lists of  personnel, bibliographies and links.&nbsp;</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The  present investigation –  begun as the PRIN 2006 project (“Aspetti  linguistici e prosopografici  dell’antroponimia della Siria  settentrionale del XXIV sec. a.C. nei  testi di Ebla”) and then renewed  as PRIN 2008 (“Aspetti linguistici e  prosopografici dell’antroponimia  dei testi di Ebla”) – has been carried  out by two Research Units, one  from the University of Florence, under  the responsibility of Pelio  Fornzaroli and then of Amalia Catagnoti,  and the other from the  University of Rome “La Sapienza”, under the  responsibility of Alfonso  Archi and then of Maria Giovanna Biga. &nbsp;</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   &nbsp;&nbsp; The results were published  first on the website&nbsp;<a href="http://www.antichita.uniroma1.it/node/5879">www.antichita.uniroma1.it/node/5879</a>,  managed by the University  of Rome “La Sapienza”, and then at the  University of Florence at <a href="http://www.ebla.unifi.it/"><strong>The Prosopography of Ebla</strong></a>.  Once  the PRIN 2008 funding had  ended, the research became a project  of the  University of Florence,  under the responsibility of Amalia  Catagnoti.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><ul class="cmpro-blockstyle cmpro-block-page"><li class="cmpro-blockstyle cmpro-block-pageitem cmpro-block-pagelinkitem"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ebla.unifi.it/">HOME PAGE</a></span></li><li class="cmpro-blockstyle cmpro-block-pageitem" style="font-weight: bold;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sagas.unifi.it/vp-337-archive.html">ARCHIVE</a></span></li><li class="cmpro-blockstyle cmpro-block-pageitem"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sagas.unifi.it/vp-338-studies.html">STUDIES</a></span></li><li class="cmpro-blockstyle cmpro-block-pageitem"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sagas.unifi.it/vp-339-links.html">LINKS</a></span></li><li class="cmpro-blockstyle cmpro-block-pageitem"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sagas.unifi.it/vp-340-contacts.html">CONTACTS</a></span></li></ul></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/post-edit.g?blogID=116259103207720939&amp;postID=8246424762897007409" id="data:post.url" name="data:post.title" onclick="return addthis_sendto()" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onmouseover="'return"></a><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"></script></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4109363790167225146/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/02/prosopography-of-ebla.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4109363790167225146"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4109363790167225146"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/02/prosopography-of-ebla.html"
         title="The Prosopography of Ebla Online"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
