<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4112836624928252824</id>
   <published>2014-03-26T18:33:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2014-03-26T18:33:20.062-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Syriac"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Aramaic"/>
   <title type="text">Syriaca.org: The Syriac Reference Portal</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://syriaca.org/index.html">Syriaca.org</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">About the Project</span></h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">Syriaca.org invites scholars interested in promoting  Syriac studies to join as collaborators in the creation of a new online  reference work for the study of Syriac authors, literature, and  manuscripts. If you are interested please follow the link above to  contact us for further details.</span><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">What is Syriaca.org?</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">We are pleased to announce that an international team of  scholars has begun work on a new online reference resource for the study  of Syriac authors, texts, manuscripts, and historical research. The  Syriac Reference Portal is designed to meet the needs of a variety of  academic users ranging from specialists in Syriac and related fields to  students and the general public.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Specifically, the Syriac Reference Portal will bring together in an information hub the following resources:</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">an ontology or classification system for Syriac studies</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">a multi-lingual authority file for standardizing references to Syriac authors, texts, and place names</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">an online encyclopedia</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">a gazetteer of maps and geographic information related to Syriac studies</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">a classified bibliography</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">The above resources will be available in the first  generation of the Portal. In later development, we will open these  resources up for collaborative augmentation and annotation by scholars  around the globe. In subsequent rounds of development, we will continue  adding to the hub by linking additional digital content to the hub – for  example, the electronic journal of Syriac studies, <i>Hugoye</i>, and  the electronic corpus of Syriac literature being prepared at Brigham  Young University. We will also add new tools such as a prosopographical  component and, ultimately, the long-desired goal of a union catalogue  for Syriac manuscripts.</span><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">How will it be useful?</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Syriac Reference Portal project was conceived to  produce tools and reference resources that will overcome some of the  access and discovery problems which currently impede scholarly research  on Syriac language, cultures, and history. The principle objectives are  threefold:</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">to compile and organize core data related to the study of Syriac sources</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">to create digital tools for widely disseminating this data and facilitating further research</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">to create an online hub (cyberinfrastructure) to assist future research in the field of Syriac studies</span></li></ul><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Who will use it?</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">            The final product will benefit a variety of users. For  students and the interested public, it will provide access to basic  reference information about the historical, cultural, and religious  diversity of the Middle East. For academics in general, it will generate  new scholarly interest in Syriac sources by making research on Syriac  accessible without the need for extensive facility in Syriac. Finally,  by opening new levels of access to the sources through new discovery  tools, the Syriac Reference Portal project will not only support the  current research aims of specialists in the field, but even offer new  ways of conceptualizing the historical evidence...</span></blockquote><div id="main">            <div class="container-fluid well" id="content">    <div class="row-fluid">        <div class="span10 offset1">            <blockquote class="tr_bq"><h1 class="about"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Syriaca.org Documentation</span></h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">            </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The creation of any reference work requires making a number of decisions simply in order to bring the project             to a stage of completion where it is useful to the scholarly community.  The documents linked to below describe             decisions taken in the development of the Syriaca.org reference tools.          </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">            </span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Research Tools:</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">            </span><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://syriaca.org/geo/index.html"><em>The Syriac Gazetteer</em></a></span>                </li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">            </span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Documentation:</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">            </span><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://syriaca.org/documentation/dates.html">Dates</a></span>                </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://syriaca.org/documentation/faq.html">Frequently Asked Questions</a></span>                </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://syriaca.org/documentation/headwords.html">Headwords</a></span>                </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://syriaca.org/documentation/view-syriac.html">How to View Syriac Text on Syriaca.org</a></span>                </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://syriaca.org/documentation/place-types.html">Place Types</a></span>                </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://syriaca.org/documentation/confessions.html">Religious Communities</a></span>                </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://syriaca.org/documentation/terms.html">Technical Terminology</a></span>                </li></ul></blockquote></div></div></div></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4112836624928252824/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/03/syriacaorg-syriac-reference-portal.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4112836624928252824"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4112836624928252824"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/03/syriacaorg-syriac-reference-portal.html"
         title="Syriaca.org: The Syriac Reference Portal"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
