<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3251703506361460557</id>
   <published>2015-12-10T15:43:00.002-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-12-10T15:43:34.404-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Jordan"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Syria"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Iraq"/>
   <title type="text">The British Academy Sir Aurel Stein Archive</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/apaame/sets/72157652009016911/">The British Academy Sir Aurel Stein Archive</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5337/buddyicons/36925516@N05_l.jpg?1369186144#36925516@N05" src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5337/buddyicons/36925516@N05_l.jpg?1369186144#36925516@N05" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="view album-stats-view requiredToShowOnServer"><div class="stats-container">    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="photo-counts">696 photos</span>        <span class="album-stats-separator">·</span>  <span class="view-counts">1,039 views</span>  </span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></blockquote><div class="body" id="yui_3_16_0_1_1449779826332_1590"><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">         </span><div class="content html-only  has-footer" id="yui_3_16_0_1_1449779826332_1589"><span style="font-size: x-small;">    These aerial photographs from 1938 and 1939 were taken as part of an  archaeological survey conducted by Sir Marc Aurel Stein in modern day  Syria, Iraq and Jordan. They were captured by or with the assistance of  the Royal Air Force, then conducting aerial reconnaissance in the  territories under British Mandate. These photographs are held by The  British Academy, and shown here with their kind permission. The  digitisation of these photographs was made possible by cooperation with  the EAMENA (Endangered Archaeology of the Middle East and North Africa)  Project (<a href="http://eamena.org/" rel="nofollow">eamena.org/</a>).<br /><br />The  photographs are a fantastic record of sites that have changed  drastically over time, including the well known sites of Qasr Azraq,  Balad Sinjar and Hatra for example. Stein's particular interest in the  Roman Limes means that a large number of circumvallations are also  photographed, many of which have never been investigated further and are  now almost invisible or erased from the landscape. </span></div><div class="content html-only  has-footer" id="yui_3_16_0_1_1449779826332_1589"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div><div class="content html-only  has-footer" id="yui_3_16_0_1_1449779826332_1589"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  photographs have been catalogued according to their noted date and The  British Academy reference number. Where known, the sites have been named  and georeferenced according to the site depicted. Where a site name  discrepancy is known, whether between the photograph information and  Stein's report, or with another source, alternatives have been given.  Where possible, the hand written notes on the obverse and reverse of the  photograph have been included in the image description. Should you know  anything further regarding any of the sites depicted, please feel free  to share your knowledge and leave a comment on the individual  photograph's page. In many cases the sites photographed do not have  known individual site names but are referenced according to the  identification provided by Stein - for example, as 'Castellum' or  'Post', but these are in no way definitive.<br /><br />This particular  collection of photographs relate to Stein's research of the Roman  'Limes' and many were intended as illustrations of his 'Limes Report'.  Stein's 'Limes Report' was posthumously published from the original and  typescript manuscripts held at The Bodleian Library in 1985: Shelagh  Gregory &amp; David Kennedy 1985 Sir Aurel Stein's 'Limes Report', BAR  International Series 272.<br /><br />This collection is held at The British  Academy, britak.co.uk, 10-11 Carlton House Terrace, London, SW1Y 5AH.  All image requests and enquiries regarding the collection should be  directed to the archivist (library@britac.ac.uk). The collection also  includes notes and plans made by Stein which are not included here.<br /><br />These images were scanned from the prints using an EPSON Perfection V700 Photo Scanner, April 2015.<br /><br />For  more information regarding the extensive collection of Stein material,  please consult the handbook to his collections edited by Helen Wang  &amp; John Perkins (2008): <a href="http://www.britishmuseum.org/research/publications/research_publications_series/2008/handbook_stein_collection.aspx" rel="nofollow">www.britishmuseum.org/research/publications/research_publ...</a></span><br />   </div></blockquote></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3251703506361460557/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/12/the-british-academy-sir-aurel-stein.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3251703506361460557"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3251703506361460557"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/12/the-british-academy-sir-aurel-stein.html"
         title="The British Academy Sir Aurel Stein Archive"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
