<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9010915461645659553</id>
   <published>2015-06-27T07:30:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-06-27T09:48:10.381-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: ARA News: The Association for Roman Archaeology</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: xx-small;">[First posted in AWOL 22 December 2010. Updated&nbsp; 27 June 2015]</span><br /><br /><a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/newnewsletter.htm">ARA News:&nbsp; The Association for Roman Archaeology</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/aralogonew.jpg" src="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/aralogonew.jpg" /> </blockquote></div><blockquote><div style="color: black; font-family: inherit; text-align: left;"><span style="color: #0b3861; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;"> The Association for Roman Archaeology uses its membership income to promote the following objectives   <span style="color: #0b3861; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;"> </span></span><br /><br /><br /><li><span style="color: #0b3861; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;"><span style="color: #0b3861; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;"> To spread knowledge of Roman civilisation.</span></span></li><span style="color: #0b3861; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;"><span style="color: #0b3861; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;"><br /><li>Research on Roman sites in the U.K. </li><br /><li>Preserve our Roman antiquities.</li><br /><li>Present Roman sites and collections.</li><br /><li>Publish findings from all our active archaeological archives.</li><br /></span></span></div><div style="color: black;"></div><div style="color: black; font-family: inherit; text-align: left;"><span style="color: #0b3861; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;"><span style="color: #0b3861; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;">Our  principal objective is to promote the advancement of the education of  the public in the history and archaeology of the Roman period.</span></span></div><div style="color: black; font-family: inherit; text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="color: black; text-align: left;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;"><span style="font-family: Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif;">The A.R.A. publish a fully coloured Newsletter annually, and we upload copies here on the website for people to view. <br /><br />The Newsletters on the website are available in PDF format, please clink on a link below.&nbsp;</span></span></div><div style="color: black; text-align: left;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;"><span style="font-family: Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif;"><br /></span></span>     <span style="color: #0b3861; font-family: Geneva,Ariel, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 12px; text-decoration: none;"><span style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><b>ARA Newsletter Number 14 </b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news14.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br />Seat of fire revealed at Colchester<br />Part of Gloucester's Roman city wall goes on display<br />Snippets: Chichester, Tivoli, Chester, Bradford-on-Avon, Chester,<br />  <br /> <b>ARA Newsletter Number 15: August 2003</b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news15.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br />  Snippets: Brough, York, Goodmanham, Chester, Utrecht, London, Southwell, Colchester<br />  <br /><b>ARA Newsletter Number 16:  March 2004</b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news16.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br /> Exciting Roman coin find<br /> Snippets: Hadrian's Wall, Leicestershire, Staffordshire, Colchester,  London, Pompeii, Higham Ferrers, Southwark, Llandeilo, Lincoln,  Hertfordshire, Coberley<br />  <br /><b>ARA Newsletter Number 17:  November 2004</b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news17.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br /> Changes in the Association's Publications<br />Members day visit to Silchester<br />Annual Dinner at Fishbourne<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Broadstairs, Vindolanda, <br />Lindsey Davis at Richborough<br />Malton Museum; two goddesses unveiled at Malton Museum<br />Archaeological News Round-up:Colchester, Abergavenny<br /><br /><b>ARA Newsletter Number 18:  November 2005</b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news18_part1.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf part 1</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news18_part2.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">/ part 2</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br /> Editorial<br />The Roman Centurian's Song _Rudyard Kipling<br />Professional obituraries<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Colchester; Rabbits in Roman Britain; Socks with Sandals; York burials; Vindolanda sculpture.<br />The Jewry Wall, Leicester:  Stuart Bailey<br />A Greek Island Villa:  Bryan Matthews<br />The Big Roman Database:  Rebecca Newman<br />Timber building at Vindolanda<br />The Roman Villa at Minori:  Thomas F Morrison<br />Crossword<br />Tales from an Itinerant Traveller:  Hardknot Roman Fort (Mediobogdum):  Don Flear<br />Anamur / Anemurium:  David Pritchard<br />The Puzzle of the Amphorae:  CA Noons<br />Traveller's Itinerary:  Allen Farnworth<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Leicestershire hoard; Staffordshire Patera <br /><br /><b>ARA Newsletter Number 19:  April 2007</b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news19%5B1%5D.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br />Editorial<br />The Lost Mosaics of Bramdean, Hampshire<br />Tales from an Itinerant Traveller: Roman Cyprus (part 1): Don Flear<br />The Roman Settlement at Crab Farm, Dorset:  Bryn Walters<br />The Dodd's Brigantia Weekend Diary:  Tim Dodd<br />An Overview of Roman Essex:  Bryn Walters<br />Imperial Emblems found in Rome:  Bryn Walters<br />Spectacular Roman Sites around Lake Garda, Italy:  Geoff and Glenis Long<br />Members visit to Northern France:  Geoff and Glenis Long<br />Rare find in Leicester:  Tom Bennett<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Silbury Hill; Newchurch (Isle of Wight);  Leicester Vine Street excavations; Lancaster bath house; Priapus statue  at Vindolanda <br />Professional obituaries<br /><br /> <b>ARA Newsletter Number 20:  April 2008 </b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news20_part1.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf part 1</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news20_part2.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">/ part 2</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br />   Editorial<br />Cologne to Eifel to Tongeren to Metz:  Allen Farnworth<br />Tales from an Itinerant Traveller: Roman Cyprus (part 2):  Don Greenword (formerly Flear)<br />Readers Letters<br />Two Venue Curators retire<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Early Roman coin found in Cornwall;  Lupercal cave possibly found on the Palatine; Herculaneum wood and ivory  thorne; Chichester<br /> excavations; House of Augustus, Rome; Aldborough, York coffin found; Lancaster Roman memorial stone found<br />A Second Fort is Confirmed in Cornwall:  Steve Hartgroves and John R Smith<br />Chester's Roman Town:  Peter Carrington<br />Archaeology in the Park:  Dan Garner<br />Impressive Villas over the Bay of Naples:  Geoff and Glenis Long<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Vindoland brooch; Suffolk Villa excavations; Vindolanda statue base found<br />Professional obituaries<br />Malton Museum<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Chester's amphitheatre; London tableware;  Ewell cult centre; London Roman door; Corbridge road ramp;<br /><br />   <b>ARA Newsletter Number 21: February 2009</b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news21.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br />Editorial<br />Third Roman Fort found in Cornwall:  Dr Chris Smart<br />Tales from an Itinerant Traveller: Roman Cyprus (part 3: Don Greenword<br />Professional obituaries<br />Readers Letters<br />Archaeological News Round up: Sagalassos, Turkey statue found<br />ARA Visit to the Greek and Roman Sites of Libya in 2008: J and LT Webb<br />Journey's End, short story:  Howard Gibbs<br />New Figured Mosaic found near Kemble, Glos:  Anthony Beeson<br />The Head in the River:  Kevin Cooke<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Arles, France bust found; Sea Mills, Bristol possible fort <br /><br /> <b>ARA Newsletter Number 22: September 2009</b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news22.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br />Editorial<br />Tales from an Itinerant Traveller: Roman Cyprus (part 4):  Don Greenword<br />ARA Information Technology and Communications<br />Towns in Britain AD300-700 Conference Report:  Rebecca Newman<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Vindolanda road and granaries; Newcastle sarcophagi; Vindolanda Jupiter Dolchenus shrine; <br />Book Reviews<br />Roman Cyprus: Salamis and other Northern Sites:  Nich Hogben<br />Archaeological News Round-up: London millefiori bowl; Silchester Iron  Age predecessor; Southwell, Notts possible Religious complex; <br /><br /> <b>ARA Newsletter Number 23: March 2010 </b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news23.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br />  Editorial<br />The great North Museum, Newcastle:  Anne Woollett<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Britain's oldest Roman coin; Rome Nero's banqueting house; South Shields / Arbeia fort excavations<br />Romans, Police Cars and Football Fans; Incidents of Travel in Algeria:  Rebecca Newman<br />The Missing 90% in Roman Britain; Conference on the Romano-British Countryside 2010 report:  Rebecca Newman<br />Roman Displays at the Grosvenor Museum, Chester:  Elizabeth Royles<br />Alderney's Shore Fort:  Nicholas Hogben<br />Professor John Wilkes; ARA's Honorary President; an introduction:  Grahame Soffe<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Arbeia altar; Cameo glass vase; Nova Zagora, Bulgaria tomb.<br /><br /> <b>ARA Newsletter Number 24</b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news24_part1.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf part 1</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_news24_part2.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">/ part 2</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br />   Editorial<br />A New Fort Discovered in Exeter:  Tim Gent<br />How were Roman villas glazed and vented?<br />Spotlight on Trimontium Museum:  Donald Gordon<br />ARA goes digital<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Suffolk lantern; Bury St Edmunds Priapus  figure; Holbrook, Suffolk figure; Folkestone re-excavations; Frome coin  hoard; Aberystwyth villa; Alton pendant.<br />Roman Bath-house Discovered at Bax Farm, Kent:  Brian Philip<br />Roman Finds in Thanet, Kent:  Gordon Taylor<br />The Tale of the Emperor's Head<br /> Archaeological News Round-up: Herculaneum recent discoveries; Chedworth  mosaic; Gloucester Roman wall; Hinton St Mary, Dorset mosaic; Caistor,  Lincolnshire excavations; Papcastle, Cumbria; Woodchester Orpheus  replica mosaic; Silchester recent finds<br />Jordon, ARA study tour:  John Bithell<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Carlisle publication; Canterbury excavations, Musselburgh altars; York burial; Southwick villa<br />A Walk Along Hadrian's Wall: A personal view : David Sleep<br />Spotlight on Newport Villa, Isle of Wight:  Nicholas Hogben<br />Third Year of Excavations at Brading Villa<br />Archaeological News Round-up: Combley Villa new display; Twekesbury Roman building<br />Book Reviews<br />  <br />  <b>ARA Newsletter Number 25 March 2011</b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_News25.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf </span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"> <br />Editorial  <br />Romans on the Rhine: ARA Study Tour 2010: John Partridge  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: New Caligula statue at Nemi; Roman crop  marks; Pompeii / Vesuvius website; 4th century paintings at Santa Tecla;  Papcastle excavations; Vindolanda finds.  <br />Vaison La Romaine and Glanum: overlooked treasures of Roman Provence: Gareth Harney  <br />Folkstone Roman Villa: 2010 excavations: Keith Parfitt  <br />The Thurmaston Milestone: Stuart Bailey  <br />Spotlight on Museum of the Iron Age, Andover: Martin Elvery  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: Survey at Caerleon; Excavation at  Caerleon; Nabatean wall paintings; Roman site beneath Kettleby; Hallaton  Helmet; History of Rome Podcasts.  <br />The Mosaics of Sousse: cultural fashion in Roman Africa: Martin Elvery  <br />Book Review: The Frome Hoard  <br />Roman Spain: Ines Garcia and Bernie Spiegelhalter   <br /><br /><b>ARA Newsletter Number 26 September 2011</b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA_News_26.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">Click here for pdf </span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"> <br />Editorial  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: Maryport excavations: Vindolanda denarii.  <br />ARA Study Tour of Classical and Roman Libya, Nov 2009: Marigold Norbye  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: Colchester mosaic; Caligula statue at  Nemi update; Herculaneum Roman sewage; Roman Doncaster excavations.   <br />Spotlight on Dolaucothi Mines: Gareth Harney  <br />Hadrian's Wall Update: David Sleep  <br />Novae and the Valetudinarium of Legio I Italica: John Bithell  <br />Re-evaluating the identification of Roman military hospitals: Patricia Baker  <br />Mithras in Scotland: spectacular new altars unveiled: Anthony Beeson  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: Rome's Tunnel of Wonders; Puddletown  Roman road; York's station baths refound; Musselburgh cemetery;  Pantheon's lighting. Latin Epigraphy: how to read and understand Roman inscriptions, Part 1:  Marigold Norbye  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: New settlement near Exeter; Roman Sheffield; Caerleon excavations. South Warwickshire Roman Hoard: Martin Elvery  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: Venta Icenorum acquired for nation; Zejtun, Malta villa restoration. Recent ARA Grants   <br /><br /><b>ARA Newsletter Number 27 March 2012</b> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARANews_27_pages01to25.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;"> Click here for pdf part 1</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARANews_27_pages26to48.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">/ part 2</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br /> <br />Editorial  <br />Campaign to preserve Southwell Roman site: Bryn Walters  <br />ARA Study Tour of Jordan, 2011: Marigold Norbye  <br />RESCUE, the British Archaeological Trust; still campaigning after 40 years: Jude Plouviez  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: Roman Swiss-army knife; Arbeia  Amphora; Lower Borrowbridge, Cumbria excavations; Corinium cemetery;  Cirencester cockerel. Land of Eagles; Journeys in Roman Albania: Gareth Harney  <br />Romans in Commagene: Rebecca Newman  <br />Excavation at Charles Street, Dorchester: John Bithell  <br />Spotlight on Lunt Roman Fort: Martin Elvery From Julius Caesar to Claudius; the late Iron Age / Roman transition,  Report on a conference at the university of Leicester 2011 Nov 5th:  Stuart Bailey  <br />The Imagery of the Hallerton helmet; decoration depicting Roman victory revealed by restoration: Anthony Beeson  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: London mithraeum; Spanish mosaic damaged; Camelon, Falkirk Roman sandals; Londinium token;  Latin Epigraphy: how to read and understand Roman inscriptions, Part 2: Marigold Norbye  <br />The Lost City of the Legion; preliminary excavations in Caerleon’s  monumental suburb hint at great future discoveries: Anthony Beeson  <br />Ramblings of an Ancient Volunteer Archaeologist, digging through his memories: Michael C Looker  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: Southwark Roman bath   <br /><br /><b>ARA Newsletter Number 28 September 2012</b>  <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARANews_28_pages01to21.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;"> Click here for pdf part 1</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"> <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARANews_28_pages22to42.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0b3861;">/ part 2</span></a></span></span><span style="color: #0b3861;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><br /> <br />Editorial  <br />A Visit to the Novium, Chichester s New Museum: Grahame Soffe  <br />The Jupiter Stone: a Romano-British sculptural treasure goes on display at the Novium: Anthony Beeson  <br />ARA Study Tour of Sicily: John Partridge  <br />Halstock Roman Villa, Dorset; a lost floor of opus sectile: Bryn Walters  <br />A Tale of Three Emperors; images of Roman defeat in Sasanian Iran: Ian Heritage  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: Lupa Capitolina Etruscan?; Tyne and  Wear Hadrian's Wall community project; Birthplace of Augustus in Rome  found; Rediscovery of statue of Mark Antony and Cleopatra's twins. Jublains; a provincial Gallo-Roman civitas: Marigold Norbye  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: Beau Street hoard; Walton, Peterborough new villa; Arch of Titus paint traces.  <br />Three treasures of Ancient Britain and Sweet Fanny Adams: Anthony Beeson  <br />Archaeological News Round-up: Maryport altar excavations  <br />Recent ARA Grants    </span></span><br /> </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span style="color: #0070aa; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: xx-small; text-decoration: none;"><span style="color: #0070aa; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; text-decoration: none;"><span style="color: #0070aa; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; text-decoration: none;"><span style="font-family: Arial,Helvetica,sans-serif;"><span style="color: #0070aa; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; text-decoration: none;"><span style="color: #0070aa; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; text-decoration: none;"><a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/ARA%20Newsletter21%20P11_24.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="color: #0070aa; font-family: Geneva,Ariel,Helvetica,sans-serif; text-decoration: none;"></span></a></span></span></span></span></span></span></div></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">And see also: <a href="http://www.associationromanarchaeology.org/bulletin.htm" id="result-1">ARA : the bulletin of the Association for Roman Archaeology</a><br /><br />See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"></script></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9010915461645659553/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/12/new-open-access-journal-ara-news.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9010915461645659553"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9010915461645659553"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/12/new-open-access-journal-ara-news.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: ARA News: The Association for Roman Archaeology"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
