<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9055250179230568992</id>
   <published>2016-02-23T17:51:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-03-02T15:09:34.624-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">News from the Cuneiform Commentaries Project</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: small;">News from the <a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/">Cuneiform Commentaries Project</a></span></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: small;"> </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Several new texts have been recently added to the corpus of the <a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/">Cuneiform Commentaries Project</a> (http://ccp.yale.edu).<br /><br />Thanks are expressed to the following scholars, who have contributed their editions and feedback: Yoram Cohen, Uri Gabbay, Strahil Panayotov, Matthew Rutz, and Henry Stadhouders. We would like to renew our invitation to Assyriologists around the world to contribute their editions of as yet unedited commentary tablets, for which they will receive full credit.<br /><br />In addition, the website has been migrated to a new server (Acquia Cloud), which has resulted in a considerable improvement in both performance and speed.<br /><br />Best wishes,<br /><br />Enrique Jiménez (Senior Editor of CCP)<br /><br />⁂<br /><br />CCP 3.1.u94.b (Astrological): The fragment VAT 9434 has received scant attention since it was published in copy in the early 1940s. (<a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/P497442">Read more</a>)<br /><br />CCP 3.2.11 (Enūma Anu Enlil / Sîn ina tāmartīšu 11): This small fragment from Kuyunjik preserves badly damaged remains of the last line of a commentary, together with the beginning of a catchline and a rubric. According to the latter, it would be the 11th [tabl]et of a mukallimtu-commentary on Enūma Anu Enlil. (<a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/P423302">Read more</a>)<br /><br />CCP 3.5.34 (Ālu 34): This fragment belongs to the British Museum’s “Babylon Collection” (its accession number is 81-4-28,294). (<a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/P461192">Read more</a>)<br /><br />CCP 3.6.3.A (Izbu 7 A): This almost perfectly preserved tablet contains a thirty-four line commentary on the 7th tablet of the teratological series Šumma Izbu. (<a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/P415763">Read more</a>)<br /><br />CCP 3.8.1.B (Iqqur īpuš, série génerale B): The tablet MLC 2627 probably stems from the city of Uruk, in Babylonia. It represents the only published commentary on a tablet with a projection (a so-called amulet-shaped tablet) discovered to date. (<a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/P297024">Read more</a>)<br /><br />CCP 4.1.3.A (Sagig 3 A): This small fragment from Uruk contains remains of a commentary on the third chapter of the medical series of diagnoses and prognoses, Sagig. (<a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/P348450">Read more</a>)<br /><br />CCP 4.1.3.B (Sagig 3 B): The present tablet, previously unidentified, consists of two nearly joinable fragments from the British Museum’s “Sippar Collection,” which in all likelihood stem from Babylon or Borsippa. The colophon dates the tablet to the 8th month of the 46th year of an Antiochus, during a period of co-regency with another Antiochus, “his son.” The only possible date is 266 BCE. (<a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/P461263">Read more</a>)<br /><br />CCP 7.2.u44 (Uncertain): This tiny fragment from the British Museum’s “Babylon Collection” preserves meager remains of a lexical list or tabular commentary dealing with field pests. (<a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/P461196">Read more</a>)<br /><br />CCP 7.2.u49 (Uncertain): The previously unpublished fragments BM 41481 and BM 41635 belong both to the British Museum’s 81-6-25 consignment of tablets, which is reported to stem mostly from Babylon. (<a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/P461204">Read more</a>)<br /><br />CCP 7.2.u51 (Uncertain): This previously unpublished commentary is preserved in two small fragments that have been joined back to back, in a so-called “sandwich join.” Both fragments belong to the 81-6-25 consignment, reported to stem from the city of Babylon. (<a href="http://ccp.yale.edu/P461207">Read more)</a></span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9055250179230568992/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/02/news-from-cuneiform-commentaries-project.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9055250179230568992"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9055250179230568992"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/02/news-from-cuneiform-commentaries-project.html"
         title="News from the Cuneiform Commentaries Project"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
