<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9032905463735985462</id>
   <published>2016-05-04T16:18:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-05-04T19:03:26.067-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Museum Catalogue"/>
   <title type="text">Getty Publications Launches Free Online Catalogues In Multiple Digital Formats</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 class="entry-title"><span style="font-weight: normal;"><a href="http://blogs.getty.edu/iris/embracing-the-digital-future-of-art-books/"><span style="font-size: small;">Embracing the Digital Future of Art Books</span></a></span></h1><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span class="author vcard"><a class="url fn" href="http://blogs.getty.edu/iris/author/jcuno/" rel="author" title="Posts by James Cuno">James Cuno</a></span>  <span class="meta-sep meta-sep-entry-date"> | </span>  <span class="entry-date"><abbr class="published" title="2016-05-04T09:00:12-0700">May 4, 2016</abbr></span><br /><span class="entry-date"><abbr class="published" title="2016-05-04T09:00:12-0700">&nbsp;</abbr></span>    </div><div class="entry-content"><span class="hide-on-launch"><b>Getty Publications has  inaugurated a new series of open-access collection catalogues  available&nbsp;online,&nbsp;as downloadable ebooks, and in print</b></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-content"><img alt="Getty Publications online catalogues" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28156" height="439" src="https://blogs.getty.edu/iris/files/2016/05/onlinecats.jpg" width="828" /></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-content">Getty Publications has just launched two born-digital collection  catalogues exploring groups of ancient objects in the Museum’s  collection: <b><a href="http://www.getty.edu/publications/terracottas">Ancient Terracottas from South Italy and Sicily</a></b> and <b><a href="http://www.getty.edu/publications/romanmosaics">Roman Mosaics</a></b>.  These two titles inaugurate a series of dynamic, user-friendly,  technologically robust digital publications focusing on the Getty  collections that complement our many distinguished print publications.<br /><h3>Terracottas and Mosaics</h3>The <i>Terracottas</i>&nbsp;catalogue, by Italian scholar Maria Lucia  Ferruzza, highlights sixty notable objects and includes an annotated  reference by Museum curator Claire L. Lyons to the more than 1,000 other  such works in the collection. </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-content">The <i>Roman Mosaics</i> catalogue documents the Museum’s complete collection of these works and is published in conjunction with the exhibition <a href="http://www.getty.edu/art/exhibitions/roman_mosaics/">Roman Mosaics across the Empire</a>,  now on view at the Villa. Curator Alexis Belis organized the exhibition  and wrote the catalogue, which also has contributions by other  scholars. </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-content"><div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_28163" style="width: 652px;"><a href="http://blogs.getty.edu/iris/embracing-the-digital-future-of-art-books/www.getty.edu/publications/romanmosaics" rel="attachment wp-att-28163"><img alt="Animated screencast of Roman Mosaics online catalogue features" class="size-full wp-image-28163" height="362" src="https://blogs.getty.edu/iris/files/2016/05/romanmosaics_screencast.gif" width="642" /></a><br /><div class="wp-caption-text"></div></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-content"><div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_28163" style="width: 652px;"><div class="wp-caption-text">The  new Roman Mosaics online catalogue includes interactive maps,  full-width zoomable images, and embedded glossary terms and reference  illustrations.</div></div><h3>Why Digital Catalogues?</h3>Following the Getty Foundation’s successful <a href="http://www.getty.edu/foundation/initiatives/current/osci/index.html">Online Scholarly Catalogue Initiative</a> (OSCI), more and more museums have been looking to digital formats for  their collection catalogues. Digital formats allow for greater access,  more flexibility, and interactive features not possible in print books. </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-content">Several museums that were part of the OSCI project are moving forward  with yet more digital catalogues. Other museums have joined these early  pioneers in exploring an expanding range of ways to make scholarly  research on their collections available online. The Getty itself made an  early foray into online publishing with <a href="http://museumcatalogues.getty.edu/amber/contents/">a catalogue on ancient ambers</a>, which was released in 2012. In short, the field is embracing digital publications, and so are we.<br /><h3>What’s Inside?</h3>Both publications offer features you might expect, like zoomable  high-resolution images and interactive maps. But beyond these more  obvious, splashy features are a number of quieter features that we hope  will make a long-term contribution to digital publishing in the  humanities. </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-content">An important part of our work at the Getty is to research our  collections and disseminate information about them as broadly as  possible. This content should be easy to find and should be preserved  over the long term. But this seemingly simple mandate is actually quite  complex, raising questions such as:<br /><ul><li>How are digital books found by readers when they live outside the traditional distribution stream, such as libraries?</li><li>How can an online book last decades or more, when the average lifespan for a website is more often measured in months?</li><li>What happens to a digital book when platforms and technologies inevitably change?</li></ul>To address these questions, the team at Getty Publications built in four key features:<br /><ul><li><b>Each of these catalogues is published in multiple formats.</b> While the primary edition is online, you can also download PDFs, ebooks  for your Kindle or iPad, and image and data sets to use in your  research and teaching. And for readers who prefer print, paperback  copies are also available.</li><li><b>The content remains in a plain-text format</b> and is fully accessible at the project repository (GitHub) for each publication.</li><li><b>Each publication features a permanent URL</b>, and any  revisions made are carefully documented so researchers can feel  comfortable citing the work, knowing that their citations will be fully  verifiable down the road.</li><li><b>These publications are issued under a Creative Commons license</b>, continuing our efforts to make information available as widely as possible.</li></ul>I hope you’ll explore the <a href="http://www.getty.edu/publications/terracottas/">Terracottas</a> and <a href="http://www.getty.edu/publications/romanmosaics">Roman Mosaics</a> catalogues online,&nbsp;or&nbsp;will download them to dig into their rich content  at your leisure. Look for more online publications in the coming months  as our efforts continue! </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-content"><div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_28164" style="width: 652px;"><a href="http://blogs.getty.edu/iris/embracing-the-digital-future-of-art-books/www.getty.edu/publications/terracottas" rel="attachment wp-att-28164"><img alt="Animated screencast of Terracottas online catalogue" class="size-full wp-image-28164" height="362" src="https://blogs.getty.edu/iris/files/2016/05/terracottas_screencast.gif" width="642" /></a><br /><div class="wp-caption-text"></div></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-content"><div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_28164" style="width: 652px;"><div class="wp-caption-text">Readers  can dynamically search and sort among the sixty objects in the  Terracottas online catalogue, view artworks in detail, and view select  objects in full 360-degree rotation.</div></div></div></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9032905463735985462/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/05/getty-publications-launches-free-onlin.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9032905463735985462"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9032905463735985462"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/05/getty-publications-launches-free-onlin.html"
         title="Getty Publications Launches Free Online Catalogues In Multiple Digital Formats"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
