<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9004704312733019633</id>
   <published>2016-07-25T16:51:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-07-25T16:52:58.065-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Linguistics"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greek"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Biblical and Ancient Greek Linguistics (BAGL)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://bagl.org/home">Biblical and Ancient Greek Linguistics (BAGL) </a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://bagl.org/img/bagl-logo.png" class="decoded" height="110" src="https://bagl.org/img/bagl-logo.png" width="200" /><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">Biblical and Ancient Greek Linguistics (BAGL) is an international journal that   exists to further the application of modern linguistics to the study of Ancient and Biblical   Greek, with a particular focus on the analysis of texts, including but not restricted to the   Greek New Testament.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span> <span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">The journal is hosted by <a href="http://www.macdiv.ca/">McMaster Divinity College</a> and works in   conjunction with its Centre for Biblical Linguistics, Translation and Exegesis, and the   OpenText.org organization (<a href="http://www.opentext.org/">www.opentext.org</a>) in the   hosting of conferences and symposia open to scholars and students working in Greek   linguistics who are interested in contributing to advancing the discussion and methods of   the field of research. BAGL is a refereed on-line and print journal dedicated to   distributing the results of significant research in the area of linguistic theory and   application to biblical and ancient Greek, and is open to all scholars, not just those   connected to the Centre and the <a href="http://www.opentext.org/">OpenText.org</a> project.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="volTitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 4 (2015)</span></div><div class="toc-abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;">				Show  				<a href="http://bagl.org/volume4?mode=toc">table of contents</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="4.1" name="4.1"></a><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="4.2" name="4.2"></a><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="4.3" name="4.3"></a><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="4.4" name="4.4"></a></span><br /><table><tbody><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span style="font-size: x-small;">4.1</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume4/BAGL_4-1_Fantin.pdf" target="_new">Society and Culture: Aspects of the First-Century World for a More Contextually Driven Exegesis</a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Joseph D. Fantin</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Dallas Theological Seminary</span></div><div class="abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;">It  is agreed that both context and Greek studies are essential components  of the exegetical process. This article explores the function of  language itself within society. The focus is not on the typical  “meaning” of language as an information carrier but rather on the  meaning that the use of particular linguistic elements brings to the  communication situation. In other words, I will consider language itself  as a social phenomenon. In order to achieve this goal, using Acts  21:27–40 as a test case, I will first consider selective elements of the  social and historical context that when understood will contribute to  recreating the context of the passage (cognitive environment). Then,  with this contextual information activated in the exegetical process, I  will consider the social impact of this information on two recorded  speech incidents from Acts 21:27–40 resulting in a better understanding  of the passage. This will demonstrate that in addition to the  informational linguistic meaning, an understanding of the social use of  language itself is a valuable tool for understanding the biblical text.</span></div><div class="keywords"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords:  Acts 21:27–40, exegesis, sociolinguistics, pragmatics, New Testament  backgrounds, New Testament contexts, cognitive environment, Greek,  relevance theory</span></div></td></tr><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span style="font-size: x-small;">4.2</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume4/BAGL_4-2_Watt.pdf" target="_new">The Living Language Environment of Acts 21:27–40</a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Jonathan M. Watt</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Geneva College, Beaver Falls, PA, USA</span></div><div class="abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;">A  sociolinguistic approach to Paul’s language usage in the Jerusalem  arrest narratives of Acts 21–22 offers inferences with regard to his  specific language choices between Greek, Hebrew and Aramaic during his  interactions. However, modern language studies show considerable  inter-language penetration that, by implication, complicate conclusions  one may reach with regard to the NT situation.</span></div><div class="keywords"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords: sociolinguistics, multilingualism, linguistic repertoire, code-switching, cross-linguistic penetration</span></div></td></tr><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span style="font-size: x-small;">4.3</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume4/BAGL_4-3_Ong.pdf" target="_new">Sociolinguistics  and New Testament Exegesis: Three Approaches to Discourse Analysis  Using Acts 21:27—22:5 (Paul’s Arrest in the Temple) as a Test Case</a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Hughson T. Ong</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span style="font-size: x-small;">McMaster Divinity College, Hamilton, ON, Canada</span></div><div class="abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This  article discusses three distinct types of discourse analysis  models—Social Identity Theory and Communication Accommodation Theory  (CAT), Conversation Analysis (CA), and SFL Register Analysis—and applies  them individually to the text in Acts 21:27—22:5 to examine various  aspects and elements that comprise the context of situation of the  incident of Paul’s arrest in the temple. The main objective is to  showcase the relevance and utility of sociolinguistic theories in New  Testament exegesis.</span></div><div class="keywords"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords: Acts  21:27—22:5, sociolinguistics, exegesis, discourse analysis, social  identity theory, speech or communication accommodation theory,  conversation analysis, register analysis</span></div></td></tr><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span style="font-size: x-small;">4.4</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume4/BAGL_4-4_Dvorak.pdf" target="_new">“Prodding with Prosody”: Persuasion and Social Influence through the Lens of Appraisal Theor</a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span style="font-size: x-small;">James D. Dvorak</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Oklahoma Christian University, Edmond, OK, USA</span></div><div class="abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This  article approaches the topic of persuasion from a social perspective  rather than rhetorical or socio-rhetorical. This is because, at heart,  persuasion—of others or of self—is ultimately a social action in which  values are negotiated. Dvorak argues that to analyze the persuasiveness  of a discourse requires a sociolinguistic model, and the model that is  best suited for the job is Appraisal Theory, which is built upon the  theoretical foundation of Systemic Functional Linguistics.</span></div><div class="keywords"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords: persuasion, appraisal, evaluation, 1 Corinthians, values, power, discourse analysis</span></div></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="volTitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 3 (2014)</span></div><div class="toc-abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;">				Show  				<a href="http://bagl.org/volume3?mode=toc">table of contents</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="3.1" name="3.1"></a><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="3.2" name="3.2"></a><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="3.3" name="3.3"></a><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="3.4" name="3.4"></a></span><br /><table><tbody><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span style="font-size: x-small;">3.1</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume3/BAGL3-1_Danove.pdf" target="_new">“Deriving” and Describing Usages of <span class="grk">Τίθημι</span> and <span class="grk">Τίθημι</span> Compounds in the Septuagint and New Testament</a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Paul L. Danove</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Villanova University, Villanova, PA, USA</span></div><div class="abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="grk">Τίθημι</span> and its compounds present the broadest range of licensing properties of  any set of verbal compounds in the Septuagint and New Testament. This  article resolves the occurrences of <span class="grk">τίθημι</span> and  its twenty compounds into twenty–six distinct usages. The discussion of  each usage “derives” the event that the verbs grammaticalize, specifies  the conceptualization of the event associated with each usage,  describes the syntactic and semantic requirements for verbs with the  usage, identifies the observed lexical realizations of required  complements, and illustrates occurrences of the verbs with the usage.  The discussion then summarizes the relationships among the usages,  proposes a further basis for relating the events, and notes the  possibility of polysemous interpretations of verbal occurrences.</span></div><div class="keywords"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords: event, lexical, semantic, syntactic, usage, verb</span></div></td></tr><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span style="font-size: x-small;">3.2</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume3/BAGL3-2_Dvorak.pdf" target="_new">Clause as Message: Theme, Topic, and Information Flow in Mark 2:1–12 and Jude</a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span style="font-size: x-small;">James D. Dvorak and Ryder Dale Walton</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Oklahoma Christian University</span></div><div class="abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Too  often, study of the biblical text degenerates into rudimentary word  studies, leaving aside larger syntactic and logical connections. This  paper proposes that careful study should include considerations of  genre, register, prime, subsequent, theme, rheme, topic, and comment. To  demonstrate this, it applies a Systemic Functional approach to Mark  2:1–12 and the book of Jude.</span></div><div class="keywords"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords:  Exegesis, Systemic Functional Linguistics, Prime, Subsequent, Theme,  Rheme, Topic, Comment, Process Chains, Semantic Shift, Cohesion,  Coherence, Linearity, Genre, Register</span></div></td></tr><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span style="font-size: x-small;">3.3</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume3/BAGL3-3_Kraeger.pdf" target="_new">Whence and Whither Greek Verbal Lexicography and Pedagogy: A Diachronic Review</a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span style="font-size: x-small;">S. M. Kraeger</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary, Wake Forest, NC, USA</span></div><div class="abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ever since the advent of the printing press, the Latin West and its lexicographic inheritors have used              the first person singular indicative verb form (e.g., λύω) as the lemma of the Greek verb.              There are historical reasons for this. These historical reasons for using the indicative form,              however, are not coextensive with those by which modern lexicographers operate.              This issue significantly overlaps with pedagogical concerns. The present article seeks to sketch a              basic history of Greek verbal treatments toward a reevaluation of lexicographic and              pedagogic practice regarding the ancient Greek verb.</span></div><div class="keywords"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords: Lexicography, Pedagogy, Verb, Lemmatization</span></div></td></tr><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span style="font-size: x-small;">3.4</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume3/BAGL3-4_Porter.pdf" target="_new">The Usage-Based Approach to Teaching New Testament Greek</a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Stanley E. Porter</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span style="font-size: x-small;">McMaster Divinity College, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada</span></div><div class="abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;">             This paper emphasizes the importance of both methodological  and pedagogical dimensions of elementary Greek grammars,              and then briefly surveys several different approaches found  in current gram- mars. The paper takes what is called the usage-based  approach,              in which grammar is introduced roughly according to  frequency of use so that students are reinforced in learning the grammar              that appears most frequently in the Greek New Testament.              Porter, Reed, and O’Donnell’s <i>Fundamentals of New Testament Greek</i> is used as the example of such an approach.          </span></div><div class="keywords"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords: Greek, grammar, elementary, usage-based approach, morphological approach, descriptivism, progressivism, immersion</span></div></td></tr></tbody></table><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="3.4" name="3.4"></a></span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="volTitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 2 (2013)</span></div><div class="toc-abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;">    Show      <a href="http://bagl.org/volume2?mode=toc">table of contents</a>&nbsp;</span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/null" id="2.1" name="2.1"></a></span><br /><table><tbody><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span style="font-size: x-small;">2.1</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume2/BAGL2-1_Danove.pdf" target="_new">Features of the Conceptualization of Transference in the New Testament</a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Paul L. Danove</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Villanova University, Villanova, PA, USA</span></div><div class="abstract"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This  article develops five features that describe the conceptualizations of  the event of transference grammaticalized by New Testament verbs,              and uses these features to formulate a model of the possible  New Testament usages of transference.              The discussion resolves all New Testament occurrences of  verbs that designate transference into one of              eighteen usages with distinct feature descriptions, and  considers the usages of transference predicted by the feature model              but not realized in the New Testament.</span></div><div class="keywords"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords: feature, transference, semantic, syntactic, verbal usage</span></div></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><div class="volTitle"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">Volume 1 (2012)</span></div><div class="toc-abstract"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">    Show      <a href="http://bagl.org/volume1?mode=toc">table of contents</a></span></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=116259103207720939" id="1.1" name="1.1"></a><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=116259103207720939" id="1.2" name="1.2"></a><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=116259103207720939" id="1.3" name="1.3"></a><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=116259103207720939" id="1.4" name="1.4"></a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><table><tbody><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">1.1</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume1/BAGL1-1_Cirafesi.pdf" target="_new"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: xx-small;"><span class="grk">ἔχειν πίστιν</span> in Hellenistic Greek              and its Contribution to the <span class="grk">πίστιϛ Χριστοῦ</span> Debate</span></a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">Wally V. Cirafesi</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">McMaster Divinity College, Hamilton, ON, Canada</span></div><div class="abstract"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">            This article argues that the construction <span class="grk">ἔχειν πίστιν</span> in Hellenistic Greek is a nominalized ideational metaphor              that is semantically related to the finite verb <span class="grk">πιστεύειν</span>. Therefore, when the construction possesses a genitive              modifier, the function of the genitive is disambiguated as denoting the object of πίστιν.              This understanding of <span class="grk">ἔχειν πίστιν</span> + the genitive has significant implications for interpreting              the construction in Mark 11:22, Jas 2:1, and Hippolytus‘s De Antichristo 61:26. (Article)             </span></div><div class="keywords"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords: <span class="grk">πίστιϛ Χριστοῦ</span>, Greek linguistics, nominalization, grammatical metaphor,              Mark 11:22, Jas 2:1, Hippolytus</span></div></td></tr><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">1.2</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume1/BAGL1-2_Fewster.pdf" target="_new"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: xx-small;">Testing the Intertextuality of <span class="grk">ματαιότηϛ</span> in the New Testament</span></a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">Gregory P. Fewster</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">McMaster Divinity College, Hamilton, ON, Canada</span></div><div class="abstract"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">            Adapting Michael Hoey‘s lexical priming theory, this article provides a new rubric for the evaluation of              intertextuality in the New Testament. This article tests the veracity of the claim that the              lexeme <span class="grk">ματαιότηϛ</span> functions to invoke the language of Ecclesiastes.              Romans 8 mirrors some of the language of Ecclesiastes, while Eph 4:17 has strong ties to Rom 8, creating              an intertextual chain via the lexeme <span class="grk">ματαιότηϛ</span>. (Article)             </span></div><div class="keywords"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords: <span class="grk">ματαιότηϛ</span>, intertextuality, priming, Romans 8, 2 Peter 2, Ephesians 3</span></div></td></tr><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">1.3</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume1/BAGL1-3_Ong.pdf" target="_new"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: xx-small;">Language Choice in Ancient Palestine: A Sociolinguistic Study of Jesus' Language Use Based on Four "I Have Come" Sayings</span></a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">Hughson Ong</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">McMaster Divinity College, Hamilton, ON, Canada</span></div><div class="abstract"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">This  article relates to the criteria of language authenticity in historical  Jesus research and inquires into the lingua franca of Je- sus’ social  environment. It demonstrates via sociolinguistic principles that  Palestine was a multilingual society, establishes that various so- cial  groups necessitate the use of language varieties, and addresses the  issue of language choice—the occasions and reasons multilingual people  use their native tongue over and against their second language. The  objective is to show in four “I have come” sayings in the Synop- tics  that, with high probability, Jesus’ internal language was Aramaic, and  his public language was Greek.</span></div><div class="keywords"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords: Historical Jesus, Greek language, sociolinguistics, Mark 2:17, Mark 10:45, Luke 12:49–51, Matt 5:17</span></div></td></tr><tr><td><div class="abs-vnum"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">1.4</span></div></td><td><div class="abs-articletitle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://bagl.org/files/volume1/BAGL1-4_Runge.pdf" target="_new"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: xx-small;">Relative Saliency and Information Structure in Mark's Parable of the Sower</span></a></span></div><div class="abs-author"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">Steven E. Runge</span></div><div class="affiliation"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">Logos Bible Software | Stellenbosh University, Stellenbosch, South Africa</span></div><div class="abstract"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">This  study applies the cognitive model of Chafe and Givón, and the  information-structure model of Lambrecht as applied by Levinsohn and  Runge to the Markan explanation of the Parable of the Sower (4:14–20).  The primary objective is to identify and analyze other linguistic  devices, besides demonstratives, which might clarify the apparent  prominence given to the unfruitful scatterings in Mark’s account. This  study provides the necessary framework for comparing Mark’s pragmatic  weighting of saliency to that found in Matthew and Luke’s accounts in  order to determine whether Mark’s version is con-sistent with or  divergent from the other traditions. </span></div><div class="keywords"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: x-small;">Keywords: saliency, information structure, Mark 4:14–20, Matt 13:19–23, Luke 8:11–15, <span class="grk">οὗτος</span>, <span class="grk">ἐκεῖνος</span></span></div></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-weight: normal;">See AWOL's full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.co.uk/2015/12/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9004704312733019633/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/07/open-access-journal-biblical-and.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9004704312733019633"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9004704312733019633"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/07/open-access-journal-biblical-and.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Biblical and Ancient Greek Linguistics (BAGL)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
