<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9088136655450482115</id>
   <published>2017-01-08T22:33:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2017-01-08T22:59:30.322-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Imagining an Open Access Journal: Epoiesen – A journal for creative engagement in history and archaeology</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://electricarchaeology.ca/2016/12/21/epoiesen-a-journal-for-creative-engagement-in-history-and-archaeology/">Epoiesen – A journal for creative engagement in history and archaeology</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="signature_nikosthenes_f102" class="attachment-gazette-single-thumbnail size-gazette-single-thumbnail wp-post-image" data-attachment-id="2839" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-description="" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="signature_nikosthenes_f102" data-large-file="https://electricarchaeologist.files.wordpress.com/2016/12/signature_nikosthenes_f102.jpg?w=720" data-medium-file="https://electricarchaeologist.files.wordpress.com/2016/12/signature_nikosthenes_f102.jpg?w=300" data-orig-file="https://electricarchaeologist.files.wordpress.com/2016/12/signature_nikosthenes_f102.jpg" data-orig-size="1599,1064" data-permalink="https://electricarchaeology.ca/2016/12/21/epoiesen-a-journal-for-creative-engagement-in-history-and-archaeology/signature_nikosthenes_f102/" height="96" src="https://electricarchaeologist.files.wordpress.com/2016/12/signature_nikosthenes_f102.jpg?w=1599&amp;h=768&amp;crop=1" width="200" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">My sabbatical so far has been shaping up as a series of small  experiments in other ways of ‘doing’ archaeology and history on (mostly)  the web, where ‘doing’ is a general purpose verb for teaching, writing,  thinking, communicating, etc. So far, I’ve <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lo_QQl22Uhg">failed productively in Michigan</a>, given a couple of talks at Carleton (on <a href="https://shawngraham.github.io/presentations/oa.html#/">OA</a>, on<a href="http://bit.ly/sg-nov16-cu"> SNA in Roman archaeology</a>), helped promoted <a href="https://electricarchaeology.ca/2016/10/08/distantly-reading-digital-archaeology-mobilizing-the-past-for-a-digital-future/">‘Mobilizing the Past’ </a>, found some cash and put together a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kYnXOxpcgRM">data viz competition in archaeology</a>,  built a board game with Tom Brughmans and Iza Romanowska featuring  trade and the Roman empire (this took most of October and November. It’s  currently in alpha, and I’ll share more on this in due course), data  mined the trade in human remains on Instagram with Damien Huffer, and  have nearly completed <a href="https://transkribus.eu/Transkribus/">transcribing</a> a traveller’s diary to Egypt in 1874, around which I’m building a <a href="http://sgcloud.graeworks.net/f/36">visual novel</a>. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">It’s been a lot of fun. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Some things I’ve long been thinking about however are the things that we publish. Look at the <a href="http://www.heritagejam.org/">HeritageJam</a>. Where could one publish&nbsp;<i>that</i> kind of work? The creative work that enables the visualization, the  reimagining, the remixing of the past? (HeritageJam triggered the  cascade of thoughts that leads to this present moment, as it happens).  The <a href="https://dhcommons.org/journal/2016">DHCommons Journal</a>&nbsp;is  one possible venue, of course, and a good one. It is an ideal spot for  publishing the ‘paradata’ that surround a project. But what I’ve had in  mind is more like a literary journal, a creative space, for projects at  the intersection of music, art, glitch, bots, games, &nbsp;poetry, prose, 3d  modeling, interactive fiction, and so on, with archaeology and history:  things that wouldn’t fit in a ‘normal’ journal. On the journal site  would be published something akin to an artist’s statement.&nbsp;<span class="s1">The  creative thing itself, if it’s code based, could be deposited in the  repo (and have its own DOI and citation) – otherwise, could just point  to wherever the canonical version of it lives/may be found in the  world.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="annotator-hl">ἐποίησεν (epoiesen)- </span><i><span class="annotator-hl">made</span></i><span class="annotator-hl"> –</span> is a journal for exploring creative engagement with the past,  especially through digital means. It publishes primarily what might be  thought of as artist’s statements that accompany playful and unfamiliar  forms of singing the past into existence. These could be visualizations,  art works, games, pop-up installations, poetry, hypertext fiction,  procedurally generated works, or other forms yet to be devised. We seek  to document and valorize the scholarly creativity that underpins our  representations of the past. <i>Epoiesen</i> is therefore a kind of  witness to the implied knowledge of archaeologists, historians, and  other professionals, academics and artists as it intersects with the  sources about the past. It encourages engagement with the past that  reaches beyond our traditional audience (ourselves).</span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">Our library has support for OA journals, and so it looks  like I’d be able to do this completely open access and charge no article  processing fees – I have an indication from our library that we’d be  able to&nbsp;host this journal for at least five years (complete with DOIs,  and indexing). We also have a Dataverse code repository. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="s1">So what about peer review? Well, I’m into  open review, dialogue, responses. This journal would seek out at least  two reviewers for every submission, to write ‘responding to…’ pieces,  which themselves would be published with their own citation, DOI, etc.  The <a href="https://hypothes.is/">Hypothesis</a> web annotation  architecture would be built into the site. Publication would happen on a  rolling basis, with each year’s materials being retroactively organized  into an ‘Annual’. Submissions would be in markdown, and the site  generated from those files (pandoc to create pdfs for folks who need  that sort of thing for annual reports and so on).</span></span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">That’s the big idea then. Interested? Drop me a line. I’d  like to have this thing up and running by the end of the next term (so  April-ish). By posting this blogpost, I’m hoping that this’ll provide  the kick in the pants that I’ll need to keep this thing going. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="p1"><span style="font-size: x-small;">(featured image: Wikimedia, ‘Nike between two youths, with  Nikosthenes’ signature (ΝΙΚΟΣΘΕΝΕΣ ΕΠΟΙΕΣΕΝ) on the neck. Side A from  an Attic black-figured Nikosthenic amphora, ca. 530–520 BC. From  Cerveteri (Caere).’ <a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Datei:Signature_Nikosthenes_F102.jpg" rel="external" target="_blank">https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Datei:Signature_Nikosthenes_F102.jpg</a> _ )</span></div></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;">S<span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="font-weight: normal;">ee AWOL's full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.co.uk/2015/12/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9088136655450482115/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2017/01/imagining-open-access-jpurnal-epoiesen.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9088136655450482115"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9088136655450482115"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2017/01/imagining-open-access-jpurnal-epoiesen.html"
         title="Imagining an Open Access Journal: Epoiesen – A journal for creative engagement in history and archaeology"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
