<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1622530330222471981</id>
   <published>2016-03-16T13:46:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-03-16T13:46:41.864-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Philosophy"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greek"/>
   <title type="text">New in California Classical Studies: Alexander of Aphrodisias and the Text of Aristotle’s Metaphysics</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[Mirjam E. Kotwick, <a href="http://calclassicalstudies.org/?p=161"><em>Alexander of Aphrodisias and the Text of Aristotle’s</em> Metaphysics</a><a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/05z6b1b1"></a>, 2016<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="Kotwick_coverImage" class="size-medium wp-image-163 aligncenter" height="200" src="http://calclassicalstudies.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/Kotwick_coverImage-199x300.jpg" width="132" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Alexander of Aphrodisias’s commentary (about AD 200) is the earliest extant commentary on Aristotle’s <em>Metaphysics</em>, and it is the most valuable indirect witness to the <em>Metaphysics</em> text and its transmission. Mirjam Kotwick’s study is a systematic investigation into the version of the <em>Metaphysics</em> that Alexander used when writing his commentary, and into the various  ways his text, his commentary, and the texts transmitted through our  manuscripts relate to one another. Through a careful analysis of  lemmata, quotations, and Alexander’s discussion of Aristotle’s argument  Kotwick shows how to uncover and partly reconstruct a <em>Metaphysics</em> version from the second century AD. Kotwick then uses this version for  improving the text that came down to us by the direct manuscript  tradition and for finding solutions to some of the puzzles in this  tradition. Through a side-by-side examination of Alexander’s text, his  interpretation of Aristotle’s thought, and the directly transmitted  versions of the <em>Metaphysics</em>, Kotwick reveals how Alexander’s  commentary may have influenced the text of our manuscripts at different  stages of the transmission process. This study is the first book-length  examination of a commentary as a witness to an ancient philosophical  text. This blend of textual criticism and philosophical analysis both  expands on existing methodologies in classical scholarship and develops  new ones. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Mirjam E. Kotwick recently received her PhD in Greek Philology from  the Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität in Munich, Germany. After being a  DAAD Postdoctoral Visiting Scholar in the Department of Classical  Studies at the University of Michigan, she is currently the Onassis  Lecturer in Ancient Greek Thought and Language at the New School for  Social Research in New York. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Kotwick’s monograph was selected by the Editorial Board as the winner  of the 2014 CCS competition to identify distinguished work by junior  scholars.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Open-access page view of her book is now available <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/16q3c0w4" target="_blank">at this link</a>.</span><br /></blockquote><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/08/california-classical-studies-launched.html">Open Access Monograph Series: California Classical Studies</a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1622530330222471981/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/03/new-in-california-classical-studies.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1622530330222471981"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1622530330222471981"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/03/new-in-california-classical-studies.html"
         title="New in California Classical Studies: Alexander of Aphrodisias and the Text of Aristotle’s Metaphysics"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
