<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2410846528681126574</id>
   <published>2015-01-22T16:02:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-01-22T16:02:53.559-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CDLI"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#"
             term="Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative"/>
   <title type="text">News from Cuneiform Digital Library Notes (CDLN)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[We are pleased to announce the publication of several new contributions to the <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/index.php">Cuneiform Digital Library Notes (CDLN)</a>:<br /><br />CDLN 2015:001<br />Klaus Wagensonner, <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000054">On an alternative way of capturing RTI images with the camera dome</a><br /><br />CDLN 2015:002<br />Strahil V. Panayotov and Kostadin Kissiov, <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000055">An administrative tablet from Puzriš-Dagān in Plovdiv, Bulgaria</a><br /><br />CDLN 2015:003<br />Klaus Wagensonner, <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000056">Turning the Laws of Ur-Namma</a><br /><br />We would like to take this opportunity to thank all contributors to CDLN for their support and would like to encourage scholars to contribute to the Notes in future as well. <br /><br />References and bibliographies: <br />As of now all bibliographical information is drawn directly from a MySQL database. It is therefore not necessary anymore to send fully formatted bibliographies along with submitted contributions. For all references that are included among the latest available bibliographies on <a href="http://vergil.uni-tuebingen.de/keibi/">KeiBi Online</a> it is possible to save references and export them into the BibTeX format and send this document along. A full <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/bibliography.php">bibliography was added on CDLN</a>, which contains all references used in the various contributions. Clicking on a year leads to the respective contribution(s), where the chosen reference is used. Vice versa, each reference list links back to the full bibliography. <br /><br />As a test run the “<a href="http://cdli.ox.ac.uk/wiki/doku.php?id=abbreviations_for_assyriology">Abbreviations for Assyriology</a>” maintained by CDLI:wiki have been imported into the database as well. By hovering over abbreviations in the bibliographies the full form and additional information is given. Further features such as indices of texts mentioned are in preparation. <br /><br />We do hope that these changes will increase the efficiency of CDLN and are therefore happy to receive contributions for the next publication of Notes on April 1, 2015. <br /><br />Submitted contributions are preferably made available as text files or in the RTF format. If the contribution contains tables, word or pages documents may be submitted as well. Please note that in order to aid the editing process, please be so kind to provide all images in separate files and not embedded in the submitted documents. <br /><br />The CDLN, together with its sister publications <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdlb.html">Cuneiform Digital Library Bulletin (CDLB)</a> and <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdlj.html">Cuneiform Digital Library Journal (CDLJ)</a>, are peer-reviewed publications that offer a persistent web presence under the auspices of the University of California system. As e-journals, the delay between submission and publication is well below that of academic print journals, while the interaction with cuneiform artifacts documented in the CDLI database offers obvious strengths for an interactive discourse. Authors should expect a two to four month interval between submission of a draft text with illustrations and its publication for substantive contributions to the CDLJ, at most two months for those made to the Bulletin, and approximately two weeks for the Notes that are conceived as an online venue for NABU-style communications that can include short philological or lexicographical contributions as well as regular updates of a more substantial nature describing the background or progress of, in particular, web-based research efforts. For submission guidelines including technicalities regarding bibliographical citations etc. please consult the information at &lt;<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/?q=about-cdln">http://cdli.ucla.edu/?q=about-cdln</a>&gt;.<br /><br />New submissions will appear in preprint status four times a year (January 1, April 1, July 1, and October 1; notices of new submissions will be made to this list) and are clearly marked as such. During the preprint period, authors will be able to make small, non-substantive changes (e.g., typographical errors) to their submissions. After two weeks, these submissions are then archived. <br /><br />Scholars are encouraged to send contributions to the CDLN at &lt;<a href="http://klaus%2Ewagensonner@orinst.ox.ac.u/">klaus.wagensonner@orinst.ox.ac.u</a>k&gt;.<br /><br />On behalf of the CDLI<br /><br />Jacob L. Dahl and Klaus Wagensonner<br />University of Oxford<br />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2410846528681126574/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/01/news-from-cuneiform-digital-library.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2410846528681126574"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2410846528681126574"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/01/news-from-cuneiform-digital-library.html"
         title="News from Cuneiform Digital Library Notes (CDLN)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
