<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2413880584905747641</id>
   <published>2016-08-01T08:52:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-08-01T08:52:21.628-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Lexicography"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Syriac"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dictionary"/>
   <title type="text">SEDRA: The Syriac Electronic Data Research Archive</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://sedra.bethmardutho.org/about/sedra">SEDRA: The Syriac Electronic Data Research Archive</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="Beth Mardutho" src="https://sedra.bethmardutho.org/bundles/sedra4homepage/images/mw_joomla_logo.gif" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">About SEDRA</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Syriac Electronic Data Research Archive (SEDRA) is a linguistic  and literary database of the Syriac language and literature. Its acronym  derives from Syriac word <span class="selectableFont" style="font-family: SertoJerusalem;">ܣܕܪܐ</span> <span style="font-style: italic;">sedrā</span> whose meanings include 'array', 'series' as well as 'order' and 'rank',  all of which are terms that are associated with database theory.</span><br /> <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Project History</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">SEDRA was established in 1988 by Alaph Beth Computer Systems, a  one-person firm founded by George A. Kiraz and based in Los Angeles,  that developed, inter alia, Syriac fonts. An early brochure of the  company stated that SEDRA "will come on floppy disks in ASCII format."</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Kiraz wanted to "crowd source"—analog style—the creation of a  linguistic database of the Syriac language. Kiraz sent out letters to  his clients who used his Syriac fonts with the word processor  Multi-Lingual Scholar and asked them to volunteer to type the lexica of  Margoliouth, Payne Smith and Brockelmann with specific ASCII tagging. A  new entry began with a caret (^) and English glosses of Margoliouth's  dictionary were delimited by a percent sign (%). A letter dated March  22, 1990 reports the status of the project and promises to look into the  possibilities of using SEDRA "in Artificial Intelligence applications,  especially Natural Language Processing." In addition, Kiraz signed an  agreement on March 2, 1988 with the Ancient Biblical Manuscript Center  for Preservation and Research and obtained a permission to use the  Peshitta New Testament Electronic Database, originally developed by The  Way International.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">SEDRA went through three incarnations. SEDRA I (1989) derived its  data from the database provided by the Ancient Biblical Manuscript  Center which provided the data as a flat file database. The data was  converted to db_VISTA, a database management system that provided a  programmable interface in the C programming language for writing  database applications.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">SEDRA II (1990) contained additional tables and fields necessary for the generation of Kiraz's <span style="font-style: italic;">Concordance to the Syriac New Testament</span> (1993). Moreover, the entire text of the New Testament was vocalized  and pointed, punctuation and accent marks were added, and the text was  normalized to represent the BFBS edition of the Syriac New Testament as  the text used by The Way was based on other manuscripts, primarily from  the British Library. To accomplish the vocalization and pointing  process, a program was written that skipped over words which had been  vocalized before. Hence, the word <span class="selectableFont" style="font-family: SertoJerusalem;">ܒܝܬܐ</span> 'house,' which appears 201 times in the corpus, is vocalized only once as <span class="selectableFont" style="font-family: SertoJerusalem;">ܒ݁ܰܝܬ݁ܳܐ</span>. Initial <span style="font-style: italic;">bgdkpt</span> letters were always marked with a <span style="font-style: italic;">quššāyā</span> point; an algorithm was written to convert the <span style="font-style: italic;">quššāyā</span> into <span style="font-style: italic;">rukkākhā</span> if the preceding word, if any, ended in a vowel and was not followed by  a punctuation mark. The dot on the feminine object pronominal suffix <span class="selectableFont" style="font-family: SertoJerusalem;">ܗ̇</span> was not included in the pointing, and was added later on by another algorithm based on morphological data.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The next incarnation of the project was SEDRA III (1991). The first  change was the move from a relational database model to a network model  where ordered, one-to-many&nbsp;parent-child relations simplified the process  of concordance generation. In this model, a parent record would have a  pointer to the first child record in another table. That child record  would have a pointer to the next child, and so on. As laptops at the  time had small hard drives of about 10 or 20 MB, SEDRA III converted its  fields into bit fields. For instance, two bits were sufficient to  indicate person (00 for 1st person, 01 for 2nd, 10 for 3rd).  SEDRA III  contained 2,050 roots, 3,559 lexemes, 31,079 word forms and 6,337  English meanings (particular to the context of the New Testament). It  was published in 1993 on the web site of the University of Cambridge,  and later on Beth Mardutho's site hosted by The Catholic University of  America's Semitics Department, as a non-commercial open source database.  A number of developers downloaded SEDRA III and used it for lexical and  concordance applications. One such developer was James W. Bennett who  used SEDRA III underlying the BFBS Peshitta in his online <a href="http://syriac.tara-lu.com/web/library" target="_blank">Syriac Library Browser</a> and <a href="http://syriac.tara-lu.com/web/syriac" target="_blank">General Syriac Tools</a>.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">In February 2013, George Kiraz and James Bennett teamed up to develop  SEDRA IV (this web site). Starting from SEDRA III, the database was  converted back into a relational database, the binary fields where  expanded (now person is a numeric fields with textual references), and  additional tables and fields were added. The lexemes table was expanded  to include all the words in the Brock-Kiraz dictionary (ca. 15,000  words). Source data from printed lexica were imported either in image or  text format. More importantly, a morphological generation component was  added to the system with a grant from the International Balzan Prize  Foundation under the direction of Peter Brown (Princeton University) and  in collaboration with <a href="http://www.syriaca.org/" target="_blank">Syriaca.org</a>.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">SEDRA IV was launched in March 2015 at the Fourth Hugoye Symposium on  Syriac and the Digital Humanities (Beth Mardutho and Rutgers  University) and a crowd sourcing call went out asking scholars to tag  images of scanned lexical entries to the lexemes of the database. It is  expected that SEDRA IV will expand as a crowd sourced project.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> As of today (08/01/2016), SEDRA contains 3228 roots, 17905 lexemes, and 44270 words.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">						 							<br /><ul class="sedraMenu"><li><a href="https://sedra.bethmardutho.org/lexeme/get">Lexeme Search</a></li><li><a href="https://sedra.bethmardutho.org/lexeme/search">Word Search</a></li><li><a href="https://sedra.bethmardutho.org/lexeme/paradigm">Paradigms</a></li><li><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null">Library</a>									<ul><li><a href="https://sedra.bethmardutho.org/library">Syriac Resources</a></li><li><a href="https://sedra.bethmardutho.org/library/import">Dynamic Markup</a></li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2413880584905747641/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/08/sedra-syriac-electronic-data-research.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2413880584905747641"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2413880584905747641"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/08/sedra-syriac-electronic-data-research.html"
         title="SEDRA: The Syriac Electronic Data Research Archive"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
