<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2495287021287524945</id>
   <published>2016-12-10T14:22:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-12-10T14:23:08.388-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Classics"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Student Journal"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Vexillum: The Undergraduate Journal of Classical and Medieval Studies</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/">Vexillum: The Undergraduate Journal of Classical and Medieval Studies</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/cropped-vexillumbanner_final_9_smaller3.png" class="transparent" src="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/cropped-vexillumbanner_final_9_smaller3.png" height="63" width="320" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><i>Vexillum</i>&nbsp;</b>is an undergraduate journal that supports and promotes undergraduate scholarship in the fields of&nbsp;<b>Classical&nbsp;</b>and&nbsp;<b>Medieval Studies</b>, and accepts scholarly papers by undergraduate students written on a wide range of topics:&nbsp;<b>history, literature, philosophy, archaeology, art history, sociology, philology, and linguistics</b>. Sponsored by the <a href="http://medieval.yale.edu/" target="_blank" title="Medieval Studies Program at Yale University">Medieval Studies Program at Yale University</a>,&nbsp;<i>Vexillum</i>&nbsp;provides  a unique opportunity for undergraduate students to submit outstanding  papers for peer review from other undergraduates. Papers address aspects  of the cultures and civilizations of Europe, the Mediterranean, the  Near East, and Central Asia between 3,600 B.C.E. and 1500 C.E. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">As <i><b>Vexillum</b></i><b>&nbsp;</b>has an open  submission policy, the journal accepts submissions throughout the year.  We publish an annual volume featuring the 8-12 most deserving of these  submissions every fall. Undergraduates looking to submit their papers  should read our <a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wordpress/submission-guidelines/" title="Submission Guidelines">Submission Guidelines</a> prior to submission.&nbsp;We encourage them to submit unpublished articles  with original ideas and interdisciplinary research that will foster  scholarly discourse and distinguish themselves from their peers. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Since 2010 it has been our aim to provide a venue for scholars early  in their careers to showcase their work and contribute their fresh  voices and perspectives to the academic world at large. If you would  like to be involved in the journal’s work and receive e-mail updates  regarding calls for papers and upcoming publications, please send us an  e-mail at <a href="mailto:vexillumcontact@gmail.com" title="vexillumcontact@gmail.com">vexillumcontact@gmail.com</a>.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h1 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/current-issue/">Current Issue</a></span></h1><h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">Issue 5 (2016)</span></h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Vexillum-5-2016.pdf">Full Issue (.pdf)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Editorial-Staff-for-Vexillum-5-2016.pdf" target="_blank" title="2014 Editorial Staff">2015-2016 Editorial Staff</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Foreword-for-Vexillum-5-2016.pdf" target="_blank" title="Foreword">Foreword</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Table-of-Contents-for-Vexillum-5-2016.pdf">Table of Contents</a></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Loritz-The-Monastic-Symbolism-of-Prostitution-in-Late-Thirteenth-Century-France.pdf">The Monastic Symbolism of Prostitution in Late-Thirteenth-Century France</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>Sean Loritz, Sarah Lawrence College</em></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The motif of the reformed harlot is prevalent in medieval saints’  lives, but its implications are problematic. This paper begins to  examine these implications by contrasting the lives of Mary of Egypt and  Mary Magdalene, which circulated in France during the late thirteenth  century, with the lives of contemporaneous women in poverty to find that  they do not in fact resemble one another. Rather, this paper argues for  a reinterpretation of the prostitute as an example for—but more  importantly as a symbol of—the monks who comprised its audience. It then  examines the impact of this symbol’s usage on gender and sexuality  within the context of faith, including a monastic ideal of androgyny and  erotic overtones in the desire for Christ, particularly in the form of  communion. Finally, it contrasts the application of the symbol of the  prostitute to monks and nuns, finding that the latter suffer from their  affiliation in cases such as those of the Beguine sect, further  emphasizing the gap between the saints and actual women, prostitutes or  not, as well as their resemblance to male clerics.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Buckingham-Public-and-Private-Layers-of-Clothing-and-Tongue.pdf">Public and Private Layers of Clothing and Tongue: Marie de France’s Medieval Werewolf as Palimpsest</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>Kerri-Leigh Buckingham, St. Thomas University, New Brunswick</em></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Marie de France’s twelfth-century lai <em>Bisclavret</em> reveals the  significance of the use of transparent technologies to construct a  paradigm of the public versus private werewolf, human versus beast, Self  versus Other, and illustrates the importance of these technologies to  social perceptions and to one’s assertion of one’s own humanity,  revealing that the human and the werewolf are not as different as the  human attempts to profess. Both the human and werewolf are palimpsests:  beings constructed from perceptions based on the addition and removal of  layers of speech and clothing.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Sausmikat-Well-Behaved-Women-Rarely-Make-History.pdf">Well-Behaved Women Rarely Make History: Eleanor of Aquitaine’s Political Career and Its Significance to Noblewomen</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Rita Sausmikat, Lycoming College</i></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Eleanor of Aquitaine played an indirect role in the formation of  medieval and early modern Europe through her resources, wit, and royal  connections. The wealth and land the duchess acquired through her  inheritance and marriages gave her the authority to financially support  religious institutions and the credibility to administrate. Because of  her inheritance, Eleanor was a desirable match for Louis VII and Henry  II, giving her the title and benefits of queenship. Between both  marriages, Eleanor produced ten children, nine of whom became kings and  queens or married into royalty and power. The majority of her  descendants married royalty or aristocrats across the entire continent,  acknowledging Eleanor as the “Grandmother of Europe.” Her female  descendants constituted an essential part of court, despite the  limitations of women’s authority. Eleanor’s lifelong political career  acted as a guiding compass for other queens to follow.&nbsp; She influenced  her descendants and successors to follow her famous example in the  practices of intercession, property rights, and queenly role. Despite  suppression of public authority, women were still able to shape the  landscape of Europe, making Eleanor of Aquitaine a trailblazer who  transformed politics for future aristocratic women.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Johnson-Defining-Excellence-A-Grid-of-Jerome%E2%80%99s-%E2%80%9CGood%E2%80%9D-and-%E2%80%9CBad%E2%80%9D-Virgin-Spouse-and-Widow.pdf">Defining Excellence: A Grid of Jerome’s “Good” and “Bad” Virgin, Spouse, and Widow</a><em><br /></em><i>Maria S. E. Johnson, University of South Florida</i></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">By late antiquity, the status of women fell into three divisions:  marriage, widowhood, or celibacy. In the eyes of intellectual early  Christians, these states were not of equal merit. Specifically, Jerome  viewed virginity as the most holy state, then widowhood, followed by  marriage. However, his deprecation of marriage can appear so potent and  his asceticism so extreme that modern scholars struggle to provide a  balanced analysis of Jerome’s works. The focus of scholars on these two  aspects of Jerome’s works restricts them from the wider spectrum of  judgments Jerome has about the above three states. Analyzing his premier  works on virginity — Letter 22, Against Jovinian, and Against Helvidius  — I will show that Jerome offers readers not only a three-tier  hierarchy, but also an elaborate “grid,” identifying the “good” and  “bad” virgin, spouse, and widow. Additionally, I will demonstrate the  necessity for this detailed grid by arguing that its components were  evident in Jerome’s construction of Paula’s chaste sanctity in his  hagiography of her. The nuance and detail Jerome infuses into all of his  works should be equally appreciated in his judgments on not only  virginity, but also widowhood and marriage.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Pelpola-Liturgical-Functions-of-Late-Byzantine-Art.pdf">Liturgical Functions of Late Byzantine Art:&nbsp;An Analysis of the Thessaloniki Epitaphios</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Judith Shanika Pelpola, Stanford University</i></span><br /> <div><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Thessaloniki Epitaphios, a late Byzantine embroidered textile, is  an important piece to consider in the study of Byzantine art and its  role in liturgy. In this paper, I undertake a stylistic and formalistic  analysis of the inscriptions, depiction of the humanity of Christ, and  treatment of time in the Thessaloniki Epitaphios to determine if the  Epitaphios had liturgical rather than simply symbolic functions, thus  helping contextualize Byzantine art within the Western canon. Analyzing  the potential for the liturgical function of this piece additionally  sheds light onto how Byzantine art itself should be classified with  regards to the Western canon.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Matthews-The-Troubadours-Woman.pdf">The Troubadour’s Woman: Mirroring the Male Gaze in Early Medieval Literature</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>Thai Catherine Matthews, Wellesley College</em></span><br /> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;">The famed “lady” of the medieval courtly love narrative is introduced  into medieval literature by the French troubadour poets of the twelfth  century. They come singing her praises, conjuring with their poems and  their songs the ideal—and original—cruel, fair mistress of affections.  This is the <em>domna</em>, an archetype upheld in later literary tradition by famous figures like Isolde and Guinevere. The <em>domna</em> is a complicated figure; she is at once chaste and erotic, married and  yet destined to be worshipped only by men who are not her husband. The <em>domna</em> is accorded tremendous power from the beginning—if the troubadours who  bring her about are to be believed, she controls their hearts and their  appetites, their minds and their souls and whether or not they live. But  is this power a power at all? Or is this figure a mere construction of  the male gaze, manipulated and agitated in turn so that these male  authors can look back on the true objects of their affection—themselves?  The <em>domna</em> is ultimately a canvas upon which the troubadours  paint their own self-portraits, illustrations of pious sacrifice,  romanticized struggles, and introspections on the concept of love that  can only persist so long as the <em>domna</em> herself remains distant  from the lover, absent from the passion she is said to inspire and  consequently stripped of any ability to respond.</span><br /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h1 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Past Issues</span></h1><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/past-issues/issue-4/">Issue 4 (2014)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/past-issues/issue-3/">Issue 3 (2013)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/past-issues/issue-2/">Issue 2 (2012)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.vexillumjournal.org/past-issues/issue-1/">Issue 1 (2011)</a></span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><div style="text-align: center;"><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span>S</span><span><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="font-weight: normal;">ee AWOL's full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.co.uk/2015/12/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></span></span></div><br />And see <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/09/list-of-student-journals.html">AWOL's List of Student Journals</a> </div></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2495287021287524945/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/open-access-journal-vexillum.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2495287021287524945"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2495287021287524945"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/open-access-journal-vexillum.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Vexillum: The Undergraduate Journal of Classical and Medieval Studies"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
