<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9113912159332801991</id>
    <published>2014-07-22T11:23:00.001-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-22T11:23:14.555-04:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economy"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Mesopotamia"/>
    <title type="text">Commodity Prices in Babylon 385 - 61 BC </title>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: small;"><a
      href="http://www.iisg.nl/hpw/babylon.php">Commodity Prices in Babylon 385 - 61
      BC</a>&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: small;">Author:
      R.J. van der Spek&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: small;">Vrije
      Universiteit Amsterdam</span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"> <span
      style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>The datafile:</strong> <a
      href="http://www.iisg.nl/hpw/babylonia.xls">spreadsheet</a> <span
      class="small">(.xls, 1.15 Mb)</span> &nbsp;&nbsp; | &nbsp;&nbsp;<a
      href="http://www.iisg.nl/hpw/babylon.php#biblio">Bibliography</a></span>
      </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"> <span style="font-size:
      x-small;"><strong>1. Introduction</strong><br />The economic historian of
      the Ancient World is confronted with a lack of numerical data on wages and prices. There is of
      course evidence (see in general HEICHELHEIM 1930), especially from Ptolemaic and Roman Egypt
      (DREXHAGE 1991; MARESCH 1996; CADELL &amp; LE RIDER 1997) and Delos (REGER 1994), but not
      on a regular year to year basis. However, there is one notable exception: late Achaemenid and
      Hellenistic Babylon. From this city in South Iraq we have the most detailed dataset of the
      ancient world, which can compete with datasets from modern history.</span><br />
      <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>1.1. The sources</strong><br
      />We owe this precious information to the conscientious work of Babylonian astronomers.
      Probably from the reign of the Babylonian king Nabonassar (747-743 BC), and at the instigation
      of this king, Babylonian astronomers started to make a daily record of the starry sky. These
      astronomers were professional scholars. From a tablet in Yale (YBC 11549) dating to the early
      Hellenistic period we know that at least 14 of them were fully employed by the temple. They
      each received 180 litres of barley per month (BEAULIEU, forthcoming). From a couple of very
      late texts (127-119 BC) we know that the job was hereditary on condition that the scholars were
      capable to do the job. They received an annual salary from the temple (60 - 120 shekels of
      silver = ca. 120 - 240 drachms = 500 to 1,000 grams of silver) plus the revenue of some tract
      of arable land (VAN DER SPEK 1985: 548ff). It is interesting to see how the payment in grain
      shifted to payment in money.<br /><br /> The records, usually called
      <strong><em>Astronomical Diaries</em></strong>, consisted of daily
      information on the position of the moon (rise and setting) and the planets in relation to the
      fixed stars, and from the early fifth century in relation to zodiacal signs. In addition,
      solstices and equinoxes, Sirius phenomena, meteors, comets and flashes and strokes of lightning
      were recorded. The diaries give also information on the weather (e.g. "clouds were in the sky;
      I could not watch") and the level of the Euphrates. At the end of a monthly section some
      historical events were recorded (mainly on campaigns of the king, visits of the king or high
      officials to Babylon, cultic events, etc.) and the prices of six commodities were given:
      barley, dates, "mustard?", "cress?", sesame and wool. Barley and dates constituted the main
      diet of the Babylonians. For more information on the diaries, see: <a
      href="http://www.livius.org/di-dn/diaries/astronomical_diaries.html">Astronomical
      diaries</a>.<br />The earliest diary we have dates to 651 BC, but we have only a
      more or less regular record from 385 BC on. Hence, our list starts in this year. Michael Jursa
      (Vienna) is presently studying the prices of the earlier periods of Babylonia. He is the leader
      of a project on the economy of first millennium Babylonia. More on this project: <a
      href="http://216.239.59.104/search?q=cache:tCWh3rcENpAJ:www.bmbwk.gv.at/medienpool/7409/preistraeger.pdf+Michael+Jursa&amp;hl=nl%20target=nw">Wittgenstein-Preisträger</a>.<br
      />Dr. Gerfrid Müller has written a Habilitationsschrift about the development of the economy
      and the prices in the period just prior to our dataset (MÜLLER, forthcoming; <em>non
      vidi</em>)...</span></blockquote>]]></content>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9113912159332801991/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/07/commodity-prices-in-babylon-385-61-bc.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9113912159332801991"/>
    <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9113912159332801991"/>
    <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/07/commodity-prices-in-babylon-385-61-bc.html"
         title="Commodity Prices in Babylon 385 - 61 BC "/>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      
    </author>
    
  </entry>
