<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2388316062585817175</id>
   <published>2014-02-15T20:10:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2014-06-02T14:43:14.495-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Monograph Series: Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization (SAOC)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/">Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization (SAOC)</a><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;<a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc68.html">SAOC 68. Extraction &amp; Control: Studies in Honor of Matthew W. Stolper.</a> Edited by Michael Kozuh, Wouter F. M. Henkelman, Charles E. Jones, and Christopher Woods. 2014.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc67/">SAOC 67. Language and Nature: Papers Presented to John Huehnergard on the Occasion of His 60th Birthday.</a> Edited by Rebecca Hasselbach and Na’ama Pat-El. 2012.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc66.html">SAOC  66. Pesher Nahum: Texts and Studies in Jewish History and Literature  from Antiquity through the Middle Ages Presented to Norman (Nahum) Golb.</a> Edited by Joel L. Kraemer and Michael G. Wechsler with the participation of Fred Donner, Joshua Holo, and Dennis Pardee. 2012</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc65.html">SAOC 65. Perspectives on Ptolemaic Thebes. Occasional Proceedings of the Theban Workshop.</a>  Peter F. Dorman and Betsy M. Bryan, eds. 2011.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc64.html">SAOC  64. Grammatical Case in the Languages of the Middle East and Europe.  Acts of the International Colloquium Variations, concurrence et  evolution des cas dans divers domaines linguistiques, Paris, 2-4 April  2007.</a> Edited by Michèle Fruyt, Michel Mazoyer, and Dennis Pardee. 2011.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc63.html">SAOC 63. Beyond the Ubaid: Transformation and integration in the late prehistoric societies of the middle east.</a> Edited by Robert A. Carter and Graham Philip. 2010.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc62.html">SAOC  62. Proceedings of the 51st Rencontre Assyriologique Internationale,  Held at the Oriental Institute of the University of Chicago, July 18–22,  2005.</a> 2008.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc54.html">SAOC 54, 4th Printing. The Mechanics of Ancient Egyptian Magical Practice, 4th Printing.</a> R. K. Ritner. Originally published in 2008.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc61.html">SAOC 61. Sacred Space and Sacred Function in Ancient Thebes.</a> Peter F. Dorman and Betsy M. Bryan, ed. 2007.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc60.html">SAOC 60. Studies in Semitic and Afroasiatic Linguistics Presented to Gene B. Gragg.</a> Cynthia L. Miller, ed. 2007.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc59.html">SAOC 59. Studies in the Archaeology of Israel and Neighboring Lands in Memory of Douglas L. Esse.</a> Samuel R. Wolff, ed. 2001.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc58.html">SAOC 58. Gold of Praise: Studies on Ancient Egypt in Honor of Edward F. Wente.</a> E. Teeter and J. A. Larson, eds. 1999.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc57.html">SAOC 57. The Presentation of Maat: Ritual and Legitimacy in Ancient Egypt.</a> By Emily Teeter. Originally published in 1997.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc56.html">SAOC 56. Portrait Mummies from Roman Egypt (I-IV Centuries A.D.) with a Catalog of Portrait Mummies in Egyptian Museums.</a> By Lorelei H. Corcoran. Originally published in 1995.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc55.html">SAOC 55. For His Ka: Essays Offered in Memory of Klaus Baer.</a> D. P. Silverman, ed. 1994.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc54.html">SAOC 54. The Mechanics of Ancient Egyptian Magical Practice.</a> R. K. Ritner. 1993.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc53.html">SAOC 53. Glass from Quseir al-Qadim and the Indian Ocean Trade.</a> C. Meyer. 1992.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc52.html">SAOC 52. A Late Period Hieratic Wisdom Text (P. Brooklyn 47.218.135).</a> R. Jasnow. 1992.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc51.html">SAOC 51. Life in a Multi-Cultural Society: Egypt from Cambyses to Constantine and Beyond.</a> Janet Johnson.</span>   </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc50.html">SAOC 50. Subsistence, Trade, and Social Change in Early Bronze Age Palestine.</a> D. L. Esse. 1991.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc49.html">SAOC 49. A Critical Study of the Temple Scroll from Qumran Cave 11.</a> M. O. Wise. 1990.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc48.html">SAOC 48. Egyptian Phyles in the Old Kingdom: The Evolution of a System of Social Organization.</a> By Ann Macy Roth. Originally published in 1991. D. L. Esse. 1991.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc47.html">SAOC 47. Essays in Ancient Civilization Presented to Helene J. Kantor.</a> A. Leonard, Jr. and B. B. Williams, eds. 1989.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc46.html">SAOC 46. The Organization of Power: Aspects of Bureaucracy in the Ancient Near East.</a> McGuire Gibson and Robert D. Biggs, eds. (Second Edition with Corrections). Originally published in 1991.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc45.html">SAOC 45. Thus Wrote ‘Onchsheshonqy - An Introductory Grammar of Demotic (Third Edition)</a>. Janet H. Johnson. Third edition, 2000.</span>   </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc44.html">SAOC 44. Nippur Neighborhoods.</a> E. C. Stone. 1987.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc43.html">SAOC 43. A Neolithic Village at Tell El Kowm in the Syrian Desert.</a> R. Dornemann. 1986.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc42.html">SAOC  42, 2nd Edition. The Road to Kadesh: A Historical Interpretation of the  Battle Reliefs of King Sety I at Karnak, 2nd Edition.</a> W. J. Murnane. Originally published in 1990.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc42.html">SAOC 42. The Road to Kadesh: A Historical Interpretation of the Battle Reliefs of King Sety I at Karnak.</a> W. J. Murnane. Originally published in 1985.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc41.html">SAOC 41. Ecology and Empire: The Structure of the Urartian State.</a> Paul E. Zimansky. Originally published in 1985.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc40.html">SAOC 40. Ancient Egyptian Coregencies.</a> By William J. Murnane. Originally published in 1977. </span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc39.html">SAOC 39. Studies in Honor of George R. Hughes, January 12, 1977.</a> J. H. Johnson and E. F. Wente, eds. 1976.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc38.html">SAOC 38. The Demotic Verbal System</a>. Janet H. Johnson. Second printing, with corrections, 2004.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc37.html">SAOC  37. The Book of the Dead or Going Forth by Day: Ideas of the Ancient  Egyptians Concerning the Hereafter as Expressed in Their Own Terms.</a> Translated by Thomas George Allen. Originally published in 1974.&nbsp;</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc36.html">SAOC  36. The Hilly Flanks and Beyond: Essays on the Prehistory of  Southwestern Asia Presented to Robert J. Braidwood, November 15, 1982.</a> T. Cuyler Young, Jr., Philip E. L. Smith, and Peder Mortensen, editors. Originally published in 1983.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc35.html">SAOC 35. Studies in Honor of John A. Wilson.</a> E. B. Hauser, ed. 1969.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc34.html">SAOC 34. A Study of the Ba Concept in Ancient Egyptian Texts.</a> By Louis V. Zabkar. Originally published in 1968. </span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc33.html">SAOC 33. Late Ramesside Letters.</a> By Edward F. Wente. Originally published in 1967. </span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc32.html">SAOC 32. Patterns in the Early Poetry of Israel.</a> Stanley Gevirtz. Originally published in 1963.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc31.html">SAOC 31. Prehistoric Investigations in Iraqi Kurdistan.</a> R. J. Braidwood and B. Howe. 1960.</span>  </li><li> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc30.html">SAOC 30. Wall Scenes from the Mortuary Chapel of the Mayor Paser at Medinet Habu.</a> By Siegfried Schott. Translated By Elizabeth B. Hauser. Originally published in 1957.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc28.html">SAOC 28. Saite Demotic Land Leases.</a> By George Robert Hughes. Originally published in 1952.</span></li><li> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc27.html">SAOC 27. Occurrences of Pyramid Texts with Cross Indexes of These and Other Egyptian Mortuary Texts.</a> By Thomas George Allen. Originally published in 1950.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc26.html">SAOC 26. The Calendars of Ancient Egypt.</a> By Richard A. Parker. Originally published in 1950.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc25.html">SAOC 25. The Comparative Archeology of Early Mesopotamia.</a> A. L. Perkins. 1949 (7th printing, 1977).</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc25.html">SAOC 25. The Comparative Archeology of Early Mesopotamia.</a> Ann Louise Perkins. Originally published in 1949.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc24.html">SAOC 24. Babylonian Chronology,  626 B.C. - A.D. 45.</a> Richard A. Parker and Waldo H. Dubberstein. Originally published in 1942.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc23.html">SAOC 23. The Comparative Stratigraphy of Early Iran.</a> Donald E. McCown. Originally published in 1942.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc22.html">SAOC 22. Hurrians and Subarians.</a> Ignace J. Gelb. Originally published in 1944.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc21.html">SAOC 21. Hittite Hieroglyphs 3.</a> Ignace J. Gelb. Originally published in 1942.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc20.html">SAOC 20. Animal Remains from Tell Asmar</a> Max Hilzheimer. 1941.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc19.html">SAOC 19. The Coregency of Ramses II with Seti I and the Date of the Great Hypostyle Hall at Karnak.</a> By Keith C. Seele. Originally published in 1940.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc18.html">SAOC 18. The Hyksos Reconsidered.</a> Robert M. Engberg. Originally published in 1939.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc17.html">SAOC 17. Notes on the Megiddo Pottery of Strata VI-XX.</a> Geoffrey M. Shipton.  Originally published in 1939.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc16.html">SAOC 16. The Monasteries of the Fayyum. By Nabia Abbott. Originally published in 1937.</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc15.html">SAOC 15. The Kurrah Papyri from Aphrodito in the Oriental Institute.</a> Nabia Abbott. Originally published in 1938.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc14.html">SAOC 14. Hittite Hieroglyphs 2.</a> Ignace J. Gelb. Originally published in 1935.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc13.html">SAOC 13. The Oriental Origin of Hellenistic Kingship.</a> Calvin W. McEwan. Originally published in 1934.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc12.html">SAOC 12. Historical Records of Ramses III: The Texts in Medinet Habu Volumes 1 and 2.</a> Translated With Explanatory Notes. By William F. Edgerton and John A. Wilson. Originally published in 1936.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc11.html">SAOC 11. Epiphanius’ Treatise on Weights and Measures: The Syriac Version.</a> James Elmer Dean, ed. With a Foreword by Martin Sprengling. Originally published in 1935.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc10.html">SAOC 10. Notes on the Chalcolithic and Early Bronze Age Pottery of Megiddo.</a> Robert M. Engberg and Geoffrey M. Shipton. Originally published in 1934.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc9.html">SAOC 9. Die Pakhy-Sprache.</a> Julius von Meszaros. Originally published in 1934.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc8.html">SAOC 8. The Thutmosid Succession.</a> By William F. Edgerton. Originally published in 1933.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc7.html">SAOC 7. Plano-Convex Bricks and the Methods of Their Employment; II. The Treatment of Clay Tablets in the Field.</a> Pinhas Delougaz. Originally published in 1933.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc6.html">SAOC 6. Kitab al-Zahrah: The Book of the Flower. Composed by Abu Bakr Muhammad Ibn Abi Sulaiman Dawud Al-Isfahani.</a> A. R. Nykl, ed. In collaboration with Ibrahim Tuqan. Originally published in 1932.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc5.html">SAOC 5. A New Inscription of Xerxes from Persepolis</a> Ernst E. Herzfeld. 1932.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc4.html">SAOC 4. Archeology and the Sumerian Problem.</a> Henri Frankfort. Originally published in 1932.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc3.html">SAOC 3. Die Hethitische Bilderschrift.</a> Emil O. Forrer. Originally published in 1932.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc2.html">SAOC 2. Hittite Hieroglyphs 1.</a> Ignace J. Gelb. Originally published in 1931.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc1.html">SAOC 1. Notes on Egyptian Marriage Chiefly in the Ptolemaic Period.</a> William F. Edgerton. Originally published in 1931.</span></li></ul>For an up to date list of all Oriental Institute publications available online see: <br /><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/10/oriental-institute-open-access.html">The Oriental Institute Open Access Publications</a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2388316062585817175/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/02/open-access-monographic-series-studies.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2388316062585817175"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2388316062585817175"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/02/open-access-monographic-series-studies.html"
         title="Open Access Monograph Series: Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization (SAOC)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
