<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7950001810712759404</id>
   <published>2015-11-11T10:56:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-11-11T10:58:25.620-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Now Available: GreekKeys 2015</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://classicalstudies.org/publications-and-research/about-greekkeys-2015">GreekKeys 2015</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">&nbsp;<img alt="https://classicalstudies.org/sites/default/files/logo_scs_fixed.png" class="transparent" src="https://classicalstudies.org/sites/default/files/logo_scs_fixed.png" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">About GreekKeys 2015&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><span style="font-size: x-small;">GreekKeys 2015 is the latest revision of a custom polytonic Greek  keyboard program with accompanying fonts that has long been useful to  many scholars, teachers, and students of the ancient and medieval Greek  worlds. GreekKeys fonts and keyboards provide easy access to many  specialized characters (e.g., for metrics, epigraphy, and papyrology)  that are absent from most system fonts and that would otherwise have to  be entered in roundabout or obscure ways.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you need only the standard polytonic Greek characters, you may  wish to try the free fonts and keyboards that come with Windows OS and  Mac OS X. GreekKeys is intended for those with particular scholarly  needs and for those who appreciate a simple scheme for the location of  the accent characters.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>NOTE:&nbsp; </b>The Society for Classical Studies (SCS) is  providing GreekKeys 2015 as a service to the scholarly community but  cannot provide support to individual users.&nbsp; SCS has reduced the price  of this software to reflect the fact that the software is being provided  on an "as is" basis.&nbsp; <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/publications-and-research/greekkeys-2015-support" target="_blank">SCS offers and will periodically update a help page for the software</a>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>System Requirements</b></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Mac OS X 10.5 or higher (can also be installed manually on 10.3 or 10.4).</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Windows 7, 8, or 10 (not tested with Windows XP, but probably works).</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Tested with the latest versions of MS Word as of 2015, but also works  with Word 2008 and later for Mac and Word 2003 and later for Windows.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Contents of the Package</b></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">This product is supplied only as a download. The download may appear as <b>GreekKeys2015.zip</b> or, if your OS automatically decompresses the archive, as a folder named <b>GreekKeys2015</b>.  If your Windows system is set up not to show file extensions, you can  recognize the difference by the icon: the compressed version has a  zipper on the icon, the uncompressed version appears as an ordinary  folder.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The folder contains important documentation as well as the installers  and fonts. Please read the QuickStart document before installing, or  for fuller instructions with illustrations <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/ckfinder/userfiles/files/GK2015UserGuide.pdf">see the UserGuide document</a>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Non-member purchasers should archive a copy of the download in a safe  location and medium (such as cloud storage or a backup disk), so that  it will be available after a total computer failure or loss or  replacement.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>What’s New in GreekKeys 2015</b></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you already own GreekKeys 2008, what are the benefits of upgrading?</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">  GreekKeys 2015 is free to members of the SCS.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">  Mac OS X keyboards contain corrections of some omissions affecting  complex key entries and have added access to some recently-approved  official Unicode code points.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">  Mac OS X keyboards now contain a language definition, which obviates  certain incompatibilities that arose in MS Word 2011 for Mac.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">  New Mac installer does not require a restart.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">  Windows keyboards have been slightly revised to work around incompatibilities that arise on some Windows systems.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">  Windows keyboards have added access to some recently-approved official Unicode code points.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">  GreekKeys fonts now use a format of OpenType substitution that works  automatically in most cases (no need to figure out how to turn on  ligatures).</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">  GreekKeys fonts now contain precomposed glyphs for lowercase Greek letters with overstroke (for numerals or for citing words).</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">  GreekKeys fonts have added some recently approved Unicode characters,  and minor aesthetic improvements and corrections have been made.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">  Documentation has been brought up to date (partly to reflect changes  in nomenclature and organization used in the latest OS versions), with  more illustrations of installation process, better Keyboard Charts, and  improved and updated documentation of Private Use Area characters and  precomposed characters of interest to advanced users.</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Pricing</b></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">GreekKeys 2015 is free to members of the SCS. <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/user/login" target="_blank">Log in to the SCS web site</a> and then <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/greek-keys" target="_blank">proceed to the purchase page</a>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Individuals who are not members of the SCS must first <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/user/register" target="_blank">create an account on the SCS web site</a>, but then may buy GreekKeys for $20.00 <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/greek-keys" target="_blank">through the purchase page</a>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Departmental licenses are also available to departments that are  departmental members of the SCS. (Departmental membership is separate  from individual membership.)&nbsp; The small department license is limited to  9 or fewer users and costs $100. The unlimited department license costs  $200. But the unlimited license is free to departments paying dues at  the Supporting or Sustaining level. Departmental licenses for GreekKeys  2015 include an extended license for distribution to students at no  extra charge.&nbsp; For more information, <a href="https://classicalstudies.org/membership/departmental-membership-scs" target="_blank">see the Departmental Membership page</a>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Purchase/Download</b></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">- See more at: https://classicalstudies.org/publications-and-research/about-greekkeys-2015#sthash.mxOmfh2R.dpuf </span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7950001810712759404/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/now-available-greekkeys-2015.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7950001810712759404"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7950001810712759404"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/now-available-greekkeys-2015.html"
         title="Now Available: GreekKeys 2015"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
