<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7999884343466068992</id>
   <published>2015-11-19T14:23:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-11-19T14:23:18.602-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="numismatics"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greece"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Macedonia"/>
   <title type="text">Pella: Coinage of the Kings of Macedonia</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://numismatics.org/pella/">The American Numismatic Society Announces the Launch of PELLA</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://numismatics.org/wikiuploads/NewsEvents/pella-heracles.jpg" height="194" src="http://numismatics.org/wikiuploads/NewsEvents/pella-heracles.jpg" width="200" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">November 19, 2015</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="urllink" href="http://numismatics.org/About/About" rel="nofollow">The American Numismatic Society</a> (ANS) is excited to announce the launch of its latest digital platform, PELLA (<a class="urllink" href="http://numismatics.org/pella/" rel="nofollow">http://numismatics.org/pella/</a>),  an important new research tool for ancient Greek numismatics that  provides a comprehensive, easily accessible online catalogue of the  coinage produced by the kings of the Macedonian Argead dynasty  (c.700–310 BC). Cataloguing the individual coin types of the kings from  Alexander I (ruled 498–454 BC), the first of the Macedonian kings to  strike coins, down to Philip III Arrhidaeus (ruled 323–317 BC), PELLA  allows users to conduct research on specific types, view examples from  multiple collections, conduct statistical analyses of weight and other  measurement data, and see maps of where the type was minted and where  examples have been found in hoards.<br /><br />As a linked data project, PELLA connects to the relevant pages within the ANS's collection website, MANTIS (<a class="urllink" href="http://numismatics.org/search/" rel="nofollow">http://numismatics.org/search/</a>), as well as Inventory of Greek Coin Hoards Online (<a class="urllink" href="http://coinhoards.org/" rel="nofollow">http://coinhoards.org</a>),  and incorporates material from other public collections. The current  version of PELLA provides links to examples of the coinage (in the name)  of Alexander the Great and Philip III Arrhidaeus present in the ANS  collection, the Münzkabinett of the State Museums of Berlin, and the  British Museum totaling nearly 10,000 examples of individual coins. The  current version of PELLA uses the numbering system and typology  originally created and published by Martin Price in <em>The Coinage in the Name of Alexander the Great and Philip Arhidaeus,</em> London 1991, with the addition of modifications that greatly enhance the volume’s usefulness as an online resource.<br /><br />PELLA is made possible by stable numismatic identifiers and linked open data methodologies established by the <a class="urllink" href="http://nomisma.org/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Nomisma.org</a> project. Coin type data are made available with an Open Database License. <br /><br /><a class="urllink" href="http://numismatics.org/About/PetervanAlfen" rel="nofollow">Dr. Peter van Alfen</a>,  Margaret Thompson Associate Curator of Greek Coins, commented on the  announcement. "The Macedonian kings of the Argead dynasty struck  arguably the most influential coinages of the ancient Greek world, so  it’s appropriate that our first digital project in Greek numismatics  focuses on their coinage. We also wanted to provide a specific platform  for facilitating research on their coinages, particularly since the ANS  holds one of the largest and most important collections of Argead  coinage in the world. By being able to link to other important  collections, the research potential is significantly enhanced. The ANS  is committed to enhancing its online presence and digitizing its  collection - PELLA is another example of our progress, and we are proud  it well help educate those with general numismatic interest as well as  academic researchers.”</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7999884343466068992/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/pella-coinage-of-kings-of-macedonia.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7999884343466068992"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7999884343466068992"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/pella-coinage-of-kings-of-macedonia.html"
         title="Pella: Coinage of the Kings of Macedonia"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
