<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-83922226196260657</id>
   <published>2014-06-05T16:23:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2014-06-05T18:34:45.047-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Rome"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="numismatics"/>
   <title type="text">News from Online Coins of the Roman Empire (OCRE)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.jiscmail.ac.uk/cgi-bin/webadmin?A2=ind1406&amp;L=DIGITALCLASSICIST&amp;F=&amp;S=&amp;P=2740">From the DIGITALCLASSICIST list</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">&nbsp;<span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://numismatics.org/ocre/">Online Coins of the Roman Empire (OCRE)</a> has seen significant progress in the last six months:</span><br /><div><div><div><div><ol><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">All types through Pupienus have been added (OCRE contains nearly 20,000 Roman imperial coin types)</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"> More than 25,000 individual physical specimens have been linked to  these types from four different collections, including the American  Numismatic Society (12,997 coins) and the British Museum (11,566 coins).  We expect to incorporate data from major archaeological  databases, such as the <a href="http://finds.org.uk/">Portable Antiquities Scheme</a> and the <a href="http://numismatics.org/ocre/">European Coin Find Network</a>, in the future.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"> The National Endowment for the Humanities awarded the project  $300,000 for three years to fund the completion of the project,  including the full photography of the ANS' Roman imperial collection.</span></li></ol></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">We're interested in expanding the base of data contributors. The greater  number of coins linked to OCRE-defined coin types, the more accurate  the quantitative and geographic analyses become. Please see <a href="http://wiki.numismatics.org/nomisma:nomisma_-_participation">here</a> for  documentation on how to contribute data to OCRE and other numismatic  linked data projects (a joint ANS-British Museum project based on  Michael Crawford's Roman Republican Coinage (1974) corpus  will launch within a few months).</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ethan Gruber<br />American Numismatic Society</span></blockquote>And from <a href="http://numishare.blogspot.com/2014/06/ocre-updates-coin-types-through.html">Numishare</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="date-header"><span>Thursday, June 5, 2014</span></div></blockquote><a href="https://draft.blogger.com/null" name="5129794792947232026"></a><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h3 class="post-title entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;">OCRE updates: coin types through Pupienus added </span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="post-header"> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="post-body entry-content"><div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">There are a few significant updates to report with <a href="http://numismatics.org/ocre/">OCRE</a> (Online Coins of the Roman Empire). First, we have added all of the  coin types through Pupienus (A.D. 238). There are now more than 19,000  Roman imperial coin types represented in OCRE. I have also generated new  RDF dumps from both the ANS and British Museum collections, so we now  have physical specimens (including images in some cases) for these new  types. The last update from the ANS is from Septimius Severus, I  believe, so we added thousands more physical coins into the <a href="http://nomisma.org/">nomisma.org</a> triplestore that power's OCRE's linking. There are about 25,000 physical objects linked to types defined on OCRE. The new <a href="http://numismatics.org/ocre/contributors">Contributors</a> page is a dynamic representation of collections that have submitted data into the triplestore. The <a href="http://coins.lib.virginia.edu/">University of Virginia collection</a> has been updated to link a few coins of Severus Alexander and Maximinus Thrax into OCRE. Two of these are from the <a href="http://numismatics.org/ocre/results?q=findspot_facet%3A%22Oliver%27s+Orchard+Hoards%22">Oliver's Orchard Hoards</a>,  a large hoard excavated in Britain in the 1980s. About half of UVA's  collection comes from this hoard, and so there will be more  georeferenced coins added into the system eventually, as we make our way  through the Crisis of the Third Century. As such, the two coins of  Severus Alexander from this hoard, published in the UVA collection, are  the first two physical objects available in OCRE that have attested  findspots.</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />Importantly, OCRE has been migrated to the newest version of Numishare.  OCRE is functionally the same as before, but the query process for  displaying thumbnails on search results pages is more efficient. Pages  will load slightly faster while browsing the collection. This migration  also means that the new version of the project uses the <a href="http://getbootstrap.com/">Bootstrap</a> framework, which means that the site is responsive, functionally equally as well on mobile devices as on desktop ones.</span></div><div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"> <span class="post-author vcard">Posted by <span class="fn">Ethan Gruber</span></span></span><span class="post-timestamp"><span style="font-size: x-small;">at <a class="timestamp-link" href="http://numishare.blogspot.com/2014/06/ocre-updates-coin-types-through.html" rel="bookmark" title="permanent link"><abbr class="published" title="2014-06-05T08:57:00-07:00">8:57 AM</abbr></a></span></span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/83922226196260657/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/06/news-from-online-coins-of-roman-empire.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/83922226196260657"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/83922226196260657"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/06/news-from-online-coins-of-roman-empire.html"
         title="News from Online Coins of the Roman Empire (OCRE)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
