<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7778105257974172378</id>
   <published>2016-07-26T10:26:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-07-26T10:26:23.581-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">News from the Corpus of Mesopotamian Anti-witchcraft Rituals Project (CMAwR)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://twitter.com/bibelorient/status/757719316699774976">News from the Corpus of Mesopotamian Anti-witchcraft Rituals Project (CMAwR)</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This year two volumes of Mesopotamian anti-witchcraft lore have appeared:<br />- Tzvi Abusch, The Magical Ceremony Maqlû (Ancient Magic and Divination 10), Leiden – Boston: Brill, 2016.<br />- Tzvi Abusch – Daniel Schwemer – Mikko Luukko – Greta Van Buylaere, Corpus of Mesopotamian Anti-witchcraft Rituals, vol. 2 (Ancient Magic and Divination 8/2), Leiden – Boston: Brill, 2016.<br /><br />Respecting Brill’s moving wall, all the texts edited in these volumes will eventually be presented online within the framework of Oracc. <br /><br />At present, CMAwRo (http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/cmawro/corpus) comprises the texts edited in Tzvi Abusch - Daniel Schwemer, Corpus of Mesopotamian Anti-witchcraft Rituals, vol. 1 (Ancient Magic and Divination 8/1), Leiden - Boston: Brill, 2011. A pdf-file with corrections and additions to this volume can be found at: <a href="http://www.cmawro.altorientalistik.uni-wuerzburg.de/cmawr_corrections/">http://www.cmawro.altorientalistik.uni-wuerzburg.de/cmawr_corrections/</a>. On this page you can also consult a list of additional manuscripts to previously edited texts. The addenda to texts from vol. 1 are being integrated online at Oracc’s CMAwRo. <br /><br />In 2017, the texts of vol. 2 and their addenda will become available in the same place. The additional manuscripts to volumes 1 and 2 will be included in the final volume of Anti-witchcraft Rituals (CMAwR 3; AMD 8/3) that we are currently working on. It will be published in 2019.<br /><br />At the moment, the Critical Catalogue of Mesopotamian Anti-witchcraft Rituals (CCMAwR; <a href="http://www.ccmawr.altorientalistik.uni-wuerzburg.de/ccmawr/index.php">http://www.ccmawr.altorientalistik.uni-wuerzburg.de/ccmawr/index.php</a>) encompasses information on the tablets published in CMAwR vol. 1 and 2 and in Tzvi Abusch’s Maqlû. Especially worth noting is the recent online prepublication of Daniel Schwemer’s hand-copies of most of the Maqlû manuscripts as part of the Critical Catalogue. <br /><br />General information on Mesopotamian witchcraft, including information on the use of CMAwRo and the Bibliography of Mesopotamian Magic, can be found at <a href="http://www.cmawro.altorientalistik.uni-wuerzburg.de/startseite/">http://www.cmawro.altorientalistik.uni-wuerzburg.de/startseite/</a>. <br /><br />Acknowledgements<br />CCMAwR, CMAwRo, and CMAwR, vol. 2, were created as part of the DFG-funded project Corpus babylonischer Rituale und Beschwörungen gegen Schadenzauber: Edition, lexikalische Erschließung, historische und literarische Analyse, directed by Daniel Schwemer at the University of Würzburg.<br />&nbsp;</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7778105257974172378/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/07/news-from-corpus-of-mesopotamian-anti.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7778105257974172378"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7778105257974172378"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/07/news-from-corpus-of-mesopotamian-anti.html"
         title="News from the Corpus of Mesopotamian Anti-witchcraft Rituals Project (CMAwR)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
