<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-999514412976597076</id>
   <published>2015-05-27T21:55:00.004-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-09-18T16:08:01.388-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Harpokration On Line</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="https://blogs.library.duke.edu/dcthree/2015/05/26/harpokration-on-line/">Harpokration On Line</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="entry-date"><a href="https://blogs.library.duke.edu/dcthree/2015/05/26/harpokration-on-line/" rel="bookmark"><time class="entry-date" datetime="2015-05-26T14:44:33+00:00">May 26, 2015</time></a></span> <span class="byline"><span class="author vcard"><a class="url fn n" href="https://blogs.library.duke.edu/dcthree/author/jds15duke-edu/" rel="author">Joshua Sosin</a></span></span><span class="comments-link"></span>     </span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">     </span></blockquote><div class="entry-content"><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">About a year ago the Suda On Line [<a href="http://www.stoa.org/sol">http://www.stoa.org/sol</a>]  passed an amazing milestone: all entries translated. This was an  exciting moment, and one that resonated here at Duke: SOL was an  inspiration for the Papyrological Editor (<a href="http://papyri.info/">papyri.info</a>), much of whose internals we call SoSOL, “<a href="http://wiki.digitalclassicist.org/SoSOL">Son of Suda On Line</a>.”</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Around that time I was starting to get interested in Harpokration’s  lexicon, mainly for the light that it shed on Athenian law. But before  long I was in deep. As Fall set in, John Paul Aldrup-MacDonald,  Mackenzie Zalin, and I decided it would be a fun service to translate  Harpokration. We began to meet every couple weeks over lunch, took our  time, learned from each other, did not rush. At some point we figured we  ought to release a few hundred entries to the web and see whether  anyone else wanted to join us, in a spirit similar to that which has  driven SOL.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">I guess we had a little too much fun: by spring we had amassed draft translations of all but a few entries. Our colleague <a href="https://ryanfb.github.io/">Ryan Baumann</a> was kind enough to whip up a lightweight tool to support crowd translation.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">So, here we are; if you would like to join us,</span><br /><ol><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">go to <a href="http://cite-harpokration.appspot.com/">http://cite-harpokration.appspot.com</a>, click on the link to ‘authorize'; use your google address</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://blogs.library.duke.edu/dcthree/files/2015/05/CITE-authorization.png"><img alt="CITE-authorization" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-257" height="195" src="https://blogs.library.duke.edu/dcthree/files/2015/05/CITE-authorization-300x195.png" width="300" /></a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">close that window and go to <a href="http://dcthree.github.io/harpokration">http://dcthree.github.io/harpokration</a> (authentication can be a little fussy; so, let us know if you encounter problems: <a href="mailto:dcthree@duke.edu">dcthree@duke.edu</a>)</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">find an entry that you would like to translate (either newly or in order to correct mistakes that we have made)</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">click on “Add translation for urn.cts:greekLit …” above the entry</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://blogs.library.duke.edu/dcthree/files/2015/05/agoranomoiTranslated.png"><img alt="agoranomoiTranslated" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-258" height="193" src="https://blogs.library.duke.edu/dcthree/files/2015/05/agoranomoiTranslated-300x193.png" width="300" /></a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">This will open a form in which you may enter a translation and any (plain text) notes that you would like to leave for others.</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://blogs.library.duke.edu/dcthree/files/2015/05/agoranomoiEditor.png"><img alt="agoranomoiEditor" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-259" height="186" src="https://blogs.library.duke.edu/dcthree/files/2015/05/agoranomoiEditor-300x186.png" width="300" /></a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Translate, click “Submit,” move on.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">We have been adding pointers to corresponding Suda entries; this is  not yet a feature of the translation form. We may add it later. If/when  we do, you will enter simply, e.g., “alpha,302″.</span></li></ol><span style="font-size: x-small;">This is meant to be simple, fast, lightweight; both tool and translations are <b>works in progress</b>. Thus,</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">There is no peer-review in the formal and narrow sense of  gate-keeping and quality control; just low barrier-to-entry, collegial,  collaborative, translation. There is no fine-grained version control. We  do not curate translations. We have no editorial board. Rather, we  concatenate multiple attributed versions. If you notice that we have  gotten a word or phrase wrong, you cannot merely change that word or  phrase, but if you click on “Add a new version of translation  urn:cite:dc3…” the form will open with the “Translation” field already  populated with the version that you would like to correct. Make your  changes, click Submit. The whole will be attributed to you, but anyone  will be able to see that you have only changed a few words. It isn’t  fancy, but it is easy and fast.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">You will see tags in some of the Greek entries (indicating authors,  works, citations, references, Pleiades IDs). This markup is not  exhaustive and may contain errors; &nbsp;some day we may do something with  it. At the moment, we don’t.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">About our translations. These are <b>drafts</b>, a first step toward  something better and more complete. You will find errors, perhaps many,  perhaps serious. If you see something wrong, please feel free to fix  it. We have tried to reflect the grammar and style of the work as  literally as possible. This sometimes results in a bit of chop and  awkwardness. If in places this seems to come at the expense of clarity,  please feel free to fix it. At this stage, we make little claim to  nuance. There may be more (or less) to Harpokration’s use of verb tense  (esp. the imperfect), or verbs of citation/attribution (μνημονεύει,  λέγει, φησί, διείλεκται, vel sim.) than we have surfaced; or to the  value of δέ (sometimes ‘and’, sometimes ‘but’), and so on. If you see  clumsiness, please feel free to fix it (or to email us, in case of  global problems).</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Greek is from Dindorf’s 1853 edition, generously shared by the <a href="http://stephanus.tlg.uci.edu/index.php">TLG</a>.  Where Keaney’s 1991 edition is clearly superior, such that a  translation should follow it, we indicate as much. To digitize Keaney  and then weigh its merits against Dindorf was out of scope.</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">We have now pushed draft translations of the first hundred entries.  Please feel free to add, to correct, to improve. If you have a google  account, you are good to go. For our part, we plan to push a new batch  of drafts each week over the course of the summer–maybe 20, maybe 50,  maybe 100 per week, depending on how things go.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">If this succeeds, who knows what comes next. A more robust,  production-oriented site supporting crowd-translation of ancient lexica,  scholia, and scholarship would certainly be a great thing to have and  to build and to contribute to.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In the meantime, feel free to pitch in.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Josh Sosin (<a href="mailto:joshua.sosin@duke.edu">joshua.sosin@duke.edu</a>)<br />John P. Aldrup-MacDonald (<a href="mailto:john.smith.macdonald@duke.edu">john.smith.macdonald@duke.edu</a>)<br />Mackenzie Zalin (<a href="mailto:mack.zalin@duke.edu">mack.zalin@duke.edu</a>)</span></blockquote></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/999514412976597076/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/05/harpokration-on-line.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/999514412976597076"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/999514412976597076"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/05/harpokration-on-line.html"
         title="Harpokration On Line"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
