<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4937728020630615723</id>
   <published>2016-06-07T16:54:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-06-07T16:54:21.520-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ancient"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ancient Science"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greece"/>
   <title type="text">The Antikythera Mechanism Research Project</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/" title="Home">The Antikythera Mechanism Research Project</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="View image on Twitter" class="NaturalImage-image" data-srcset="https%3A%2F%2Fpbs.twimg.com%2Fmedia%2FCkTNtzPWsAACCVY.jpg%3Alarge 768w,https%3A%2F%2Fpbs.twimg.com%2Fmedia%2FCkTNtzPWsAACCVY.jpg 768w,https%3A%2F%2Fpbs.twimg.com%2Fmedia%2FCkTNtzPWsAACCVY.jpg%3Asmall 606w" height="200" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/CkTNtzPWsAACCVY.jpg:small" title="View image on Twitter" width="178" /> </blockquote><div class="content">        <blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><div class="field-items"><div class="field-item even"><span style="font-size: x-small;">More  than a hundred years ago an extraordinary mechanism was found by sponge  divers at the bottom of the sea near the island of Antikythera. It  astonished the whole international community of experts on the ancient  world. Was it an astrolabe? Was it an orrery or an astronomical clock?  Or something else?</span> </div></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><div class="field-items"><div class="field-item even"><span style="font-size: x-small;">For decades, scientific investigation failed to yield much light and  relied more on imagination than the facts. However research over the  last half century has begun to reveal its secrets. The machine dates  from around the end of the 2nd century B.C. and is the most  sophisticated mechanism known from the ancient world. Nothing as complex  is known for the next thousand years. The Antikythera Mechanism is now  understood to be dedicated to astronomical phenomena and operates as a  complex mechanical "computer" which tracks the <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/faq/astronomical-questions">cycles of the Solar System</a>.</span> </div></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><div class="field-items"><div class="field-item even"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/history/people">Previous Antikythera researchers</a> have used the latest technologies available to them -such as x-ray  analysis- to try to begin to unravel its complex mysteries. From 2005, a  new initiative is building on this previous work, using the <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/data">very latest techniques available today</a>. The Antikythera Mechanism Research Project is an <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/team/academic">international collaboration of academic researchers</a>,  supported by some of the world's best high-technology companies, which  aims to completely reassess the function and significance of the  Antikythera Mechanism.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The project is under the aegis of the Hellenic Ministry of Culture  and was initially supported by a grant from the Leverhulme Trust, UK.  More <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/credits">details about subsequent funding are here</a> and the <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/acknowledgments">full acknowledgement list is here</a>. The project has received strong backing from the <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/museum">National Archaeological Museum</a> in Athens, which is custodian of this unique artefact. Two of the Museum's senior staff, Head of Chemistry, <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/team/museum/eleni-magou">Eleni Magou</a>, and Archaeologist-museologist, <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/team/museum/mary-zafeiropoulou">Mary Zafeiropoulou</a>, have co-ordinated the Museum's side of the project and are actively involved with the research.</span> </div></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><div class="field-items"><div class="field-item even"><span style="font-size: x-small;">One UK and two Greek universities are the core of the academic research group -the astronomer <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/team/academic/mike-edmunds">Mike Edmunds</a> and the mathematician and filmmaker <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/team/academic/tony-freeth">Tony Freeth</a> (University of Cardiff), the astronomer <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/team/academic/john-seiradakis">John Seiradakis</a> (University of Thessalonica), the astronomer <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/team/academic/xenophon-moussas">Xenophon Moussas</a> and the physicist and historian of science <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/team/academic/yanis-bitsakis">Yanis Bitsakis</a> (University of Athens). And last, but not least, the philologist and palaeographer <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/team/academic/agamemnon-tselikas">Agamemnon Tselikas</a> (NBG Cultural Foundation).</span> </div></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><div class="field-items"><div class="field-item even"><span style="font-size: x-small;">During the first data-gathering phase in the autumn of 2005, the most  innovative technologies were used to reveal unknown elements of the  mechanism. This research was carried out by two world-class high  technology companies, Hewlett Packard (US) and X-Tek Systems (UK).  X-Tek's superb three-dimensional x-rays were imaged using software from  the leading German company, Volume Graphics. Technical support was also  provided by the University of Keele (UK). The whole process was filmed  by Tony Freeth's Film and Television production company, Images First,  for the <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/media/movies/worlds-first-computer">TV documentary "The World's First Computer"</a>.</span> </div></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><div class="field-items"><div class="field-item even"><span style="font-size: x-small;">During September 2005, three specialized scientists from  Hewlett-Packard's Mobile and Media Systems Laboratory came to Athens  with their innovative digital imaging system to examine the surface  inscriptions and other features on the Antikythera Mechanism. The <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/team/hp">HP team</a>,  Tom Malzbender, Dan Gelb and Bill Ambrisco-brought with them a  remarkable piece of specialist equipment: a Dome that surrounds the  sample under examination and takes a series of still photos to analyze  the three-dimensional structure of the surface. This enables  astonishingly detailed examination of fine details such as faded and  worn inscriptions. It has been a revelation for the research team. <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/data/ptm/full-resolution-ptm">See here</a> for this data.</span> </div></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><div class="field-items"><div class="field-item even"><span style="font-size: x-small;">During October 2005, another team of specialists from the  cutting-edge company, X-Tek Systems, came to Athens. Led by the  company's pioneering proprietor, Roger Hadland, the group of experts  consisted of David Bate, Andrew Ramsey, Martin Allen, Alan Crawley and  Peter Hockley. Their aim was to use the very latest x-ray technology to  look at the internal structure of the mechanism with its complex and  confusing gear trains. With them they brought the prototype of a very  powerful new x-ray machine, the eight-tonne "Bladerunner". Originally  designed to search for minute cracks in turbine blades, this machine  gives astonishingly detailed three-dimensional x-rays, using the latest  "microfocus" x-ray techniques. It has opened a remarkable window on  microscopic internal details of inscriptions and gearing at a resolution  better than a tenth of a millimeter. Inscriptions can now be read that  have not been seen for more than two thousand years and this is helping  to build a comprehensive picture of the functions of the Antikythera  Mechanism. [weblink:187|Browse here] some of the initial images from the  Blade Runner.</span> </div></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><div class="field-items"><div class="field-item even"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>This is work-in-progress and results are emerging on a stable basis as the data is analyzed:</strong></span><br /> <ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">At the autumn of 2006, the Antikythera Mechanism Research Project has organized <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/node/463">a major conference in Athens</a> to present their research findings. These results opened a new chapter  in the understanding of this extraordinary mechanism. The conference  coincided with the <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/publications/nature-2006">publication of the first results at the journal "Nature"</a>. </span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">In July 2008, new results were <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/project/publications/nature-2008">published in Nature</a>. These were focused on the functions of Back Dials of the Mechanism. </span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">In July-August 2009, <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/node/473">a major symposium was organized within the scope of the 23rd International Congress of History of Science and Technology</a>.  Members and collaborators of the research project and leading  historians of science and technology discussed the position of the  Antikythera Mechanism within the history of science, technology and  ideas. </span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">A workshop took place in Athens (July 2011), in order to discuss new  data about the front plate inscriptions and planetary data. Results are  being processed and should soon be made public. Some partial results  about inscriptions and planetary data were integrated into the <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/events/exhibitions/nam-2012">Antikythera wreck exhibition</a> and the documentary <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/media/movies/worlds-first-computer">The World's First Computer"</a>. </span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/events/621">A workshop is organized in Leiden (June 2013)</a>,  where members of the AMRP, collaborators and specialists of the ancient  world will discuss the trheme "The Antikythera Mechanism: Science and  Innovation in the Ancient World ". </span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">A new survey on the Antikythera wreck site has been announced for 2014. Stay tuned! </span></li></ul></div></div></div></blockquote></div><blockquote><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Models</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">                            </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Digital and solid models of the Antikythera Mechanism.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">                            </span><div class="readmore">                                <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/data/models">Read More</a></span>                            </div><span style="font-size: x-small;">                                                                                                        </span><div class="one-half last"><span style="font-size: x-small;">                            <br />                            </span><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Bibliography</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">                            </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">An extensive bibliography about the Antikythera Mechanism and related ancient astronomy and technology.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">                            </span><div class="readmore"><span style="font-size: x-small;">                                <a href="http://www.antikythera-mechanism.gr/bibliography">Read More</a></span>                            </div></div></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4937728020630615723/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/06/the-antikythera-mechanism-research.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4937728020630615723"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4937728020630615723"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/06/the-antikythera-mechanism-research.html"
         title="The Antikythera Mechanism Research Project"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
