<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4941125934698753842</id>
   <published>2016-02-02T12:52:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-02-02T12:52:08.393-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Geography"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="app"/>
   <title type="text">TOPOSText</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://topostext.org/">TOPOSText</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="" id="jsn-logo-desktop" src="http://topostext.org/templates/jsn_decor_pro/images/colors/blue/logo.png" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">ToposText is an indexed collection of  ancient texts and mapped places relevant the the history and mythology  of the ancient Greeks from the Neolithic period up through the 2nd  century CE. It was inspired by two decades of exploring Greece by car,  foot, or bicycle, and by clumsy efforts to appreciate επί τόπου the  relevant information from Pausanias or other primary sources. The  development of mobile electronic devices since 2010 has coincided with  an increasingly comprehensive assortment of ancient texts available on  the internet. The digital texts I collected on an e-reader in 2012 made  clear both the pleasure of having a portable Classics library but also  the desperate need to organize the information it contained. Discovering  the <a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/">Pleiades Project</a>, with its  downloadable database of thousands of ancient place names and  coordinates, opened the door to indexing ancient texts geographically,  using a map of Greece as the basic interface. </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">ToposText was designed as an application  for mobile devices. Opening it presents a scrolling alphabetical list  of 5000+ Greek cities, colonies, sanctuaries, archaeological sites,  museums, and other points of interest, side-by-side with a  location-aware map showing the nearby places by name, icon (city,  sanctuary, theatre, etc), and the number of ancient references in the TT  database. The texts and index and a basic map are stored on the device  and requires no internet connection. </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: justify;">Selecting a site from either the list or  the map opens up a table of two-line snippets from ancient authors,  headed where available by a modern description. Selecting from this  index list, which can be filtered by date, genre, and relevance,  connects one to the full text of 240-odd works in English translation,  some with the original Ancient Greek as well. Thus, at a glance and from  any location, you can select and read the passages in ancient  literature that give a place its historical and cultural meaning. While  you are reading, the map alongside shows the location of the ancient  places mentioned. In most cases, book and paragraph numbers of texts  correspond to those conventionally used in printed texts. Where the  online text available had no internal numbering, arbitrary paragraph  numbering has been added. A scrolling feature hidden in the right margin  allows rapid navigation through the books and chapters of a given text...</div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><ul class="menu-mainmenu"><li class="current active first jsn-icon-home"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="current" href="http://topostext.org/index.php" title="Start..."> <span>  <span class="jsn-menutitle">Home</span> </span></a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://topostext.org/index.php/who-we-are"> <span>  Who we are </span></a></span></li><li class="parent"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://topostext.org/index.php/our-texts"> <span>  Ancient Texts </span></a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://topostext.org/index.php/our-places"> <span>  Places </span></a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://topostext.org/index.php/the-project"> <span>  The project </span></a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://topostext.org/index.php/feedback-and-support"> <span>  Feedback </span></a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://topostext.org/index.php/news"> <span>  News </span></a></span></li><li class="last"><a href="http://topostext.org/index.php/contact-us"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> <span>  Contact Us </span></span></a></li></ul></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4941125934698753842/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/02/topostext.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4941125934698753842"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4941125934698753842"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/02/topostext.html"
         title="TOPOSText"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
