<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4023361518568191267</id>
   <published>2014-08-23T07:18:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2014-08-23T08:35:15.511-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Networks and Neighbours</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://networksandneighbours.org/index.php/Networks_and_Neighbours/index">Networks and Neighbours</a><br />ISSN: 2372-4889&nbsp;     <br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://networksandneighbours.org/public/site/images/jrberg/Cover.jpg" class="shrinkToFit decoded" height="200" src="http://networksandneighbours.org/public/site/images/jrberg/Cover.jpg" width="163" /> </blockquote><div id="body"><div id="main"><div id="content"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The journal <em>Networks and Neighbours</em> (<em>N&amp;N</em>)  is a voice of the larger project of scholars by the same name. The  project sponsors conference panels and runs masterclasses, lectures and  other events, including our annual symposium rotating biannually between  the University of Leeds and select sites around the globe. This  international, or rather post-national, and also extra-institutional,  intellectual spirit is embodied in the journal <em>N&amp;N</em>. To this  end we invite, in addition to original research articles and book  reviews in a diversity of languages, reports from conferences and other  related early medieval research activities worldwide. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The editorial board of <em>N&amp;N </em>consists  of established leaders in the field as well as emerging young scholars  working in early medieval studies. The methodologies, styles, chosen  historiographies, historical representations and theses of the board  members complement each other in various ways and provide emulative  models of historical research and authorship. They also represent though  the firm, critical and confrontational interrogations needed to advance  early medieval scholarship in radical directions and towards truly  alternative ways of thinking and emerging the early medieval past. <em>N&amp;N </em>is in close dialogue with other previous and current, related academic projects such as the <em>Transformation of the Roman World</em>, <em>Texts and Identities</em> and <em>HERA: Cultural Memory and Resources of the Past</em>. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div align="justify"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>N&amp;N</em> provides immediate and permanent open access to its content on the  principle that making research freely available to the public supports a  greater global exchange of knowledge. We are, and will always be, <strong>100% free</strong> to publish in, <strong>free</strong> to read online, and <strong>free</strong> to share. For more information on our Open Access policy click <a href="http://networksandneighbours.org/index.php/n/about/editorialPolicies#openAccessPolicy" target="_self" title="Open Access policy">here</a>.</span></div><div style="float: left; width: 100%;">  <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">2014</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">     </span><div id="issue" style="clear: left;">   <h4><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://networksandneighbours.org/index.php/n/issue/view/3">Vol 2, No 2 (2014): Cultural Capital</a></span></h4><div class="issueDescription"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Since the idea was first proposed by  Pierre Bourdieu and Jean-Claude Passeron, ‘Cultural Capital’ has  broadened the way researchers of the modern world consider the meanings  of ‘wealth’, ‘power’ and their relationship to real ‘capital’. The idea  is no less relevant to the study of the Early Middle Ages. For this  issue, we are seeking papers which investigate the literature and  material goods of Late Antiquity and the Early Middle Ages; the polemics  and the paintings, the buildings, coins, jewelry, <em>topoi</em>,  prejudices, languages, dress, songs, and hairstyles that framed the  early medieval world(s), and consider them in terms of ‘Cultural  Capital’.</span><span style="font-size: x-small;">For example, what relation did Charlemagne’s moustache, his  penchant for Augustine, and an elephant called Abul-Abbas have to his  success as emperor? How did Rome become so central to the European  imagination, even as its military and economic relevance waned? What  role, if any, do Late Antiquity and the Early Middle Ages have in both  the modern ‘European’ debate and the question of Scottish independence?  Other issues to consider include: what constituted Cultural Capital in  the Early Middle Ages, and why does it matter? Who created, exchanged,  brokered, and consumed Cultural Capital? How did it translate into  economic, symbolic, and social capital? And was Cultural Capital a force  for social change, or inertia?</span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">    </span><div id="issue" style="clear: left;">      <h4><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://networksandneighbours.org/index.php/n/issue/view/2">Vol 2, No 1 (2014): Comparisons and Correlations</a></span></h4></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">       </span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">   <br />           </span><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">2013</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">     </span><div id="issue" style="clear: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   </span><h4><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://networksandneighbours.org/index.php/n/issue/view/1">Vol 1, No 1 (2013)</a></span></h4></div><table class="tocArticle" style="width: 100%px;"><tbody><tr valign="top"><td class="tocTitle"><br /></td><td class="tocGalleys"><br /></td></tr><tr><td class="tocAuthors"><br /></td> <td class="tocPages"><br /></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote></div></div></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;<span style="font-family: inherit;">See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4023361518568191267/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/07/new-open-access-journal-networks-and.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4023361518568191267"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4023361518568191267"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/07/new-open-access-journal-networks-and.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Networks and Neighbours"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
