<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8631197759599746853</id>
   <published>2014-02-12T12:53:00.004-05:00</published>
   <updated>2014-02-12T12:53:36.123-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Roman"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="numismatics"/>
   <title type="text">News from OCRE (Online Coins of the Roman Empire) </title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://numismatics.org/ocre/">OCRE – Online Database of Coinage of the Roman Empire becomes Bigger, Multi-Contributor and Multi-Lingual</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://numismatics.org/ocre/images/banner.png" class="decoded" src="http://numismatics.org/ocre/images/banner.png" height="51" width="320" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">In collaboration with New York University’s Institute for the Study of  the Ancient World, the American Numismatic Society (ANS) is pleased to  announce the release of a new version of OCRE (Online Coins of the Roman  Empire) (<a href="https://xmail.uchicago.edu/owa/redir.aspx?C=8JbY7yze2Umfsvj_uS2w4JbHWkAv-dAIQ06L7rIg0Fvl2fVkNZWJAMt3LOtPh6xPZ7J0u3cmhe0.&amp;URL=http%3a%2f%2fnumismatics.org%2focre%2f" target="_blank">numismatics.org/ocre/</a>).   The OCRE project is creating a revolutionary new tool designed to help  in the identification, cataloguing, and research of the rich and varied  coinage of the Roman Empire. It aims to provide a comprehensive online  resource encompassing every known Roman Imperial  coin type. The end result will be:</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">•A database of 50,000 coin types</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">•A resource that collectors can use to identify their coins, estimate their rarity, and discover unknown varieties.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">•An online reference tool for researchers to help in new research on this important series.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">•Easy to use, downloadable catalogue entries for the coinage of every  Roman Emperor from Augustus in 31 BC, until the death of Zeno in AD 491.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The new version of the tool contains important new improvements.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">OCRE’s first version drew only on the collection of the American  Numismatic Society, but the database now has multiple contributing  collections, with the addition of the Roman Imperial collection of the  Münzkabinett of the State Museum of Berlin and the University  of Virginia Art Museum. Between these three collections, OCRE is now  able to illustrate 50% of the imperial coin types that it contains.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">“Such a joint collaborative effort between major public and private  collections should lead to a comprehensive catalogue that will  eventually incorporate and display almost all recorded Roman Imperial  coin-types,” explains ANS Executive Director, Ute Wartenberg  Kagan. More collections will follow soon, bringing OCRE closer to that  aim.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Along with adding new specimens, the database has grown since its launch  in July 2012 to contain descriptions of known types through the emperor  Septimius Severus. To date, more than 15,000 coin types are described.  “The time range covered by OCRE is now incorporating  250 years of monetary and numismatic history, from 30 BC until AD 211,  effectively covering the entire High Empire. We should very soon include  the entire Severan dynasty and then the later 3rd century,” explains  OCRE project manager, ISAW Research Associate  and ANS Romanist, Gilles Bransbourg.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">In a further development, OCRE can now link to another ANS developed resource, Coin Hoards of the Roman Republic (<a href="https://xmail.uchicago.edu/owa/redir.aspx?C=8JbY7yze2Umfsvj_uS2w4JbHWkAv-dAIQ06L7rIg0Fvl2fVkNZWJAMt3LOtPh6xPZ7J0u3cmhe0.&amp;URL=http%3a%2f%2fnumismatics.org%2fchrr%2f" target="_blank">numismatics.org/chrr/</a>).  This enables OCRE to draw on findspot data for some early imperial coin types, and map their distribution.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">As ANS database developer, Ethan Gruber, notes, “the new version of OCRE  is a significant step forward over the previous in that the  architecture for linking coin types to physical coins and hoard data has  been completely rewritten to use Linked Open Data technologies.  SPARQL is the backbone for new geographic and quantitative  visualizations.”</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">OCRE also allows users to search in 10 languages other than English. This is made possible by multilingual labels provided by <a href="https://xmail.uchicago.edu/owa/redir.aspx?C=8JbY7yze2Umfsvj_uS2w4JbHWkAv-dAIQ06L7rIg0Fvl2fVkNZWJAMt3LOtPh6xPZ7J0u3cmhe0.&amp;URL=http%3a%2f%2fnomisma.org" target="_blank">nomisma.org</a>'s identifiers. “This was a clear prerequisite in order  to allow OCRE to become a truly international platform,” notes Andrew  Meadows, ANS Deputy</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Director. Spanish, German, French, Russian, Greek, and Italian are among  the languages offered by OCRE, alongside Romanian, Bulgarian, Swedish,  and Dutch.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8631197759599746853/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/02/news-from-ocre-online-coins-of-roman.html#comment-form"
         title="1 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8631197759599746853"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8631197759599746853"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/02/news-from-ocre-online-coins-of-roman.html"
         title="News from OCRE (Online Coins of the Roman Empire) "/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
