<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4630277670508325078</id>
   <published>2015-07-10T15:25:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-07-10T15:25:17.952-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Cyprus"/>
   <title type="text">Troodos Archaeological and Environmental Survey Project </title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/taesp_ahrc_2007">Troodos Archaeological and Environmental Survey Project</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Michael Given, Vasiliki  Kassianidou, A Bernard Knapp, Jay Noller, Luke Sollars, Hugh Corley</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Troodos Archaeological and Environmental Survey Project (TAESP)  worked in the northern foothills of the Troodos Mountains in central  Cyprus. It was directed by Dr Michael Given and Prof. A. Bernard Knapp  (University of Glasgow), Dr Vasiliki Kassianidou (University of Cyprus)  and Prof. Jay Noller (Oregon State University). In six seasons of  fieldwork between 2000 and 2004 our team collected and analysed a  substantial archaeological and geomorphological data set. This  encompasses all periods from the Neolithic to the present day, a wide  range of topographical and environmental contexts, and a broad spectrum  of disciplinary and interdisciplinary expertise. </span><br />     <h4><span style="font-size: x-small;">Aims</span></h4><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Troodos Archaeological and Environmental Survey Project (TAESP)  investigated human activity in the north-central Troodos mountains of  Cyprus during all time periods. The core of its methodology consisted of  intensive archaeological and geomorphological survey. The survey area  includes fertile and well-watered valleys, drier plains, copper-bearing  foothills, and the northern part of the Troodos Range itself. Other than  some rescue excavation of tombs, no systematic archaeological work had  been done in this area.&nbsp;</span><br /><br />   <span style="font-size: x-small;">Our research focused on the dynamic relationship between human  society and the environment. We documented and analysed settlement  patterns, land use patterns and communication networks across the  landscape at all time periods, and related them to environmental factors  such as physical landforms, soils and sediments, vegetation and water. A  particular focus was the nature and development of resource  exploitation, especially agriculture and metallurgical production.  Related themes included the production of pottery and stone tools,  forest resources and soil management. </span><br />   <span style="font-size: x-small;">This digital archive was undertaken in conjunction with an  electronic publication through the Linking Electronic Archives and  Publications (LEAP) project.  The corresponding article is '<em>Joining  the Dots: Continuous Survey, Routine Practice and the Interpretation of a  Cypriot Landscape (with interactive GIS and integrated data archive)</em>' by Michael Given, Hugh Corley, and Luke Sollars, which can be found in <a href="http://intarch.ac.uk/journal/issue20/taesp_index.html">Internet Archaeology 20</a>. </span><br />                                                                      <br /><ul class="dlMenu"><li>  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/taesp_ahrc_2007/index.cfm">Introduction</a></span> </li><li>  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/taesp_ahrc_2007/overview.cfm">Overview</a></span> </li><li>     <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/taesp_ahrc_2007/downloads.cfm">Downloads</a></span>  </li><li>   <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/taesp_ahrc_2007/metadata.cfm">Metadata</a></span>  </li><li>   <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/taesp_ahrc_2007/stats.cfm">Usage Statistics</a></span>  </li></ul></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4630277670508325078/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/07/troodos-archaeological-and.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4630277670508325078"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4630277670508325078"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/07/troodos-archaeological-and.html"
         title="Troodos Archaeological and Environmental Survey Project "/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
