<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4575962423970105112</id>
   <published>2015-09-12T09:45:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-09-12T09:45:40.589-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Monograph Series: Oriental Institute Publications (OIP)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/publications/oriental-institute-publications-oip">Oriental Institute Publications (OIP)</a><br />ISSN: 0069-3367  <br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">&nbsp;OIP 141. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/publications/oip/oip-141-bir-umm-fawakhir-3">Bir Umm Fawakhir 3. Excavations 1999–2001</a>.  By By Carol Meyer, with contributions by Lisa A. Heidorn, Salima Ikram,  Richard L. Jaeschke, Thomas C. Roby, and Wendy Smith. 2014.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;">OIP 140.<span style="font-family: inherit;"> </span><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/publications/oip/oip-140-ancient-settlement-systems-and-cultures-ram-hormuz-plain">Ancient  Settlement Systems and Cultures in the Ram Hormuz Plain, Southwestern  Iran: Excavations at Tall-e Geser and Regional Survey of the Ram Hormuz  Area</a>. Abbas Alizadeh, with contributions by Loghman Ahmadzadeh and Mehdi  Omidfar, and appendices by John R. Alden, Leah Minc, Jacques Connan,  John Zumberge, and Kendra Imbus. 2014</span></span><span style="font-size: xx-small;"> </span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip139.html">OIP  139. Early Megiddo on the East Slope (the “Megiddo Stages”): A Report  on the Early Occupation of the East Slope of Megiddo (Results of the  Oriental Institute’s Excavations, 1925-1933)</a>. Eliot Braun, with David Ilan, Ofer Marder, Yael Braun, and Sariel Shalev. 2013. </span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip138.html">OIP 138. Bismaya: Recovering the Lost City of Adab.</a> Karen Wilson, with Jacob Lauinger, Monica Louise Phillips, Benjamin Studevent-Hickman, and Aage Westenholz. 2012.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip137.html">OIP 137. Tell Hamoukar, Volume 1. Urbanism and Cultural Landscapes in Northeastern Syria: The Tell Hamoukar Survey, 1999-2001.</a> Jason A. Ur. 2010.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip136.html">OIP  136. Medinet Habu IX. The Eighteenth Dynasty Temple, Part I: The Inner  Sanctuaries. With Translations of Texts, Commentary, and Glossary.</a>By The Epigraphic Survey. 2009.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip135.html">OIP  135. Kerkenes Special Studies 1: Sculpture and Inscriptions from the  Monumental Entrance to the Palatial Complex at Kerkenes Dag, Turkey.</a> Catherine M. Draycott and Geoffrey D. Summers, with contribution by  Claude Brixhe and Turkish summary translated by G. Bike Yazıcıoglu.  2008.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip134.html">OIP  134. The Archaeology and Geography of Ancient Transcaucasian Societies,  Volume 1: The Foundations of Research and Regional Survey in the  Tsaghkahovit Plain, Armenia.</a> Adam T. Smith, Ruben S. Badalyan, Pavel Avetisyan. With contributions by Alan Greene and Leah Minc. 2009.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip133.html">OIP 133. Baked Clay Figurines and Votive Beds from Medinet Habu.</a> Emily Teeter. 2010.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip132.html">OIP 132. The Egyptian Coffin Texts, Volume 8. Middle Kingdom Copies of Pyramid Texts.</a> James P. Allen. 2006.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip131.html">OIP 131. The Amuq Valley Regional Projects, Volume 1 - Surveys in the Plain of Antioch and Orontes Delta, Turkey, 1995–2002.</a> Kutlu Aslihan Yener. 2005.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip130.html">OIP  130. Chogha Mish, Volume II. The Development of a Prehistoric Regional  Center in Lowland Susiana, Southwestern Iran: Final Report on the Last  Six Seasons of Excavations, 1972–1978.</a> Abbas Alizadeh. 2008.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip129.html">OIP 129. The Early Dynastic To Akkadian Transition: The Area WF Sounding At Nippur</a>. Augusta McMahon. 2006.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip128.html">OIP 128. The Origins of State Organizations in Prehistoric Highland Fars, Southern Iran: Excavations at Tall-e Bakun.</a> Abbas Alizadeh. 2006.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip127.html">OIP 127. Megiddo 3: Final Report on the Stratum VI Excavations.</a> Timothy P. Harrison, with contributions by Douglas L. Esse, Andrew Graham, Ronald G. V. Hancock, and Patricia Paice. 2004.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip126.html">OIP  126. Taxes, Taxpayers, And Tax Receipts In Early Ptolemaic Thebes -  Demotic and Greek Ostraca from the Oriental Institute Museum, Chicago.</a> Brian P. Muhs. 2005.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip125.html">OIP  125. Excavations at Tell es-Sweyhat, Syria, Volume 2: Archaeology of  the Bronze Age, Hellenistic, and Roman Remains at an Ancient Town on the  Euphrates River.</a> Thomas A. Holland. 2006. </span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip124.html">OIP  124. Excavations at Tell Es-Sweyhat, Syria, Volume 1: On the Margin of  the Euphrates: Settlement and Land Use at Tell Es-Sweyhat and in the  Upper Lake Assad Area, Syria.</a> Tony J. Wilkinson. 2004.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip123.html">OIP 123. Temple of Khonsu, Volume 3. The Graffiti on the Khonsu Temple Roof at Karnak: A Manifestation of Personal Piety.</a> Helen Jacquet-Gordon. 2003.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip122.html">OIP 122. Neo-Babylonian Texts in the Oriental Institute Collection.</a> David B. Weisberg. 2003.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip121.html">OIP  121. Cuneiform Texts from the Ur III Period in the Oriental Institute,  Volume 2: Drehem Administrative Documents from the Reign of Amar-Suena</a> Markus Hilgert. 2003.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip120.html">OIP 120. Excavations at the Prehistoric Mound of Chogha Bonut, Khuzestan, Iran, Seasons 1976/77, 1977/78, and 1996.</a> Abbas Alizadeh. 2003.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip119.html">OIP  119. Theban Desert Road Survey in the Egyptian Western Desert, Volume  1: Gebel Tjauti Rock Inscriptions 1-45 and Wadi el-Hôl Rock Inscriptions  1-45.</a> J. C. Darnell, with the assistance of D. Darnell. 2002.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip118.html">OIP 118. Scarabs, Scaraboids, Seals, and Seal Impressions from Medinet Habu.</a> Emily Teeter. 2003.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip117.html">OIP 117. Seals on the Persepolis Fortification Tablets, Volume I: Images of Heroic Encounter.</a> Mark B. Garrison and Margaret Cool Root. 2001.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip116.html">OIP  116. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Luxor Temple, Volume 2: The Facade,  Portals, Upper Register Scenes, Columns, Marginalia, and Statuary in the  Colonnade Hall.</a> The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1998.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip115.html">OIP  115. Cuneiform Texts from the Ur III Period in the Oriental Institute,  Volume 1: Drehem Administrative Documents from the Reign of Shulgi.</a> M. Hilgert. 1998.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip114.html">OIP 114. Nippur, Volume 4: The Early Neo-Babylonian Governor’s Archive from Nippur.</a> S. W. Cole. 1996.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip113.html">OIP  113. The Oriental Institute Hawara Papyri: Demotic and Greek Texts from  an Egyptian Family Archive in the Fayum (Fourth to Third Century B.C.).</a> G. R. Hughes and R. Jasnow. 1997.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip112.html">OIP 112. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Luxor Temple, Volume 1: The Festival Procession of Opet in the Colonnade Hall.</a> The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1994.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip111.html">OIP 111. Nippur, Volume 3: Kassite Buildings in Area WC-1.</a> R. L. Zettler. 1993.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip110.html">OIP 110. Town and Country in Southeastern Anatolia, Volume 2: The Stratigraphic Sequence at Kurban Höyük.</a> G. Algaze, ed., et. al. 1990.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip109.html">OIP  109. Town and Country in Southeastern Anatolia, Volume 1: Settlement  and Land Use at Kurban Höyük and Other Sites in the Lower Karababa  Basin.</a> T. J. Wilkinson, et. al. 1990.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip108.html">OIP 108. The Holmes Expeditions to Luristan.</a> E. F. Schmidt, et. al. 1989.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip107.html">OIP 107. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Karnak, Volume IV: The Battle Reliefs of King Sety I.</a> The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1986.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip106.html">OIP 106. The Great Hypostyle Hall at Karnak, Volume 1, Part 1: The Wall Reliefs.</a> By Harold Hayden Nelson. Edited by William J. Murnane. Originally published in 1981</span>   </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip105.html">OIP 105. Prehistoric Archeology Along the Zagros Flanks.</a> L. S. Braidwood, et. al. 1983.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip104.html">OIP 104. Earliest Land Tenure Systems in the Near East: Ancient Kudurrus.</a> I. J. Gelb, et. al. 1989, 1991.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip103.html">OIP 103. The Temple of Khonsu, Volume 2: Scenes and Inscriptions in the Court and the First Hypostyle Hall.</a> The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1981.</span>   </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip102.html">OIP 102. The Tomb of Kheruef: Theban Tomb 192.</a> The Epigraphic Survey. </span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip101.html">OIP 101. Chogha Mish, Volume 1: The First Five Seasons, 1961-1971.</a> Helene Kantor and P. Delougaz. 1996.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip100.html">OIP 100. The Temple of Khonsu, Volume 1: Scenes of King Herihor in the Court.</a> The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1979.</span>   </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip99.html">OIP 99. Inscriptions from Tell Abu Salabikh.</a> R. D. Biggs. 1974.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip98.html">OIP  98. Old Babylonian Public Buildings in the Diyala Region. Part One:  Excavations at Ishchali, Part Two: Khafajah Mounds B, C, and D.</a> H. D. Hill, et. al. 1990.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip97.html">OIP  97. Nippur, Volume 2. The North Temple and Sounding E: Excavations of  the Joint Expedition to Nippur of the American Schools of Oriental  Research and the Oriental Institute of the University of Chicago.</a> D. E. McCown, et. al. 1978.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip95.html">OIP  95. Excavations in the Plain of Antioch, Vol. II: The Structural  Remains of the Later Phases: Chatal Hüyük, Tell Al-Judaidah, and Tell  Tayinat.</a> R. C. Haines. 1970.</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip94.html">OIP 94. Medinet Habu, Vol. VIII: The Eastern High Gate with Translations of Texts.</a> The Epigraphic Survey. 1970.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip93.html">OIP  93. Medinet Habu, Vol. VII: The Temple Proper, Pt. III: The Third  Hypostyle Hall and All Rooms Accessible from It with Friezes of Scenes  from the Roof Terraces and Exterior Walls of the Temple.</a> The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1964. </span>   </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip92.html">OIP 92. Persepolis Fortification Tablets.</a> R. T. Hallock. 1969.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip91.html">OIP 91. Aramaic Ritual Texts from Persepolis.</a> R. A. Bowman. 1970.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip90.html">OIP 90. Ptolemais: City of the Libyan Pentapolis.</a> Carl H. Kraeling. 1962.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip88.html">OIP 88. Private Houses and Graves in the Diyala Region.</a> Pinhas Delougaz, Harold D. Hill, and Seton Lloyd. 1967</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip87.html">OIP 87. The Egyptian Coffin Texts 7, Texts of Spells 787-1185.</a> By Adriaan de Buck. Originally published in 1961</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip86.html">OIP 86. The Tomb of Tjanefer at Thebes. </a> By Keith C. Seele. Originally published in 1959</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip85.html">OIP 85. A Byzantine Church at Khirbat al-Karak.</a> Pinhas Delougaz and Richard C. Haines. Originally published in 1960.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip84.html">OIP  84. Medinet Habu, Volume VI. The Temple Proper, Part II: The Re Chapel,  the Royal Mortuary Complex, and Adjacent Rooms with Miscellaneous  Material from the Pylons, the Forecourts, and the First Hypostyle Hall.</a> By The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1963. </span>   </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip83.html">OIP  83. Medinet Habu, Volume V. The Temple Proper, Part I: The Portico, the  Treasury, and Chapels Adjoining the First Hypostyle Hall with Marginal  Material from the Forecourts.</a> By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1957.&nbsp;</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip82.html">OIP 82. The Egyptian Book of the Dead: Documents in the Oriental Institute Museum at the University of Chicago.</a> Edited by Thomas George Allen. Originally published in 1960</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip81.html">OIP 81. The Egyptian Coffin Texts, Volume 6: Texts of Spells 472-787.</a> By Adriaan de Buck. Originally published in 1956.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip80.html">OIP 80. Demotic Ostraca from Medinet Habu. By Miriam Lichtheim.</a> Originally published in 1957.&nbsp;</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip79.html">OIP 79. Soundings at Tell Fakhariyah.</a> C. W. McEwan, et. al. 1957.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip78.html">OIP  78. Nippur I, Temple of Enlil, Scribal Quarter, and Soundings:  Excavations of the Joint Expedition to Nippur of the University Museum  of Philadelphia and the Oriental Institute of the University of Chicago.</a> Donald E. McCown and Richard C. Haines, assisted by Donald P. Hansen. 1967</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip77.html">OIP 77. Studies in Arabic Literary Papyri, Volume III: Language and Literature.</a> N. Abbott. 1972.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip76.html">OIP 76. Studies in Arabic Literary Papyri II: Qur'anic Commentary and Tradition.</a> N. Abbott. 1967.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip75.html">OIP 75. Studies in Arabic Literary Papyri I: Historical Texts.</a> N. Abbott. 1957.</span>  </li><li> <span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip74.html">OIP 74. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Karnak, Volume III. The Bubastite Portal.</a> By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1954.&nbsp;</span></li><li> <span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip73.html">OIP 73. The Egyptian Coffin Texts 5: Texts of Spells 355-471.</a> By Adriaan de Buck. Originally published in 1954.&nbsp;</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip72.html">OIP 72. Stratified Cylinder Seals from the Diyala Region.</a> Henri Frankfort with a chapter by Thorkild Jacobsen. 1955</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip71.html">OIP 71. Coptic Ostraca from Medinet Habu.</a> By Elizabeth Stefanski and Miriam Lichtheim. Originally published in 1952&nbsp;</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip70.html">OIP 70. Persepolis III: The Royal Tombs and Other Monuments.</a> E. F. Schmidt. 1970.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip69.html">OIP 69. Persepolis II: Contents of the Treasury and Other Discoveries.</a> Erich F. Schmidt with contributions by Sydney P. Noe et al., Frederick  R. Matson, Lawrence J. Howell, and Louisa Bellinger. 1957</span>  </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip68.html">OIP 68. Persepolis I: Structures, Reliefs, Inscriptions.</a> Erich F. Schmidt with contribution by F. R. Matson. 1953</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip67.html">OIP 67. The Egyptian Coffin Texts, Volume 4: Texts of Spells 268-354.</a> By Adriaan De Buck. Originally published in 1951.&nbsp;</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip66.html">OIP 66. Post-Ramessid Remains. The Excavation of Medinet Habu, Volume 5.</a> By Uvo Hölscher. Originally published in 1954 </span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip65.html">OIP 65. Persepolis Treasury Tablets.</a> George G. Cameron. 1948</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip64.html">OIP 64. The Egyptian Coffin Texts 3: Texts of Spells 164-267.</a> By Adriaan de Buck. Originally published in 1947 </span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip63.html">OIP 63. Pottery from the Diyala Region.</a> Pinhas Delougaz. 1952 </span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip62.html">OIP 62. Megiddo 2. Seasons of 1935-39: Text and Plates.</a> Gordon Loud.  Originally published in 1948.</span>    </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip61.html">OIP 61. Excavations in the Plain of Antioch I: The Earlier Assemblages Phases A-J.</a> By Robert J. Braidwood and Linda S. Braidwood. Originally published in 1960.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip60.html">OIP 60. More Sculpture from the Diyala Region.</a> Henri Frankfort. 1943</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip59.html">OIP 59. Tall-i-Bakun A: Season of 1932.</a> Alexander Langsdorff and Donald E. McCown. 1942</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip58.html">OIP 58. Pre-Sargonid Temples in the Diyala Region.</a> Pinhas Delougaz and Seton Lloyd with chapters by Henri Frankfort and Thorkild Jacobsen. 1942</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip57.html">OIP 57. Nuzi Personal Names.</a> Ignace J. Gelb, Pierre M. Purves, and Allan A. MacRae. Originally published in 1943.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip56.html">OIP 56. Key Plans Showing Locations of Theban Temple Decorations.</a> By Harold Hayden Nelson. Originally published in 1941.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip55.html">OIP 55. The Excavation of Medinet Habu, Volume IV. The Mortuary Temple of Ramses III, Part II.</a> By Uvo Hölscher. With contributions by Rudolf Anthes. Originally published in 1951. </span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip54.html">OIP 54. The Mortuary Temple of Ramses III, Part 1. The Excavation of Medinet Habu, Volume 3.</a> By Uvo Hölscher. Originally published in 1941 </span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip53.html">OIP 53. The Temple Oval at Khafajah.</a> Pinhas Delougaz, with a chapter by Thorkild Jacobsen. 1940</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip52.html">OIP 52. The Megiddo Ivories.</a> Gordon Loud.  Originally published in 1939.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip51.html">OIP 51. Medinet Habu, Volume 4. Festival Scenes of Ramses III. By the Epigraphic Survey.</a>Originally published in 1940.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip50.html">OIP  50. The Rise of the North Arabic Script and Its Kur'anic Development,  with a Full Description of the Kur'an Manuscripts in the Oriental  Institute</a>. By Nabia Abbott. Originally published in 1939.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip49.html">OIP 49. The Egyptian Coffin Texts, Volume 2: Texts of Spells 76-163.</a> By Adriaan De Buck. Originally published in 1929.&nbsp;</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip48.html">OIP 48. Mounds in the Plain of Antioch: An Archeological Survey.</a> Robert J. Braidwood. Originally published in 1937.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip47.html">OIP 47. Ancient Oriental Cylinder and Other Seals with a Description of the Collection of Mrs. William H. Moore. </a> Gustavus A. Eisen. Originally published in 1940.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip46.html">OIP  46. Paleolithic Man and the Nile Valley in Lower Egypt with Some Notes  upon a Part of the Red Sea Littoral: A Study of the Regions during  Pliocene and Pleistocene Times.</a> By K. S. Sandford and W. J. Arkell. Prehistoric Survey of Egypt and Western Asia, Volume IV. Originally published in 1939.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip45.html">OIP 45. Hittite Hieroglyphic Monuments.</a> Ignace J. Gelb. Originally published in 1939.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip44.html">OIP 44. Sculpture of the Third Millennium B.C. from Tell Asmar and Khafajah.</a> Henri Frankfort. 1939</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip43.html">OIP 43. The Gimilsin Temple and the Palace of the Rulers at Tell Asmar.</a> Henri Frankfort, Seton Lloyd, and Thorkild Jacobsen, with a chapter by Günter Martiny. 1940</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip42.html">OIP 42. Megiddo 1. Seasons of 1925-34: Strata I-V.</a> Robert S. Lamon and Geoffrey M. Shipton. 1939</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip41.html">OIP 41. The Excavation of Medinet Habu, Volume 2: The Temples of the Eighteenth Dynasty.</a> By Uvo Hölscher. Originally published in 1939 </span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip40.html">OIP 40. Khorsabad, Part 2: The Citadel and the Town.</a> Gordon Loud and Charles B. Altman. 1938</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip39.html">OIP  39. The Mastaba of Mereruka, Part II: Chamber A 11-13, Doorjambs and  Inscriptions of Chambers A 1-21, Tomb Chamber, and Exterior.</a> By the Sakkarah Expedition. Originally published in 1938.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip38.html">OIP 38. Khorsabad, Part 1: Excavations in the Palace and at a City Gate.</a> Gordon Loud. 1936</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip37.html">OIP 37. Ancient Oriental Seals in the Collection of Mrs. Agnes Baldwin Brett.</a> Hans Henning von der Osten. Originally published in 1936</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip36.html">OIP 36. Medinet Habu Graffiti: Facsimiles.</a> Edited by William F. Edgerton. Originally published in 1937.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip35.html">OIP  35. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Karnak, Volume II. Ramses III's Temple  within the Great Inclosure of Amon, Part II; and Ramses III's Temple in  the Precinct of Mut.</a> By The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1936.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip34.html">OIP 34. The Egyptian Coffin Texts 1: Texts of Spells 1-75.</a> By Adriaan De Buck. Originally published in 1935.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip33.html">OIP 33. Megiddo Tombs.</a> P. L. O. Guy.  Originally published in 1938.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip32.html">OIP 32. The Megiddo Water System.</a> Robert S. Lamon.  Originally published in 1935.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip31.html">OIP 31. The Mastaba of Mereruka, Part I. Chambers A 1-10.</a> By The Sakkara Expedition. Originally published in 1938.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip30.html">OIP 30. Researches in Anatolia 9. The Alishar Hüyük Seasons of 1930-32, Part 3.</a> Hans Henning von der Osten, with contributions by Wilton Marion Krogman and Others. Originally published in 1937.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip29.html">OIP 29. Researches in Anatolia 8. The Alishar Hüyük Seasons of 1930-32, Part 2.</a> Hans Henning von der Osten. Originally published in 1937.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip28.html">OIP 28. Researches in Anatolia 7. The Alishar Hüyük Seasons of 1930-32, Part 1.</a> Hans Henning von der Osten. Originally published in 1937.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip27.html">OIP 27. Researches in Anatolia 6. Inscriptions from Alishar and Vicinity.</a> Ignace J. Gelb. Originally published in 1935.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip26.html">OIP 26. Material Remains of the Megiddo Cult.</a> Herbert Gordon May.  Originally published in 1935.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip25.html">OIP 25. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Karnak, Volume I. Ramses III's Temple with the Great Inclosure of Amon, Part I.</a> The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1936.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip24.html">OIP 24. Sennacherib’s Aqueduct at Jerwan</a> Thorkild Jacobsen and Seton Lloyd. 1935</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip23.html">OIP 23. Medinet Habu, Volume III. The Calendar, the “Slaughterhouse,” and Minor Records of Ramses III. </a> By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1934.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip22.html">OIP 22. Ancient Oriental Seals in the Collection of Mr. Edward T. Newell.</a> Hans Henning von der Osten. Originally published in 1934.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip21.html">OIP 21. The Excavation of Medinet Habu, Volume 1: General Plans and Views. 1934</a> Uvo Hölscher. </span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip20.html">OIP 20. Researches in Anatolia 5. The Alishar Hüyük Seasons of 1928 and 1929, Part 2.</a> Erich F. Schmidt with a chapter by Wilton Marion Krogman. Originally published in 1933.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip19.html">OIP 19. Researches in Anatolia 4. The Alishar Hüyük Seasons of 1928 and 1929, Part 1.</a> Erich F. Schmidt. Originally published in 1932.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip18.html">OIP  18. Paleolithic Man and the Nile Valley in Upper and Middle Egypt: A  Study of the Region during Pliocene and Pleistocene Times. By K. S.  Sandford.</a> Prehistoric Survey of Egypt and Western Asia, Volume III. Originally published in 1934.&nbsp;</span></li><li> <span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip17.html">OIP  17. Paleolithic Man and the Nile-Faiyum Divide in Nubia and Upper  Egypt: A Study of the Region during Pliocene and Pleistocene Times.</a> By K. S. Sandford and W. J. Arkell. Originally published in 1933.&nbsp;</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip16.html">OIP 16. Cuneiform Series, Volume IV: Sumerian Texts of Varied Contents.</a> Edward Chiera. 1934</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip15.html">OIP 15. Cuneiform Series, Volume III: Sumerian Epics and Myths.</a> Edward Chiera. 1934</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip14.html">OIP 14. Cuneiform Series, Vol. II: Inscriptions from from Adab.</a> Daniel David Luckenbill. 1930</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip13.html">OIP 13. Barhebraeus' Scholia on the Old Testament. Part I: Genesis - II Samuel.</a> Martin Sprengling and William Creighton Graham, editors. Originally published in 1931.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip12.html">OIP 12. The Proverbs of Solomon in Sahidic Coptic According to the Chicago Manuscript.</a> Edited by William H. Worrell. Originally published in 1931.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip11.html">OIP 11. Cuneiform Series, Volume I: Sumerian Lexical Texts from the Temple School of Nippur.</a> Edward Chiera. 1929</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip10.html">OIP  10. Prehistoric Survey of Egypt and Western Asia, Vol. I: Paleolithic  Man and the Nile-Faiyum Divide: A Study of the Region During Pliocene  and Pleistocene Times.</a> K. S. Sandford and W. J. Arkell. 1929</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip9.html">OIP 9. Medinet Habu, Volume II. <i>The Later Historical Records of Ramses III</i></a>. The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1932.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip8.html">OIP 8. Medinet Habu, Volume I. Earlier Historical Records of Ramses III.</a> By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1930.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip7.html">OIP 7. Researches in Anatolia 3. The Alishar Hüyük Season of 1927, Part 2.</a> Hans Henning von der Osten and Erich F. Schmidt. Originally published in 1932.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip6.html">OIP 6. Researches in Anatolia 2. The Alishar Hüyük Season of 1927, Part 1.</a> Hans Henning von der Osten and Erich F. Schmidt. Originally published in 1930.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip5.html">OIP 5.Researches in Anatolia 1. Explorations in Central Anatolia, Season of 1926.</a> H. H. von der Osten. Originally published in 1929.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip4.html">OIP 4.The Edwin Smith Surgical Papyrus, Volume 2: Facsimile Plates and Line for Line Hieroglyphic Transliteration. </a> J. H. Breasted. Originally published in 1930, revised in 1991. </span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip3.html">OIP 3. The Edwin Smith Surgical Papyrus, Volume 1: Hieroglyphic Transliteration, Translation, and Commentary.</a> J. H. Breasted. Originally published in 1930, revised in 1991. </span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip2.html">OIP 2. The Annals of Sennacherib.</a> By Daniel David Luckenbill. Originally published in 1924.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip1.html">OIP  1. Oriental Forerunners of Byzantine Painting: First-Century Wall  Paintings from the Fortress of Dura on the Middle Euphrates.</a> James Henry Breasted. Originally published in 1924.</span></li></ul><br /><br /><br /><br /><div style="text-align: center;">For an up to date list of all Oriental Institute publications available online see: </div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/10/oriental-institute-open-access.html">The Oriental Institute Open Access Publications</a><br /><br />&nbsp;See AWOL's <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/06/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">Alphabetical List of Open Access Monograph Series in Ancient Studies</a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4575962423970105112/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/09/open-access-monograp-series-oriental.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4575962423970105112"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4575962423970105112"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/09/open-access-monograp-series-oriental.html"
         title="Open Access Monograph Series: Oriental Institute Publications (OIP)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
