<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9203095607743723224</id>
   <published>2015-10-14T10:37:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-10-14T10:37:22.511-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="numismatics"/>
   <title type="text">Dar al-Kutub: Numismatic Collection of the Egyptian National Library</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://enl.numismatics.org/">Dar al-Kutub: Numismatic Collection of the Egyptian National Library</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://numismatics.org/egypt_images/thumbnail/1325_obv.jpg" src="http://numismatics.org/egypt_images/thumbnail/1325_obv.jpg" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Our catalog of 6,500 numismatic pieces – coins, glass weights, dies,  medals, etc. - is the third major catalog of Islamic numismatic material  held in the Egyptian National Library, formerly the   Khedivial Library, Egypt’s most important library. Our catalog differs  from its predecessors in a number of ways. First, it is a new catalog  in that we had to read the inscriptions from the   digital images which were taken under difficult and rushed conditions  and not from the actual objects for reasons which are explained in the  section entitled Introduction. Second, we included   in this electronic catalog inscriptions in Arabic as Dr. Sherif Anwar  read them, which was never possible in the previous studies because of  costs. Inscriptions in European languages and   references are the work of Dr. Norman D. Nicol from the 1982 catalog  of the collection.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Third, images of every piece are part of this  catalog, which was financially impossible when the earlier catalogues  were published. Fourth, the images are in color which modern technology   permits at no additional cost. On the other hand the Egyptian National  Library required that all images used on this webpage carry a  watermark. Images without watermarks of specific items can   be acquired by contacting the Egyptian National Library citing the  1982 catalog number, which is the last number in the title listing for  each item. Fifth, whenever a mint was named and could   be located, an accompanying map is included on the webpage. Finally,  as far as possible, all the data and search tools are available in both  Arabic and English for the first time in a catalog.   Electronic searches in Arabic and English can by undertaken by going  to the category “browse” and then using the various lists to narrow the  search. In order to find a specific piece based   upon its 1982 catalog number go to the heading “search” and under  “keyword” go to “recordId” and type in the appropriate number.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">This project is a result of the cooperation of the <a href="http://darelkotob.gov.eg/">Egyptian National Library and Archives</a> and the <a href="http://numismatics.org/">American Numismatic Society</a> with funding from USAID through the American Research Center in   Egypt. This electronic catalog is made available under the <a href="http://opendatacommons.org/licenses/odbl/1.0/">Open Database License</a>. It is powered by <a href="https://github.com/ewg118/numishare">Numishare</a> and numismatic concepts defined on <a href="http://nomisma.org/">Nomisma.org</a>.</span></blockquote><ul class="nav navbar-nav"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://enl.numismatics.org/results">Browse</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://enl.numismatics.org/search">Search</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://enl.numismatics.org/maps">Maps</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://enl.numismatics.org/visualize">Visualize Queries</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://enl.numismatics.org/pages/introduction">Introduction</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://enl.numismatics.org/pages/acknowledgments">Acknowledgments</a></span></li><li class="dropdown"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="dropdown-toggle" data-toggle="dropdown" href="http://enl.numismatics.org/#">Language</a></span><form action="results" class="navbar-form" method="get" role="search"><div class="input-group">&nbsp;</div></form></li></ul>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9203095607743723224/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/10/dar-al-kutub-numismatic-collection-of.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9203095607743723224"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9203095607743723224"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/10/dar-al-kutub-numismatic-collection-of.html"
         title="Dar al-Kutub: Numismatic Collection of the Egyptian National Library"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
