<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9216406026324163727</id>
   <published>2015-09-21T11:31:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-09-21T11:31:10.853-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Call for Papers: Thersites: Journal for Transcultural Presences &amp; Diachronic Identities from Antiquity to Date</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.thersites.uni-mainz.de/index.php/thr/index">Thersites: Journal for Transcultural Presences &amp; Diachronic Identities from Antiquity to Date</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h3><a href="http://www.thersites.uni-mainz.de/index.php/thr/about/editorialPolicies#custom-1">Call For Papers</a></h3><strong>Annemarie Ambühl (ed.), War of the Senses - The Senses in War</strong><br /><strong><strong>(open until November 30, 2015)</strong></strong><br /><div align="center"><strong>Interactions and tensions between representations of war in classical and modern culture</strong></div>War  has again become an omnipresent phenomenon, sadly not only in the  academic world. In view of the ongoing violence and its huge impact on  individual human beings and society as a whole, the question arises how  such experiences can be processed and reworked in different cultural  contexts. To what extent do modern war narratives still use patterns  deriving from a tradition that reaches back to the classical world? How  are the ruptures due to the technological incommensurability between  ancient and modern warfare reflected in various media? In accordance  with the scope of <em>thersites</em>, the planned special issue on  interactions and tensions between representations of war in classical  and modern literature and culture emphatically invites innovative  contributions that venture beyond the conventional areas and boundaries  of (classical) scholarship. For this purpose, reception studies in a  broad sense are not constrained to direct responses to classical works  or the perspective of classical scholars on contemporary wars, but  include comparing and contrasting ancient and modern war narratives in a  typological sense. Finally, the issue is to be addressed in what  respects the war experiences of the 20<sup>th</sup> and 21<sup>st</sup> centuries have irrevocably transformed our views of the classical texts.<br />The  present special issue will highlight the role of sensory perception and  the emotions in classical and modern representations of war in  literature and other media. In recent years, classical studies have  responded to the cultural turn by contextualizing war and violence in  the ancient world, from battlefield archeology, the reconstruction of  ‘face of battle’-experiences by ancient soldiers and the application of  trauma theory to narratological and aesthetical analyses of war  narratives in Greek and Roman literature. However, the role of the  senses in experiencing ancient war is still a marginalized topic,  despite the fact that current research especially on World War I has  foregrounded the impact of modern war as an overwhelming sensory  experience. Notwithstanding recent attempts to write a cultural history  of the senses from antiquity to the present, the specific quality of  sensory and emotional experience in ancient battles and their fictional  representations needs to be studied in depth.<br />In this respect, the  field of (fictional) war prose is still largely unexplored, as  reception studies have mainly concentrated on the representation of war  in Greek literature (Homer, tragedy) and on classical receptions in the  modern genres of drama and lyric. Therefore one focus of this special  issue of <em>thersites</em> is to lie on war narratives in Roman  literature in comparison with modern war novels. For example, based on  the hypothesis that the Roman civil wars as well as the First World War  both as catastrophes and as catalysts mark crucial thresholds of their  respective epochs that brought forth revolutions in politics, society,  culture and aesthetics, a comparative approach to the literary  productions provoked by these two momentous events seems fruitful. To be  sure, any other contributions that study reflections of modern wars  from the American or the Spanish Civil Wars to the ongoing wars of the  21<sup>st</sup> century and their interactions and tensions with wars  from various historical and cultural contexts of the ancient world are  highly welcome.<br />A selection of issues to be addressed:<br /><ul><li>comparing  and contrasting the psychological and aesthetic dimensions of battle  descriptions and aftermath narratives in Roman literature with  autobiographic or fictional eyewitness accounts describing the  experiences of soldiers fighting in modern wars (e.g. Caesar’s <em>Commentarii</em> and modern war diaries or novels such as Claude Simon, <em>La bataille de Pharsale</em>, 1969, or Alexis Jenni, <em>L’art français de la guerre</em>, 2011; Vergil’s, Lucan’s and Statius’ epics and the historiographical works by Livy and Tacitus compared to modern war novels)</li><li>representations  in literature and other media of experiencing war and battle through  the senses; besides the well-known focus on the visual (the general’s  gaze), especially the acoustic dimension and the other senses (smell,  taste, touch) are to be studied (including synaesthetic phenomena), as  well as the emotional responses by audiences</li><li>interactions between war literature and other media (classical iconographies of war, modern war movies, etc.)</li></ul><br /><strong>Deadline for the submission of abstracts: November 30, 2015</strong><br />Please send your proposals (in German, English, Italian, French or Spanish) including a brief outline of contents to: <a href="mailto:ambuehl@uni-mainz.de">ambuehl@uni-mainz.de</a><br />Specific bibliographical references for the topic are available on request.<br />Papers that have been accepted will undergo a peer reviewing process according to the guidelines of <em>thersites.</em></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span><span><span><span><span>See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></span></span></span> </span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9216406026324163727/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/09/call-for-papers-thersites-journal-for.html#comment-form"
         title="1 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9216406026324163727"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9216406026324163727"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/09/call-for-papers-thersites-journal-for.html"
         title="Call for Papers: Thersites: Journal for Transcultural Presences &amp; Diachronic Identities from Antiquity to Date"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
