<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4387841193762667589</id>
   <published>2015-04-01T22:49:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-04-01T22:49:27.353-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">News from Cuneiform Digital Library Notes</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[From Klaus Wagensonner &lt;klaus.wagensonner@orinst.ox.ac.uk&gt;:<br />==========================================<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">We are pleased to announce the publication of several new<br />contributions to the Cuneiform Digital Library Notes (CDLN)<br />(<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/index.php">http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/index.php</a>):<br /><br />CDLN 2015:004<br />Armando Bramanti, A Jemdet Nasr Fragment in the Collections of the<br />Oriental Institute of Chicago<br />(<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000057">http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000057</a>)<br /><br />CDLN 2015:005<br />Troels Pank Arbøll, A curious Ur III Tablet at the University of<br />Copenhagen: Notes on the History of Pinches’ Collection and an<br />Official named Abbagina<br />(<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000058">http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000058</a>)<br /><br />CDLN 2015:006<br />Klaus Wagensonner, A legal text at the Russell Library, Maynooth University<br />(<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000059">http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000059</a>)<br /><br />CDLN 2015:007<br />Strahil V. Panayotov, The tablet of the Middle Assyrian ‘coronation’<br />ritual: the placement of VAT 10113 and the displacement of VAT 9978<br />(<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000060">http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000060</a>)<br /><br />CDLN 2015:008<br />Gábor Zólyomi, Ashm 1924-478: a new ms. of the “The temple hymns” (ETCSL 4.80.1)<br />(<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000061">http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/single.php?id=000061</a>)<br /><br />We would like to take this opportunity to thank all contributors to<br />CDLN for their support and would like to encourage scholars to<br />contribute to the Notes in future as well.<br /><br />References and bibliographies:<br />All bibliographical information is drawn directly from a MySQL<br />database. It is therefore not necessary anymore to send fully<br />formatted bibliographies along with submitted contributions. For all<br />references that are included among the latest available bibliographies<br />on KeiBi Online (&lt;<a href="http://vergil.uni-tuebingen.de/keibi/">http://vergil.uni-tuebingen.de/keibi/</a>&gt;) it is<br />possible to save references and export them into the BibTeX format and<br />send this document along. A full bibliography was added on CDLN<br />(&lt;<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/bibliography.php">http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/php/bibliography.php</a>&gt;), which<br />contains all references used in the various contributions. Clicking on<br />a year leads to the respective contribution(s), where the chosen<br />reference is used. Vice versa, each reference list links back to the<br />full bibliography.<br /><br />As a test run the “Abbreviations for Assyriology” maintained by<br />CDLI:wiki (&lt;<a href="http://cdli.ox.ac.uk/wiki/doku.php?id=abbreviations_for_assyriology">http://cdli.ox.ac.uk/wiki/doku.php?id=abbreviations_for_assyriology</a>&gt;)<br />have been imported into the database as well. By hovering over<br />abbreviations in the bibliographies the full form and additional<br />information is given. Further features such as indices of texts<br />mentioned are in preparation.<br /><br />We do hope that these changes will increase the efficiency of CDLN and<br />are therefore happy to receive contributions for the next publication<br />of Notes on July 1, 2015.<br /><br />Submitted contributions are preferably made available as text files or<br />in the RTF format. If the contribution contains tables, word or pages<br />documents may be submitted as well. We would appreciate as few<br />formatting as possible. Please note that in order to aid the editing<br />process, please be so kind to provide all images in separate files and<br />not embed them in the submitted documents.<br /><br />The CDLN, together with its sister publications Cuneiform Digital<br />Library Bulletin (CDLB; &lt;<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdlb.html">http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdlb.html</a>&gt;) and<br />Cuneiform Digital Library Journal (CDLJ;<br />&lt;<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdlj.html">http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdlj.html</a>&gt;), are peer-reviewed publications<br />that offer a persistent web presence under the auspices of the<br />University of California system. As e-journals, the delay between<br />submission and publication is well below that of academic print<br />journals, while the interaction with cuneiform artifacts documented in<br />the CDLI database offers obvious strengths for an interactive<br />discourse. Authors should expect a two to four month interval between<br />submission of a draft text with illustrations and its publication for<br />substantive contributions to the CDLJ, at most two months for those<br />made to the Bulletin, and approximately two weeks for the Notes that<br />are conceived as an online venue for NABU-style communications that<br />can include short philological or lexicographical contributions as<br />well as regular updates of a more substantial nature describing the<br />background or progress of, in particular, web-based research efforts.<br />For submission guidelines including technicalities regarding<br />bibliographical citations etc. please consult the information at<br />&lt;<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/?q=about-cdln">http://cdli.ucla.edu/?q=about-cdln</a>&gt;.<br /><br />New submissions will appear in preprint status four times a year<br />(January 1, April 1, July 1, and October 1; notices of new submissions<br />will be made to this list) and are clearly marked as such. During the<br />preprint period, authors will be able to make small, non-substantive<br />changes (e.g., typographical errors) to their submissions. After two<br />weeks, these submissions are then archived.<br /><br />Scholars are encouraged to send contributions to the CDLN at<br />&lt;<a href="mailto:klaus.wagensonner@orinst.ox.ac.uk">klaus.wagensonner@orinst.ox.ac.uk</a>&gt;.<br /><br />On behalf of the CDLI<br /><br />Jacob L. Dahl and Klaus Wagensonner<br />University of Oxford</blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4387841193762667589/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/04/news-from-cuneiform-digital-library.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4387841193762667589"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4387841193762667589"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/04/news-from-cuneiform-digital-library.html"
         title="News from Cuneiform Digital Library Notes"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
