<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4361084251201553016</id>
   <published>2015-08-24T11:26:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-08-24T11:26:10.987-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Latin"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Pedagogy"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Language"/>
   <title type="text">Imperium Latin – free of charge to all</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.theclassicslibrary.com/imperium-latin-free-of-charge-to-all/">Imperium Latin – free of charge to all</a><br /><em>By <span class="author vcard sc"><span class="fn"><a href="http://www.theclassicslibrary.com/author/stephenjenkin/" rel="author" title="Posts by Stephen Jenkin">Stephen Jenkin</a></span></span> On <time class="date time published updated sc" datetime="2015-08-24T14:19:06+00:00">August 24, 2015</time></em><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><em><time class="date time published updated sc" datetime="2015-08-24T14:19:06+00:00"><strong></strong></time></em><span style="font-size: x-small;">I have just made Books 1, 2 and 3 of my Imperium Latin course  available free of charge to all via TES Resources, in the form of  downloadable pdf files. I have done this so that:</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><ol><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">more teachers and students will become aware of Imperium Latin,  which is already attracting some very positive reactions in a wide  variety of schools.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">these materials will help schools and individuals whose budgetary  pressures are making it difficult to learn and teach Latin, especially  those who find it hard to find money to buy books and startup resources.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">using Imperium will help with recruitment to Latin and to classical  studies generally, especially as it moves so quickly and adds so much  humour to the process.</span></li></ol><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The link for downloading the pdf files can be found here:</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.tes.com/member/imperiumlatin">https://www.tes.com/member/imperiumlatin</a> </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Here you will also find translations of four Greek plays, which have also been posted there to be downloaded free of charge. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">All of these files are restricted against copying and pasting but in other ways, their use is governed by the Creative Commons <strong><b>NoDerivatives</b></strong> licensing system, which says that if you remix, transform, or build  upon the material, you may not distribute the modified material.</span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Some background for those who are new to Imperium…</strong> </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">I started work on Imperium Latin in 2007 and it&nbsp;is now in use in  around 30-40 schools, some in the UK, some in the rest of Europe and a  few in the USA. It has had a couple of terrific reviews from the  American Classical League and JACT. The course follows the life of the  Emperor Hadrian, an intellectual of the first rank, an architect without  parallel and a traveller who made many fascinating journeys across the  empire. The story becomes a potent mix when you throw in his dubious  relationship with Trajan, a wife who hated him, the dark business of  Antinous and his strange and obsessional behaviour in later life. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Imperium Latin was written to be delivered via screens, using data  projectors or smartboards. Early on, I hit on a box-based approach,  which has proved very successful in classes. No single exercise in the  course ever spills over beyond one page, and no page has more than 10  boxes in any exercise. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The linguistic sequence was designed to rely on the present tense for  as long as possible, a technique which has been found successful by  many modern language teachers. The hardest clauses and constructions are  kept back until later, so the exercises remain accessible. Imperium is  rigorous and includes exercises of English into Latin in every chapter,  though there is often an overlap between the Latin to English and  English to Latin, which makes it possible to lift some of the answers,  as well as a full set of MP3 exercises, which can equip either student  or teacher to prepare for a class. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">When there is something to laugh about, learning often becomes more  motivational and it is a central pillar of the course that the material  shouldn’t take itself too seriously. Books 1 and 2 are filled with my  own jokes, whereas in Book 3, the focus shifts onto Latin witticisms,  through a collection of more than 50 poems of Martial. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">In addition to the books, the <strong><b>Imperium Word Tools App</b></strong> is a unique system which supports the Latin to English exercises. It  draws on the models of open-ended systems such as Perseus and  Nodictionaries but is carefully matched to this course and the needs of  its students. It runs on Mac, PC, Linux, Android and iOS devices, so it  is a complete solution for use at home as well as in the classroom. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">All the printed books can be bought via Amazon (simply enter Imperium  Latin), and the Apps can be bought from the App Store, Google Play, or  the project’s website. It should be noted that for schools wanting to  implement the course, the Site Support Pack should be regarded as a  basic essential. This includes printable pdf files of all the materials,  the Apps for Mac and PC, lots of teaching notes and details, MP3 files,  correct answers, tests, unseens, and lots more besides. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">In addition to three main coursebooks the <strong><b>Imperium Latin Grammar and Syntax Guide</b></strong> has been designed for use by any student of Latin. There is also a second range of resources called <strong><b>Imperium Latin Unseens</b></strong>, designed for more advanced students. This includes a book, MP3 files and the <strong><b>Imperium Unseen Tools</b></strong> App, as well as a Site Support Pack. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you want to know more, please visit: <a href="http://www.imperiumlatin.com/">www.imperiumlatin.com</a> and/or email: <a href="mailto:julian@imperiumlatin.com">julian@imperiumlatin.com</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Julian Morgan</span><br /> <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><time class="date time published updated sc" datetime="2015-08-24T14:19:06+00:00"></time></em></span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">And see AWOL's list of <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/09/open-access-textbooks.html">Open Access Textbooks and Language Primers</a></div><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><time class="date time published updated sc" datetime="2015-08-24T14:19:06+00:00">&nbsp;</time></em> </span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4361084251201553016/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/08/imperium-latin-free-of-charge-to-all.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4361084251201553016"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4361084251201553016"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/08/imperium-latin-free-of-charge-to-all.html"
         title="Imperium Latin – free of charge to all"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
