<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5723100344286666495</id>
   <published>2016-01-14T14:33:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-01-14T14:33:02.305-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Open Access Publisher"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="open access"/>
   <title type="text">Why the American Numismatic Society is Open Access . . . and why your institution, learned society, publisher, etc., should be, too</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.anspocketchange.org/on-open-access/">On Open Access</a><br /> 		<div class="entry-meta">			<span class="entry-date"><a href="http://www.anspocketchange.org/on-open-access/" rel="bookmark"><time class="entry-date" datetime="2016-01-14T11:24:09+00:00">January 14, 2016</time></a></span> <span class="byline"><span class="author vcard"><a class="url fn n" href="http://www.anspocketchange.org/author/areinhardnumismatics-org/" rel="author">Andrew Reinhard</a></span></span></div><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: small;"><span class="byline"><span class="author vcard"><span>Reposted with permission from</span>&nbsp; </span></span></span><a href="http://www.anspocketchange.org/">Pocket Change</a>: The blog of the <a href="http://numismatics.org/" target="_blank">American Numismatic Society.</a></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Why the American Numismatic Society is Open Access . . . and  why your institution, learned society, publisher, etc., should be, too</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://i1.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Open_Access_logo_PLoS_white.svg_.png" rel="attachment wp-att-2203"><img alt="Open_Access_logo_PLoS_white.svg" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2203" height="300" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Open_Access_logo_PLoS_white.svg_.png?zoom=2&amp;resize=192%2C300" width="192" /></a></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Academic  and scholarly publication is at a crossroads as publishers, authors,  and institutions of research and higher learning consider both the  financial and ‘moral’ implications of publishing new scholarship as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_access" target="_blank">Open Access</a>.  The American Numismatic Society (ANS) has adopted what some would  consider a progressive approach, while others would find these points to  simply be common sense and good manners. As you read the points below, I  challenge you to formulate arguments against each one that does not  include money. Profit and loss in academic publishing is a very real  concern, but it can be demonstrated (and has been in my nine years of  experience as an academic publisher) that publishing niche scholarship  is (and likely always will be) a money-losing venture. Publication is  often built into the mission statements of learned societies, and  funding needs to be sought from sources beyond&nbsp;book sales and journal  subscriptions to keep the publishing enterprise sustainable.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The ANS has addressed each of the following problems in its efforts  to make published research open without taking a hit financially.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Problem: Gold Open Access</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">One method some publishers use to offset production costs is to  charge those authors (or their institutions) who wish to make their  research freely available online immediately upon publication instead of  waiting some contractually agreed amount of time before being given  permission to post the work the web or via a university repository.  These costs often range from the hundreds into the low thousands of  dollars (e.g., Maney Publishing’s “<a href="http://www.maneyonline.com/page/openaccess" target="_blank">Article Publishing Charge</a>”  (APC) for immediate Open Access publication). Charging authors for Open  Access creates an economic barrier to scholars, some of whom cannot  afford the fee, and whose institutions may not have budgeted for such  costs. Unaffiliated and independent scholars are especially affected by  these fees, which they have to pay out-of-pocket&nbsp;and may even&nbsp;require  securing a loan.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>What the ANS is Doing About It:&nbsp;</strong></em>It is our  opinion that authors (and their institutions) should never be charged to  make their own research available to the world immediately upon  publication.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://i0.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/ajn26cover.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-2231"><img alt="ajn26cover" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2231" height="300" src="http://i0.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/ajn26cover.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=207%2C300" width="207" /></a></strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Problem: Embargo Periods</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Going hand-in-glove with “gold” Open Access is the common practice of  an embargo period, which is the time (anywhere from one to five years  in most cases) between when research is published and when an author can  make that work freely available. The point of the embargo period is to  allow the publisher to recover the production costs of that publication  prior to making it available as Open Access. Authors are forbidden to  post more than a citation or abstract, and their work is often locked  behind a paywall until the embargo expires. Timely research becomes less  so as long as the embargo period lasts, except to those readers who opt  for early access. Scholars who wish to access that author’s work must  either pay to access the publication, wait until the embargo ends, ask  the author for a PDF offprint (which is normally forbidden) or their  login credentials to a paywalled platform (even more forbidden). As with  file-sharing of other media, many people tend to look for the free  version of something they would otherwise have to pay for, thereby  short-circuiting the embargo period and the paywall, which nets both the  publisher and paywall provider nothing, i.e., the same amount they  would make by giving away the published work.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong><a href="http://i1.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/cc.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-2233"><img alt="cc" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2233" height="225" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/cc.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=225%2C225" width="225" /></a></strong></em></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>What the ANS is Doing About It:</strong></em> Authors of ANS publications may place their published work wherever they like upon publication, and may assign to it whichever <a href="https://creativecommons.org/" target="_blank">Creative Commons license</a>&nbsp;that they are the most comfortable using. A brief word on the types of Creative Commons licenses follows below.</span></div></blockquote><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Problem: Paywalls</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">As stated above regarding embargos on published research, paywalls do  little to discourage the exchange of files between colleagues, and also  place a barrier in the way of scientific progress. Platforms such as <a href="http://www.jstor.org/" target="_blank">JSTOR</a> can strike a happy medium in curating content into packages to which  institutional libraries may subscribe, thereby providing a revenue  stream for publishers. That same content can be shared with individuals  on a non-commercial basis provided the publisher has successfully  negotiated a content-sharing agreement.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>What the ANS is Doing About It:</strong></em> The ANS has  such an agreement with JSTOR, and is making some of its publications  available on that platform for library subscribers, while also making  those same publications available for free to individuals via the <a href="https://www.hathitrust.org/" target="_blank">Hathi Trust Digital Library</a>&nbsp;and with our own <a href="http://numismatics.org/digitallibrary/id/Miller-ANS-Medals" target="_blank">Digital Library</a>.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://i2.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/books.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-2234"><img alt="books" class="aligncenter wp-image-2234 size-large" height="264" src="http://i2.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/books.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=474%2C264" width="474" /></a></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong></strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Problem: “Predatory” Publishers</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Following the paywall model is the usury of so-called “predatory”  publishers that charge libraries and individuals hundreds and even  thousands of dollars to access newly published research. Authors should  be wary of publishing in journals owned by these companies as their work  will reach a limited set of eyes. If most authors found other journals  in which to publish, the dearth of content would force predatory  publishers to either change their business model or to close entirely.  Libraries can also choose not to subscribe to those journals, favoring  instead those with a more reasonable Open Access policy.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>What the ANS is Doing About It:</strong> </em>The ANS has  no intention of partnering with any of the large publishing companies  that choose to lock current research behind paywalls with formidable  access costs.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Problem: Geography-Based Access</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Some Open Access content is not globally available. Sometimes this is  a technical issue, and, for some publishers, this is a conscious  decision based on their understanding and implementation of copyright.  Actively choosing to limit access to content that is otherwise open  deprives international scholars of their ability to read that work  freely, at which point they must resort to paying for access, or to  bending the rules and asking colleagues for a free copy or access  to&nbsp;something.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>What the ANS is Doing About It:</strong></em> The ANS makes every effort to ensure that its Open Access content is available worldwide. Much of it is hosted via <a href="http://numismatics.org/" target="_blank">numismatics.org</a> and various subdomains. Agreements signed with partners such as  HathiTrust make sure that the content is available globally without  restriction.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><figure class="wp-caption alignleft" id="attachment_2236" style="width: 225px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://i2.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/0000.999.52801.obv_.noscale.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-2236"><img alt="ANS, 0000.999.52801" class="wp-image-2236" height="225" src="http://i2.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/0000.999.52801.obv_.noscale.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=225%2C225" width="225" /></a></span><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">ANS, 0000.999.52801</span></figcaption></figure><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Problem: Profit-Based Publishing</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">One of the greatest mistakes a learned society or institution can  make is to become focused on making&nbsp;its publications turn a profit.  Scholarly publications typically cater to a niche market and sell dozens  or occasionally hundreds of copies over a period of three years. Sales  beyond three years of the original publication date are rare. If an  organization recognizes the fact that it will realize little (or no)  profit from the sale of what it publishes, it can strategize how to pay  the not inconsiderable production costs. These costs can be built into  annual budgets, can be inserted into grant applications for projects,  and can be sought in the form of subventions. Basing choices of what to  publish by&nbsp;what the publisher (or Board) thinks will sell can be a  mistake, especially when what is to be published fulfills the mission of  the parent institution.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>What the ANS is Doing About It:</strong> </em>The ANS  favors a mission-based approach to publishing. It understands that some  publications will never recover their production costs, but nevertheless  that the content is exceedingly important in fulfilling the Society’s  stated goals for research and dissemination of that research.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Problem: “Commercial” Publications</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Non-profit, academic institutions historically have published  scholarship as non-commercial ventures. As stated above, the publication  of journals and monographs is hardly a money-making enterprise. Books  and subscriptions are sold in order to recover some production costs.  Recently one major <a href="http://www.britishmuseum.org/about_this_site/terms_of_use/copyright_and_permissions.aspx" target="_blank">international rights-holder</a> updated its Terms of Service regarding the reproduction of its images  in scholarly publications, classing journals and scholarly monographs as  “commercial”, which then allows&nbsp;charging for image permissions.  Typically a reciprocal relationship exists between institutions where no  permissions fees are charged for non-commercial, scholarly, short-run  publications. In switching the Terms of Service to “commercial”, the  budget for publishing books or articles featuring images from one of  these rights-holders expands by hundreds if not thousands of dollars.  This charge represents another barrier to scholarship; publishers will  simply go elsewhere for similar images. This also actually hurts the  rights holder, in effect limiting wider access to its own holdings and  hiding them behind a self-inflicted paywall.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>What the ANS is Doing About It:</strong></em> The ANS  will never class scholarly publications as “commercial,” and will not  charge reproduction fees for the use of its images in scholarly  publications.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://i1.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Screen-Shot-2016-01-14-at-11.10.05-AM.png" rel="attachment wp-att-2237"><img alt="Screen Shot 2016-01-14 at 11.10.05 AM" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2237" height="300" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Screen-Shot-2016-01-14-at-11.10.05-AM.png?zoom=2&amp;resize=293%2C300" width="293" /></a></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong></strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Problem: Permissions Charges</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Most academic publishers ask the authors to pay for their own image  permissions. The publishers cannot themselves afford to pay the fees, so  the charges get passed to the author. For many authors, however, many  of their images can be used without any permissions fees because of the  non-commercial nature of their work. Should an institution opt to charge  an author for an image, it is possible that the author will opt to find  a similar image elsewhere, or will choose not to use an image at all.  Either way, the rights holder receives no revenue, and also loses  whatever additional exposure it would have otherwise received via a  credit line in the publication. Charging authors for image permissions  further limits access to content that would otherwise be freely  available.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>What the ANS is Doing About It:</strong></em> The ANS will not charge authors for the use of its images in non-commercial publications.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><figure class="wp-caption alignright" id="attachment_2238" style="width: 240px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://i2.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/1916.192.368.obv_.noscale.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-2238"><img alt="ANS, 1916.192.368" class="wp-image-2238" height="237" src="http://i2.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/1916.192.368.obv_.noscale.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=240%2C237" width="240" /></a></span><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">ANS, 1916.192.368</span></figcaption></figure><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Problem: Print-Only Publishing</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Arguably the biggest roadblock to Open Access research is publishing  solely in print. Publishing in print restricts access to the content  locked on the pages and favors those readers with library access or the  ability to purchase the publication. Print editions of scholarship,  while useful to many, are themselves silos of information, unable to  interact with anything other than the active reader. This is the  opposite of Open Access. Making print editions available online as  digital editions unlocks that content, making it searchable, and perhaps  more importantly, gives the content the ability to link to any other  data available openly online, as well as making itself available to be  linked to from other online sources.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><strong>What the ANS is Doing About It:</strong></em> The ANS  will continue to produce print editions of scholarship, but it will make  digital editions of all of its publications past, present, and future  available online as Open Access. Doing so allows the ANS to play well  with others, to be a good academic citizen, and to contribute to the  work of others. By sharing publications openly, this guarantees that  multiple copies will be made and circulated thereby preventing loss of  that content should something happen to the original publisher.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>A Word on Creative Commons Licensing</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">There are several varieties of Creative Commons (CC) licensing  available to authors and publishers that both protect and promote  content on the Internet and elsewhere. Anything published as Open Access  must have a CC license attached to it, otherwise the content is not  free to use. Most Open Access publications have a <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/" target="_blank">CC-BY</a> (users must cite the source) or <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank">CC-BY-NC</a> (citation required, and must be used for non-commercial purposes only). On rare occasions, the most open CC license, <a href="https://creativecommons.org/about/cc0/" target="_blank">CC0</a> (content may be used for any purpose, commercial or otherwise, with or  without citation) is used. The ANS’s Open Access publications online are  posted under a CC license, usually CC-BY or CC-BY-NC. Its publications  on HathiTrust are posted as CC0. The ANS works with its authors to  determine which CC license they are most comfortable with prior to  posting their work online.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><figure class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_2239" style="width: 300px;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://i0.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/1927.64.5.obv_.noscale.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-2239"><img alt="ANS, 1927.64.5" class="size-medium wp-image-2239" height="300" src="http://i0.wp.com/www.anspocketchange.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/1927.64.5.obv_.noscale.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=300%2C300" width="300" /></a></span><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><span style="font-size: x-small;">ANS, 1927.64.5</span></figcaption></figure><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Conclusions:</strong></span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">If Open Access publication of content is not part of your  institution’s/society’s/publisher’s strategy, it should be. As authors  and as consumers of content, it is within your rights to ask (and in  some cases demand) that your research (or the scholarship you need) be  made openly available online. Open Access does not require the cessation  of the sale of that same content. Many readers still prefer to read  printed books and journals, and will pay for them (or will ask their  libraries to pay for them). Most readers prefer a suite of media with  which to work, using print in concert with digital as they produce new  scholarship. The end goal of the production of that scholarship should  not be to make money, but instead to advance the humanities, arts, and  sciences. The best way to do that is to make that scholarship available  immediately to the world upon publication. Openly. The ANS hopes that  other institutions, learned societies, and publishers will share in this  approach to placing published work online without cumbersome  restrictions. The Internet is genetically predisposed to facilitate such  sharing, which makes it the greatest enabler of advancing our  collective&nbsp;intellectual enterprise.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">—<a href="http://numismatics.org/About/Andrewreinhard" target="_blank">Andrew Reinhard</a></span></div>&nbsp;</div></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5723100344286666495/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/01/why-american-numismatic-society-is-open.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5723100344286666495"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5723100344286666495"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/01/why-american-numismatic-society-is-open.html"
         title="Why the American Numismatic Society is Open Access . . . and why your institution, learned society, publisher, etc., should be, too"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
