<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6621720812997442712</id>
   <published>2015-04-08T13:00:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-04-08T13:00:27.207-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Aramaic"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Palmyrene"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Syria"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Palmyra"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="inscriptions"/>
   <title type="text">The Wisconsin Palmyrene Aramaic Inscription Project (WPAIP)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://uwdc.library.wisc.edu/collections/ClassicalStudies/WPAIP">The Wisconsin Palmyrene Aramaic Inscription Project (WPAIP)</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="image: WPAIP" border="0" height="200" src="http://uwdc.library.wisc.edu/images/stories/WPAIP.jpg" width="172" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Roman-controlled city of Palmyra (1st c. BCE–3rd c. CE), once a  major economic hub in the Levant, is the source of thousands of  inscriptions in a dialect of Aramaic, as well as many in Latin and Greek  (Yon 2012). The entire corpus of Palmyrene Aramaic inscriptions known  before 1996 has been collected in the comprehensive volume, <cite>Palmyrene Aramaic Texts</cite> (Hillers &amp; Cussini 1996); those inscriptions discovered since 1996  have been recently published as well (Yon 2013; see also Yon 2012 for  the Greek and Latin inscriptions from Palmyra). These studies have  contributed greatly to the study of Palmyrene Aramaic, but none of them  have directly addressed the development of the locally indigenous script  (<em>paleography</em>), nor do the studies of Hillers &amp; Cussini  1996 and Yon 2013 provide photographs or drawings of the inscriptions  (in contrast, see Yon 2012 for photos of the Greek and Latin texts), nor  do they provide translations. Previous studies of the script  (paleography) have usually been limited to short, now outdated articles  whose authors worked without the benefit of high-quality photographs and  comprehensive textual editions (e.g., Naveh 1970; Klugkist 1983).</span><br /> <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The immediate goal of the Wisconsin Palmyrene Aramaic Inscription  Project (WPAIP) is to re-collate the corpus of Palmyrene Aramaic  inscriptions as we are able, providing detailed photographic records and  new editions of each epigraph. In this project, several facets of the  inscriptions will be investigated. These facets include the development  of and stylistic variation within the Palmyrene Aramaic script; the  language represented in the epigraphs; the onomastic features (personal  naming conventions) and prosopography (familial relations) exhibited in  the epigraphs (e.g., Stark 1970; Piersimoni 1995); and the modes and  avenues of the inscriptions’ distribution through the antiquities market  since the 19th century. These goals are commensurate with those of the  Palmyra Portrait Project of Aarhus University in Denmark (link below),  which is currently working to compile a comprehensive catalogue of  Palmyrene portraiture. Yet, the compilation of the corpus of epigraphic  texts for the purposes of research is important not only for its own  sake, but because of its preservation of Syrian cultural heritage in the  face of recent Syrian political unrest. This new danger poses a clear  and immediate threat not only to the current Syrian population, but to  Palmyrene antiquities as well, placing a major portion of Roman-era  Syrian culture in jeopardy. The ruins of the ancient city are in danger,  with increasing numbers of objects being sold on the black market. In  light of the imminent threat to Palmyra and its unique cultural and  linguistic heritage, the immediate goals of this project contribute to a  much wider goal as well: the participants hope, in some small way, to  make a lasting contribution to the preservation of Palmyrene history and  culture.</span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" name="nav"></a>  <ul class="navigation"><li> <a href="http://digicoll.library.wisc.edu/WebZ/initialize?sessionid=0&amp;javascript=true&amp;dbchoice=1&amp;active=1&amp;entityCurrentPage=Search1&amp;dbname=ClassicalStudies&amp;style=ClassicalStudies&amp;next=NEXTCMD%7FSortedQuery?&amp;context;&amp;termsrch=%28is%3D+%28Wisconsin+Palmyrene+Aramaic+Inscription+Project%29%29&amp;fmtclass=gallery&amp;next=html/nfbrief.html&amp;bad=error/badsearch.html&amp;entitytoprecno=1&amp;entitycurrecno=1&amp;entitytempjds=TRUE&amp;numrecs=12%7F"> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>B</em>rowse Wisconsin Palmyrene Aramaic Inscription Project</span></a></li><li> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="searchLink" href="http://digicoll.library.wisc.edu/WebZ/initialize?sessionid=0&amp;active=4&amp;next=html/advancedsearch.html&amp;bad=html/advancedsearch.html&amp;javascript=true&amp;dbname=ClassicalStudies&amp;dbchoice=1&amp;entityCurrentPage=Search4&amp;style=ClassicalStudies&amp;subcollection=Wisconsin+Palmyrene+Aramaic+Inscription+Project"> <em>S</em>earch the collection</a> <img border="0" height="1" src="http://uwdc.library.wisc.edu/images/collections/common/spacer.gif" width="1" /> <a class="tip" href="http://uwdc.library.wisc.edu/collections/ClassicalStudies/WPAIP#"><img alt="information about searching the collection" border="0" height="15" src="http://uwdc.library.wisc.edu/images/collections/common/info-icon.png" width="15" /></a></span></li></ul></blockquote></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6621720812997442712/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/04/the-wisconsin-palmyrene-aramaic.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6621720812997442712"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6621720812997442712"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/04/the-wisconsin-palmyrene-aramaic.html"
         title="The Wisconsin Palmyrene Aramaic Inscription Project (WPAIP)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
