<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-10634957762651323</id>
   <published>2015-12-09T07:26:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-12-09T07:26:28.366-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Elephantine"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Papyri"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egypt"/>
   <title type="text">Rubensohn-Sammlung - Rubensohn Collection</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://elephantine.smb.museum/">Rubensohn-Sammlung - Rubensohn Collection</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img height="56" src="http://elephantine.smb.museum/wp-content/themes/elephantine/images/headers/RubensohnBiblLogo_l.jpg" style="display: inline;" width="200" /><img height="84" src="http://elephantine.smb.museum/wp-content/themes/elephantine/images/headers/RubensohnBiblLogo_r.jpg" style="display: inline;" width="200" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">During the 5th century BCE, while Egypt stood under Persian sovereignty, an Aramaeo-Jewish community settled on an <strong>island in the Nile River called Elephantine</strong>,  opposite the city Syene, today’s Aswan. The Hebrew Bible sources in  Jeremiah 41 and 2 Kings 25 refer to the existence of this Jewish  diaspora in Egypt; this description has been confirmed by a <strong>sensational discovery of Aramaic papyri</strong> on Elephantine Island itself, whose extra-biblical texts provide  contemporaneous attestation to the community. By means of commercial  trade, Aramaic papyri from Elephantine Island emerged early in the  European antiquities market; in this way, Richard Lepsius would obtain  an Aramaic papyrus for his Egyptian and Nubian collection. This papyrus  was an Aramaic text from the Athanasi Collection, which Lepsius had  purchased on behalf of the Museum in Berlin in 1842. In Syene, the city  opposite Elephantine, a larger find of very well preserved papyri was  acquired by Robert Mond, and equally as many by Lady William Cecil.  These were published in 1906 by Sayce and Cowley. Subsequently, the  desire arose to complete the new holdings through <strong>systematic archaeological excavation</strong>, and thereby recover additional papyri prior to their deterioration. Under orders from the Königliche Museen zu Berlin, <strong>three  archaelogical campaigns on Elephantine Island were ultimately conducted  by the German archaeologist Otto Rubensohn and the German papyrologist  Friedrich Zucker between 1906 and 1908</strong>. Adolf Erman, the Director of the Egyptian Museum at the time, wrote concerning these events in his memoirs: </span><br /> <blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">„Smaller excavations, which we had attempted at various  Egyptian sites with city ruins in order to obtain papyri, caused us far  fewer efforts and costs than these large excavations. Nevertheless, at  least one of them produced outcomes that are of the greatest scholarly  significance. It was known that the Fellahin had found papyrus in the  old city of Elelphantine Island, and in 1904 a large find came to light  there, which included Aramaic documents concerning Jewish soldiers; in  the Persian era a garrison of all manner of foreigners had been situated  in this border fortification. In order to follow this lead further,  Otto Rubensohn went to Elephantine in 1906, and at the same time French  scholars also went there with the same purposes. The general director  Maspero divided the excavation site between both parties, but we were  the ones who drew the better lot this time, because in our area, close  to the boundary of the French area, Rubensohn came upon a simple house,  and it turned out to contain the records of the Jewish community.“ </span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">Rubensohn also began his excavation report summary with a reference to the Aramaic document, stating: </span><br /> <blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">„The Elephantine excavations are a result of the  discovery of a few Aramaic papyri, which have been published by Sayce  and Cowley as „Aramaic Papyri discovered at Assuan.“ Another visit to  Aswan in the year of the discovery, 1904, allowed me to gain the  acquaintance and the trust of those considered dealers and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sebakh" target="_blank" title="Wikipedia article: Sebakh">Sebakh</a> diggers. At my request they led me to discovery site of the papyri. The  site which they showed me did not lie in Aswan, but rather on the  western edge of the koms of Elephantine. It was a spot about 1 meter  north of the location at which we would later make the larger find of  Aramaic papyri. At my proposal the general administration of the royal  museums in Berlin shut down the work that had begun, and with customary  courteousness Mr. Maspero in the name of the Service des Antiquités  issued the requested permission to operate papyrus excavation on the  western half of the Koms of Elephantine.“ </span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">On December 5, 1904 the excavation license was issued to „Monsineur  le Docteur Rubensohn, in the name of the direction of the Royal Museums  of Berlin“ for the duration of one year; on November 8, 1905 and again  on December 10, 1906 additional one-year extensions were granted, and at  last the license was transferred to Friedrich Zucker. […] </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Today, the largest portion of the papyri, ostraca, and seal stamps  that were granted via partage to the Berlin Museums on December 24, 1907  is found in the Ägyptisches Museum und Papyrussammlung Berlin. </span><br /></blockquote><div id="access" role="navigation">                  <blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="menu-header"><ul class="menu" id="menu-hauptmenue"><li class="menu-item menu-item-type-post_type menu-item-object-page menu-item-has-children menu-item-36" id="menu-item-36"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://elephantine.smb.museum/suche/?lang=en">Search</a></span> </li><li class="menu-item menu-item-type-post_type menu-item-object-page current-menu-item page_item page-item-24 current_page_item menu-item-35" id="menu-item-35"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://elephantine.smb.museum/?lang=en">Rubensohn Collection</a></span></li><li class="menu-item menu-item-type-post_type menu-item-object-page menu-item-has-children menu-item-32" id="menu-item-32"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://elephantine.smb.museum/projekt/?lang=en">Project</a></span> </li><li class="menu-item menu-item-type-post_type menu-item-object-page menu-item-has-children menu-item-31" id="menu-item-31"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://elephantine.smb.museum/nutzungshinweise/?lang=en">Documentation &amp; How To</a></span> </li><li class="menu-item menu-item-type-post_type menu-item-object-page menu-item-30" id="menu-item-30"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://elephantine.smb.museum/kontakt/?lang=en">Contact</a></span></li></ul></div></blockquote></div><div id="header"><div id="masthead"><div id="access" role="navigation"><form action="http://elephantine.smb.museum/suche/result/" id="searchform" method="get"><blockquote><div id="menu_header_search_all"><span style="font-size: x-small;">      </span><a href="http://elephantine.smb.museum/" title="Zur deutschen Version wechseln"><span style="font-size: x-small;">       </span><br />        </a>     </div></blockquote></form></div></div></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/10634957762651323/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/12/rubensohn-sammlung-rubensohn-collection.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/10634957762651323"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/10634957762651323"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/12/rubensohn-sammlung-rubensohn-collection.html"
         title="Rubensohn-Sammlung - Rubensohn Collection"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
