<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1085884112062982075</id>
   <published>2016-12-20T17:45:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2016-12-20T17:47:57.674-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Architecture"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egyptology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egypt"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: The Journal of Ancient Egyptian Architecture</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/">The Journal of Ancient Egyptian Architecture</a><br />ISSN: 2472-999X <br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img src="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/ressources/JOAEA_logo.jpg" height="36" width="320" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Journal of Ancient Egyptian Architecture is a scientific, open  access and annual periodical. Its purpose is to promote the publication  of research devoted to Ancient Egyptian architecture (domestic, civil,  military, ritual/religious and funerary), from the Predynastic Period to  the Roman imperial era, whatever the modern geographical context  (Egypt, Sudan, Near East, etc). The subject scope includes everything  relating to construction, regardless of its original importance or  purpose.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The journal publishes fieldwork reports and studies undertaken in  the Egyptological tradition, including discussions of epigraphy and  iconography, but also work that utilizes specific skills such as  structural and materials sciences, or modern investigative techniques.  In this way, <i>JAEA</i> seeks to encourage the development of detailed  technical descriptions, and deeply theorized understanding (of  architectural symbolism, propaganda, climatic and geological influences,  etc.). This interdisciplinary approach will help connect adjacent areas  of expertise which, alone, could not reflect the richness and  complexity of the Ancient Egyptian built heritage.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The periodical welcomes any study that meets any one of these  goals, only on the condition that the formatting and content of articles  are subject to <i>JAEA</i> scientific publication requirements.  </span></blockquote>Volume 1 (2016) is complete <br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div id="RightBar"><a href="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/JAEA1/JAEA1-2016.pdf" target="_blank"></a><br /><div class="fullvolume" id="ArticleName"><h1><a href="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/JAEA1/JAEA1-2016.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Download the full volume</span></a></h1><a href="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/JAEA1/JAEA1-2016.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="font-size: x-small;">     </span></a><br /><h3><a href="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/JAEA1/JAEA1-2016.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="font-size: x-small;">27 Downloads</span></a></h3><a href="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/JAEA1/JAEA1-2016.pdf" target="_blank"><span style="font-size: x-small;">     </span></a></div><a href="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/JAEA1/JAEA1-2016.pdf" target="_blank"></a><span style="font-size: x-small;">        </span><br /><div class="white" id="ArticleName"><h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">The use of the ‘ceremonial’ cubit rod as a measuring tool. An explanation (p. 1)</span></h1><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Fr. Monnier, J.-P. Petit &amp; Chr. Tardy</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">This article deals with data inscribed on Ancient Egyptian cubit  rods, and more specifically on the ceremonial cubit rods. Following a  description of their technical and symbolic aspects, the paper reveals a  property of the fine subdivisions engraved on the graduated part of  these objects, and demonstrates that they could have allowed the cubits  to be used as very accurate measuring rulers for architectural drawings  and craft works.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Published 22 July 2016<img src="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/ressources/views.png" /> 11794 Views <img src="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/ressources/download.jpg" /> 517 Downloads</span></h3></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">       </span><br /><div class="white" id="ArticleName"><h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">Varieties and sources of sandstone used in Ancient Egyptian temples (p. 11)</span></h1><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">J. A. Harrell</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Sandstone was one of the principal building materials of ancient  Egypt, and this paper provides an overview of the varieties and sources  of sandstone used in temples and other monuments. Included are lists of  all known sandstone temples and quarries with precise locations given  for each along with their age and status, and additionally for the  quarries, size and petrology. Three megascopic properties (grain size,  bedding type, and color) and one microscopic property (total feldspar  content) are assessed in terms of their usefulness in recognizing  sandstone varieties and their sources.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Published 26 August 2016<img src="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/ressources/views.png" /> 2624 Views <img src="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/ressources/download.jpg" /> 236 Downloads</span></h3></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">     </span><br /><div class="white" id="ArticleName"><h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">Biography of a Great Pyramid Casing Stone (p. 39)</span></h1><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">D. I. Lightbody</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">In the collection of the National Museum of Scotland is a block  of limestone that was once part of the outer face of the Great Pyramid  of pharaoh Khufu. This article presents the results of a new study of  the stone carried out in Edinburgh in April of 2013, with permission  granted by National Museums Scotland. The stone was originally brought  to Edinburgh in 1872 for Charles Piazzi Smyth who was interested to  study the principles of its dimensions and proportions. This new study  demonstrates that when appropriately investigated, the stone reveals  significant information about its original position on the Great  Pyramid, as well as information regarding the Ancient Egyptians' own  systems of measurement and architectural construction. The article also  addresses the symbolic significance of the principal dimensions of this  stone, and the monument on which it was placed.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Published 24 September 2016<img src="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/ressources/views.png" /> 1232 Views <img src="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/ressources/download.jpg" /> 118 Downloads</span></h3></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">        </span><br /><div class="white" id="ArticleName"><h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">A look through his window: the sanctuary of the divine Apis Bull at Memphis (p. 57)</span></h1><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">N. Marković</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">The divine Apis bulls were kept, lived, died, and were prepared  for burial within the building complex known as the Place of Apis,  somewhere in the vicinity of the main temple of Ptah at Memphis.  Unfortunately, its exact location and layout are yet to be identified on  site since large parts of the Ptah temple enclosure today lie under the  modern settlement of Mit Rahina. Yet, since the Place of Embalmment has  already been discovered in the south-western corner of the Ptah temple  precinct, the rest of the sanctuary must have been located nearby. The  purpose of this article is to propose a completely new layout for the  sanctuary of Apis based on all available source material in order to  connect parts of the burial ritual, known as the Apis Embalming Ritual,  with actual localities inside the sanctuary itself.  </span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Published 1 November 2016<img src="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/ressources/views.png" /> 1055 Views <img src="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/ressources/download.jpg" /> 112 Downloads</span></h3></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">               </span><br /><div class="white" id="ArticleName"><h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">Les constructions axiales thoutmosides devant le 4<sup>e</sup> pylône de Karnak (p. 71)</span></h1><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">F. Larché</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Hatshepsut Ma'atkare spectacularly monumentalized the two main entrances to the temple of Karnak. To the south she built the 8<sup>th</sup> pylon, and to the west the 4<sup>th</sup> pylon as well as a pylon further to the west which has not survived.  After her disappearance, Thutmosis III transformed both of these  entrances. He had the 7<sup>th</sup> pylon erected on the southern entry  way, and this article proposes that he also installed two pairs of  obelisks to the west, between the 4<sup>th</sup> pylon and the obelisks  already erected by Hatshepsut Ma'atkare (with the name of Tuthmosis II).  The analysis indicates that this transformation was completed by his  successor Amenhotep II, who also built a calcite chapel between the two  pairs of obelisks. This chapel was in turn dismantled by his son,  Thutmosis IV, at the time of the construction of his portico court.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Published 28 November 2016<img src="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/ressources/views.png" /> 511 Views <img src="http://www.egyptian-architecture.com/ressources/download.jpg" /> 91 Downloads</span></h3></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">            </span><br /><div class="submit" id="ArticleName"><span style="font-size: x-small;">     </span><br /><h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">Submissions are open for the 2017 issue !</span></h1></div></div><div id="bottombar"></div></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-weight: normal;">See AWOL's full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.co.uk/2015/12/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span> </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1085884112062982075/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/06/forthcoming-open-access-journal-journal.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1085884112062982075"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1085884112062982075"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/06/forthcoming-open-access-journal-journal.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: The Journal of Ancient Egyptian Architecture"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
