<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6906133954471367529</id>
   <published>2015-11-15T20:20:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2015-11-15T20:20:30.762-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Epigraphy"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Arabia"/>
   <title type="text">OCIANA: Online Corpus of the Inscriptions of Ancient North Arabia</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/ociana/index.php">OCIANA: Online Corpus of the Inscriptions of Ancient North Arabia</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="ociana logo bluegold" height="72" src="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/ociana/images/ociana_logo_bluegold.png" style="float: left;" width="320" /> </blockquote><br /><br />&nbsp;<span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Arabian Peninsula lies at the heart  of the Middle East. Today, it is of enormous strategic and commercial  importance and this was also the case in antiquity. Yet, most of what we  know about its ancient history, languages and cultures comes from  contemporaries looking at it from outside, such as the Assyrians,  Greeks, and Romans, or from much later reports on what was considered  the "Age of Ignorance". Excavations and surveys have been undertaken in  the rest of the Middle East for more than a century and a half, but the  archaeological exploration of Arabia is still in a pioneering stage. For  a brief history of Ancient Arabia and a timeline <a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/resources/publications/macdonald/Ancient%20Arabia%20a%20Brief%20History%20and%20Time-Line.pdf" target="_blank">click here</a>.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The western two-thirds of the Arabian  Peninsula were home to numerous literate societies. Indeed, one of the  two branches of the alphabet — the South Semitic script family — was  used exclusively in ancient Arabia, and still exists in the vocalized  alphabets used in Ethiopia. Throughout the Peninsula, literacy was  extremely widespread, not only among the settled peoples but —  exceptionally — also among the nomads, who covered the rocks of the  deserts from southern Syria to Yemen with scores of thousands of  graffiti, many of which give us a vivid picture of their daily life and  emotions.</span></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Scholars and travellers have been  recording Ancient North Arabian inscriptions in what is now Syria,  Jordan and Arabia since the 1858, and by now some 70,000 are known, with  more being discovered every year. However, their finds have been  published in hundreds of books and articles in numerous languages and  many are extremely difficult to track down, even for the specialist.  There are also very few research tools such as up-to-date lists of  names, grammars, dictionaries, etc.</span></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  Online Corpus of the Inscriptions of Ancient North Arabia [OCIANA] aims  to transform our knowledge of the history, languages and cultures of  ancient Arabia. It is doing this by creating a digital corpus of all  known pre-Islamic inscriptions in North and Central Arabia. It provides a  reading of each text both in roman transliteration and in fonts  reproducing the ancient letters, together with a translation in English,  references to earlier readings, commentary where necessary,  bibliography, and all known information about the inscription  (provenance, carving technique, relationship to other texts or to rock  drawings, structures, etc.). Photographs (when available) and facsimiles  of each text will also be shown on each record and will eventually be  downloadable free at publishable resolutions. The Corpus will be easily  updatable as new discoveries are made and will be fully searchable for  names, words, grammatical features and subjects.</span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><ul class="menu"><li class="item-653 current active"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/ociana/index.php">Home</a></span></li><li class="item-652"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/ociana/index.php/staff">Staff</a></span></li><li class="item-654"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/ociana/index.php/contributors">Contributors</a></span></li><li class="item-655"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/ociana/index.php/news-and-events">News and Events</a></span></li><li class="item-656"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/ociana/index.php/bibliography">Bibliography</a></span></li><li class="item-657"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/ociana/index.php/database">Database</a></span></li><li class="item-658"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/ociana/index.php/documentation">Documentation</a></span></li><li class="item-659"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/ociana/index.php/links">Links</a></span></li></ul></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6906133954471367529/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/ociana-online-corpus-of-inscriptions-of.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6906133954471367529"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6906133954471367529"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/11/ociana-online-corpus-of-inscriptions-of.html"
         title="OCIANA: Online Corpus of the Inscriptions of Ancient North Arabia"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
