<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6109470182677382117</id>
   <published>2015-05-01T22:04:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-05-01T22:05:49.028-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="e-Sasanika"/>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="History"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Iran"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Sasanika Newsletter</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">[First posted in AWOL 30 September 2011. Updated 1 May 2015] </span><br /><br /><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/">Sasanika Newsletter</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h2 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-8/">Newsletter 8</a></span></h2><div class="author_name tax"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span>Author: </span></span><div class="authors"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Sasanika Team</span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-8/" title="Newsletter 8"><img alt="Khodadad poster-sm" class="alignleft post-image" height="134" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/Khodadad-poster-sm.jpg" width="134" /></a></span> <table align="left" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="newsletter" style="height: 1000px; width: 700px;"><tbody><tr><td colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="breadcrumbs"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/">Newsletters</a> &gt; Newsletter 8</span></span></td></tr><tr bgcolor="#FFFFFF"><td class="hbox" colspan="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="Header2">May 2015<br />– Sasanika Newsletter No. 8 </span> <a href="https://www.blogger.com/null" id="top" name="top"></a></span></td></tr><tr class="cbox"><td align="left" valign="top" width="146"><div class="Header1"><span style="font-size: x-small;">In This Issue</span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#member">New Team Member</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#projects">Upcoming Projects</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#journal">DABIR</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#lectures">Lectures at UCI</a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#books">Publications</a></span></td><td align="left" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>A Word from the Editor</strong></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>Sasanika</em> is dedicated to the promotion of research and study on the history of the Sasanian dynasty. It is the aim of <em>Sasanika: Late Antique Near East Project</em> to bring to light the importance of the Sasanian civilization in the  context of late antique and world history. Although most of our team  members volunteer their time to maintain the site, the production of  high-quality articles and the support of research projects require  funding. It is through the generosity of Sasanian enthusiasts and those  interested in the history of pre-Islamic Iran that <em>Sasanika </em>thrives. Please consider joining us!</span></td></tr><tr><td align="center" class="nline" colspan="2" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Separator" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2054" height="12" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/line_03.png" width="539" /></span></td></tr><tr class="cbox"><td align="center" height="147" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/Scherwin1.jpg"><img alt="Scherwin" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2358" height="132" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/Scherwin1.jpg" width="132" /></a></span></td><td align="left" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><br /><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#memberLG">New Sasanika Team Members</a></strong><br />Our new member is Shervin Farridnejad, a postdoc research fellow at the  Department of Iranian Studies of University of Göttingen and lecturer of  Zoroastrianism in the Institute of Religious Studies of the Freie  Universität Berlin. He received his PhD in Ancient/Middle Iranian and  Zoroastrian Studies in 2014.</span></td></tr><tr><td align="center" class="nline" colspan="2" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Separator" height="12" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/line_03.png" width="539" /></span></td></tr><tr class="cbox"><td align="center" height="143" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/logo-sasanika.jpg"><img alt="sasanika" class=" size-full wp-image-2156 alignleft" height="133" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/logo-sasanika.jpg" width="133" /></a></span></td><td align="left" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#projectsLG">Sasanika upcoming projects</a></strong><br />Sasanika is about to lunch tow new online projects, which are still in  planning and preparation status. The first, preliminary titled “<em>Corpus Inscriptionum et toreumatum</em><em> Sasanidarum </em>(CITS):  Sasanika Late Antique Iran Inscriptions and Reliefs Databank” aims to  establish a databank for the integration, ensuring public access and  long-term availability of interdisciplinary data to Sasanian epigraphic  and iconographic monuments.</span></td></tr><tr><td align="center" class="nline" colspan="2" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Separator" height="12" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/line_03.png" width="539" /></span></td></tr><tr class="cbox"><td align="left" height="139" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/logo-sasanika.jpg"><img alt="sasanika" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2156" height="133" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/logo-sasanika.jpg" width="133" /></a></span></td><td align="left" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#journalLG">New Lunched e-Journal on Iranian Studies </a></strong><br />The <strong><em>D</em></strong><em>igital </em><strong><em>A</em></strong><em>rchive of </em><strong><em>B</em></strong><em>rief notes &amp; </em><strong><em>I</em></strong><em>ran </em><strong><em>R</em></strong><em>eview</em> (DABIR) is an&nbsp;open access, peer-reviewed online journal published by  the Dr. Samuel M. Jordan Center for Persian Studies and Culture at the  University of California, Irvine. DABIR aims to quickly and efficiently  publish brief notes and reviews relating to the pre-modern world in  contact with Iran and Persianate cultures.</span></td></tr><tr><td align="center" class="nline" colspan="2" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Separator" height="12" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/line_03.png" width="539" /></span></td></tr><tr class="cbox"><td align="left" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/Khodadad-poster-sm.jpg"><img alt="Khodadad poster-sm" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2356" height="134" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/Khodadad-poster-sm.jpg" width="134" /></a></span></td><td align="left" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#lecturesLG">Lectures at the Jordan Center for Persian Studies </a></strong><br />“From Behistun to Bamiyan: Meetings Between Ancient Empires” by Jenny  Rose; “Memories of Decline: The Islamic Conquests of Sasanian Iran and  Modern Historiography” by Khodadad Rezakhani; “The Creation and  Destruction of the Iranian Past and the Topography of Power of the  Sasanian Empire” by Matthew P. Canepa</span></td></tr><tr><td align="center" class="nline" colspan="2" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Separator" height="12" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/line_03.png" width="539" /></span></td></tr><tr class="cbox"><td align="left" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/logo-sasanika.jpg"><img alt="sasanika" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2156" height="133" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/logo-sasanika.jpg" width="133" /></a></span></td><td align="left" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><br /><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#booksLG">Recent Books &amp; Journals on the Sasanians &amp; Related Topics </a></strong><br />There are a number of recent publications, including Persian Martyr Acts  in Syriac, the architectural and figurative culture of Sasanian Iran,  the 22<sup>th</sup> volume of the series Res Orientales, a number of  edited volumes and monographs in areas related to the study of the  Sasanian period. This section provides a summary and publication details  of these works.</span></td></tr><tr><td align="center" class="nline" colspan="2" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Separator" height="12" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/line_03.png" width="539" /></span></td></tr><tr class="cbox"><td align="left" colspan="2" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>New Sasanika Team Members</strong></span><br />Our new member is Shervin Farridnejad, a postdoc research fellow at the  Department of Iranian Studies of University of Göttingen and lecturer of  Zoroastrianism in the Institute of Religious Studies of the Freie  Universität Berlin. He received his PhD in Ancient/Middle Iranian and  Zoroastrian Studies in 2014. In his dissertation „The language of  images: A study on iconographic exegesis of the anthropomorphic divine  images in Zoroastrianism” (forthcoming in Iranica GOF), he investigates  the perception, significance and representation of Zoroastrian  anthropomorphic deities in ancient Iranian religious imagery in light of  both material and written sources. He applies an interdisciplinary  method, based on both image and text exegesis to (re)evaluate the  ancient Iranian and Zoroastrian visual world.Shervin Farridnejad is  mainly working on the pre-Islamic Iranian and Zoroastrian art,  iconography and History as well as Zoroastrian rituals and ritual  literature. He will also be in charge of two upcoming projects for  Sasanika, namely the <em>tabulāria sasanidarum</em>: Sasanika Late  Antique Iran Project’s Databank: A predominantly databank of scholarly  projects related to Late Antique Iran and <em>Corpus Inscriptionum et toreumatum</em><em> Sasanidarum</em>:  Sasanika Late Antique Iran Inscriptions and Reliefs Databank (for more  information see Sasanika upcoming projects in this Newsletter).</span><div align="right"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#top">Back to top</a></span></div></td></tr><tr><td align="center" class="nline" colspan="2" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Separator" height="12" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/line_03.png" width="539" /></span></td></tr><tr class="cbox"><td align="left" colspan="2" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Sasanika upcoming projects</strong></span><br />Sasanika is about to lunch tow new online projects, which are still in  planning and preparation status. The first, preliminary titled “<em>Corpus Inscriptionum et toreumatum</em><em> Sasanidarum </em>(CITS):  Sasanika Late Antique Iran Inscriptions and Reliefs Databank” aims to  establish a databank for the integration, ensuring public access and  long-term availability of interdisciplinary data to Sasanian epigraphic  and iconographic monuments. A major part of the project is dedicated to  build a database of Sasanian rock reliefs. In the first phase of this  project, it will allocate all scholars and students with both high  quality, free accessible images of all known Sasanian reliefs and  inscriptions, as well as line drawings, basic information and a detailed  “pre-iconographic description”. In the following phases, each entry  will round out with extensive bibliographical references to scholarly  works related to each relief. Where applicable, also will added other  historical and iconographical information. A rich account of recently  taken high-quality photos will show the current status of the reliefs  and inscriptions and make it possible to have an exact look for further  investigations. The databank provides also tools for thematic,  geographical etc. searching in reliefs.The second project is preliminary  titles “<em>tabulāria sasanidarum</em>: Sasanika Late Antique Iran  Project’s Databank. A predominantly databank of scholarly projects  related to Late Antique Iran”. This predominantly databank aims to list  all those scholarly running projects related directly or indirectly to  Late Antique Iran studies as well as Sasanian Era. It shall informs all  scholars and students about current works in progress in all related  fields of history, religious studies, philology, art history etc. This  will help scholars and students to be aware of similar, related,  connected or parallel research projects in order to accomplish a good  network.The Sasanika team invites all scholars, researches,  post-doctorates, PhD, graduate and undergraduate Students to send us a  brief description of their running research projects, dissertations or  MA thesis related to these topics.</span><div align="right"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;<a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#top">Back to top</a></span></div></td></tr><tr><td align="center" class="nline" colspan="2" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Separator" height="12" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/line_03.png" width="539" /></span></td></tr><tr class="cbox"><td align="left" colspan="2" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">New Lunched e-Journal on Iranian Studies</span> </strong><br />The <strong><em>D</em></strong><em>igital </em><strong><em>A</em></strong><em>rchive of </em><strong><em>B</em></strong><em>rief notes &amp; </em><strong><em>I</em></strong><em>ran </em><strong><em>R</em></strong><em>eview</em> (DABIR) is an&nbsp;open access, peer-reviewed online journal published by  the Dr. Samuel M. Jordan Center for Persian Studies and Culture at the  University of California, Irvine. DABIR aims to quickly and efficiently  publish brief notes and reviews relating to the pre-modern world in  contact with Iran and Persianate cultures. The journal accepts  submissions on art history, archaeology, history, linguistics,  literature, manuscript studies, numismatics, philology and religion,  from Jaxartes to the Mediterranean and from the Sumerian period through  to and including the Safavid era (3500 BCE-1500 CE). Work dealing with  later periods can be considered on request. Above all DABIR aims to  provide a venue for scholars to rapidly publish their shorter notes and  observations, which are usually missed by other journals.The editorial  members of DABIR are Parsa Daneshmand (Oxford University), Touraj  Daryaee (UC Irvine), Arash Zeini (University of St Andrews) and Shervin  Farridnejad (University of Berlin), as Book Review Editor. The advisory  board of DABIR consists of 24 international scholars of different  disciplines related to Iranian and Persianate studies, who will  undertake the journal’s double-blind peer-review process. The inaugural  issue is announced to be published in the spring of 2015.</span><div align="right"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#top">Back to top</a></span></div></td></tr><tr><td align="center" class="nline" colspan="2" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Separator" height="12" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/line_03.png" width="539" /></span></td></tr><tr class="cbox"><td align="left" colspan="2" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Lectures </strong><strong>at the Jordan Center for Persian Studies</strong></span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><br />“From Behistun to Bamiyan: Meetings Between Ancient Empires by Jenny Rose</span>On  Thursday, April 2, 2015, Dr. Jenny Rose (Claremont Graduate University)  gave a talk titled “From Behistun to Bamiyan: Meetings Between Ancient  Empires” in Dr. Samuel M. Jordan Center for Persian Studies at UC  Irvine. In her illustrated presentation Rose has focused on the  interaction between the three successive Iranian world empires and  contemporary regimes in India. At Behistun in northwestern Iran, a  remarkable rock-cut inscription proclaims that the Achaemenid king  Darius I came to the throne ‘with the aid of Ahura Mazda.’ The same  relief mentions three subject countries to the east of Iran, which later  formed part of the Mauryan Empire. Beginning with depictions of various  tribute-bearers from India at the Ancient Persian capital of  Persepolis, Dr. Rose has traceed the interplay of Iranian  (‘Zoroastrian’) and Indian (‘Hindu’ and Buddhist) concepts and  iconographies through Ashoka Maurya’s Arameo-Iranian edicts, the coinage  of Indo-Parthian and Kushan rulers in Gandhara, to the Sasanian period,  when Zoroastrian merchants from Iran established trading posts on the  northwest coast of India, and those from Sogdiana inscribed graffiti  alongside Indian Hindus and Buddhists on the Karakorum highway.<span style="text-decoration: underline;">“Memories of Decline: The Islamic Conquests of Sasanian Iran and Modern Historiography”by Khodadad Rezakhani</span>On Nov. 20<sup>th</sup>,  Dr. Khodadad Rezakhani (Freie Universität Berlin) gave a talk titled:  “Memories of Decline: The Islamic Conquests of Sasanian Iran and Modern  Historiography” in Dr. Samuel M. Jordan Center for Persian Studies at UC  Irvine. He addressed in his lecture the questions of the reasons for  the collapse of the Sasanian Empire as well as how have modern  historians approached this topic in the twentieth century.<a href="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/Khodadad-poster.jpg"><img alt="Khodadad poster" class=" size-medium wp-image-2355 aligncenter" height="300" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/Khodadad-poster-210x300.jpg" width="210" /></a><span style="text-decoration: underline;">“The Creation and Destruction of the Iranian Past and the Topography of Power of the Sasanian Empire” by Matthew P. Canepa</span>On  April 25th gave Dr. Matthew P. Canepa (University of Minnesota) a  lecture titled “The Creation and Destruction of the Iranian Past and the  Topography of Power of the Sasanian Empire” in Dr. Samuel M. Jordan  Center for Persian Studies at UC Irvine.Canepa has been recently named a  fellow of the John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation for 2015-16 in  support of a multi-volume research project on the development of the  visual cultures and spatial environments of power in Persia and the  ancient Iranian world. The Guggenheim fellowship will allow him to  finish his second book, entitled The Iranian Expanse, which explores the  interrelation and transformation of ancient Iranian landscapes,  architecture and identities. During the fellowship period he also plans  to continue work on a long-term project, “Royal Glory, Divine Fortune,”  which examines the contested image of Iranian sovereignty between  Alexander and Islam.</span><div align="right"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#top">Back to top</a></span></div></td></tr><tr><td align="center" class="nline" colspan="2" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Separator" height="12" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/line_03.png" width="539" /></span></td></tr><tr class="cbox"><td align="left" colspan="2" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Recent Books &amp; Journals on the Sasanians &amp; Related Topics </span></strong>Persian Martyr Acts in Syriac: Text and Translation<br />Persian Martyr Acts in Syriac is a series of Syriac martyrological texts  composed from the fourth century into the Islamic period. They detail  the martyrdom of a diversity of Christians at the hands of Sasanian  kings, bureaucrats, and priests. These documents vary from purely  mythological accounts to descriptions of actual events with a clear  historical basis, however distorted by the hagiographer’s hand. Two new  volumes are now released in this series:<strong>Smith, Kyle. 2015. <em>The Martyrdom and History of Blessed Simeon bar Sabba’e</em>. (Persian Martyr Acts in Syriac: Text and Translation 3). Gorgias Press. ISBN 978-1-4632-0245-3. 289 pp. $63.80.</strong>Around  the year 339 CE, Simeon bar Sabbae (the bishop of Seleucia-Ctesiphon on  the Tigris) was killed by the Persian king Shapur II. Simeon was  arrested for refusing to collect taxes from his flock, and he was  beheaded for disobeying the king’s order to worship the sun. The bishop  of Seleucia-Ctesiphon was no minor figure. In fact, Simeon’s martyr acts  proclaim that he was the leader of the Christians of Persia and the  protomartyr of Shapur’s forty-year persecution. Curiously, however, two  very different versions of Simeon’s death exist. Each is presented here  with an accompanying translation and notes.The shorter and earlier  version of Simeon’s death, the Martyrdom, compares the Christians of  Persia to the Maccabees and equates Simeon with the great Jewish warrior  Judah the Maccabee. The much longer and later version, the History,  takes a different approach. Omitting all references to the Maccabees,  the History compares the Christians of the East (Persia) to the  persecuted Christians of the West (the Roman Empire) prior to  Constantine.Simeon’s Martyrdom and History are fundamental sources for  chronicling the history of Christianity in Sasanian Persia. Together,  these texts testify to the centrality of martyrdom literature in late  ancient Syriac Christianity, and they show how Persian Christians forged  their own political and religious identities amidst the ongoing  Christianization of the Roman Empire.<strong>Brock, Sebastian. <em>The Martyrs of Mount Ber’ain</em> (Persian Martyr Acts in Syriac: Text and Translation 4). Gorgias Press. ISBN 978-1-4632-0421-1. $51.16.</strong>The  Martyrs of Mount Ber’ain is the poignant tale of an Iranian nobleman’s  three children, Adarparwa, Mihrnarse, and Mahdukht, who embrace  Christianity after the youngest brother’s near-death vision of God. This  decision estranges them from their disbelieving father and ultimately  results in death at the hands of King Shapur II. Gabriel “the Cow,”  abbot of the monastery of Beth ‘Abe, composed the account of these  events in the middle of the seventh century.The Martyrs of Mount Ber’ain  provides important evidence for enduring concerns of Christian  self-definition in the framework of the Sasanian Empire, especially as  represented by the Zoroastrian priesthood. The three children,  Adarparwa, Mihrnarse, and Mahdukht, work to forget their education by  the Magi, with whom they soon find themselves engaged in battle; and yet  some key features of the narrative, especially Mihrnarse’s vision,  reflect shared idioms between Christians and their Zoroastrian rivals.  This rivalry was committed to writing and commemorated even after the  Arab conquest, and one of these three sibling-martyrs, the sister  Sultana Mahdukht, is still memorialized in both Iraq and the United  States.<strong>Callieri, Pierfrancesco. 2015. Cahiers de Studia Iranica, 50. Peeters Publishers. ISBN: 978-2-910640-36-1. 298 pp. €50,00.</strong><strong>&nbsp;</strong>This  volume contains the text of the five “Ehsan and Latifeh Yarshater  Distinguished Lectures on Iranian Studies”, organized by the Unité Mixte  de Recherche 7528 “Mondes iranien et indien”, and delivered in 2014 at  the College de France in Paris. The aim of this book is to take stock of  the architectural and figurative culture of Sasanian Iran on the basis  of a new comprehensive evaluation of the varied range of architectural  and artistic evidence known to us, and in the light of the recent  discoveries published in Iran over the last few years. Without any  pretence of being exhaustive, the idea is to bring more light to bear on  the utilisation of built-up areas, forms of expression and visual  communication, and the mechanisms involved in artisanal production. Two  chapters are dedicated to the architecture, a field in which we are far  from having arrived at a general consensus, while another chapter deals  with a category of artistic production closely linked to the  architecture, namely stucco work. The other two chapters look into the  technical-stylistic aspects of types of production so far studied mainly  from the iconographic point of view: the rock reliefs and the seals.<strong>Gyselen, Rika (ed.) 2014. <em>Documents, argenterie et monnaies de tradition Sassanide</em>. Res Orientales, 22. ISBN 978-2-9521376-6-9. 189 pp. €70,00.</strong></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The 22<sup>th</sup> volume of the series Res Orientales consists of  the following articles: Maryse Blet-Lemarquand &amp; Rika Gyselen, «Sur  la composition élémentaire de quelques monnaies de cuivre  arabo-sassanides»; Philippe Gignoux, «Une archive post-sassanide du  Tabaristan (II)»; Rika Gyselen, «Inscriptions en moyen-perse sur la  vaisselle d’argent sassanide: quelques nouvelles données»; Dieter Weber,  «Arabic Activities Reflected in the Documents of the “Pahlavi Archive”  (Late 7th and Early 8th Centuries)».</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Raffaelli, Enrico. 2014. The <em>Sih-Rozag</em> in Zoroastrianism: A textual and historico-religious analysis. Routledge. ISBN: 978-0-415-81232-0. 368 pp. $160.00.</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Focusing on the Avestan and Pahlavi versions of the <em>Sih-rozag</em>,  a text worshipping Zoroastrian divine entities, this book explores the  spiritual principles and physical realities associated with them.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Introducing the book is an overview of the structural, linguistic and historico-religious elements of the Avestan <em>Sih-rozag</em>.  This overview, as well as reconstructing its approximate chronology,  helps in understanding the original ritual function of the text and its  relationship to the other Avestan texts.The book then studies the  translation of the text in the Middle Persian language, Pahlavi, which  was produced several centuries after its initial composition, when  Avestan was no longer understood by the majority of the Zoroastrian  community.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Addressing the lacuna in literature examining an erstwhile neglected Zoroastrian text, The <em>Sih-Rozag</em> in Zoroastrianism includes a detailed commentary and an English  translation of both the Avestan and Pahlavi version of the Sih-rozag and  will be of interest to researchers and scholars of Iranian Studies,  Religion, and History.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Moazami, Mahnaz. Wrestling with the Demons of the Pahlavi  Widēwdād. 2014. Transcription, Translation, and Commentary. Iran Studies  9. Brill. ISBN: 9789004269217. 602 pp. €158,00.</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Pahlavi <em>Widēwdād</em> (<em>Vidēvdād</em>), The Law (Serving to Keep) Demons Away, a fifth-century Middle Persian commentary on the Avestan <em>Widēvdād</em>,  describes rules and regulations that serve to prevent pollution caused  by dead matter, menstrual discharges, and other agents. It recognizes  the perpetual presence of the demons, the forces of the Evil Spirit  –forces that should be fought through law-abiding conduct. In spite of  its formidable textual problems, the commentary provides an invaluable  quarry for the rules of the Zoroastrian community through its citation  of regulations for the conduct of its members. Many topics are covered,  from jurisprudence to penalties, procedures for dealing with pollution,  purification, and arrangements for funerals. Viewed together, they  provide the reader with an exquisite interlace of a community’s  concerns.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Secunda, Shai. 2013. <em>The Iranian Talmud: Reading the Bavli in Its Sasanian Context</em>. University of Pennsylvania Press. ISBN 978-0-8122-4570-7. 272 pp. $55.00.</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">“Shai Secunda not only persuades his readers of the need for  contextual study of the Bavli but also facilitates such study by  educating them about the religious and ethnic communities of the  Sasanian empire, the forms of literary and nonliterary evidence  available, and appropriate methodological and theoretical approaches to  the comparative study of Talmudic and Middle Persian literature. The  Iranian Talmud will be the first sustained attempt both to demystify the  project of Irano-Talmudic research and to provide a basic orientation  to it.”—Christine Hayes, Yale University</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Although the Babylonian Talmud, or Bavli, has been a text central and  vital to the Jewish canon since the Middle Ages, the context in which  it was produced has been poorly understood. Delving deep into Sasanian  material culture and literary remains, Shai Secunda pieces together the  dynamic world of late antique Iran, providing an unprecedented and  accessible overview of the world that shaped the Bavli.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Secunda unites the fields of Talmudic scholarship with Old Iranian  studies to enable a fresh look at the heterogeneous religious and ethnic  communities of pre-Islamic Iran. He analyzes the intercultural dynamics  between the Jews and their Persian Zoroastrian neighbors, exploring the  complex processes and modes of discourse through which these groups  came into contact and considering the ways in which rabbis and  Zoroastrian priests perceived one another. Placing the Bavli and  examples of Middle Persian literature side by side, the Zoroastrian  traces in the former and the discursive and Talmudic qualities of the  latter become evident. The Iranian Talmud introduces a substantial and  essential shift in the field, setting the stage for further  Irano-Talmudic research.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Shayegan, M. Rahim. 2012. <em>Aspects of History and Epic in Ancient Iran: From Gaumāta to Wahnām</em>. Hellenic Studies Series 52. Center for Hellenic Studies – Harvard University Press. ISBN 9780674065888. 244 pp. $24.95.</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>Aspects of History and Epic in Ancient Iran</em> focuses on the  content of one of the most important inscriptions of the Ancient Near  East: the Bisotun inscription of the Achaemenid king Darius I (6th  century BCE), which in essence reports on a suspicious fratricide and  subsequent coup d’état. Moreover, the study shows how the inscription’s  narrative would decisively influence the Iranian epic, epigraphic, and  historiographical traditions well into the Sasanian and early Islamic  periods.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Intriguingly, our assessment of the impact of the Bisotun narrative  on later literary traditions—in particular, the inscription of the  Sasanian king Narseh at Paikuli (3rd–4th centuries CE)—necessarily  relies on the reception of the oral rendition of the Bisotun story  captured by Greek historians. As Rahim Shayegan argues, this oral  tradition had an immeasurable impact upon the historiographical writings  and epic compositions of later Iranian empires. It would have otherwise  remained unknown to modern scholars, had it not been partially  preserved and recorded by Hellanicus of Lesbos, Herodotus, Ctesias, and  other Greek authors. The elucidation of Bisotun’s thematic composition  therefore not only allows us to solve an ancient murder but also to  reevaluate pre-Thucydidean Greek historiography as one of the most  important repositories of Iranian epic themes.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The purpose of the study is twofold. In the first part, it examines  the content of one the most important inscriptions of the Ancient Near  East: the Bisotun inscription of the Achaemenid king Darius I (6th  century BCE), which in essence reports on a suspicious fratricide and  subsequent coup-d’état. The study shows how the inscription’s narrative  would decisively influence the Iranian epic, epigraphic, and  historiographical traditions well into the Sasanian and early Islamic  periods. Intriguingly, the author’s assessment of the impact of the  Bisotun narrative on later literary traditions—in particular, on the  inscription of the Sasanian king Narseh at Paikuli (3rd–4th centuries  CE)—relies on the reception of the oral rendition of the Bisotun story  captured by Greek historians.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">In the second part of the study, Shayegan investigates how this  originally oral narrative, preserved by Herodotus and other Greek and  Latin authors, could impact the “historiographical” writings and epic  compositions of later Iranian empires, such as the Sasanians, over nine  centuries later. Not only do Sasanian inscriptions, especially the  inscription of king Narseh at Paikuli, make use of the same story  pattern that one encounters in the accounts of Greek and Latin authors  describing Bardiya’s murder, especially with regard to the theme of two  evil usurpers (called here Warahrān and Wahnām), but also the epic  tradition, as reflected in the “Book of the Kings” (Šāhnāme), and the  medieval romances called the “Book of Darius” (Dārābnāme), and “Samak,  the ʿayyār” (Samak-e ʿAyyār) shows that the story of Bardiya’s murder  had penetrated epic composition and had become part of the epic canon.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Finally, the study seeks to demonstrate that in Ancient, Late  Antique, and Medieval Iran the interaction between epic and  historiographical practices were varied and intricate. “Historical  records” could be generated in conformity with the ideals of epic, or  composed by being cast into the mold of the oral epic tradition, thereby  losing their individual “historical” tenor to conform to the normative  frame of the epic. An example in case is the (Indo)-Iranian epic theme  of the Twins that decisively shaped the oral composition of the murder  story of Bardiya and Gaumāta. However, the prestige of the oral  rendition of the Bisotun must have been such that the theme of the two  evil brothers was projected back (under new guise) into the oral epic  tradition and replaced the older Iranian theme of the Twins, thus  re-juvenating the thematic inventory of the epic tradition.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Geoffrey Herman (Ed.). 2014. Jews, Christians and  Zoroastrians. Judaism in Context 17. Gorgias Press. ISBN  978-1-4632-0250-7. 325 pp. $95.00 </strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Sasanian Empire was home to many religious communities. It was  also a place of meeting and transformation. It was where old religions  met more recent arrivals, and where both new and old were transformed as  a result of this contact. While some religious communities shared more  than others, and this for historical or geographical reasons, some form  of contact and exchange with Zoroastrianism, the religion of the ruling  dynasty and of many of the inhabitants of the empire was undoubtedly the  rule for all.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The studies in this volume explore the dynamics between these  communities within the broad Sasanian religious and cultural context and  encompass a diverse array of topics concerning, in particular, Jews,  Christians, and Manichaeans. Some include the Roman East in their  deliberations. Most, however, deal with the interaction of one or other  Sasanian religious community with Zoroastrianism.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Desmond Durkin-Meisterernst. 2014. Grammatik des  Westmitteliranischen (Parthisch und Mittelpersisch). Sitzungsberichte  der phil.-hist. Klasse 850. Veröffentlichungen zur Iranistik 73.  Grammatica Iranica, Band 1. Verlag der Österreichischen Akademie der  Wissenschaften. ISBN 978-3-7001-7556-8. 602 pp. € 98,00.</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Following on a number of individual descriptions of the phonology and  morphology of the languages Middle Persian and Parthian and an attempt  to place aspects of the syntax of both languages side-by-side, the  Grammatik des Westmitteliranischen (Parthisch und Mittelpersisch)  [Grammar of Western Middle Iranian (Parthian and Middle Persian)] is the  first attempt to describe all areas of the two languages Middle Persian  and Parthian together in a meaningful and balanced way. After an  overview of the extant material, the scripts used for these languages  are described. Chapters on phonology, morphology and syntax follow. The  common history of these neighbouring and closely related languages  during about a thousand years means that it is very useful to deal with  them together, because in the epigraphical testimonies of the 3rd  century and in the Manichaean material from Turfan on the Silk Road (9th  and 10th-century copies of originals from the 3rd up to the 7th  century) these languages are attested together and with interaction.  These source groups offer an excellent and very reliable basis for the  description. Literary, mostly Zoroastrian, Middle Persian from the  Sasanian Empire and era was also consulted; but not the “scholastic”  Zoroastrian literature of the 9th century which follows its own rules.  The depiction is well-organized, the quotations are clearly marked for  language. In the extensive chapter on syntax the quotations are  presented in a clear transcription; the originals (in transliteration)  are given in a separate listing and are made accessible by an index.  Scholars and students of Iranian linguistic, cultural and religious  history, Manichaeologists, those interested in Central Asia and  Indoeuropeanists will consult this book.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Sarah Bowen Savant. 2013. The New Muslims of Post-Conquest  Iran. Tradition, Memory, and Conversion. Cambridge Studies in Islamic  Civilization. Cambridge University Press. isbn: 9781107014084. 294 pp.  $90.00.</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">How do converts to a religion come to feel an attachment to it? The  New Muslims of Post-Conquest Iran answers this important question for  Iran by focusing on the role of memory and its revision and erasure in  the ninth to eleventh centuries. During this period, the descendants of  the Persian imperial, religious, and historiographical traditions not  only wrote themselves into starkly different early Arabic and Islamic  accounts of the past but also systematically suppressed much knowledge  about pre-Islamic history. The result was both a new “Persian” ethnic  identity and the pairing of Islam with other loyalties and affiliations,  including family, locale, and sect. This pioneering study examines  revisions to memory in a wide range of cases, from Iran’s imperial and  administrative heritage to the Prophet Muhammad’s stalwart Persian  companion, Salman al-Farisi, and to memory of Iranian scholars,  soldiers, and rulers in the mid-seventh century. Through these  renegotiations, Iranians developed a sense of Islam as an authentically  Iranian religion, as they simultaneously shaped the broader  historiographic tradition in Arabic and Persian.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Domenico Agostini. 2013. Ayādgār ī Jāmāspīg, un texte  eschatologique zoroastrien. BIBLICAL – Biblica et orientalia. Gregorian  &amp; Biblical Press. ISBN 9788876533532. 542 pp. €60.00. </strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Ayādgār ī Jāmāspīg (“the memorial of Jamasp”) is one of the  important Zoroastrian texts. Probably It was composed as a veritable  encyclopedia for laymen. Various manuscript traditions of this text are  available, namely Pahlavi, Pāzand and Parsi. Focusing on the Avestan and  Pahlavi versions of the Sih-rozag, a text worshipping Zoroastrian  divine entities, Agostini made a new and comprehensive philological  edition of this work. His edition is enriched with a  historical-religious commentary dealing with the most challenging and  interesting topics form the narrative and explores the spiritual  principles and physical realities associated with them.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Michiel de Vaan; Javier Martínez García. 2014. Introduction  to Avestan. Brill Introductions to Indo-European Languages, Vol. 1.  Brill. ISBN 9789004258099. 160 pp. €37,00.</strong></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">This <em>Introduction to Avestan</em> provides a concise grammar of  the Avestan language, the language of the followers of the Iranian  prophet Zarathustra. The grammar focuses on spelling, phonology and  morphology, but also includes a chapter on syntax. Abundant information  on the historical development of the language is included, which renders  the grammar very useful for students of Indo-Iranian and Indo-European.  Also, a small number of selected Avestan texts is added, with a  complete glossary, so that students can practise reading Avestan.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Robert G. Hoyland. 2015. In God’s Path. The Arab Conquests and the Creation of an Islamic Empire. Oxford University Press. ISBN </strong><strong>978-0-19-991636-8. 320 pp. £18.99.</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">In just over a hundred years—from the death of Muhammad in 632 to the  beginning of the Abbasid Caliphate in 750—the followers of the Prophet  swept across the whole of the Middle East, North Africa, and Spain.  Their armies threatened states as far afield as the Franks in Western  Europe and the Tang Empire in China. The conquered territory was larger  than the Roman Empire at its greatest expansion, and it was claimed for  the Arabs in roughly half the time. How this collection of Arabian  tribes was able to engulf so many empires, states, and armies in such a  short period of time is a question that has perplexed historians for  centuries. Most recent popular accounts have been based almost solely on  the early Muslim sources, which were composed centuries later for the  purpose of demonstrating that God had chosen the Arabs as his vehicle  for spreading Islam throughout the world.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">In this ground-breaking new history, distinguished Middle East expert  Robert G. Hoyland assimilates not only the rich biographical and  geographical information of the early Muslim sources but also the many  non-Arabic sources, contemporaneous or near-contemporaneous with the  conquests. The story of the conquests traditionally begins with the  revelation of Islam to Muhammad. In God’s Path, however, begins with a  broad picture of the Late Antique world prior to the Prophet’s arrival, a  world dominated by the two superpowers of Byzantium and Sasanian  Persia, “the two eyes of the world.” In between these empires, in  western (Saudi) Arabia, emerged a distinct Arab identity, which helped  weld its members into a formidable fighting force. The Arabs are the  principal actors in this drama yet, as Hoyland shows, the peoples along  the edges of Byzantium and Persia—the Khazars, Bulgars, Avars, and  Turks—also played important roles in the remaking of the old world  order. The new faith propagated by Muhammad and his successors made it  possible for many of the conquered peoples to join the Arabs in creating  the first Islamic Empire.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Ichaporia, Pallan; Malandra, William W. 2013. The Pahlavi  Yasna of the Gathas and Yasna Haptanhaiti. Reichert Verlag. ISBN:  9783895009686. 264 pp. €78,00. </strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">As the title suggests the book is a study of the Pahlavi Yasna, a  Middle Persian (Pahlavi) gloss on the liturgical text, the Yasna. The  study is restricted to the G?th?s or Hymns of Zarathustra (Zoroaster)  and to the Yasna Hapta?h?iti, a prose text composed in the same dialect  of Avestan. There are three main sections: Introduction, The Text, and  Glossary. In addition there are two Appenices: I Parallel Text of the  Avestan and Pahalvi Gloss; II The aš?m voh? and its Variants in the  D?nkart. The Introduction is a text-critical study of the Pahlavi Yasna  which addresses the main issues of the nature of the text, its  authorship and dating, and its relationship to parallels in the D?nkard.  In the presentation of the text, the position is taken that the  fundamental text is a nearly word-by-word gloss on the original Avestan.  That is, it is not a translation as we might understand the term.  Interspersed in the gloss are miscellaneous comments inserted by later  hands to illuminate certain words and passages. Appendix I is provided  to portray how the glosses line up with the Avestan, ignoring the later  comments. The text itself is based on the 1946 critical edition of B. N.  Dhabhar given in the Pahlavi script and to which we have provided many  improvements. In footnotes we have cited all the parallel passages from  the D?nkard. These reveal that there were exegetical traditions other  than the official Pahlavi Yasna. Although Dhabhar’s edition included a  glossary, it is not up to the philological standards of current  scholarship. There is deliberately no translation into English, as a  running gloss of this sort does not lend itself to a coherent  translation.<br />The contribution to the fields of Middle Persian and Zoroastrian studies  is really threefold: 1) to establish a reliable text in Roman  transliteration; 2) to provide an extensive glossary of all lexical  items; 3) to contribute to an understanding of the nature and formation  of the text. The intended readership is primarily scholars and students  who have some acquaintance with Pahlavi and have an interest in the  history of Zoroastrianism.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Utas, Bo. Editor: Jahani, Carina; Fallahzadeh, Mehrdad. 2013.  From Old to New Persian. Collected Essays. Reichert Verlag. ISBN:  9783895009709. 304 pp. € 69,00. </strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">In a long series of essays, written during almost half a century, Bo  Utas analyses the development of West Iranian languages, particularly  Old, Middle, and New Persian, from various perspectives. The focus is  placed on the transition from Middle to New Persian and the final essays  (hitherto partly unpublished) especially elucidate this process in the  light of an interaction between oral and written language.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Stephen H. Rapp Jr. 2014. The Sasanian World through Georgian  Eyes. Caucasia and the Iranian Commonwealth in Late Antique Georgian  Literature. Ashgate. ISBN 9781472425522. 540 pp. £90.00.</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Georgian literary sources for Late Antiquity are commonly held to be  later productions devoid of historical value. As a result, scholarship  outside the Republic of Georgia has privileged Graeco-Roman and even  Armenian narratives. However, when investigated within the dual contexts  of a regional literary canon and the active participation of Caucasia’s  diverse peoples in the Iranian Commonwealth, early Georgian texts  emerge as a rich repository of late antique attitudes and outlooks.  Georgian hagiographical and historiographical compositions open a unique  window onto a northern part of the Sasanian world that, while sharing  striking affinities with the Iranian heartland, was home to vibrant,  cosmopolitan cultures that developed along their own trajectories.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">In these sources, precise and accurate information about the core of  the Sasanian Empire-and before it, Parthia and Achaemenid Persia-is  sparse; yet the thorough structuring of wider Caucasian society along  Iranian and especially hybrid Iranic lines is altogether evident.  Scrutiny of these texts reveals, inter alia, that the Old Georgian  language is saturated with words drawn from Parthian and Middle Persian,  a trait shared with Classical Armenian; that Caucasian society, like  its Iranian counterpart, was dominated by powerful aristocratic houses,  many of whose origins can be traced to Iran itself; and that the  conception of kingship in the eastern Georgian realm of K’art’li  (Iberia), even centuries after the royal family’s Christianisation in  the 320s and 330s, was closely aligned with Arsacid and especially  Sasanian models.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">There is also a literary dimension to the Irano-Caucasian nexus,  aspects of which this volume exposes for the first time. The oldest  surviving specimens of Georgian historiography exhibit intriguing  parallels to the lost Sasanian Xwadāy-nāmag, The Book of Kings, one of  the precursors to Ferdowsī’s Shāhnāma. As tangible products of the dense  cross-cultural web drawing the region together, early Georgian  narratives sharpen our understanding of the diversity of the Iranian  Commonwealth and demonstrate the persistence of Iranian and Iranic modes  well into the medieval epoch.</span><br /> <div align="right"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://sasanika.org/e-categories/newsletters/#top">Back to top</a></span></div></td></tr><tr><td align="center" class="nline" colspan="2" valign="middle"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Separator" height="12" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/line_03.png" width="539" /></span></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><br /><blockquote><div class="hfeed" id="content"><div class="post-2104 esasanika type-esasanika status-publish format-standard hentry entry"><h2 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-7-2/" rel="bookmark" title="Newsletter 7 – February 2014">Newsletter 7 – February 2014</a></span></h2><div class="author_name tax"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Author: </span><br /><div class="authors"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Sasanika Team</span></div></div><div class="entry-content"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-7-2/" title="Newsletter 7 – February 2014"><img alt="sasanika" class="alignleft post-image" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/logo-sasanika.jpg" height="133" width="133" /></a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;Newsletters  &gt; Newsletter 7   &nbsp;February 2014 - Sasanika Newsletter No. 7     In This Issue New &amp; Improved Sasanika  New Sasanika Team Members Sasanika Lectures at UCI New Publications A Word from the Editor Sasanika is dedicated to the promotion of research and study on the  history of the Sasanian dynasty. It is the aim of Sasanika: Late Antique  Near East Project to bring to light the importance of the Sasanian  civilization in the context of late antique and world history. Although  most of our team members volunteer their time to maintain the site, the  production of high-quality articles and the support of research projects  require funding. We are planning major changes in the website and  inclusion of further information and research about the Sasanian Empire.  It is through the generosity of Sasanian enthusiasts and those  interested in the history of pre-Islamic Iran that Sasanika thrives.  Please consider joining us!      &nbsp; New &amp; Improved Sasanika It is  ... <a class="more-link" href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-7-2/">READ MORE</a></span></div></div><div class="post-2057 esasanika type-esasanika status-publish format-standard hentry entry"><h2 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-6-june-2012-2/" rel="bookmark" title="Newsletter 6 – June 2012">Newsletter 6 – June 2012</a></span></h2><div class="author_name tax"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Author: </span><br /><div class="authors"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Sasanika Team</span></div></div><div class="entry-content"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-6-june-2012-2/" title="Newsletter 6 – June 2012"><img alt="DSCF1663-sm" class="alignleft post-image" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/DSCF1663-sm1.jpg" height="133" width="133" /></a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Newsletters  &gt; Newsletter 6    June 2012 - Sasanika Newsletter No. 6      In This Issue Religion, Cosmology &amp; Empire  Late Antique Iran Lecture New Publications e-Sasanika Series Obituary A Word from the Editor Sasanika is dedicated to the promotion of research and study on the  history of the Sasanian dynasty. It is the aim of Sasanika: Late Antique  Near East Project to bring to light the importance of the Sasanian  civilization in the context of late antique and world history. Although  most of our team members volunteer their time to maintain the site, the  production of high-quality articles and the support of research projects  require funding. We are planning major changes in the website and  inclusion of further information and research about the Sasanian Empire.  It is through the generosity of Sasanian enthusiasts and those  interested in the history of pre-Islamic Iran that Sasanika thrives.  Please consider joining us!       Religion, Cosmology and Empire  ... <a class="more-link" href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-6-june-2012-2/">READ MORE</a></span></div></div><div class="post-2090 esasanika type-esasanika status-publish format-standard hentry entry"><h2 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-5-september-2011-4/" rel="bookmark" title="Newsletter 5 – September 2011">Newsletter 5 – September 2011</a></span></h2><div class="author_name tax"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Author: </span><br /><div class="authors"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Sasanika Team</span></div></div><div class="entry-content"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-5-september-2011-4/" title="Newsletter 5 – September 2011"><img alt="coin" class="alignleft post-image" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/coin.jpg" height="133" width="139" /></a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Newsletters  &gt; Newsletter 5    September 2011 - Sasanika Newsletter No. 5      In This Issue Sasanian Numismatics  Sasanian &amp; World Histor The Other Great Empire  Kingship, Rel. &amp; Coinage New Publications e-Sasanika Series Obituary Photos to Share A Word from the Editor Sasanika is dedicated to the promotion of research and study on the  history of the Sasanian dynasty. It is the aim of Sasanika: Late Antique  Near East Project to bring to light the importance of the Sasanian  civilization in the context of late antique and world history. Although  most of our team members volunteer their time to maintain the site, the  production of high-quality articles and the support of research projects  require funding. It is through the generosity of Sasanian enthusiasts  and those interested in the history of pre-Islamic Iran that Sasanika  thrives. Please consider joining us.        Rika Gyselen: Sasanian Numismatics &amp; History On February 15, 2011, Dr. Rika  ... <a class="more-link" href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-5-september-2011-4/">READ MORE</a></span></div></div><div class="post-2111 esasanika type-esasanika status-publish format-standard hentry entry"><h2 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-4/" rel="bookmark" title="Newsletter 4 – December 2010">Newsletter 4 – December 2010</a></span></h2><div class="author_name tax"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Author: </span><br /><div class="authors"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Sasanika Team</span></div></div><div class="entry-content"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-4/" title="Newsletter 4 – December 2010"><img alt="sasanika" class="alignleft post-image" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/logo-sasanika.jpg" height="133" width="133" /></a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Newsletters  &gt; Newsletter 4    December 2010 - Sasanika Newsletter No. 4      In This Issue New Website  Roshan Grant  Sasanika Workshop  ISIS in LA Lecture Series New Publications Obituary A Word from the Editor Sasanika is dedicated to the promotion of research and study on the  history of the Sasanian dynasty. It is the aim of Sasanika: Late Antique  Near East Project to bring to light the importance of the Sasanian  civilization in the context of late antique and world history. Although  most of our team members volunteer their time to maintain the site, the  production of high-quality articles and the support of research projects  require funding. We are planning major changes in the website and  inclusion of further information and research about the Sasanian Empire.  It is through the generosity of Sasanian enthusiasts and those  interested in the history of pre-Islamic Iran that Sasanika thrives.  Please consider joining us!       New and Improved Website During  ... <a class="more-link" href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-4/">READ MORE</a></span></div></div><div class="post-2161 esasanika type-esasanika status-publish format-standard hentry entry"><h2 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-3/" rel="bookmark" title="Newsletter 3 – December 2009">Newsletter 3 – December 2009</a></span></h2><div class="author_name tax"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Author: </span><br /><div class="authors"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Sasanika Team</span></div></div><div class="entry-content"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-3/" title="Newsletter 3 – December 2009"><img alt="DSCF1663-sm" class="alignleft post-image" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/DSCF1663-sm1.jpg" height="133" width="133" /></a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Newsletters  &gt; Newsletter 3    December 2009 - Sasanika Newsletter No. 3    In This Issue MESA 2009  Travel to the Republic of Azerbaijan Azerbaijan: Historical Survey  New Publications A Word from the Editor  Sasanika is dedicated to the promotion of research and study on the  history of the Sasanian dynasty. It is the aim of Sasanika: Late Antique  Near East Project to bring to light the importance of the Sasanian  civilization in the context of late antique and world history. Although  most of our team members volunteer their time to maintain the site, the  production of high-quality articles and the support of research projects  requires funding. It is through the generosity of Sasanian enthusiasts  and those interested in the history of pre-Islamic Iran that Sasanika  thrives. Please consider joining us.       MESA 2009 In November 2009 there were four panels dedicated to the Sasanian Iran.  The speakers were brought together by Professor Parvaneh Pourshariati of   ... <a class="more-link" href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-3/">READ MORE</a></span></div></div><div class="post-2135 esasanika type-esasanika status-publish format-standard hentry entry"><h2 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-2/" rel="bookmark" title="Newsletter 2 – December 2008">Newsletter 2 – December 2008</a></span></h2><div class="author_name tax"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Author: </span><br /><div class="authors"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Sasanika Team</span></div></div><div class="entry-content"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-2/" title="Newsletter 2 – December 2008"><img alt="Cereti" class="alignleft post-image" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/Cereti_b.jpg" height="133" width="133" /></a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Newsletters  &gt; Newsletter 1   December 2008 - Sasanika Newsletter No. 2    In This Issue Lectures Travelogue New Publications Obituary Fundraising A Word from the Editor  Sasanika is dedicated to the promotion of research and study on the  history of the Sasanian dynasty. It is the aim of Sasanika: Late Antique  Near East Project to bring to light the importance of the Sasanian  civilization in the context of late antique and world history. Although  most of our team members volunteer their time to maintain the site, the  production of high-quality articles and the support of research projects  requires funding. It is through the generosity of Sasanian enthusiasts  and those interested in the history of pre-Islamic Iran that Sasanika  thrives. Please consider joining us.       Dr. Carlo G. Cereti in California State University, Fullerton On November 1, 2008, California State University at Fullerton hosted the  second installment of the Rastegar Family Iraj Afshar Iranica  ... <a class="more-link" href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-2/">READ MORE</a></span></div></div><div class="post-2118 esasanika type-esasanika status-publish format-standard hentry entry"><h2 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-1/" rel="bookmark" title="Newsletter 1 – June 2008">Newsletter 1 – June 2008</a></span></h2><div class="author_name tax"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Author: </span><br /><div class="authors"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Sasanika Team</span></div></div><div class="entry-content"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-1/" title="Newsletter 1 – June 2008"><img alt="kerdir" class="alignleft post-image" src="http://www.sasanika.org/wp-content/uploads/kerdir_b.jpg" height="133" width="133" /></a></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Newsletters  &gt; Newsletter 1   June 2008 - Sasanika Newsletter No. 1      In This Issue Sasanika's Mission Our New Look e-Sasanika Programs &amp; Events Joint Project  Sasanika's Mission  One of the most remarkable civilizations of the first millennium CE was  that of the Sasanian Empire. Emanating from southern Iran's Persis (Fars) region in the third century AD, the  Sasanian domain eventually encompassed not only modern day Iran and  Iraq, but also the greater parts of Central Asia and the Near East,  including at times the regions corresponding to present-day Israel, Turkey, and Egypt. This geographically diverse empire brought together a striking array of  ethnicities and religious practices. Arameans, Arabs, Armenians,  Persians, Romans, Goths as well as a host of other peoples all lived  under the Sasanian rule. It is the aim of Sasanika: the Late Antique Near East Project to  bring to light the importance of the Sasanian civilization in the  context of world and late  ... <a class="more-link" href="http://www.sasanika.org/esasanika/newsletter-1/">READ MORE</a></span></div></div></div></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span class="titol"><span class="text">See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></span> </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6109470182677382117/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/open-access-journal-sasanika-newsletter.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6109470182677382117"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6109470182677382117"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/open-access-journal-sasanika-newsletter.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Sasanika Newsletter"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
