<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7670706713009602351</id>
   <published>2014-10-19T11:27:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2014-10-19T11:28:10.490-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="numismatics"/>
   <title type="text">SCADS: Seleucid Coins Addenda System</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<br /><a href="http://scaddenda.org/">SCADS: Seleucid Coins Addenda System: Addenda to Seleucid Coins Parts 1 and 2</a><br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://seleucidaddenda.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/horse1.jpg?w=200&amp;h=200" class="decoded" src="http://seleucidaddenda.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/horse1.jpg?w=200&amp;h=200" height="200" width="194" />&nbsp;</blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">In&nbsp;2002 and 2008 the <a href="http://www.numismatics.org/">American Numismatic Society</a> and <a href="http://cngcoins.com/">Classical Numismatic Group</a> published the two parts of&nbsp;<a href="http://www.cngcoins.com/Coin.aspx?CoinID=134194"><i>Seleucid Coins: A Comprehensive Catalogue</i></a>, by <a href="https://independent.academia.edu/ArthurHoughton">Arthur Houghton</a>, <a href="https://independent.academia.edu/CatharineLorber">Catharine Lorber</a>, and <a href="https://numismatics.academia.edu/OHoover">Oliver Hoover</a>.  The first part, by Houghton and Lorber, presented and interpreted&nbsp;all  the &nbsp;numismatic material for Seleucus I to Antiochus III known up to  2002. The second part, by Houghton, Lorber, and Hoover, did the same for  the Seleucid kings from Seleucus IV to &nbsp;Antiochus XIII. In total, more  than 2,491 primary coin types were published in these volumes.</span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">No sooner had these important books come out&nbsp;in print than new types  and varieties began to appear at the rate of almost 100 a year. This  rapid growth of material made necessary the development of a system that  could keep up with the coins.&nbsp;The <i>Seleucid Coins</i> Addenda  System (SCADS) is intended to provide online access to the new material  that has appeared since 2008. As there is no indication that the flow of  previously unrecorded types and varieties will stop anytime soon, it is  expected that the SCADS database will continue to grow over time.  Interested parties will be instantly notified of new additions to the  database through alerts on Facebook, Twitter, and direct email  subscription.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The coins in the SCADS database are categorized by ruler, making it  easy for users to find all new entries for a particular king with a  single click. Extensive tagging of entry content allows for full  searchability. Thus, for example, a user interested in all new material  depicting Apollo &nbsp;would simply enter “Apollo” as the search criterion  and SCADS would provide all the relevant entries. If a user was  interested only in Apollo on issues of bronze denomination C,  “denomination C” could be added to narrow down the search. The coins in  the database have all been given a unique catalogue&nbsp;number (SCADS1,  SCADS2, SCADS3, etc.) for ease of reference, but these only reflect the  order of entry and are not tied to the numbering system used in the <i>Seleucid Coins</i> volumes.</span></blockquote><br /><br />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7670706713009602351/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/10/scads-seleucid-coins-addenda-system.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7670706713009602351"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7670706713009602351"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/10/scads-seleucid-coins-addenda-system.html"
         title="SCADS: Seleucid Coins Addenda System"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
