<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5155402879516776261</id>
   <published>2017-01-08T22:56:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2017-01-08T22:56:38.599-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Chris Francese on Classics Podcasts</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://blogs.dickinson.edu/dcc/2017/01/08/classics-podcasts/">Classics Podcasts</a>				<br /><header class="entry-header"><div class="entry-meta">			<span class="sep">Posted on </span><a href="http://blogs.dickinson.edu/dcc/2017/01/08/classics-podcasts/" rel="bookmark" title="11:45 am"><time class="entry-date" datetime="2017-01-08T11:45:35+00:00" pubdate="">January 8, 2017</time></a><span class="by-author"> <span class="sep"> by </span> <span class="author vcard"><a class="url fn n" href="http://blogs.dickinson.edu/dcc/author/latin-poetry-podcast/" rel="author" title="View all posts by Chris Francese">Chris Francese</a></span></span>		</div></header> 	<div class="entry-content">		<blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Surprisingly few academics have learned how to podcast – but it’s a great way to reach a wider audience. A recent&nbsp;article in <em>The Guardian</em> makes the case for the medium, and offers some how-to advice:</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Todd Landman, “Podcasting is perfect for people with big ideas. Here’s how to do it.”&nbsp; <em>The Guardian</em> January 13, 2016. &nbsp;<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/higher-education-network/2016/jan/13/podcasting-is-perfect-for-big-ideas">https://www.theguardian.com/higher-education-network/2016/jan/13/podcasting-is-perfect-for-big-ideas</a></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Here is a list of classics podcasts ( I would appreciate notice if you know of others!):</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Jessica Hughes and Elton Marker, <em>Classics Confidential</em>.  Interviews with classical scholars on various subjects, since 2010. The  producers are members of the Department of Classical Studies at The Open  University.&nbsp; <a href="https://classicsconfidential.co.uk/2016/12/12/senses/">https://classicsconfidential.co.uk/2016/12/12/senses/</a></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Ryan Stitt, <em>The History of Greece Podcast</em>. By a self-confessed “enthusiastic amateur.”&nbsp; <a href="http://www.thehistoryofancientgreece.com/">http://www.thehistoryofancientgreece.com/</a></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Rhannon Evans, <em>Emperors of Rome</em>. Dr. Evans is Lecturer in Ancient Mediterranean Studies at La Trobe University, Melbourne <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/podcast/emperors-of-rome/id850148806">https://itunes.apple.com/podcast/emperors-of-rome/id850148806</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Alessandro Conti, <em>Semones Raedarii</em>. <a href="https://www.podomatic.com/podcasts/sermonesraedarii">https://www.podomatic.com/podcasts/sermonesraedarii</a> “Podcast Latinum incisum dum autoraedam moderor. Loquor prolixe et mendose de arte docendi. Interdum etiam fabulas narro.”</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Jeff Wright, <em>Trojan War: The Podcast</em>. “History’s most awesome epic.” Retelling of Trojan War mythology with comment on matters mythological.&nbsp; <a href="http://trojanwarpodcast.com/">http://trojanwarpodcast.com/</a></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Chris Francese, <em>Latin Poetry Podcast</em>. <a href="http://blogs.dickinson.edu/latin-poetry-podcast/">http://blogs.dickinson.edu/latin-poetry-podcast/</a> &nbsp;a series of short Latin passages, discussed, translated, and read aloud.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Lantern Jack, <em>Ancient Greece Declassified. </em><a href="http://greecepodcast.com/">http://greecepodcast.com/</a> “a podcast about making the Classics accessible to everyone.” “Lantern Jack” is a graduate student in ancient philosophy.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Alison Innes and Darrin Sunstrum, <em>mythTake</em>. <a href="https://mythtake.blog/">https://mythtake.blog/</a> Scholarly informed discussions of mythological heroes and topics.  Alison Innes is a journalist with an MA in classics from Brock  University, in Ontario. They also maintain a <a href="https://mythtake.blog/humanitiespodcasts/">list of humanities podcasts</a>.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Nowadays podcasting is a highly developed and diverse medium, widely  enjoyed as recreation be people as they exercise, walk, travel, go about  housework routines, etc. This is an audience hungry for new content,  eager to explore new ideas, and interested in all sorts of things. For  my podcast I did a series of 5–10 minute recordings on Latin metrics,  close readings of interesting passages, and whatever I was reading or  thinking about at the time. I felt that the podcast medium was ideal to  discuss Latin pronunciation and metrics, which are passions of mine, but  also to bring across Latin poetry as a performance art. I never focused  on grammar or translation as I would have in a classroom setting, but  tried to foster appreciation and aesthetic enjoyment. I kept the tone  informal, warm, and conversational. My model has always been <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karl_Haas">Karl Haas</a>,  the classical music radio host, who used to make the world of classical  music sound like the most welcoming, wonderful place, and who could  effortlessly pronounce half a dozen languages. With him you always felt  like you were getting the benefit of a lifetime of experience and wisdom  in the presence of a true humanist.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">There are now a variety of podcasts on classical topics, many  especially on Greek mythology and history, and Roman history. None of  them is overwhelmingly successful, or up to the Karl Haas level, and  suffice it to say there is room for a lot of innovation and improvement  in this medium.</span><br /> <blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">I’m a journalism student from Australia, who also learnt  Latin in high school (read at poetry competitions too) and I have  desperately been trying to find someone who still reads it. Your site is  perfect.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">I have been teaching myself Latin over the last 8 years and I really  enjoy your podcasts! I hope we’ll be getting some new updates soon!</span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">Many of the comments I got on my podcasts were urging me to get off  my duff and produce more, or noting problems in download. This is not  the place to get into the mechanics of podcasting. Suffice it to say  that it is well within the technological competence of most classicists,  and there are several good how-to guides to be found on the internet.  The most gratifying aspect of podcasting is that it gets you in touch  with a whole audience of like-minded enthusiasts and autodidacts out  there who really appreciate hearing from somebody with some expertise.  They often show their appreciation by leaving comments or voting in  various podcast awards competitions.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Success in the medium, as with much teaching, requires a  conversational style, a sense of humor, and an ability to tell stories.  It’s important to have fun with it, not to be turgid or pedantic.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Podcasting principles:</span><br /> <ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Be conversational. Imagine talking to your mom.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Tell good stories.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Be enthusiastic. Enjoy yourself.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Listen to other podcasts.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Always respond promptly to comments.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Buy a Snowball microphone ($50 US)</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you have thoughts about what makes an effective podcast, or know of any classics ones that I missed, please leave a comment!</span><br /><br /> 			</blockquote></div><blockquote> 	<footer class="entry-meta"><span style="font-size: x-small;">		This entry was posted in <a href="http://blogs.dickinson.edu/dcc/category/pedagogy/" rel="category tag">pedagogy</a>, <a href="http://blogs.dickinson.edu/dcc/category/how-tos/" rel="category tag">how tos</a> and tagged <a href="http://blogs.dickinson.edu/dcc/tag/podcasting/" rel="tag">podcasting</a> by <a href="http://blogs.dickinson.edu/dcc/author/latin-poetry-podcast/">Chris Francese</a>. Bookmark the <a href="http://blogs.dickinson.edu/dcc/2017/01/08/classics-podcasts/" rel="bookmark" title="Permalink to Classics Podcasts">permalink</a>.		 			</span></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5155402879516776261/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2017/01/chris-francese-on-classics-podcasts.html#comment-form"
         title="2 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5155402879516776261"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5155402879516776261"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2017/01/chris-francese-on-classics-podcasts.html"
         title="Chris Francese on Classics Podcasts"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
