<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-527600434549518880</id>
   <published>2015-10-23T14:02:00.003-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-10-23T14:02:35.402-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">New Open Access Journal: DHCommons journal</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://dhcommons.org/journal/issue-1">DHCommons journal</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://dhcommons.org/sites/dhcommons.org/themes/dhc/assets/img/logos/dhc_journal_logo.png" class="transparent" height="196" src="http://dhcommons.org/sites/dhcommons.org/themes/dhc/assets/img/logos/dhc_journal_logo.png" width="200" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">        <div class="item even"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>DHCommons</em> is the official  Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations (ADHO)-sponsored  publication of centerNet, the international network of Digital  Humanities Centers with the support of the European DARIAH  infrastructure in the Arts and Humanities. The <em>DHCommons </em>journal overlays and interacts with the <em>DHCommons </em>project registry and will provide peer review for mid-stage digital projects. The most ambitious aim of <em>DHCommons</em> is to make visible the important, developmental work that often goes  unseen in the midst of a DH project and to help DH scholars claim  departmental, disciplinary, and institutional credit for that labor. <em>DHCommons</em> will become the robust and recognizable system of academic credit that its practitioners require. </span></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><div class="item even"><span style="font-size: x-small;">As the journal of centerNet, <em>DHCommons</em> aims to bridge the  “evaluation gap” between the Digital Humanities and more traditional  disciplinary scholarship. Digital projects often continue for many years  as a continuum of work. Rather than building to a single publication  moment as monographs do, digital projects often mark mark progress  through a series of significant milestones. <em>DHCommons</em> will  provide a concrete way to certify the value of long-standing,  influential, but unfinished projects to colleagues unfamiliar with the  contours of digital scholarship. <em>DHCommons</em>’ primary goals are:</span><br /> <ol><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">To represent the global, multilingual, and multidisciplinary scope of the digital humanities community. <em>DHCommons</em>’  editors-in-chief and editorial board come from around the world, work  in a range of academic disciplines, and speak diverse languages. They  will work with Anvil Academic, <em>DHCommons’</em> publisher, to identify reviewers capable of assessing each project submitted to the journal. <em>DHCommons</em> will make its best effort to review submissions in the language submitted to the journal by the project’s directors.</span></li><li value="2"><span style="font-size: x-small;">To certify the scholarly contributions made by digital  projects-in-progress, helping scholars articulate the interventions of  their digital work to dissertation readers, hiring committees,  department colleagues, funding and research agencies, administrators,  and/or tenure and promotion committees. For DH scholars, the <em>DHCommons</em> review will compare in prominence to a peer-reviewed article. <em>DHCommons</em> aims to speak not just to digital humanities practitioners, but also to  members of each humanities discipline or other such as computer  science, from which its contributors come.</span></li><li value="3"><span style="font-size: x-small;">To foster an innovative, truly developmental model of peer review. <em>DHCommons</em> will review mid-stage, rather than finished, projects so that the ideas  and suggestions of its expert reviewers can help DH scholars improve  those projects moving forward. By mid-stage projects we refer to  projects that have moved well beyond the planning stage and have made  concrete advances without having necessarily completed the project. <em>DHCommons</em>’  review process aims to establish a productive dialogue between project  teams and reviewers which will form the core of each journal issue.  Projects will be assessed for both their form (technical aspects) and  content (humanities content).</span></li></ol><span style="font-size: x-small;">By default, all content in the DHCommons journal is licensed using a <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution license</a>. However, authors may choose another Creative Commons license for their submissions. </span></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"><div class="item even"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The journal is available online at http://dhcommons.org/journal, at  no cost. An RSS feed will be available once the first issue is  published.</span></div></div></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span><span>See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span> </span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/527600434549518880/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/10/new-open-access-journal-dhcommons.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/527600434549518880"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/527600434549518880"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/10/new-open-access-journal-dhcommons.html"
         title="New Open Access Journal: DHCommons journal"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
