<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5278937253756980754</id>
   <published>2015-07-23T17:20:00.003-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-07-23T17:20:32.353-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Oral History of Egyptology</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.ees.ac.uk/research/AEP%20Oral%20History.html">Oral History of Egyptology</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.ees.ac.uk/images/leftheader.jpg" height="78" src="http://www.ees.ac.uk/images/leftheader.jpg" width="200" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Society’s Director, Dr Chris  Naunton, is leading a project to record the memories and experiences of  Egyptologists. The personal history of the major players in Egyptology  has had an important impact on the development of the subject, and in  turn on our understanding of ancient Egypt. This has led to a growing  appreciation of the importance of Egyptological archives and to public  and media interest in the better known personalities in the field.  However, most accounts of the history of Egyptology have concentrated on  the earliest years of the subject. This project aims to create a new  resource for the study of the more recent history of the discipline: an  archive of recorded conversations capturing the thoughts and  recollections of senior Egyptologists who have played a significant part  in the development of our subject. The recordings now form part of the  archives of the EES, and represent an invaluable complement to the  photographs, notes and correspondence already housed at Doughty Mews.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Since  2008 the team has interviewed Professor Kenneth Kitchen, Professor  Harry Smith, Eric Uphill, Jessie Aldred (widow of Cyril Alrdred) and Dr  Robert Anderson and excerpts from the recordings have been made  available online (see below). In addition cassette recordings of  interviews made during the 1990s by&nbsp;Mrs Rosalind Janssen have  been&nbsp;digitised, and copies of the recordings are now kept in the digital  archive.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Recordings of some of the first interviews are now available online (see below and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/EgyptExplorSociety#g/c/56598894BE8A8BD4">here</a>). An article on the project's work to date was published in Egyptian Archaeology 36 (2010) and is available for download, <a href="http://www.ees.ac.uk/userfiles/file/EA36Naunton%281%29.pdf">here</a>.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5278937253756980754/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/07/oral-history-of-egyptology.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5278937253756980754"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5278937253756980754"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/07/oral-history-of-egyptology.html"
         title="Oral History of Egyptology"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
