<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5242873347292284351</id>
   <published>2016-10-13T07:23:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-10-13T07:23:10.773-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text"> “Freely available online”: What I really want to know about your new digital manuscript collection </title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[Dot Porter asks five important questions for those planning to put images online<br /><br />&nbsp;<a href="http://www.dotporterdigital.org/?p=263">“Freely available online”: What I really want to know about your new digital manuscript collection					</a><br /><header class="post-title"><div class="post-date">			<strong>13</strong>			<em>Thursday</em>			<span>Oct 2016</span></div><div class="post-date"><span>Dot Porter in </span><a href="http://www.dotporterdigital.org/" rel="home" title="Dot Porter Digital">Dot Porter Digital</a> ~ Development in production</div><div class="post-date">			  			</div><div class="post-date">		</div></header> 	<div class="post-content clear-fix">			<div class="post-extras">					</div><div class="post-entry">			<blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">So you’ve just digitized medieval manuscripts from your collection  and you’re putting them online. Congratulations! That’s great. Online  access to manuscripts is so important, for scholars and students and  lots of other people,&nbsp;too (I know a tattoo artist who depends on digital  images for design ideas). As the number of collections available online  has grown&nbsp;in recent years (<a href="http://digitizedmedievalmanuscripts.org/app/">DMMAP lists 545 institutions offering at least one digitized manuscript</a>),  the use of digital manuscripts by medievalists has grown right along  with supply.[1] If you’re a medievalist and you study manuscripts, I’m  confident that you regularly use digital images of manuscripts. So every  new manuscript online is a celebration. But now, you who are making  digitized medieval manuscripts available online, tell us more. How,  exactly, are you making your manuscripts available? And please don’t say  you’re making them&nbsp;<em>freely available online</em>.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">I hate this phrase. It makes my teeth clench and my heart beat  faster. It makes me feel this way because it doesn’t actually tell me&nbsp;<em>anything at all</em>.  I know you are publishing your images online, because where else would  you publish them (the age of CDRom for these things is long gone) and I  know they are going to be free, because otherwise you’d be making a very  different kind of announcement and I would be making a very different  kind of complaint (I’m looking at you,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.brill.com/products/online-resources/codices-vossiani-latini-online">Codices Vossiani Latini Online</a>). What else can you tell me?</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Here are the questions I want answered when I read about an online manuscript collection.</span><br /> <ol><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><strong>How are your images licensed?</strong> </strong>This  is going to be my first question, and for me it’s the most important  because it defines what I can do with your images. Are you placing them  in the public domain, licensing them <a href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">CC0</a>? <a href="http://openn.library.upenn.edu/">This is what we do at my institution</a>,  and it’s what I like to see, since, you know, medieval manuscripts are  not in copyright, at least not in the USA (I understand things are more  complicated in Europe). If not CC0, then what restrictions are you  placing on them? <a href="https://creativecommons.org/choose/">Creative Commons has a tool where you can select the restrictions you want and then gives you license options</a>. Consider using it as part of your decision-making process.&nbsp;A clear license is a good license.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>How can I find your manuscripts?</strong>&nbsp;Is there a search and browse function on your site, or do I have to know what I’m looking for when I come in?</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Will your images&nbsp;be served through the <a href="http://iiif.io/">International Image Interoperability Framework</a>&nbsp;(IIIF)?</strong>&nbsp;IIIF  has become very popular recently, and for good reason – it enables  users to pull manuscripts from any IIIF-compliant repository into a  single interface, for example comparing manuscripts from different  institutions in a single browser window. A user will need access to the <strong>IIIF manifests</strong>&nbsp;to  make this work – the manifest is essentially a file containing metadata  about the manuscript and a list of links to image files. So, if you are  using IIIF, will the manifests be easily accessible so I can use them  for my own purposes? (For reference, <a href="http://www.e-codices.unifr.ch/en/searchresult/list/one/kba/0003">e-codices links IIIF manifests to each manuscript record</a>, and it couldn’t be easier to find them.)</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>What kind of interface will you have?</strong> I usually assume that a page-turning interface will be provided, but if there is some other interface (like, for example, <a href="http://brbl-dl.library.yale.edu/vufind/Record/3519597">Yale University, which links individual images from a thumbnail strip on the manuscript record</a>)  I’d like to know that. Will users be able to build collections or make  annotations on page images, or contribute transcriptions? I’d like to  know that, too.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>How can I get your images?</strong> I know you’re proud of  your interface, but I might want to do something else with your images,  either download them to my own machine or point to them from an  interface I’ve built myself or borrowed from someone else (maybe using  IIIF, but maybe not). If you provide&nbsp;IIIF manifests I have a list of  URLs I can use to point to or download your image files (<a href="http://www.dotporterdigital.org/?p=250">more</a> or <a href="http://www.dotporterdigital.org/?p=266">less</a>,  depending on how your server works), but if you’re not using IIIF, is  there some other way I can easily get a list of image URLs for a  manuscript? For example, <a href="http://openn.library.upenn.edu/">OPenn</a> and <a href="http://thedigitalwalters.org/">The Digital Walters</a> publish TEI documents with facsimile lists. If you can’t provide a  list, can you at least share how your urls are constructed? If I know  how they’re made I can probably figure out how to build them myself.</span></li></ol><span style="font-size: x-small;">Those are the big five questions I like to have answered when I read  about a new digital manuscript collection, and they very rarely  are.&nbsp;Please, please, please, next time you announce a new collection,  try to go beyond&nbsp;<em>freely available online</em> and tell us all more about&nbsp;<em>how</em> your collection will be made available, and what users will&nbsp;be able and allowed to do with it.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">[1] In 2002 33% of survey respondents reported manuscript facsimiles  “print mostly, electronic sometimes” and 47% reported using “print  only”. In 2011, 44% reported using them “electronic mostly, print  sometimes” and 17% reported using “electronic only”. This is an enormous  shift. From Dot Porter, “Medievalists and the Scholarly Digital  Edition,”&nbsp;<em>Scholarly Editing: The Annual of the Association for Documentary Editing</em> Volume&nbsp;34, 2013.&nbsp;<a href="http://www.scholarlyediting.org/2013/essays/essay.porter.html">http://www.scholarlyediting.org/2013/essays/essay.porter.html</a></span></blockquote></div></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5242873347292284351/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/10/freely-available-online-what-i-really.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5242873347292284351"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5242873347292284351"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/10/freely-available-online-what-i-really.html"
         title=" “Freely available online”: What I really want to know about your new digital manuscript collection "/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
