<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5226422678327412061</id>
   <published>2016-06-03T19:11:00.003-04:00</published>
   <updated>2016-06-03T19:11:42.016-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Pleiades News: Recent Improvements (May 2016) </title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/news/blog/recent-improvements">Recent Improvements (May 2016)                </a><br />                                                                                               <div id="viewlet-below-content-title"><div class="documentByLine" id="plone-document-byline"><blockquote class="tr_bq">           <span class="documentAuthor">      <span style="font-size: x-small;">Creators: <span><a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/author/thomase">Tom Elliott</a></span>    </span></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">                 Copyright © The Contributors. Sharing and remixing permitted under  terms of the Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License (cc-by).       </span><div class="documentModified">    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span>      Last modified     </span>    Jun 03, 2016 05:01 PM        </span></div></blockquote></div></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="documentDescription" id="parent-fieldname-description">                   <span style="font-size: x-small;">On May 13th, 2016, the Pleiades 3 development team  deployed a package of upgrades to the Pleiades website. This blog post  summarizes the changes.                 </span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">                                                                                               </span><div id="viewlet-above-content-body"> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;">                             </span></blockquote><div id="content-core"><blockquote>                                                <div class="newsImageContainer">            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/news/blog/recent-improvements/image/image_view_fullscreen" id="parent-fieldname-image">               <img alt="Recent Improvements (May 2016)" class="newsImage" height="128" src="http://pleiades.stoa.org/news/blog/recent-improvements/image_mini" title="" width="128" />            </a></span>                     </div></blockquote><div class="plain" id="parent-fieldname-text"><blockquote>            <span style="font-size: x-small;">The primary concern that motivated the <a class="external-link" href="http://isaw.nyu.edu/" target="_self" title="">Institute for the Study of the Ancient World</a> at New York University&nbsp;<a class="external-link" href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/docs/reports/pleiades-3-proposal-narrative/view" target="_self" title="">to apply for a Digital Humanities Implementation grant</a>&nbsp;for <em>Pleiades</em>&nbsp;from the <a class="external-link" href="http://www.neh.gov/" target="_self" title="">National Endowment for the Humanities</a> was website speed and reliability. <a class="external-link" href="https://securegrants.neh.gov/publicquery/main.aspx?f=1&amp;gn=HK-230973-15" target="_self" title="">The grant was awarded in August 2015</a> and work began in earnest in January 2016.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Late on the 13th of May, 2016, software developers from <a class="external-link" href="https://jazkarta.com/" target="_self" title="">Jazkarta, Inc.</a>,  who are working on the grant under subcontract to NYU, deployed a  series of software upgrades designed primarily to address site  performance. These upgrades were deployed to a new, more capable web  server, provided under contract by long-time <em>Pleiades</em> hosting provider <a class="external-link" href="https://www.tummy.com/" target="_self" title="">Tummy.com</a>. During the subsequent two weeks, Jazkarta and Tummy personnel have collaborated with members of the <a class="external-link" href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/credits" target="_self" title=""><em>Pleiades</em> editorial college</a> to monitor, analyze, and tune these upgrades for optimum performance.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Compared with the same period two years ago, <strong>the average download time for <em>Pleiades</em> pages has improved by nearly 75%</strong>,  from a painfully-long 12 seconds down to about 3 seconds. The following  plot, generated with Google Analytics, provides a day-by-day visual  comparison.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="A graph of page load timings, generated with Google Analytics." class="image-inline" src="http://pleiades.stoa.org/news/blog/assets-2016/initial-2016-performance-improvements" title="Initial 2016 Performance Improvements" /></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Google defines average page download time as follows: "the average  amount of time (in seconds) it takes for pages from the sample set to  load, from initiation of the page view (e.g. click on a page link) to  load completion in the browser."</span><br /> <h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Improved and Reinstated Features</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">These performance improvements have been achieved even though we have <strong>re-enabled or upgraded several features</strong> that were aging, had failed, or had been disabled previously in order  to combat periodic site slow downs and failures. These include:</span><br /> <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Flickr "Photos" Portlet</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="The Pleiades Flickr Portlet, as seen on the Nemea page. The portrait photo, by Carole Radato, depicts the Temple of Zeus at Nemea." class="image-inline" src="http://pleiades.stoa.org/news/blog/assets-2016/flickr-porlet-on-nemea-page" style="float: right;" title="Flickr Porlet on Nemea page" />The <em>Pleiades Flickr Photos Portlet</em>&nbsp;once again appears on each place page. It automatically queries <a class="external-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/" target="_self" title="">the Flickr photo-sharing website</a> for images that have been "<a class="external-link" href="http://horothesia.blogspot.com/2011/12/pleiades-flickr-and-ancient-world-image.html" target="_self" title="">machine tagged</a>" using <a class="internal-link" href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/help/what-are-pleiades-uris" target="_self" title=""><em>Pleiades</em> identifiers</a>.  The portlet constructs a link to all such images. Moreover, if the  editorial college has identified one of these images as a "place  portrait image" by adding it to the <a class="external-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/groups/pleiades-places/" target="_self" title="">Pleiades Places Group</a> on Flickr, that image is displayed in the portlet. The portlet was updated to work with the latest version of <a class="external-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/services/api/" target="_self" title="">Flickr's Application Programming Interface (API)</a>.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The screen capture at right shows the <em>Flickr Photos Portlet</em> as it appears on <a class="external-link" href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/places/570504" target="_self" title="">the <em>Pleiades</em> place page for ancient Nemea</a> in Greece. The featured portrait photo was taken and published on Flickr under open license by <a class="external-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/41523983@N08/" target="_self" title="">Carole Raddato (a.k.a. Following Hadrian)</a>.</span><br /> <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Pelagios "Related Content" Portlet<span>&nbsp;</span></span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Image of the Pelagios Portlet as it appears on the Pleiades Place page for Ara Ubiorum/Col. Claudia Ara Agrippinensium." class="image-inline" src="http://pleiades.stoa.org/news/blog/assets-2016/pelagios-porlet-for-cologne" style="float: left;" title="Pelagios Porlet for Cologne" />The collaborative <a class="external-link" href="http://commons.pelagios.org/" target="_self" title="">Pelagios Commons</a> project (funded by the <a class="external-link" href="https://mellon.org/" target="_self" title="">Andrew W. Mellon Foundation</a>) has been a long-time <em>Pleiades</em> partner. Through its <a class="external-link" href="http://pelagios.org/peripleo/map" target="_self" title=""><em>Peripleo</em> website</a>, the Pelagios community collates and maps <a class="external-link" href="http://pelagios.org/peripleo/pages/datasets" target="_self" title="">open data about the ancient world that has been published online</a> by over twenty (and growing) academic projects, museums, libraries, and archives. Following <a class="external-link" href="https://github.com/pelagios/pelagios-cookbook/wiki/Joining-Pelagios" target="_self" title="">procedures laid down by the Pelagios team</a>,  these data providers include in their publications information about  the relationships between ancient places (as represented in <em>Pleiades</em>)  and the artifacts, art works, texts, historical persons, and other  objects of interest registered, described, or depicted in their data. &nbsp;</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The <em>Pleiades Pelagios Releated Content Portlet</em> appears on each place page (screen shot at left from <a class="external-link" href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/places/108751" target="_self" title="">the <em>Pleiades</em> place page for ancient Ara Ubiorum, modern Cologne</a>). It automatically queries the Pelagios <em>Peripleo</em> website for related records in other databases and returns a summary of matching records. The portlet creates links to a <em>Peripleo</em> query for each matching dataset. The portlet has been updated to work with the latest version of <a class="external-link" href="https://github.com/pelagios/peripleo/blob/master/README.md" target="_self" title="">the <em>Peripleo</em> API</a>.</span><br /> <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>Dickinson College Commentaries</em> (DCC) and the AWLD.js</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="external-link" href="http://dcc.dickinson.edu/nepos-hannibal/chapter-1" target="_self" title=""><img alt="A Pleiades link, enhanced with a mouseover pop-up provided by the Ancient World Linked Data JavaScript library, on a page of the Dickinson College Commentaries website." class="image-inline" src="http://pleiades.stoa.org/news/blog/assets-2016/awld-js-pop-up-in-dcc" style="float: right;" title="AWLD.js pop-up in DCC" /></a>The <em><a class="external-link" href="http://dcc.dickinson.edu/" target="_self" title="">Dickinson College Commentaries</a></em> (and several other websites) make use of the <a class="external-link" href="http://isawnyu.github.io/awld-js/" target="_self" title=""><em>Ancient World Linked Data JavaScript Library</em> (AWLD.js)</a> to enhance links to <em>Pleiades</em> (and other data sources) with informative pop-up windows as illustrated  in the screen capture at right. AWLD.js creates these pop-ups in each  user's browser by scanning the current page for links to select websites  (like <em>Pleiades</em>). It then pre-fetches information from those websites -- in <em>Pleiades</em>' case, it requests <a class="external-link" href="http://api.pleiades.stoa.org/" target="_self" title="">the GeoJSON serialization</a> for each place link -- and uses the contents to prepare the contents of the pop-ups.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Prior to the most recent upgrade, the <em>Pleiades</em> website was  vulnerable to performance degradation when receiving multiple page (or  JSON serialization) requests in a short amount of time. Consequently, a  web page with several <em>Pleiades</em> links and AWLD.js &nbsp;(especially  when visited by multiple users at one time, as might happen during a  class session) could significantly slow or even disable <em>Pleiades</em> for a period of time. To mitigate such effects, we had configured our  server to block large numbers of requests coming from a particular  external page. This meant that users of sites like DCC often got  incomplete pop-ups or even non-working links.&nbsp;The upgraded website is no  longer vulnerable to these effects, and so we have updated the server  configuration to ensure the best possible user experience for our  AWLD.js friends.&nbsp;</span><br /> <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Bots, Spiders, and Crawlers</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Requests for <em>Pleiades</em> resources don't just come from browsers. A variety of automated agents (often called <a class="external-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_bot" target="_self" title="">bots</a>, spiders, or <a class="external-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_crawler" target="_self" title="">crawlers</a>) gather information from websites for all manner of purposes. The major search engines (e.g., <a class="external-link" href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/182072?hl=en" target="_self" title="">Google</a>, <a class="external-link" href="https://www.bing.com/webmaster/help/which-crawlers-does-bing-use-8c184ec0" target="_self" title="">Bing</a>, <a class="external-link" href="https://chineseseoshifu.com/blog/what-is-baiduspider.html" target="_self" title="">Baidu</a>),  as well as many minor ones, employ bots to maintain and update the  digital indices of web content that underpin the services they provide.  The <a class="external-link" href="https://archive.org/details/archive.org_bot" target="_self" title="">Internet Archive operates a bot</a> that retrieves web pages for inclusion in <a class="external-link" href="https://archive.org/" target="_self" title="">the <em>Wayback Machine</em></a>. Some <em>Pleiades</em> and Pelagios partner projects use bots to gather, check, or update local copies of <em>Pleiades</em> data for project use. Still other bots serve commercial data-mining  purposes, or academic or student research projects in computer and  information science. And there are bots that serve more nefarious  purposes, scanning servers and software for security vulnerabilities  that can be exploited or hacked. Bots that make many rapid-fire  requests, that ignore usage guidelines set forth in the <em>Pleiades</em> robots.txt file, or that happen to visit concurrently with other bots have all caused performance problems for <em>Pleiades</em> in the past.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The same, old traffic-limiting factors described in the preceding  section were also designed to reduce the impact of bots. These  restrictions have now been removed.&nbsp;The upgraded site is now serving the  Google, Bing, and Archive.org bots -- as well as all other third-party  bots without a history of misbehavior -- at full speed and without  restriction.&nbsp;</span><br /> <h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Next Steps</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Another key aspect of the upgrade was the installation of tools to perform "<a class="external-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_analytics" target="_self" title="">software analytics</a>" on the <em>Pleiades</em> website. This new feature, which has been implemented with <a class="external-link" href="https://newrelic.com/" target="_self" title="">the commercial New Relic service</a>. It provides <em>Pleiades</em> software developers and managing editors with performance metrics gathered from within each component of the <em>Pleiades</em> web application. The resulting insight enables us to tune performance  in specific areas&nbsp;and to target code components for additional,  performance-enhancing upgrade or replacement. We will continue in coming  weeks to monitor site performance, using New Relic and Google  Analytics, to seek additional improvements.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">We are also undertaking a number of feature enhancements, as outlined  in the original proposal. At present, planning and coding work is  underway on upgrades to our:</span><br /> <ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">JSON serializations and new comprehensive JSON dumps);</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="external-link" href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/vocabularies/time-periods" target="_self" title="">Time Periods Vocabulary</a> (to include integration with <a class="external-link" href="http://perio.do/" target="_self" title="">the <em>PeriodO</em> gazetteer of time periods</a>);</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="external-link" href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/vocabularies/place-types" target="_self" title="">Place Types Vocabulary</a> (to include integration with <a class="external-link" href="http://www.getty.edu/research/tools/vocabularies/aat/" target="_self" title="">the Getty <em>Art and Architecture Thesaurus</em></a> and the <em><a class="external-link" href="http://dare.ht.lu.se/" target="_self" title="">Digital Atlas of the Roman Empire</a></em>);&nbsp;</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Bibliographic citation system (to include integration with <a class="external-link" href="http://zotero.org/" target="_self" title="">the <em>Zotero.org</em> citation management system</a>).</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">Updates will be announced on this blog.</span><br /> <h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Technical Specifics</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Major changes incorporated in the recent upgrade include:</span><br /> <ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Moved to a new dedicated host, running <a class="external-link" href="http://releases.ubuntu.com/16.04/" target="_self" title="">Ubuntu 16.04 LTS</a>, with more memory and faster processors</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Upgraded &nbsp;the web application framework and content management system from Plone 3 to <a class="external-link" href="https://plone.org/news/old-news/plone-4-3-released" target="_self" title="">Plone 4.3</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Bug fixes in core code for speed, lower memory footprint, and more efficient use of the <a class="external-link" href="http://www.zope.org/" target="_self" title="">Zope</a> catalog and database</span></li><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">More efficient population of pages, maps, and editors' dashboards and review lists</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">More efficient creation of alternate serializations of content and export "dumps" via <a class="external-link" href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/downloads" target="_self" title="">the downloads page</a></span></li></ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Removed under- and un-used code components and plugins</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Eliminated <a class="external-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightweight_Directory_Access_Protocol" target="_self" title="">LDAP</a> for user account management</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Fixes to icons, map symbols, and vocabulary displays</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Scripted deployment with <a class="external-link" href="https://www.ansible.com/" target="_self" title="">Ansible</a></span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">Users are invited to follow progress, report problems, request features via <a class="external-link" href="https://github.com/isawnyu/pleiades-gazetteer/issues" target="_self" title="">the <em>Pleiades</em> gazetteer issue tracker on Github</a>.</span></blockquote></div></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5226422678327412061/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/06/pleiades-news-recent-improvements-may.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5226422678327412061"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5226422678327412061"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2016/06/pleiades-news-recent-improvements-may.html"
         title="Pleiades News: Recent Improvements (May 2016) "/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
