<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8429908667355765966</id>
   <published>2015-08-25T12:17:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2015-08-25T12:17:27.827-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Recently Published at Archaeopress: Open Access</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: small;"><a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/defaultAll.asp?OpenAccess=Y&amp;intro=true"><span><span style="font-family: inherit;">Recently Published at<span> Archaeopress: Open Access</span></span></span></a></span> <br /><div style="text-align: center;"><blockquote><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/8370411E51564553B0C7780CF07BE3F9%5C9781784911478.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Bronze Age Tell Communities in Context – An Exploration Into Culture, Society and the Study of European Prehistory</b> <i>Part 1 – Critique: Europe and the Mediterranean</i> by Tobias L. Kienlin. vi+168 pages; illustrated throughout in colour and black &amp; white.<img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This study challenges current modelling of Bronze Age  tell communities in the Carpathian Basin in terms of the evolution of  functionally-differentiated, hierarchical or ‘proto-urban’ society under  the influence of Mediterranean palatial centres. It is argued that the  narrative strategies employed in mainstream theorising of the ‘Bronze  Age’ in terms of inevitable social ‘progress’ sets up an artificial  dichotomy with earlier Neolithic groups. The result is a reductionist  vision of the Bronze Age past which denies continuity evident in many  aspects of life and reduces our understanding of European Bronze Age  communities to some weak reflection of foreign-derived social types – be  they notorious Hawaiian chiefdoms or Mycenaean palatial rule. In order  to justify this view, this study looks broadly in two directions:  temporal and spatial. First, it is asked how Late Neolithic tell sites  of the Carpathian Basin compare to Bronze Age ones, and if we are  entitled to assume structural difference or rather ‘progress’ between  both epochs. Second, it is examined if a Mediterranean ‘centre’ in any  way can contribute to our understanding of Bronze Age tell communities  on the ‘periphery’. It is argued that current Neo-Diffusionism has us  essentialise from much richer and diverse evidence of past social and  cultural realities. Instead, archaeology is called on to contribute to  an understanding of the historically specific expressions of the human  condition and human agency, not to reduce past lives to abstract stages  on the teleological ladder of social evolution. <br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>This book is also available in paperback, priced £38.00. <a href="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/displayProductDetail.asp?id=%7BA9CE4A63-76D9-4635-A366-34EA8A3CB165%7D">Click here for more information.</a></b></span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>&nbsp;</b></span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/748FDAB8EFBC4270BEB3B8E13CB85636%5C9788876992278.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Ostentazione di rango e manifestazione del potere agli albori della società micenea</b> by Federica Gonzato. 262 pages; black &amp; white illustrations. Italian text. 4 2012. ISBN 9788876992278. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Le manifestazioni materiali del potere sono una  caratteristica fondamentale delle società umane e costituiscono  pertanto, per lo studioso delle culture antiche, una delle chiavi di  lettura più ricche e promettenti. In questo volume, l’autrice propone  una interpretazione delle prime fasi di formazione (XVII-XV secolo a.C.)  dell’organizzazione sociale della cultura micenea attraverso l’esame  degli attributi di potere (insignia dignitatis) trovati nelle sepolture  di questo periodo in Argolide, culla della civiltà micenea in Grecia. Lo  sviluppo della realtà micenea precedente la grande fase palaziale del  XIV-XIII secolo a.C. viene analizzato da un punto di vista  etnoantropologico e storico, introducendo una fondamentale distinzione  fra beni di prestigio ed attributi di potere (spesso effimeri e  polisemantici, in quanto soggetti ad una continua variazione della  nozione di valore), ma ponendo anche attenzione alle storia delle  dinamiche sociali e alle strategie per il mantenimento della leadership  attraverso la manipolazione di una ideologia di cui gliinsignia  dignitatis rappresentano la materializzazione.</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/D46DFB58DEC94EFA84388C6ECB1FC211%5C9788876992230.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Site, Artefacts and Landscape</b> <i>Prehistoric Borġ in-Nadur, Malta</i> by Davide Tanasi and Nicholas C. Vella. 450 pages; illustrated throughout in black &amp; white. 3 450. ISBN 9788876992230. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Bronze Age of the Maltese archipelago has long been  overlooked by archaeologists whose attention has mostly been focused on  the Late Neolithic temples. This book attempts to understand the  islands’ Bronze Age society in the course of the second millennium BC by  exploring the history of Borg in-Nadur in south-east Malta. The site of  a megalithic temple and re-used in later periods when a fortified  settlement was built on the plateau, Borg in-Nadur was visited by  travellers and antiquarians in the course of the Early Modern period,  and was investigated by archaeologists in the late nineteenth and early  twentieth century. This collection of essays discusses the early  attempts to understand the site, and presents a comprehensive catalogue  of the finds that have never been properly published. It also considers  the site in its local landscape setting and in its regional  south-central Mediterranean context, and explores issues related to past  and present public outreach and site management.</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/248FD57DD1F34263A763FFB8002165D2%5C9788876991158.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>La necropoli protostorica di Montagna di Caltagirone</b> by Davide Tanasi. 451 pages; illustrated throughout in black &amp; white. 1 2008. ISBN 9788876991158. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Il sito della Montagna di Caltagirone (CT), indagato per  la prima volta in modo sistematico da Paolo Orsi nel 1903, rappresenta  un importante caso studio per la pre e protostoria siciliana e  costituisce un osservatorio privilegiato per un’analisi delle  problematiche legate all’interrelazione tra popolazioni autoctone e  straniere. Dalla metà del II millennio a.C. fino alla colonizzazione  greca, infatti, la Montagna ha svolto un ruolo fondamentale nei fenomeni  d’aggregazione della popolazione del territorio calatino. Nell’età del  Bronzo Tardo (XIII-XI secolo a.C.), il suo insediamento ha raggiunto il  momento di maggiore splendore, con l’impianto della grande necropoli,  ponendosi, insieme a Pantalica, come principale centro produttore di  cultura della Sicilia Orientale.</span></div></div></blockquote><br /><blockquote><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/5F963497D9894750822D7139DBD291E6%5C9781784911454.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Found: the Palaeolithic of Qatar</b> <i>Taken from <b>Proceedings of the Seminar for Arabian Studies 45 (2015)</b></i> by Julie E. Scott-Jackson, Jeffrey I. Rose, William Scott-Jackson &amp;  Faisal al-Naimi. Pages 329–336; colour and black &amp; white  illustrations. PSAS. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The seeming lack of evidence for a Palaeolithic presence  in Qatar has been enigmatic. This has now changed. Here we report on  discoveries made by the PADMAC Unit during 2013/2014 and the  far-reaching implications of these findings. Our preliminary analysis of  the Qatar lithic assemblages — QSS25, QSS29 (PADMAC Unit collection)  and A-group Site I and A-group Site III (Kapel collection) — revealed  the presence of large chopping tools and crude ‘Abbevillian’ cores, both  indicative of an early stage within the lower Palaeolithic period,  while the absence of classic Acheulean hand axes might even suggest a  date exceeding one million years. Furthermore, the particular suite of  technological traits we identified in Umm Taqa ‘B-group’ Site XXXIV  (Kapel collection) lithic assemblage, are characteristic of middle–upper  Palaeolithic transitional industries found in the Levant, Nile Valley,  and southern Arabia. Hence, we tentatively assign the ‘Taqan’ industry  to the upper Palaeolithic. Specific lithics from the QSS32 (PADMAC Unit  collection) assemblage, allude to further ‘Taqan’ sites in southern  Qatar.</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/F90D7E0BF4064CA5A105D87B1DD24323%5C9781784911454.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>Generosity, gift giving, and gift avoiding in southern Oman</b> <i>Taken from <b>Proceedings of the Seminar for Arabian Studies 45 (2015)</b></i> by Marielle Risse. Pages 289–296. PSAS. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Gibali (Jibbali/Shahri) is a Modern South Arabian  language spoken in the coastal plain and mountains of the Dhofar region  of southern Oman. Although there are researchers actively documenting  Gibali, there has been little anthropological work on the speakers of  this non-written language. Building on nine years of research about, and  interactions with, Gibali speakers the author describes the concept of  the gift in the Arab, Muslim, tribal culture of Gibali speakers. This  article tries to form an appreciation of Gibalis by explaining their  understanding of the definition of gifts as well as gift giving,  receiving, reciprocating, and avoiding. From the field of gift theory,  the author draws on Mauss, Godelier, Bourdieu, Appadurai, and Godbout  and Caillé, to create a framework for the ‘what’, ‘when’, ‘why’, and  ‘how’ of gifts. From the fields of travel writing and history, examples  from Wilfred Thesiger and the memoirs of soldiers from the Dhofar War  (1965–1975) are used to provide a historical perspective. The result is  an insight into a culture in which gifts are, for the most part, not  necessary as there are many limits placed on who can give/receive, the  time to give/receive, and the kind of object that is considered a gift.&nbsp;</span></div><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></div></div><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="left" hspace="5" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Photos/CD167AA93BEB48BFAAA0EF0867D34BB7%5C9781784911249.jpg" style="display: block; text-align: left; vertical-align: top;" vspace="2" width="150" /><b>To See the Invisible</b> <i>Karelian Rock Art</i> by Arsen Faradzhev. iv+19 pages; illustrated throughout in colour and black &amp; white.ISBN 9781784911249. <img align="absmiddle" alt="Book contents page" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butContents.gif" width="82" /><img align="absmiddle" alt="Download" border="0" height="25" src="http://archaeopress.com/ArchaeopressShop/Public/imagesArchaeopress/butDownload.gif" width="82" /><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">This contribution considers 25 years of discovery of the  possible origins and development of the Rock Art Tradition to create  Karelian Rock Art images under the open sky through the analysis of  different types of intercessions into the horizontal surface of granite  rocks. <br /><br />Karelian petroglyphs are located-at the eastern bank of the Onega Lake  and 300 km to the north, close to the southern bank of the White Sea.  One of them, the “New Zalavruga,” was discovered by the expedition of  U.Savvateev under the Neolithic cultural layer and sterile sand layer in  1963-1968. This is a great and very rare opportunity to obtain direct  dating of the end of the tradition to create Karelian Rock Art images  around 5-6 ka ago. Therefore, the task was to find the “Invisible”  evidences of the tradition’s origins and development similar to both  regions via the different use of context.</span></div></div></blockquote><div class="bookBox"><div class="bookBoxInner">And See also <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/04/recently-published-at-archaeopress-open.html">here</a>, and <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/07/archaeopress-open-access.html">here</a>.</div></div></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8429908667355765966/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/08/recently-published-at-archaeopress-open.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8429908667355765966"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8429908667355765966"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2015/08/recently-published-at-archaeopress-open.html"
         title="Recently Published at Archaeopress: Open Access"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
