<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8487094831235187971</id>
   <published>2014-03-21T11:43:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2014-03-21T11:43:14.312-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Announcing the Perseus Lexical Inventory</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://sites.tufts.edu/perseusupdates/2014/03/21/announcing-the-perseus-lexical-inventory-an-open-linked-data-set/">Announcing the Perseus Lexical Inventory – an open linked data set</a><br /><div class="entry-meta">       <span class="meta-sep">by</span> <span class="author vcard"><a class="url fn n" href="http://sites.tufts.edu/perseusupdates/author/balmas01/" title="View all posts by Bridget  Almas">Bridget  Almas</a></span> <span class="meta-prep meta-prep-author">Posted on</span> <a href="http://sites.tufts.edu/perseusupdates/2014/03/21/announcing-the-perseus-lexical-inventory-an-open-linked-data-set/" rel="bookmark" title="7:49 am"><span class="entry-date">March 21, 2014</span></a>      </div><div class="entry-content">      <blockquote class="tr_bq"><div dir="ltr"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Many different linguistic services and tools are  dependent on lexical information as it is commonly found in Latin and  Greek dictionaries. Most of these applications rely on their own  implementation of dictionaries, stem databases etc. but there is no  centralized open-access resource on which these services can draw for  supporting data. The Perseus Digital Library is releasing its lexical  data as an open linked data set, starting with Latin and to be followed  by Greek, &nbsp;in the hopes that it may eventually become such a resource.  Work on producing this data set has been a collaborative effort, and  would not have been possible without the guidance of <a href="http://shot.holycross.edu/%7Ensmith/">Neel Smith</a> of Holy Cross and <a href="http://classics.uchicago.edu/faculty/dik">Helma Dik</a> of the University of Chicago.</span></div><div dir="ltr"><br /></div><div dir="ltr"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The core of the Perseus Lexical Inventory is a <a href="http://www.homermultitext.org/hmt-doc/cite/index.html">CITE collection</a> of Lexical Entity URIs. Each Lexical Entity identifier has associated  properties including a normalized form of the lexical entity (or lemma)  and a short definition. &nbsp;&nbsp;The accompanying linked data set includes  links between the Lexical Entity URIs, morpheus lemmas, and entries in  the Lewis and Short lexicons on <a href="http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/">Perseus</a>, <a href="http://alpheios.net/">Alpheios</a> and <a href="http://logeion.uchicago.edu/">Logeion</a>. &nbsp;A VOID file describing the data set is available at<a href="http://data.perseus.org/ds/lexical/void"> http://data.perseus.org/ds/lexical/void</a> and a SPARQL endpoint for querying the data set is at&nbsp;<a href="http://services.perseus.tufts.edu/fuseki/sparql.html">http://services.perseus.tufts.edu/fuseki/sparql.html</a>. &nbsp;&nbsp;There is also a simple demonstration query form that looks up entries based upon the Latin form at <a href="http://perseids.org/tools/lexical/query.html">http://perseids.org/tools/lexical/query.html</a>. &nbsp;The <a href="https://wikihub.berkeley.edu/display/pbamboo/Morphological+Analysis+Service+Contract+Description+-+v1.1.1">Tufts Morphology Service</a>&nbsp;(currently available at <a href="http://services.perseids.org/bsp/morphologyservice?_wadl">http://services.perseids.org/bsp/morphologyservice</a> )&nbsp;also supplies the corresponding Lexical Entity URIs for lemmas returned by Morpheus.</span></div><div dir="ltr"><br /></div><div dir="ltr"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Subsequent updates to the data set will include links to  ontologies and other collections of uniquely identifiable entities,  including part of speech, lexical tokens or forms, stems, prefixes and  suffixes, morphological analyses, metrical data, orthographical  variants, and named entities. &nbsp;The lexical entities and tokens will also  be linked to their occurrences in dictionaries and other lexica, texts  (i.e. of the Perseus corpus, among others), treebanks, etc. Finally we  expect to link to other established and emerging data sets, including  the <a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/">Pleiades</a> Gazetteer and the <a href="http://snapdrgn.net/">SNAP</a> dataset of ancient prosopography, among others.</span></div><div dir="ltr"><br /></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">Our ultimate goal is for the lexical data sets to be completely open  with various channels, including both user interfaces and service-based  APIs, through which people and systems can contribute new data and  corrections.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">In keeping with the approach we have been taking with the release of our data (see the Perseus Catalog’s <a href="http://sites.tufts.edu/perseuscatalog/documentation/release-notes/next-steps-roadmap/roadmap-towards-linked-data-standards-compliance/">Roadmap towards Linked Data standards compliance</a>)  we are releasing the data knowing we have much work to do still, and  will make progress towards the larger vision in incremental steps. &nbsp;Our  next steps will include release of a companion Greek Lexical Inventory,  followed by the addition of the stem and lexical token data sets and  development of APIs and interfaces for using and contributing to the  data.</span></blockquote><br />            </div><div class="entry-meta">       <span class="meta-sep"><br /></span><a href="http://sites.tufts.edu/perseusupdates/2014/03/21/announcing-the-perseus-lexical-inventory-an-open-linked-data-set/" rel="bookmark" title="7:49 am"><span class="entry-date"></span></a>      </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8487094831235187971/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/03/announcing-perseus-lexical-inventory.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8487094831235187971"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8487094831235187971"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/03/announcing-perseus-lexical-inventory.html"
         title="Announcing the Perseus Lexical Inventory"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
